<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000117_000218_0000">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Letter,
					<name>Jos W. Allen</name>
				                    in Nashville, Tenn. to David Burford in Dixons Springs, Smith Co., Tenn.,<date when="1854-05-29">1854 May 29</date>
            </title>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
          <name>Jennings, Sabra</name>
        </respStmt>
        <author>
          <name type="person">Jos W. Allen</name>
        </author>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
        <date>2013</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
        </availability>
        <idno type="SPC">0012_000117_000218_0000</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Letter, Jos W. Allen in Nashville, Tenn. to David Burford in Dixons Springs, Smith Co., Tenn.,1854 May 29</title>
          <date when="1854-05-29">1854 May 29</date>
          <author>
            <name type="person">Jos W. Allen</name>
          </author>
          <extent>5 pages</extent>
          <note type="collection">David Burford Papers</note>
          <note type="manuscript">MS.1185</note>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
        <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
        <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
        <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as "turn page over" have been
						omitted.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy>
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="LCSH">
          <term>Slavery -- Tennessee</term>
          <term>Tennessee -- Commerce.</term>
          <term>Tennessee -- Politics and government -- To 1865.</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change when="2013" who="Jennings, Sabra">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
      <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e38">
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_000117_000218_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e39"/>
        <p>Via Chattanooga</p>
        <p>&amp; Nashville</p>
        <p>Maj D. Burford</p>
        <p>Dixons Springs,</p>
        <p>Smith Count</p>
        <p>Tennessee</p>
        <p>From Jo. W. Allen</p>
        <p>dated 29 May &amp; rec'd 6 June 54 Containing Statement of Nashville loan at New Orleans <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SLJ">Ke</unclear> for me and 6 June </p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_000117_000218_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e60"/>
        <p>New Orleans May 29 th 1854</p>
        <p>Maj. D Burford</p>
        <p>Dear Sir,</p>
        <p>I enclose you a statement of the desposition I have made of your money. I have loaned it to my brother James for 12 months with the understanding that if you wish to have it for any longer time he is to have the preference on continuting the same sincerity. He has executed a mortgage on his plantation at Thirty nine negroes worth at a fair valuation $100,000.</p>
        <p>To share you the faith I have in the security it is only necessary to tell you that I have loaned him Six thousand dollars of my own money his whole indebtedness including your doll and &amp; mine is $39,000 his crop this year at the present low price will bring him about $20,000 after paying overseer and all other expenses. He prefers borrowing this money from us to coming under obligations to Commissioners charts and paying their charges for accepting and the exhoribitant rate of interest it costs them to raise money. he Can pay you &amp; I look from his crop in live years and will raise yours fro you at the end of 12 months if you require it. The mortgage is recorded in the office of A Mazureau notary public No 22 Camp Street N Orls and James takes a cofey home with him today to have it recorded in his own parish which he will have certified and return to me. I have your note and will keep that and the copy of the mortgage. You must give</p>
        <pb n="3" facs="0012_000117_000218_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e72"/>
        <p>me timely notice next spring whether you will want the money paid up or renewed. </p>
        <p>I hope you will be pleased with the disposition I have made of your funds I am certain if you was here you would not under existing circumstances be willing to invest in Commercial paper. There were two failures day before yesterday. Moses Greenwoods and Wright Williams, of the latter, the largest cotton house in New Orleans their liabilities  are nearly two million dollars and there is no telling who may be affected by their failure. I have never seen as much distrust and uneasiness <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SLJ">unarifested</unclear> in Commercial Circles as exists here now.  </p>
        <p>I enclose you a slip from the Delta of yesterday relative to this failure. The Banks would have sustained the house (SSH) if they had have had any security to offer that would have been considered good but they had none.</p>
        <p>The thirty nine negroes in the mortgage are all field hands able bodied no <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SLJ">zoan</unclear> old negroes or children in it. I leave here for home on the 19 th of June. will be here long enough to receive a letter from you.</p>
        <p>Your friend</p>
        <p>Jos W Allen</p>
        <pb n="4" facs="0012_000117_000218_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e92"/>
        <p>Copy of note in my possession belonging to D Burford</p>
        <p>New Orleans May 23 rd 1854</p>
        <p>$16070</p>
        <p>Twelve months after date I promise to pay David Burford on order Sixteen thousand and Seventy Dollars value rec'd with interest at the rate of eight per cent per annum from maturity until paid. Payable at the Canal and Banking Co New Orleans </p>
        <p>Signed James G Allen</p>
        <note type="transcription">The following text is a continuation of the second page of the letter.</note>
        <p>
          <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SLJ">So Vier alur Hm azurean</unclear>
        </p>
        <p>Notary Public</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
