<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000599_000251_0000">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Letter,
					<name>Henry Brown</name>
				                     to Caroline M. Brown,<date>undated</date>
            </title>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
          <name>White, Park</name>
        </respStmt>
        <author>
          <name type="person">Henry Brown</name>
        </author>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
        <date>2013</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
        </availability>
        <idno type="SPC">0012_000599_000251_0000</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Letter, Henry Brown to Caroline M. Brown,</title>
          <date>undated</date>
          <author>
            <name type="person">Henry Brown</name>
          </author>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <note type="collection">Henry Brown Collection</note>
          <note type="manuscript">MS.599</note>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
        <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
        <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
        <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as "turn page over" have been
						omitted.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy>
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="LCSH">
          <term>Ohio -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives.</term>
          <term>Ohio -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.</term>
          <term>Soldiers -- Ohio -- Correspondence.</term>
          <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives.</term>
          <term>United States. Army. Ohio Infantry Regiment, 31st (1861-1865)</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change when="2013" who="White, Park">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
      <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e37">
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_000599_000251_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e38"/>
        <p>I have said Something about A great many me before This but i had Saw None until we got on The advance as it ware
				       In aline of battle and We could See the troop To to the rite and left of us on the line as far as far as we could See boath
				       ways the Woods are alive with Troops and horses and Mules and the ground Coverd with waggons And tents whare we
				       are Now our pickets and The rebels pickets are A shooting at Each other Most all the time with But any affect they kill</p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_000599_000251_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e42"/>
        <p>One once awhile in boath Sides but verry Seldom I was verry Sorry to hear That Simon marshall was dead  Such things Must
				  be allso Henry Gaver i could hardly Beleave it for awhile I Shall have to Close My remark to you And Say a few word To to the
				  boys I Want you to prey for Me when ever you Can I for got one Thing you said Some Thing about Mrs gheen Getting $70
				  dollars you had better that Thay us while it is plenty So good by</p>
        <pb n="3" facs="0012_000599_000251_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e46"/>
        <p>To Isaiah and george  Now boys from the way you all write I think you are doing verry well i hope you will continue So untill
				  get home and You will See things That you never saw  Something good to eat And drink Boath for You and your mother you
				  must watch the Squirrels out of your Corn field when it Begins to come up  And tend it the best you can for the Roots i think
				  you Can raise Some good In that new ground</p>
        <pb n="4" facs="0012_000599_000251_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e50"/>
        <p>If it is well tended And a good season  Now be right good Boys and do your work well what you do I would like to know 
				  Whether your bread Stuff was agoing to Last you till after Harvest or not  No more at present But Still remain Affectionate
				  father untill Death</p>
        <p>Be good boys</p>
        <p>To Isaiah and george Brown</p>
        <p>From their father</p>
        <p>Henry Brown</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
