<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000543_000217_0000">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Letter,
					<name>John Sevier</name>
				                    to George Washington Sevier, <date when="1815-01-22">1815 January 22</date>
            </title>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
          <name>White, Park</name>
        </respStmt>
        <author>
          <name type="person">John Sevier</name>
        </author>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
        <date>2013</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
        </availability>
        <idno type="SPC">0012_000543_000217_0000</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Letter, John Sevier to George Washington Sevier, 1815 January 22</title>
          <date when="1815-01-22">1815 January 22</date>
          <author>
            <name type="person">John Sevier</name>
          </author>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <note type="collection">John Sevier Collection </note>
          <note type="manuscript">MS.1941</note>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
        <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
        <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
        <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as "turn page over" have been
						omitted.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy>
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="LCSH">
          <term>Blount, William, 1749-1800</term>
          <term>Dearborn, Henry, 1751-1829</term>
          <term>Henley, David, 1749-1823</term>
          <term>Meigs, Return Jonathan, 1740-1823</term>
          <term>Overton, John, 1766-1833</term>
          <term>Governors -- Tennessee.</term>
          <term>United States -- History -- War of 1812.</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change when="2013" who="White, Park">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
      <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e38">
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_000543_000217_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e39"/>
        <p>John Sevier  </p>
        <p>Colonel George Washington Sevier</p>
        <p>Knoxville</p>
        <p>Tennessee</p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_000543_000217_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e49"/>
        <p>Washington 22 January 1815</p>
        <p>Dear Sir</p>
        <p>Your favor of the 8th instant has just come to Hand and am rejoiced to hear from you all, but am sorry 
				  to find that the Ulcer in your neck seems to continue so obstinate, You will have to be very careful  how
				  it is managed, and to be in time with it, no time ought to be lost. I am very glad to hear that Major M.Clellan
				  have arrived, and hope his disorder will leave him now he has got home__ The Major is promoted to the
				  16 Regiment of Infantry commanded by Col. Pearce, and Now on the lines, was raised in Pensylvania.</p>
        <p>We have <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">pafsed</unclear>The bank bill, but it remains yet to be
				  afronted to by The President. It is not believed it will be usefull to the Government, it has been modeled
				  <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">intirely</unclear>by the Minority. additional Tax's is pro-
				   posed by the Secretary of Treasury, probably to make up for the defiency in the bank, which wont 
				  <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">affoarcs</unclear>any <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">Telie</unclear>
				  to the fiscal measures of Government. I need not give you any news from Orleans as you will hear from that 
				  place before we can.</p>
        <p>It is thought that there either have or will be, a number of black troops introduced into the Southern States.
				  I fear we shall be much embarrassed <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">Tasfsecting</unclear> money
				  to Supply the Army, and dont know in which way it can be guaranteed now</p>
        <pb n="3" facs="0012_000543_000217_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e76"/>
        <p>Now the bank have so much failed, us before had calculated very much upon that institution, but the 
				  hope is blasted___ This supposed We must have Recourse to Treasury notes, and it is to be feared that so
				  much paper will soon become Much depreciated __ I wish you to write Col. Sparks &amp; Rutha to bring off 
				  their Negroes &amp; property as Quick as possible, and while they can pass in safety through the Indian
				  Country. I shall be very uneasy about them till they arrive and shall fear much on their account.</p>
        <p>I have observed what you say respecting my suit at Moabile, and shall Sense on by this mail a power to 
				  William making him my attorney in fact. Shall also write General Gains to have an eye to the business, and 
				  wish you also to do the same___ I dont apprehend there is any danger of your Regiment being transferred,
				  as to the Col. that wants to be at the head of it, I cant believe any thing like that of a Gentleman___</p>
        <p>The Secretary of War has been dangerously ill, and yet very much indisposed, so that no business can
				  be transacted in that department, I shall use all possible means to do something to settle that business with
				  Kings executon__ I wish M. Rhea could make some sales__ He wrote me some time ago he had made some,
				  to the amount of four or five hundred dollars, and expected to make more__ If you dont come on until 
				  First of april, I suppose I shall not have an opportunity of getting My mail __ I am still enjoying good health,
				  but clearly surround ed with sickness __ Y. affectionate father</p>
        <p>My affectionate<unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">illegible</unclear> to all our Friends</p>
        <p>Col. Sevier     John Sevier</p>
        <pb n="4" facs="0012_000543_000217_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e91"/>
        <p>PS. Major A Sevier have set out for Charleston So. Carolina, and from there to N.Orleans &amp;take
				  command of the Marines 23. This morning the snow in some <gap reason="indecipherable" resp="White"/>deep,
				  and in common <gap reason="indecipherable" resp="White"/>half. we have not as much wood for 10 or 12 fire
				  places as would make one fire for my room at home, nor do the House Keeper know where to get one single
				  cord. for my own pail I expect perhaps Secured some coal from The Russian Minister, otherways by night
				  we shall have no fire.</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
