<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000115_000276_0000">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Memoir,
					<name>David Burford</name>
				                    of the trial of Judge Haskell <date when="1831-11">1831 Nov.</date>
            </title>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
          <name>Mincey, Jennifer</name>
        </respStmt>
        <author>
          <name type="person">David Burford</name>
        </author>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
        <date>2013</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
        </availability>
        <idno type="SPC">0012_000115_000276_0000</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Memoir, David Burford of the trial of Judge Haskell 1831 Nov.</title>
          <date when="1831-11">1831 Nov.</date>
          <author>
            <name type="person">David Burford</name>
          </author>
          <extent>32 pages</extent>
          <note type="collection">David Burford Papers</note>
          <note type="manuscript">MS.1027</note>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
        <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
        <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
        <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as "turn page over" have been
						omitted.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy>
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="LCSH">
          <term>Slave trade -- Southern States.</term>
          <term>Slavery -- Tennessee</term>
          <term>Slavery -- Virginia.</term>
          <term>Tennessee. Militia.</term>
          <term>United States -- History -- War of 1812.</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change when="2013" who="Mincey, Jennifer">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
      <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e38">
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_000115_000276_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e39"/>
        <p>D. Burford</p>
        <p>Mem,o of the trial of Judge Haskell</p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_000115_000276_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e45"/>
        <p>Memorandum of Joshua Haskell Esqr Judge of the Eighth Judicial circuit of the State of Tennessee began before the Senate on the day of, November 1831</p>
        <p>Court met on Wednesday the 2nd day of Nov, 1831, and the managers on the part of the House of Rep,s asked the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">postponment</unclear> of this cause until the 14th day of this month and was insisted upon by the managers and opposed by the respondents counsil</p>
        <p>Thursday November 3 - 1831 court met at 10, o,clock A.M. present the managers on the part of the House of Rep,s and the respondent and his counsil, The grounds urged by the managers was that many witnesses had been <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">sumonsed</unclear> and had failed to attend, amongst the number Judge Turley, and Mr Cook and others: also that there was other witnesses who had not come their knowledge until lately, and that <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">supenies</unclear> had issued for others and had not been exicuted by the Sargant at arms - It was <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">objected</unclear> by the counsil for Def,t that the managers had been guilty of <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">laches;</unclear> that they should <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">shew</unclear> that supenies had issued and proper means used for their exicution, and the common rules of law should and ought to govern in this as in all other cases; that that had not been done; that to pospone the trial of this cause would be ruinous to the respondant, that the expense was moore than he could ba <gap resp="Mincey"/>
            </p>
        <pb n="3" facs="0012_000115_000276_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e73"/>
        <p>tht Justice required and the constitution gave to him the right of a spedy and impartial trial &amp; that they demand an immediate trial.</p>
        <p>The court after much argument had theron, decided that the time asked for by the mamagers should not be granted, the vote yeas 8 and nays 10 Mr. Joseph H. Talbot, Andrew L. Martin, &amp; Alexander B. Bradford, witness introduced on the part of the mamagers, and in support of the first specification of the first artickle-</p>
        <p>Mr J. H. Talbot, being first called upon stated that a court was held in the county of Henderson on the second Monday in April 1828, at which Judge Haskell presided, this was objected to by cousil of the defendant, whereupon much argument was had and and the court finally adjourned utnil tomorrow morning 10 o,clock Friday Morning Nov 4th 1831, court met pursuant to adjournment, and the court purmitted further argument on the subject of the admisibility of the evidence, when Mr Allen &amp; others on the part of the managers, and the cousel of the defendant, and after much argument on both sides until 5 o,Clock P.M. when the house adjourned until 10 o,clock A.M. Saturday morning 10 o,clock The court met pursuant adjournment and after much arguement from the mamagers as well as counsel for the respondent the court unamemusly decided that that records <gap resp="Mincey"/> be produced.</p>
        <note type="transcription">The following text is a continuation of the third page of the memorandum.</note>
        <p>1 Specification 1st artickle</p>
        <note type="transcription">The preceding text is a continuation of the third page of the memorandum.</note>
        <pb n="4" facs="0012_000115_000276_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e89"/>
        <p>The managers then (in writing) submitted a statment, asking for time until Tuesday next 10 o,clock A.M. upon the ground,s that from the decision of the court Just made requiring a copy of the records it was nessesary that they should have time to produce the records, and that they had dispached pursons for said record,s which they had reason to beleive would be here by that time. the motion for further time was argued by Mr Allen &amp; Mr. claburn in behalf of the motion, and opposed by Mr Fletcher and Mr Anderson on behalf of the respondant.</p>
        <p>And in the question being put by the chairman it was unanimusly decided that time should be given; whereupon the court adjourned to meet on Tuesday next at 10 o,Clock A.M.</p>
        <p>Tuesday Morning 10 o,Clock A.M. Court met pursuant to adjournment. the managers on the part of the House of representatives produced a copy of the record certifyed by the clerk of the circuit court of Montgomery county as relates to the trial of Andrew Johnston on an indctment for horse stealing which paper is marked B.</p>
        <p>Mr Cave Johnston appeared and was qualifyed - He states that he was <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">Soliston</unclear> at the time of the trial of Andrew Johnston mentioned in the 2nd specification for horse stealing, that the Jude was absent at the time of said trail for half an hour at one time as he supposes at lastbut will not be positive as to the time and was several <gap resp="Mincey"/>
            </p>
        <note type="transcription">The following text is a continuation of the fourth page of the memorandum.</note>
        <p>2 Specification 1 artickle</p>
        <note type="transcription">The preceding text is a continuation of the fourth page of the memorandum.</note>
        <pb n="5" facs="0012_000115_000276_0005.jpg" xml:id="d4e109"/>
        <p>absent during the trial of causes that term of the court, freequently behind the bar, at the court house doore and elsewhere. the counsel for Def,t objected to witness answering as to the Judges conduct generally or to any other question or subject matter not embraced in the specification, and after argument heard on both sides the court sustained Deft,s objection counsels - Witness states that def,t Johnston who was on trial had a wife which was considered a learned woman, and from Judge Hashells conduct, and the conduct of said Johnstons wife, whose husband was on trial, she being frequently sitting beside the Judge while on the bench, and from other circumstances drew his attention particularly to his absence, question by myself what was goin on while the absence of the Judge? answ the attourneys was speaking.</p>
        <p>Witness was then examined as to the fifth specification the mamagers then read the record of the clerk of Dickson County Circuit Court, Marked No 5 court then adjourned for dinner - court met after dinner and mamagers on the part of the House proceeded to read a copy of the record, in which the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">name of Ausenus</unclear> S. Merritt, as mentioned in the fifth specification was written <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">Arsemus insted of Ausemus</unclear> whereupon the respondants counsil objected that the variance was fatal, and filed <gap resp="Mincey"/> objection in writing to the reading of such record</p>
        <note type="transcription">The following text is a continuation of the fifth page of the memorandum.</note>
        <p>5 Specification 1st artickle 2 Specification 1st artickle</p>
        <note type="transcription">The preceding text is a continuation of the fifth page of the memorandum.</note>
        <pb n="6" facs="0012_000115_000276_0006.jpg" xml:id="d4e129"/>
        <p>on the grounds of the variance between the spelling of the given name "Ausemus" and "Orsemus" The court overuled this objection made by the Def,t counsel years and ways</p>
        <p>The managers then proceeded to th examination of Mr Johnston as to the 5 Secification - the question as to wheather witness should give testimony as relates to the expanding of the Jury in the case of the State vs Merritt as mentioned in the fifth Specification. was objected to by the counsil for def,t and after argument on the part of the defendants counsil, as well as the managers on the part of the House the court refused to sustain the objection. Whereupon the court adjourned until tomorrow morning 10 o,Clock A.M.</p>
        <p>Wednesday Novr 9th 1831</p>
        <p>Court met pursuant to adjournment, Mr Johnston witness on the part of the State was then called, and asked to state what he knew of the conduct of Judge Haskell in <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">relation</unclear> to the trial of the State vs Merritt at September term 1828, Judge was absent during the empanneling of the Jury, and had almost completed the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">empanding</unclear> of the Jury when the witness who was then acting Solisitor &amp; the def,t Merritts councillor disagred, and he at that time went to court House doore to see the Judge who was some fifty yards from the court House in conversation with several other Gentlemen, he then returned and th <gap resp="Mincey"/>
            </p>
        <note type="transcription">The following text is a continuation of the sixth page of the memorandum.</note>
        <p>Spec 5th artickle 1st</p>
        <note type="transcription">The preceding text is a continuation of the sixth page of the memorandum.</note>
        <pb n="7" facs="0012_000115_000276_0007.jpg" xml:id="d4e152"/>
        <p>compleated the empaneling the Jury - Qn by Mr Anderson of the court, how long was the Judge absent, Answr I cannot say precisely how long he was absent, but suppose near or quite one hour - Qn - by by Managers did you want to the doore to see where the Judge was? ansr I went to the doore to look for the Judge and with the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">view</unclear> to invite him in to settle the difficulty, or dispute as to the empanding of the Jury - Qn by same How far was the Judge from court House, and was he too far off to hear what was going on - Ansr he was at the Tavern talking with some Gentlemen, say 70 or 80 yards, too far to hear what was going on. Wtiness thinks did not send for the Judge - was some time absent after witness went to the court House doore - dont recollect wheather Judge returned before Jury was qualifyed - thinks it was the competency of a Juror which Induced him to go to the doore to look for the Judged. The counsil for Respondend then proceeded to cross examine Witness. and amoung other Questions asked withess wheather any exceptios was taken to respondants opinions, and wheater there was not as much business done by respondant at these terms, to wit, those terms mentioned in the 2nd and 5th specification - as was usually done - witness answered that respndant done as much business or moore than was usual - Managers asked Witness as to the Judges conduct generally at those terms; to which respondants counsil objected; and</p>
        <note type="transcription">The following text is a continuation of the seventh page of the memorandum.</note>
        <p>5th Specification 1st artickle C. Johnston witness</p>
        <note type="transcription">The preceding text is a continuation of the seventh page of the memorandum.</note>
        <pb n="8" facs="0012_000115_000276_0008.jpg" xml:id="d4e165"/>
        <p>the question was submitted to the court without argument, and the objection overuled -</p>
        <p>Mr Allen was then called and proceeded to state the conduct of Judge Haskell at the time of impanding the Jury - Witness was one Merritts counsil thinks the Judge was present at the time of empanding the Jury - thinks respondant was absent during trial of the case of Merrit for some time - recollects that the questions turned upon two law pints; the facts ware plain - these was the questions fist, how far a man was guilty who had in custody a run away negro - 2nd was, how far a man was bound &amp; liable who received a negro from one who had stolen or kidnaped the slave. Qn by Managers how long was the Judge absent at a time - Anr does not know how long he was absent at any one time, but was ferquntly absent during the trial - Witness had to address the Jury as to the law on account of the absence of the Judge off of the bench; thinks respondant was absent when a question was made as to admisability of evidence and was settled by a compromise. Qn by the court as to time of absence of the Judge at one time Ansr, at one time thinks respondant was absent upwards of half an hour after Sunday other questions of explanation the witness was discharged.</p>
        <p>Mr Joseph Hise, was then qualifyed, and gave evidence in behalf of the state, witness states that he was present at the trial of Johnston as mention</p>
        <note type="transcription">The following text is a continuation of the eighth page of the memorandum.</note>
        <p>5 Specification 1 artickle</p>
        <note type="transcription">The preceding text is a continuation of the eighth page of the memorandum.</note>
        <pb n="9" facs="0012_000115_000276_0009.jpg" xml:id="d4e179"/>
        <p>in the 2nd Specification - Witness states that during the trial there was two Women sitting on the Judges bench, both women of bad character, and one of them the wife of the prisenor - W. see the Judge make signs or make motion with his lips to the women as though speaking, or making intimations to those women - the Judge at about 9 or 10 o clock at night left the bench, Judge H. left the bench during his argument of the cause; In the progress of the trial respondant stated to witness that Johnston had been tryed before him for Horse stealing before; that the present was the third offense; the respondant stated to witness that he was then under sentance of death, at the time of pronouncing sentance, Witness was then discharged - Mr Leonard P. Cheatham witness on behalf of the prosecution was then called, Qn by Managers was you present at Dickson Septr Circuit Court, and tell us what you know of teh trial of merrit, the Judge was sent for to the palce where there was an exibition of wild animals - respond was there about 1 hour; business of the court stopped for the want of the Judge, The witness was then discharged, and the court adjourned until tomorrow morning 10 o, cloc</p>
        <p>Thursday Morning 10 o,clock A. M. Novm 10th 1831 Court met pursuant to adjournment, Docr, <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">Sebastion</unclear> deputy clerk of Hickman circuit court, Examined as to 2nd artickle &amp; 2 Specification; the clerk then read the proceedings of the circuit court on 12 Septr 1828, witness</p>
        <note type="transcription">The following text is a continuation of the ninth page of the memorandum.</note>
        <p>2 Specification 1 Artickle</p>
        <note type="transcription">The preceding text is a continuation of the ninth page of the memorandum.</note>
        <pb n="10" facs="0012_000115_000276_0010.jpg" xml:id="d4e194"/>
        <p>states that respondant did not hear the whole of the answer to the order for the dissolution of injunction read, but while reading the Answer, Judge stated, that if answer swore away the equity the Injunction must be dissolved - the order for dissolution of Injunction had been previously written out at the suggestion of attourney for Def,t - Judge absent purhaps 10 minutes during the trial or reading of injunction &amp; answer. Witnes thinks Hickson read the bill of Injunction, and thinks Mr. Hickson was present when the Judge directed that if the answer swore away the equity the Injunction must be dissolved - Witness examined as to 1st artickle &amp; 3 Specification as to the trial of Geoge W Garrett on an indictment for purgury. at Hickman circuit court commenced 2nd Monday in Septr, 1828, Witness states Judge left the bench after the Jury was empaneled, and Mr Nixon commenced his arguement before the return of the Judge, and after proceeding some time asked the Sheriff to go for the Judge that it was nessesary the Judge should be there Judge was absent during the examination of the witnesses; and absent say 10 or 15 minutes at a time - Judge was absent during examination of part of the witnesses; dont knwo how long, absent during close of examination; the testimony was all opposed to sustaining the indictment, witness was then discharged.</p>
        <p>Mr Gabriel Fulks, witness for the State, was then called and stated that he attened as sheriff of Hickman circuit court at Sept Term 1828, Witness was sent for Judge at some time during term of the court, witness things Mr Ni <gap resp="Mincey"/> the Solicitor sent him for Judge, stating that part of his</p>
        <note type="transcription">The following text is a continuation of the tenth page of the memorandum.</note>
        <p>2 Specification 2 Artickle</p>
        <note type="transcription">The preceding text is a continuation of the tenth page of the memorandum.</note>
        <pb n="11" facs="0012_000115_000276_0011.jpg" xml:id="d4e208"/>
        <p>argument was for the court and requested him to go for the Judge; Witness was present when court adjourned, and thinks part of the minutes was read before the court adjourned, and that part of the minutes had been previously read while the Jury was out; Witness was then discharged.</p>
        <p>Mr Henry Nixon Witness for state was then called and states that he was atty Genl when Garret was tryed, W. states that Judge was absent during part of the trial, Garrett was anctious to take up the cause and was prevented by the adjournment of the court; <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">Ur</unclear> dont recollect that called upon the court to wait untill he could draw out a bill of exceptions. the Judge was not upon the bench during part of his arguement. Witness filed the answer for Def,t in the case of Wright vs Pace &amp; others Plantiffs atty was present, and the answer swore away the Equity of the plff bill of injunction - Witness knows not that any complaints was made by plff counsil - Judge was absent during the trial of Gairot, but does not know where he was saw Judge absent at Tavern once &amp; sent for him once during the argument. Evidence as to the 1st artickle &amp; 11 Specifications in the case of <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">Thompson vs Spous</unclear> witness stats that the judge left the court house shortly after empanding the Jury, and about the time the first witness was called, and did not return until the arguments was through - the Judge gave a small charge to the Jury on his (witness) suggestion, a difficulty occured as to evidence and had to call upon a lawyer for his decission, the Judge not being present. Judge gave the better</p>
        <note type="transcription">The following text is a continuation of the eleventh page of the memorandum.</note>
        <p>11 Specification 1 Artickle - 3 Specification 1st Artickle</p>
        <note type="transcription">The preceding text is a continuation of the eleventh page of the memorandum.</note>
        <pb n="12" facs="0012_000115_000276_0012.jpg" xml:id="d4e227"/>
        <p>charge than could have been expected not having heard the testimony witness see the Judge during his absence once 50 or 60 yards from the court house. Witness was then discharged Artickle 1st 1 Specification. Andrew L. Martin - witness for the state says he does recollect that respondant was absent during the trial of Newbold &amp; does not recolelct that he was absent during examination of evidence:</p>
        <p>Mr Huntsman Witness for state, vs states that he met respondant when going into court house, and that the att,y Gen,l was then concluding his speech; dont <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">Hucon</unclear> how long res,t was absent wheather 2-10-15 or 20 minutes w, does not recollect of seeing any Judge elave the bench unless in J. Haskells dis,t and at the Supreme court. court then adjourned until tomorrow morning 10 o,Clock A. M.</p>
        <p>Friday Morning 10 o,Clock A.M. Novr 11th 1831 Mr Adam Hunsman was then called and examined as to the 7th Specification and 1st artickle, states he was present at the trial of Walden, after the trial was taken up the Judge left the bench, W. see Judge some 70 to 100 yards from the court house, also see J. looking at some horses also see him at Cake cart. some difficulty took place between counsil and sent for J. the W. states that J was absen either at examination of witness or a ttime of argument of counsel: W. thinks J. was absent upwards of half an hour: thinks J came shortly after being sent for Deft,s counsil Qn does it not frequently occur that J are frequently absent. W, does not recollect what dispute</p>
        <pb n="13" facs="0012_000115_000276_0013.jpg" xml:id="d4e238"/>
        <p>between the counsil was about, wheather <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">as</unclear> to admisability of evidence or as to what witness had sworn. Qn is it not nessesay for Judge to always be upon the bench, anr, it has been customary wherever he has practised, except in the J. circuit - it has been the invariable practice in all other circuits but the 8 circuit W says practice is for a court to decide what evidence has been, but sometimes send for witness under direction of court and witness ruled to asnwer or explain the testimony not understood.</p>
        <p>A. L. Martin witness for the state.</p>
        <p>says he was present at trial of Walden - Judge was absent at least half an hour: dont knwo where I was - see him once 20 yeards from court house - J. wanted to purchase horse having sold his; when J. was braught witness was present &amp; dispute was as to testimony. Witness then discharged.</p>
        <p>Joseph H. Talbut, witness for state</p>
        <p>was present during trial of Walden - J. was absent he suppose at least 30 minutes, difficulty arose as to evidence and had to send for the Judge, Witness feel sure this difficulty arose before arguements commenced - atty,s appealed to some of the bar to decide the question, who decliend by saying that the Judge was appointed for the purpose. Witness <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">Hous</unclear> he sent for Judge before arguement commenced - argument commenced after night. Witness knows he made his own argument after night and thinks Bradford made his argument after night also.</p>
        <p>Mr Bradford witness for the state W. says he was counsil for state on the part of the state vs Walden, Judge</p>
        <pb n="14" facs="0012_000115_000276_0014.jpg" xml:id="d4e258"/>
        <p>was absent during examination of witness, and had to send for Judge, the difficulty arose before the storm and argument commenced after the storm. see him out before argument commenced and in day time -.</p>
        <p>Mr martin states Mr Bradford opened the argument on the part of the state before suppoer, and the difficulty took place when the Judge was sent for before the argument and difficulty when Judge was sent for did not relate to venue -</p>
        <p>Mr Marshall witness for the state - was Dep,y Sheriff at the time of the trial of Walden, was sent for the Judge when for the Judge before the storm - found the Judge looking at a horse some 20 or 30 yd from court house - it has run into his mind witness was <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">reatted</unclear> dont recollected what took place when Judge left the bench. Thins storm took place after dinner - went for Judge before the argument commenced. Court adjourned until tomorrow morning 10 o,Clock A.M.</p>
        <p>Saturday Morning 10 o,Clock A.M. Nov 12th 1831 And the mamagers asked for a continuance of the cause until Monday morning next on account the falure of the Sergant at arms having failed to return or the witness not having arrived that was sent for. to which the respondant objected, and the objection was overuled by the court. The court then adjourned until Monday next 10 o,Clock A. M.</p>
        <pb n="15" facs="0012_000115_000276_0015.jpg" xml:id="d4e271"/>
        <p>Monday Morning 14 Novr 1831 10 o,Clock A.M. Court met pursuant to adjournment the mamgers and respondants counsel being present. The mamagers on the part of the H. R. Asked to withdraw <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">4 &amp; 6th</unclear> Spec, 8 Spec, 9 Spec 10 Spec of the first artickle and 1 Spec 2 Artic</p>
        <p>The respondant then proceeded to to examination of witnesses - Judge <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">Iro;</unclear> Question was then called and qualifyed, witness states he commenced the practice of law spring 1789, was Judge nearly 12 years - The respondants counsel then asked the witness what had been his practice when a Judge - this was objected to on the part of the managers, and the decission of the question in the case of the state vs N. W. Williams Impeachment, Journal page 82 &amp; 83, respondants counsil then asked Judge over to to state what was the practice of the courts in which he practised as a lawyer, and what was the course of the lawyers when the Judges have been absent off of the bench: to which the managers objected, which objection was sustained by the court. The court then adjourned until tomorrow morning 10 o,clock A.M.</p>
        <p>Tuesday morning 10 o, clock A. M. Novr 15th 1831 court met according to adjournment, Mr A.S. Millin one of the witnesses for the state was then introduced by the mamagers and asked that he should be qualifyed and give evidence as to the 11 Specification 1st artickle. to which the counsil for respondant objected, and the objection overuled by the court, Vm. by Mr Clabourn was you present at May Term</p>
        <note type="transcription">The following text is a continuation of the fifteenth page of the memorandum.</note>
        <p>11 Specification 1st change</p>
        <note type="transcription">The preceding text is a continuation of the fifteenth page of the memorandum.</note>
        <pb n="16" facs="0012_000115_000276_0016.jpg" xml:id="d4e291"/>
        <p>1829 and present at the trial of John Thompson as Wm Slone? witness recollects that he was told that the Judge had requested him to give his opinion in the case of Thompson vs Slone or Northcut vs lone he did not recollect which he gave his opinion on a question of law at request of counsil, and thinks he was in the Judges chair: W, was called upon twice to give his opinion - thinks the counsil called upon him for his opinion when he asked them if they would abide by his opinion, which they agreed to, when he proceeded to give his opinion and the attourneys then proceeded - Witness dont recollect wheather the Judge was present there during the trial, but thinks it likely that he was, as it was not common to take up causes without the Judges being present; dont recollect to have seen the Judge after trial was taken up. Qn by Mr Clabourn, can you recollect that the J. was present during the examination of any one witness on that trial? Ansr, I think he was present at the commencement of the trial but does not recollect that he was present afterrwards. court held in a log cabbin and verry disagreeable situation for Judge and others; flees in the house - W. was called upon during examination of witnesses to give his opinion - dont recollect ever to see him out of sight or moore than 50 to 100 yards - W. thinks that he was called upon to state his impressions as to the evidence because the Judge was not present and they had no other way to assertain what was the evidence - He was called upon by the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">bar</unclear> in open court in the presence of the court to state what the evidcen was.</p>
        <pb n="17" facs="0012_000115_000276_0017.jpg" xml:id="d4e298"/>
        <p>Respondant introduced Mr Armor, who states that he was one of the Jurors, on the trial of Newbold as mentioned in the 7 Specifycation - the Judge was not off the bench during the whole trial</p>
        <p>Witness states the Judges charractor is correct as far as he knows - hard to get money out off - the people as far as he know has allways been well pleased - Qn, by Managers, are you acquainted with the general character of Andrew L. Martin &amp; Adam Huntsman: Qn would you give them full credit upon their oaths ansr, I would-</p>
        <p>Mr H. Bradburry - a Juror on the trial of walden dont recollect the Judge was absent but once and dont think it was but a fiw minutes - dont recollect wheather he was absent on examination of witness or when one called back - Judges standing verry good in the county of Henderson - other Questions was asked and objected to by the mamgers and the objections sustained - thecourt then adjourned until tomorrow.</p>
        <p>Wednesday Novr 16th 1831 court met pursuant to adjournment Mr Purkeins a witness for respondant was then sworn  witness says he was present at the time of the trial of the state vs Garret he heart the evidence in that case, the man was indicted for purgury - was presnt when I, Haskell and J. Green had a conversation about going together - see Judges Green &amp; Haskell together out of the doore, thinks after the trial - was present injunction was read -</p>
        <pb n="18" facs="0012_000115_000276_0018.jpg" xml:id="d4e308"/>
        <p>Qn by mamagers, was you and Judge Green &amp; Haskell sitting together anr yes, did you not then hear the lawyers then pleading in the court House - beleives the business was done - W. thinks J. Green asked J. Haskell what was going on in the court house and J. Haskell answered his court - the circuit court and that he was presiding J. Haskell said he must go to receive a verdict of the Jury - dont recollect to have heard the lawyers speaking supposes Green &amp; Haskell was together from 15 to 30 minutes - Qn by Anderson of court, do you think Judge was absent during the trial of Garret, Anr, I do recollect that he was absent during a part of that trial several times -</p>
        <p>Doc,r Joal Walker Deft,s witness sworn - Witness was a Juror at the court - called J. Green to stop - J. Haskell came out and asked J. Green to wait until court adjourned that he would go with him - thinks they ware going into the trial of Garrett when J. Greeen rode up - thinks J. Green sayed there three hours he took dinner after the regular dinner was over - think J. H. stated to J. G. that htey was about closing the cause thinks it was an hour or hour and a half after taking prost, with the cost before the court adjourned - counsil was present on the dissolution of injunction - J. H. was present and directed the making up the record - was not in the court house but little during the progress of the trial of Garrett - think it was an hour after dissolution of injunction beofre the Judge left there. </p>
        <pb n="19" facs="0012_000115_000276_0019.jpg" xml:id="d4e314"/>
        <p>William H. Dortch witness for respondant - Examined as to 2 Spec 2 artickle - W. was consil for <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">respondant</unclear> Def,t in the case of the state vs Johnston - Has no recollection that Judge H. was off the bench; and thinks that if he had been off the bench he would have known it - witness stayed in court until 120 o, Clock at night 0 def,t had three counsil - thinks the moon had not rissen - he went to his friends house and so dark that could not see the dog - when witness heard J. Haskell was impeached he thought as to what could be the Judges impropieties in the trial of Johnston - did not notice any women sitting on the bench - dont recollect to have seen any women - W. never see Judge Haskall before the trail of Johnston - Qn by managers are you acquainted with <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">Cave</unclear> Johnston - general charracter anr yes - would you give him credit, anr as much as any other purson -</p>
        <p>Mr Kimboll witness for respondant - was present on the trial of Johnston - was employed as one of prosicution counsil - was alte at night say 12 o,clock - see Judge Haskell off the bench at one time - dont know how long - nothing transpired to induce him to mark his absence - dont know how long the Judge was absent - does not suppose it was as much half an hour - Witness see two women on the bench, both in the day and night time - Witness is acqainted with Mr Hise and would beleive him upon his oath - his impression is that it was rather dark when he left the court house, but is not certain but the moon was up - it wmight or might not have been up - thinks the Judge was absent not half an hour -</p>
        <pb n="20" facs="0012_000115_000276_0020.jpg" xml:id="d4e326"/>
        <p>Mr Ges. W. Terrall, witness for respondant - Witness has known J. Haskell for upowards of five years - as a man he stood fair - as a Judge &amp; man has never heard his Charactor questioned - Qn by managers has he not been in the habit of leaving the bench frequently - and is that not his general character -has heard complaint of negligance, and particularly amoung the lawyers - dispaches busness verry fast, heard no complaint. people of the Dis,t are satisfyed so far as he knows W. never practised in his circuit. seen him frequently engaged in concentration during trail. </p>
        <p>William R. Harriss - States his opinion would not vary from Mr Terrallys, think J. Haskell dispaches business verry fast - frequently heard the lawyers in J. H. circuit complain of his levity, leaving the bench &amp;c &amp;c Qn by M. what is the opinion a majorety of those who you have heard speak of him - heard some two or three lawyers speak of his negligance &amp; levity - Qn what is his charactor of his morrals, anr, thinks it is good as far as he has heard W has practised near two yeasr in two of the Judges Dis,t</p>
        <p>H. Bradburry - again called 0 has been acqainted with J. Haskells for five or six years - thinks he has a good character generally and the people &amp; lawyers are well pleased with him - thinks the J. has not left the bench moor than other Judges, and not moore than Judge Turley - never see the J. absent off the bench while examining witnesses or argument of causes.</p>
        <pb n="21" facs="0012_000115_000276_0021.jpg" xml:id="d4e334"/>
        <p>Blackman Coleman - W. has known J. Haskell for twenty years, is Clerk of circuit court for Haywood Country so far as w. knows or has heard J. Haskells Judicial charractor has been good generally - has seen J Haskell asbsent from bench has heard some fiew lawyers complain of J. Haskell, about leaving bench &amp; for <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">stoping</unclear>
            </p>
        <p>Mr <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">Harriglol-</unclear> freequently attended the circuit courts, of Haywood county, the J. private charractor, and as a Judge are good - has conducted with propiety - Witness toasted J. H. since his his impeachment - offered the toast to J. H. because W. thought he deserved it - W. has seen the Judge walk out doore and shake hands with his friends and talk to them some little -</p>
        <p>Mr S. P. Ash - a citizen of Haywood county has been a Juror for every Term since 1826 but one time - J. Haskell he has heard no complaint only that he would leave the bench during the pleading - J. attends better th is appointments after dinner since impeachment than before - July Term 1829 - the grand Jury made no presentment in favour of J. Haskell - W. has seen the J. off of the bench at times - sometimes the Jury was detained - is satisfyed that J. has been off of the bench - people satisfyed with J. Haskell as a Judge - presentment in favour of a Judge July Term 1828</p>
        <p>Nicolas P. Purkins - has known J. Haskell since 1814 has lived in Haywood county Eight years; has known J. Haskell as a Judge ever since he was a Judge - business of Haywood county done with dispach.</p>
        <pb n="22" facs="0012_000115_000276_0022.jpg" xml:id="d4e349"/>
        <p>Thursday 10 o,clock A.M. court  met pursuant to adjournment, Novr 17th 1831</p>
        <p>Mr Nickson, was called by respondant, Qn by m, court Mr Anderson was you att, y for plff in case on Thompson as Slone? Anr, I was - W says there was a man by the name of Johnston, Alias Putnam Alias Wm Johnston - was tryed at Perry circuit court, in 1824 or 1825 and on producing of copy o fthe record from Bedford county showing his previous conviction, and upon trial was again found guilty of horse stealing and sentenced to death - Johnson had light hair, about 25 to 30 years old about common size - slender made -</p>
        <p>Qn by rspondants counsil as to what J. Haskell had told him - objected to by managers, and objection overuled by the court.</p>
        <p>Qn by managers what is J. Haskells charractor as a Judge Anr, before impeachment he was in the habit of leaving the bench during argument of counsil - and some times during examination of Witness, in the case of Thompson vs Slone.</p>
        <p>John Read, sworn - have seen a Mr Johnston at Sharlot in the Spring of 1825 brought there from Perry ct,y looked to be 24 or 25 years old - 5, 10 or 11 inches pale swarthy look - light hair - Thinks he was called Johnston The court house at Jackson is so arranged the Jurry box is under the Judges bench, <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">Judge</unclear> might go off bench without being seen - Judge attentive as to examination of witnesses</p>
        <pb n="23" facs="0012_000115_000276_0023.jpg" xml:id="d4e365"/>
        <p>but frequently absent in argument of causes - on the trial of Newboll, attended to hi argument, might have been absent during examination of witnesses for a short time - might possably have been absent during the trial for 15-20 or 30 minutes - dont know wheather he was out of the court house or not. J. H. general charractor is good -</p>
        <p>Adam Huntsman, Johsnton was tryed witness his att,y Murry failed to attend, he witness was appointed by the court to defend him - Johnston confessed he had been convicted before - would not go to trial - thought he could brake Jail - thinks Johnston was 6 feet high - light hair, blue eys, committed 1825 supposed he was 25 or 26 years old -</p>
        <p>Tho. H. Fletcher, knew a man called Andrew Johnston, been convicted at Clarksville, sent here for confinement, was accosted by him - his name was George Wilson - thinks about 6 feet high well built, same man wich was convicted by states atty at Winchester in 1823 or 1824 and thinks, after consultation, tht he defended him-</p>
        <p>Gen,l Tipton, general charractor of Judge Haskell is verry good indeed - thinks the people of his county <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">wate</unclear> if left to them relain him,</p>
        <p>Dan,l A. Dunham - lives in Tipton county, has been a Jury at every circuit court since he has lived there which has been 5 years; his general charractor as a man &amp; Judge has been good. no complaints again in Tipton county - Was foreman of grand Jury made</p>
        <pb n="24" facs="0012_000115_000276_0024.jpg" xml:id="d4e380"/>
        <p>presentment in J. Haskell favour last June term -</p>
        <p>Mr G. D. Searcy W. Tipton county in fall 1828 - some dissatisfaction with the bar as to J. Haskell, and as he supposed for want of dignity, for levity-</p>
        <p>Mr D. Dunn - Shelby county has known J. Haskell since 1821 - frequently attended as a Juror - J. H. general charractor as a Judge is without objection to him - first thought the J. was unpopular - people did not like to be restrained - without law or gospell</p>
        <p>Mr Sam,l Brown, has lived in Shelby county since 1821 confirms the statement of may,r Dunn as above, J. Haskell gave him his pro term appointment of clk circuit court</p>
        <p>Jw. K. Balch, Sheriff of Shelby county &amp; deputy for the last five years, J. H. charractor as a man and Judge is verry good</p>
        <p>Joel. L. Jones. Sheriff of Fayette county - J. Haskells charractor as a man and Judge is verry good in that county</p>
        <p>W. L. Hannum, Fayette county, has been acquainted with J. H. for 20 years, benevolent &amp; kind - tells anecdotes and never knew him injure anyone -</p>
        <p>Joseph Philips - of Davidson County, has known J. Haskell eve since 1811 so far as he knows the J. general charracter is good -</p>
        <p>Hardiman, of Hardiman county, clerk of the cty court, J. Haskells generall charractor is verry good, has known J. H. since 1823</p>
        <p>Mr W. D. Barry - of hardiman county, has known J. Haskell since 1821 atty Gen,l for 4 of J. H. counties the</p>
        <pb n="25" facs="0012_000115_000276_0025.jpg" xml:id="d4e402"/>
        <p>W. has seen nothing against the Judge, and he knows of no improprieties of the Judges. J. H. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">seases</unclear> upon cases better than any man he ever heard. </p>
        <p>Col Alexander - of Harderman county, says previous to the impeachment had heard J. H. frequently and has heard him spoken verry well heard nothing against him</p>
        <p>E,d R. Belcher lived in Bolivar five to six years, so far as he knows J. H. is considered an honest and correct man and Judge - Has seen the Judge leave the bench frequently - dont recollect to see the Judge moore than five to ten minutes speeches made by lawyers that never heard the proof</p>
        <p>Gen. J. coffees, Deposition, has been acquainted with J. Haskell ever since he came to the country - a good soldier - in the army &amp;c &amp;c</p>
        <p>Rob,t C. M,c Alpen, lives in Shelby county, comm,d practice law in 1827 - J. H. as a man honset and upright, as a Judge unimpeached so far as he knows never see the J. off the bench during examination of Witnesses - during arguments absent once.</p>
        <p>Judge Mitchell, has known J. H. since 1812 has enquired from the Dis,t if he has a spark of dishonesty he dont know it, had a good oportunity to know him</p>
        <p>Gen. White, has known J. h. for 20 years they</p>
        <pb n="26" facs="0012_000115_000276_0026.jpg" xml:id="d4e421"/>
        <p>was in the war together, is not able to charge him with anything - was susspected by some for not having courage - as far as he knows J. H. conduct was good in the army</p>
        <p>Bengamin Wright - MCnairy county, was cleark of M,Cnairy circuit court until May 1829, verry little littigation in his county dispached business verry fast known J. H. 20 years in the army together -</p>
        <p>Mr Marshall, has known J. H. 21 or 22 yeasr was with him in the army has heard nothing against J. H. as soldier - J,s standing in Henderson county as good as any mans alive</p>
        <p>Mr Bullock, see J. Haskell in 1822 and see him no moore until May 1829, J. H. charracter is that of honesty &amp; <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">probety</unclear> esteemed as a man &amp; Judge, heard the circumstance of Walden spoken off -</p>
        <p>Ja,s R. White, of Henderson county has Knonw J. H. for but little time went to Henderson county in June 1830 Witness thinks from his intercourse with the people supposes his charractor was as good as any man - supposees J. H. had been in Henderson county sine his impeachment and before he was there -</p>
        <p>Judge Stuart - has known J. H. about 20 years, has practiced law before witness - J. appeared to an active young man done verry well as a lawyer - was anctious know how he done as a Judge, enquired, was informed he done verry well restrained the lawyers too much and spoke too much himself - he thought he would do &amp; made no further enquiry - said talked too much with lawyers &amp; people heard nothing against his honesty as a man or Judge.</p>
        <pb n="27" facs="0012_000115_000276_0027.jpg" xml:id="d4e438"/>
        <p>John rurdy - of Henderson county survey,r Generals, lived there since county first organised - attended the circuit court frequently = known J. H. since 1819 thinks his charractor as a man &amp; Judge - astonished to hear of his impeachment.</p>
        <p>Jereod S. Allen, of Perry county, lived there before J. H. went there, has attended court, J. H. general charractor as a Judge and man dont recollect ever having heard it censured - no individual complaints - heard Mr Nixon &amp; Mr Scott, gave an opinion in advance &amp; then sustained it. has heard P. M. Miller complian, Qn was not J. H. verry much in the habit of leaving the bench <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">Awr</unclear> dont recollect ever knowing J. to leave the bench during examination of witness, but once while they was arguing the cause. Gov. Carroll, has known J. H. for 20 years, has been quite intimate with him for part of the time - a man of fine feelings - acted as <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">aps:</unclear> Qn Master in the creed campaighn - See him in one battle - oursued the Indians after the battled - never see Judge Haskell on the bench. Corut then adjourned until tomorrow morning 10 o,clock A. M.</p>
        <p>Friday Novr 18th 1831, court met pursuant to adjournment, Mr John M Lemoore was then qualifyed - states he has known J. H. for 20 years always considered him a man of good hart and clever man, stood far in the Dis,t previous to 1829.</p>
        <p>c. D. Mc,Clain, Rep,e has known J. H. for 7 or 8 years has heard no particular objection to the Judge, heard no objecti</p>
        <pb n="28" facs="0012_000115_000276_0028.jpg" xml:id="d4e454"/>
        <p>on particularly - some lawyers conplained of the Judges leaving the bench - never see anything which induced him to think that he neglected his business as a Judge.</p>
        <p>James Gray, Rep,s dont know anything about respondant before Impeachment.</p>
        <p>Col doherty, of Carroll County - has lived in the Dis,t for 11 years has known Respondant for 9 years his general charractor as a man and Judge was good -</p>
        <p>Lewis H. Brayls, of Hardin county - was clerk of the cirucit court part of the time - never heard anything against the J. as a man or a Judge so far as he knows would be bound to give Mr Nixon credit upon his oath.</p>
        <p>Mr Hadley, Rep,s of Hardemon County - never heard J. H. general charractor spoken of before the Impeachment.</p>
        <p>P. M. Miller - became acquainted with J. H. in 1817, has been acquainted with since - has left the bench when witness speaking, and he the w. sit down - threw out hints about cases and offended him and other lawyers - dont think the lawyers with im removed in this way - thinks Nixon was prejudiced against the Judge, thought W. had too much influance with the Judge - Knows the Judge has frequently left the bench sit down to insult the Judge - thought it verry improper that the Judge should leave the bench as he did - told him so publickly &amp; privatly. may have stated that the Judge praised the Jury for political effect and so told him, which he the Judge denied. Nixon is diserving of credit. never knew the Judge in the cirucit to proceed with business when the Judges</p>
        <pb n="29" facs="0012_000115_000276_0029.jpg" xml:id="d4e468"/>
        <p>walked off from the bench, but has known it in the supreme court.</p>
        <p>alfred Balch - Judges frequently have leave the bench - A case of chancery court at Columbia - Judge <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">wont heare</unclear> him, but took out his opinion out of his pockett &amp; read it, and it against him - J. Haywood prosided - Judge White absent during whole of the argument - James Collingsworth - never new of any circuit Judges leaving the bench during examination or trial of any cause -</p>
        <p>the deposition of Daniel Cherry read by consent of parties Mr Fletcher again called, and states that in the case of U. States vs. . . that Judge M,cClain left the bench for 5 to 7 minutes</p>
        <p>Wm e. Anderson, sites some cases in which the fe,d Judge left the bench, and also where one of the Supreme court left the bench - never knew the cause to go on in the supreme court without leaving a competant corut never knew in the circuit court for the business to process while the Judge was absent. after which evidence the respondant stated that the evidence on the part of the respondant was closed -</p>
        <p>Adam <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">Hurstman-</unclear>states witness again called - Qn - by managers, what was the general practice of J. H. as to leaving the bench - dont recollect of his leaving the bench during examination of witnesses except in the case of the state vs vs Walden - in civil cases has frequently left the bench frequent complain to with the bar - they confined together upon that subject - publick compliant by the bar - also taking examination out of the hand of the</p>
        <pb n="30" facs="0012_000115_000276_0030.jpg" xml:id="d4e486"/>
        <p>bar - practiced before most of the circuit Judes in the state never knew the Judges or any of them to leave the bench as Judge Haskell did - dont think any setled <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">hastilety</unclear> against J. Haskell except on account of his leaving the bench before the Impeachment - Nixon was not dissatisfyed With J. H. as a man but did not think he done him Justice as an attourney -</p>
        <p>Judge Mitchell - never knew a Judge to leave the bench without stopping them - holds a tight reighn - dont let the bar wander from his subject - thinks he has seen the supreme court, or a member of the court leave the bench - but never a circuit Judge - generally gives a synopsis of the testimony, and a general view of the law - has published to the world his views</p>
        <p>Mr. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">Tobbert-</unclear> has frequently known Judge Haskell to leave the court house during trials - it was so common that he seldom noticed it - the bar made some objection to his course - bar remonstrated - the J. feelings was much hurt - talked of resighning - told him if he wished to do well but not that they desired him, that they only wanted him to change his course - frequently stopped - he would then return and tell them to go on and again leave the bench - thought it was treating the adminestration of Justice lightly, destroy the respect for the court -</p>
        <p>Wm Hodart - Judge Haskell frequently left the bench during the trial of causes, oftener during the aruement, but was not confined to those times only - the bar complained verry much of him as a Judge, but was personally friendly towards him - but where so much complaint <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">caul</unclear>
            </p>
        <pb n="31" facs="0012_000115_000276_0031.jpg" xml:id="d4e504"/>
        <p>not long remain so friendly - in the case of Newbold he was atty for the plantiff - his course on that occasion met his approbation - not near so much in the habit of laving the bench during the examination of witnesses, as in the argument of causes, but has known him accasionly to leave the bench during the examination of witnesses - the J. appeared to be displeased when the attourneys stopped - thinks Novm Term 1825 much <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">Jaring</unclear> between the Judge and the bar; J. complained at the bar, he told the J. they felt dissatisfyed also at the Judge, and mentioned to him that he took the examination of witnesses from the bar, and get into disoussion with the bar - Judge H, was fond of talking, would talk - the Judge seemed much hurt at what took place - talked of resigning if they wished him to do so: the bar was also affected - they wrote him a letter - he could not keep still and quiet - people talked about , that the lawyers could not mamage their own business and that the Judge ahd to maage their causes for them - commenced leaving the bench after the above difficulty say in 1825, has known him leave the bench out of hearing during examination of witnesses - but not often - his opinion now is that the testimony was not important when the Judge left the bench, that he could not hear what was going on in court verry  hospitable : the Judges standing before impeachment was good in Tipton and Haywood, in Maddison it is tolerable good - thinks the people was pleased to have Hamilton for Judge - the mamagers the stated that they was through with their evidence.</p>
        <pb n="32" facs="0012_000115_000276_0032.jpg" xml:id="d4e511"/>
        <p>Monday Morning Novr 21st 1831</p>
        <p>court met pursuant to adjournment, when the court by consent of the respondants counsil as well as the mamagers on the part of the house, adjournment was made to the Hall of the House of Representatives, to which they had been invited by the House of Rep,s Mr Allen, one of the managers opined the areument on the part of the H of Rep,s Mr dunlap, another of the managers then followed on the same side, and continued his argument until 40 minutes after 4 o,clock, he then requested the court ot adjourn until next morning, which I opposed, but a majority rose in favour of adjournment, court adjourned until 1/2 after 8 A.M.</p>
        <p>Tuesday Morning 1/2 after 9 o,clock court met, Novr, 22-1831 Mr Dunlap then continued his argument until 12 o,Clock M.</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
