<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000205_000200_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter, <name>E. Waldo Stacy</name> in Camp near Mossy Creek, Tenn. to Mother
                <date when="1862-03-09">1864 March 9</date>
            </title>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>Rozema, Laurel</name>
               <name>Dyson-Smith, Bridger</name>
            </respStmt>
            <author>
               <name type="person">
                  <name type="person">E. Waldo Stacy</name>
               </name>
            </author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <availability status="restricted">
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_000205_000200_0000</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Letter, E. Waldo Stacy in Camp near Mossy Creek, Tenn. to Mother 1864 March 9</title>
               <date when="1862-03-09">1864 March 9</date>
               <author>
                  <name type="person">E. Waldo Stacy</name>
               </author>
               <title>[Letter] <date when="1864-03-09">Mar 9th [1864]</date> Camp near Mossy
                        Creek Tenn [to] Mother</title>
               <date>2006-05-22</date>
               <author>
                  <name/>
               </author>
               <author>
                  <name type="person">Stacy, E. Waldo</name>
               </author>
               <date when="1864-03-09">Mar 9th [1864]</date>
               <extent>4p</extent>
               <note type="abstract">This letter, dated March 9th, 1864 from camp at Mossy
                        Creek, TN, is from E. Waldo Stacy of the 36th Massachusetts Infantry. The
                        letter details the events of February 23-March 9, 1864. Stacy and his
                        regiment advanced to Strawberry Plains before withdrawing to Mossy Creek
                        (now Jefferson City). He describes an encounter with a &quot;drunken rebel
                        lieutenant.&quot;</note>
               <note type="collection">Civil War Letter of E. Waldo Stacy, 1864</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS-2743</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
						omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH"/>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013" who="Rozema, Laurel">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
         <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e97">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_000205_000200_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e98"/>
            <p>Camp near Mossy Creek Tenn Mar 9th</p>
            <p>Dear Mother</p>
            <p>I suppose that before this letter reaches you, you will begin to wonder why I do
                    not write. But I will explain it to you. My last letter was written when we were
                    at Knoxville on the 23d of Febuary. On the 24th we received orders to take four
                    dats rations and be ready to march in light marching order. So we left our
                    knapsacks behind and I left all my writing materials in mine but last night
                    Nohum Farmer had a bunch of envelopes sent to him and he lent me one so with the
                    paper you sent I can now write. We expect our knapsacks will come up to us in a
                    few days. Well at eight o clock on the morning of the 24th we left our</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_000205_000200_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e106"/>
            <p>camp near Knoxville and marched that day to Strawberry Plains 16 miles. The
                    rebels left the day before so we had no trouble with them. We remained at the
                    Plains during the next day waiting for pontoons and rations to come up. On the
                    26th the boats having come up we crossed the river and went into camp. Our
                    regiment was on picket that day and over 20 deserters from Longstreets army come
                    in and gave themselves up. On the 27th we marched to Mossy Creek 14 miles. On
                    the 28th We marched to Morristown 11 miles. The day we marched to Morristown was
                    rainy and so was the next and we remained in camp during the 29th. The rain
                    carried away the railroad bridge over Flat Creek between Strawberry Plains and
                    Knoxville but they have got it <unclear reason="illegible" resp="lr">returned</unclear> now I believe. On the first of March we received orders to
                    fall back to Mossy Creek and accordingly we did so and we have been in camp here
                    since. I do not know what the reason</p>
            <pb n="3" facs="0012_000205_000200_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e113"/>
            <p>for falling back was but it is said that Gen Schefield had orders from Gen. Grant
                    not to advance further than five miles beyond Strawbery Plains but I do not know
                    how true it is. Longstreet and his army are reported to be all the other side of
                    Bulls Gap all but a few cavalry. Some of their cavalry came down as far as this
                    place the other day scouting round and drove in our cavalry pickets and attacked
                    our infantry pickets but they found out we were here which was probably all they
                    wanted and then retreated. We had one man belonging to the 17th Michigan
                    wounded. Part of our regiment was sent out to support the pickets at the time of
                    the attack. Col. Morrison went out with us. Col M. is a brave soldier he went
                    ahead of us to find out what he could about the enemy he did call on some
                    private to go. He wen out to a cornfield ahead of us and there he saw a rebel
                    riding along a little ahead of him. The rebel drew his pistol or attempted to
                    but Col. M. got</p>
            <pb n="4" facs="0012_000205_000200_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e117"/>
            <p>his out first and told the rebel to surrender which he did. He proved to be a
                    drunken rebel lieutenant. He was so drunk he could not walk straight when he got
                    off his horse. He had on one of our overcoats and Gen. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="lr">Feners</unclear> who was out also told our boys
                    if any of them wanted it to take it so one of them went and got it. The bridge
                    at Strawberry Plains is about half done I understand. We do not hear so much
                    talk about going north to recruit now as we did though it is still said we shall
                    go with Barnside when he goes which will not be till the middle of May. I do not
                    place to much dependace on going at all however for I should not be surprised if
                    we had to stay here. I am glad to hear that father is getting along so well give
                    my love to him. I have received your letters of the 7th and 20th and Mary of the
                    18th of Feb. I have also received some papers. I get a good many papers from you
                    and am very glad to get them but presume I do not get all you send. But I have
                    got most to the end of my sheet and I must close. </p>
            <p>My love to Mary and yourself.</p>
            <p>from your son</p>
            <p>E.W. Stacy.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
