<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000203_000200_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter, <name>Charles Fox</name> near Winchester, Tenn., to Sister <date when="1862-07-27">1862 July 27</date>
            </title>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>Rozema, Laurel</name>
               <name>Dyson-Smith, Bridger</name>
            </respStmt>
            <author>
               <name type="person">
                  <name type="person">Charles Fox</name>
               </name>
            </author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <availability status="restricted">
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_000203_000200_0000</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Letter, Charles Fox near Winchester, Tenn., to Sister 1862 July 27</title>
               <date when="1862-07-27">1862 July 27</date>
               <author>
                  <name type="person">Charles Fox</name>
               </author>
               <title>[Letter] <date when="1862-07-27">Sunday July 27th 1862</date> [near
                        Winchester, Tenn. to] Sister</title>
               <date>2006-05-22</date>
               <author>
                  <name/>
               </author>
               <author>
                  <name type="person">Fox, Charles</name>
               </author>
               <date when="1862-07-27">Sunday July 27th 1862</date>
               <extent>4p</extent>
               <note type="abstract">In a letter dated July 27, 1862, Charles Fox, a soldier
                        from Indiana, writes to his sister from camp &quot;within three miles of
                        Winchester, Tenn.&quot; Fox tells his sister that he is &quot;very tired of the
                        service and would give anything to get out of it.&quot; He complains of the
                        actions of the commissioned officers and expresses his desire for a quick
                        end to the war. </note>
               <note type="collection">Charles Fox Civil War Letter, 1862</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS.2763</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
						omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH"/>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013" who="Rozema, Laurel">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
         <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e100">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_000203_000200_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e101"/>
            <p>Dear Sister</p>
            <p>I heard from you a day or so ago, so I thought I would answer your kind letter to
                    me throug Miss Mary Smith by the way a particular friend of mine I am glad to
                    heare you are well and getting along finely Mary did not write me much news
                    concerning what was in your letter but wished me to answer it which I am trying
                    to do I am well at present But very tired of the service And would give anything
                    to get out of it it is such a mean Batterry that one can hardly live. The
                    officers are not worth a cent I would as soon have a wooden man over me as any
                    of them I was Gunner on a six pound Gun and I <unclear reason="illegible" resp="lr">resined</unclear> the other day and now I am high private, But it is not with us non commissioned
                    officers as it is With the commissioned for when they resign they can quit and
                    go home But we</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_000203_000200_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e110"/>
            <p>Cannot But have to stay until the war is over or our three years is out which I
                    hope will soon be. But I cannot tell when it will we have left Corinth and we
                    Came on East further within 50 or 60 miles of Chattanooga where there are some
                    abel troops at present - But I should not <unclear reason="illegible" resp="lr">wonder</unclear> if we went thru to Clean them out before long we are now
                    within three miles of Winchester Tenn with a verry wet camping Ground in the
                    woods, We cannot get any papers here at all and cannot tell whether Richmond is
                    taken or not I wish you would send me papers the Grunfield Paper especially for
                    there is always a lot of News in it It is almost as good as a letter of itself,
                    Well tell me how are all the folks in The old town and how are times there at
                    present and how are you getting along and tell me whether Father thinks of
                    coming out west or not we all expect the war will be pretty much over When
                    Richmond is taken Although there is Some few Guerrillas they will soon be </p>
            <pb n="3" facs="0012_000203_000200_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e117"/>
            <p>whiped out If I had Knowed as much before I enlisted as I do now I would never
                    come as a private soldier (no not I) But here I am and cannot help it and here I
                    have got to stay unless I get sick, and then only go home on a sick furlough I
                    got a letter from Father some time ago and he said Fostina was not married yet
                    and that Cistopher Clapp was in McClellans Army and Dwight married Widow Cronin,
                    Dan Cronins widow I think Girls are scarce there to marry such a woman as she is
                    why here in the south where we are there 20 Girls to one young man and as pretty
                    us over I saw and rich one the trouble with them is they are Decent and dont
                    like the northern men You need not be surprised to hear of me being <unclear reason="illegible" resp="lr">married</unclear> if ever I get out of this
                    army Write me all the news and give my best respects to all the Folks and my
                    friends and tell them the west is the place to <unclear reason="illegible" resp="lr">make</unclear> money write soon no more at present</p>
            <p>Excuse this writing and mistakes from Your Brother Chas. G Fox</p>
            <pb n="4" facs="0012_000203_000200_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e129"/>
            <p>Direct</p>
            <p>6th Ind. Battery</p>
            <p>In Care of Capt Geo. T. Cochran,</p>
            <p>6th Division Gen Woods Div</p>
            <p>To follow the Batterry</p>
            <p>Battery</p>
            <p>Batterry</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
