<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000115_000279_0000">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Legal Document,
					<name>State of Tennessee Smith County</name>
				                    , deed of land to David Burford<date when="1837-10-26">1837 October 26</date>
            </title>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
          <name>Jennings, Sabra</name>
        </respStmt>
        <author>
          <name type="person">State of Tennessee Smith County</name>
        </author>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
        <date>2013</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
        </availability>
        <idno type="SPC">0012_000115_000279_0000</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Legal Document, State of Tennessee Smith County , deed of land to David Burford1837 October 26</title>
          <date when="1837-10-26">1837 October 26</date>
          <author>
            <name type="person">State of Tennessee Smith County</name>
          </author>
          <extent>5 pages</extent>
          <note type="collection">David Burford Papers</note>
          <note type="manuscript">MS.1027</note>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
        <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
        <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
        <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as "turn page over" have been
						omitted.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy>
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="LCSH">
          <term>Slave trade -- Southern States.</term>
          <term>Slavery -- Tennessee</term>
          <term>Slavery -- Virginia.</term>
          <term>Tennessee. Militia.</term>
          <term>United States -- History -- War of 1812.</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change when="2013" who="Jennings, Sabra">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
      <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e38">
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_000115_000279_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e39"/>
        <p>State of Tennessee Smith County</p>
        <p>Personally appears before me Mr John J Burnett luk of Smith County Court. William Paym the within names Bargain in with whom I am personally aquainted and who adknowledged that he securited the within deed in Trust to David Burford Trustee, for 222 acres of land non or legs lying in Smith County. also Ten Negros bearing date the 26 th Day of October 1837 for the purchases this Court and Notary my hand at office this 27 th day of October 1837 </p>
        <p>John J Dummot <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SLJ">elutt</unclear>
            </p>
        <p>of Smith County Court</p>
        <p>State of Tennesse</p>
        <p>Smith County Registers office Oct. 27 th 1837 I hereby certify that the enclosed deed in trust from William Payne to David Burford Trustee together with the above probate for Registration is duly Reistered in any office in Bank of <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SLJ">Jeage 65 &amp; 66 HGY</unclear>
            </p>
        <p>
          <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SLJ">Manary Mazy Register</unclear>
        </p>
        <p>of Smith County</p>
        <note type="transcription">The following text is a continuation of the second page of the letter.</note>
        <p>William Payne to Trust deed David Burford</p>
        <p>222</p>
        <p>100</p>
        <p>25</p>
        <p>$1.47 note</p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_000115_000279_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e75"/>
        <p>This deed made the twenty sixth day of October, anno domini, eighteen hundred and thirty seven, between William Payne of the one part and David Burford of the other part, both of Smith County, witnesseth that for and in consideration of the sum of ten dollars by the said David to the said William in hand paid and for and in consideration of the uses and trusts here in after mentioned, the Lord William Payne hath granted, bargaind, sold transferred and conveyed to the said David Burford the following real and personal estate, trust, one tract of land lying in said County, containing two hundred and twenty two acres, more or less,  adjoining the lands of Mrs Hammock ,Thomas Willbourn and others, part of said tract being the same conveyed to said William Payne by William Parker, as <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SLJ">[smudge]</unclear> residence of said tract being the same conveyed to said William Payne by Richard Parker and Thomas Willbourne - and reference is to be had to said deeds for the boundaries of said tract - said tract of land is the same on which the said William Payne now resides.</p>
        <p>Also one negro man slave, named Bird, of dark colour aged twenty five years - one negro woman slaved named Patty of yellow colour, aged thirty years - one negro boy slave named Joe, of yellow colour aged sixteen years - one negro boy slave named Cephus, of dark colour, aged fifteen years - one negro girl slave named Mary, of dark colour, aged six years - one negro girl slave named Letha of dark colour, aged five years - One negro boy slave named Lawson, of yellow colour aged eighteen months - One negro woman slave named Charlotte of dark colour, aged thirtyfive years - one negro girl slave</p>
        <pb n="3" facs="0012_000115_000279_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e84"/>
        <p>named Judy, of dark colour aged three years, daughter of said Charlotte - also an infant child of said negro woman Charlotte, five weeks old - in all ten negro slaves - said negroes Joe, Mary, Letha, Cephus and Lawson being children of said negro Patty. </p>
        <p>To have and to hold said tract of land, and said ten negro slaves with their future increase, to the said David Burford, his heirs and assigns forever against the claim of the said William Payne and all other persons whatsoever. In trust, nevertheless, for the following uses and purposes. times. Whereby said William Payne and one Hamilton Payne heretofore on the 17 January 1837 executed three promissory notes to Johnson and Corley due the 1 st January 1838, the first of said notes, for the sum of Seven hundred dollars, and which has since been endorsed by said Johnson &amp; Corley to Bryan, Rodem and Heylar, the sum of said notes, <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SLJ">[smudge]</unclear> sum of four hundred and fifty dollars ninety six cents, and the third of said notes, for the sum of one hundred dollars - said sums and third mentioned notes have since been endorsed by said Johnson &amp; Corley to Wingate Sarcall &amp; Knox, and whereas also said William Payne &amp; Hamilton have this day executed three other promissory notes to said Johnson &amp; Corley, the first of said last mentioned notes, for the sum of nine hundred &amp; eighty nine 32/100 dollars, due 25 December 1838 - the sums of said last mentioned notes, for the sum of one thousand and forty five 33/100 dollars, due 25th December 1839 and the third of said cash mentioned notes, for the sum of Eleven hundred and one 33/100 dollars and due 25 December 1840 - said there last mentioned notes being for the amount of principal and interest to said cash mentioned duts, of five promissory notes executed to said Johnson &amp; Corly by said William &amp; Hamilton Payne, on the 17 January 1837, and being the same filed as exhibits.</p>
        <pb n="4" facs="0012_000115_000279_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e93"/>
        <p>with the bill of said Johnson &amp; Corley against said William &amp; Hamilton Payne, in the Chancery court at Carthage. and where as said parties have compromised said suit in Chancery, and said Johnson &amp; Corley, have extended the time for payment of the amount of said exhibited notes as aforesaid; and the said William &amp; Hamilton Payne desirous of securing the payment of the notes by them executed to said Johnson &amp; Corley, and which has been by them endorsed as aforesaid; and of also securing the payment of said notes also executed to said Johnson &amp; Corley and due December 1838, December 1839 and December 1840 as aforesaid, this deed has been executed, and the parties have mutually chosen said David Burford as trustee - and it is hereby agreed and declared, that if said William &amp; Hamilton Payne shall fail to pay said first mentioned notes due 1st January 1838 as aforesaid (and endorsed by said Johnson &amp; Corley as aforesaid), when the same shall fall due and payable, that then, the said David Burford shall whenever thento afterwards requested by the said William &amp; Corley or the said Hiram H. Johnson their agent or attorney, proceed to sell so much of the property herein conveyed as shall be sufficiently to pay said first mentioned promissory notes and all interest and charges due them and it is further agreed and declared that if the said William &amp; Hamilton Payne shall fail to pay said last mentioned notes as they annually become due and payable, to mit, on the 25 December 1838, 25 December 1839 and 25 December 1840, that Thurs, and upon each failure to pay as either of said last mentioned notes shall fall due, the said David Burford shall whenever thereafter, by the said Johnson &amp; Corley or either fo them, or their agent or attorney requested, proceed to sell such part, or the whole of the property herein conveyed as will be sufficient to pay said last mentioned notes, as they</p>
        <pb n="5" facs="0012_000115_000279_0005.jpg" xml:id="d4e97"/>
        <p>may become due as aforesaid and all interest and charges. It is agreed and declared that said David Burford shall give ten days notice of all sales to be made by him, by advertisement in writing at the Parish, and also in Carthage - and that the sales shall be for cash, and by public auction - provided however, said sales or either of them may be by private contract, the said William Payne consenting and joining in the deed or bill of sale with said trustee, and the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SLJ">process</unclear> of said sale being by said trustee applied to the payment of said notes.</p>
        <p>This further agreed and declared that said William Payne may continued in possession of said land and also of the negroes, until the same may be called for by said David Burford for the purpose of making sales as herein decided. Unless, in the opinion of said trustee, said property or any part thereof shall be in danger of being removed, mal treated, or the safety of said Corley &amp; Johnsons claims otherwise endangered - Then or in within of said courts, it is agreed and declared that said David Burford shall take said property into his possession, and appoint such receiver, manager or overseer as he may deem necessary - should the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SLJ">[smudge]</unclear> the debts herein mentioned be paid by said William &amp; Hamilton, without a sale of said property, or any part thereof, then, said David Burford is to recovery the same, to said William Payne, at his the said Payees, cost and charges - so, any surplus of said property or the proceeds thereof, after satisfying the debts herein mentioned, is to be conveyed, or paid over, to said William Payne. All cost and charges incurred by said David Burford in the execution of the within trusts to be paid out of the estate conveyed or by the said William Payne. In the event of sale, it is agreed that payment to the trustee, the said David Burford, shall discharge the purchaser from seeing to the application of the purchase money. And it is further understood and agreed that said Johnson &amp; Corley hold a lien in Equity on the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SLJ">hory</unclear>and let purchased of them by the said William &amp;Hamilton Payne - and nothing herein shall be so construed, as waiving, or abandoning, said lien for the purchase money for said house &amp; lot; said lot is situated at the parish, and is the same previously sold by said David Burford to said Johnson &amp; Corley - The three notes held by said Johnson &amp;Corley or said Msr hamilton Payne and due as aforesaid 25. Dec. 1838, 25 dc. 1839 &amp; 25 Dec. 1840.- Witness my hand and seal date <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SLJ">fish</unclear>within.</p>
        <p>ack</p>
        <p>Wm Payne seal</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
