<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:id="ms0012_001303_000234_0000">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Letter,
					<name>James L. Dodds</name>
				                   in France to Ellen Smith in Jackson, Tenn.,<date when="1918-12-05">1918 Dec. 5</date>
            </title>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
          <name>White, Park</name>
        </respStmt>
        <author>
          <name type="person">James L. Dodds</name>
        </author>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
        <date>2013</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
        </availability>
        <idno type="SPC">0012_001303_000234_0000</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Letter, James L. Dodds in France to Ellen Smith in Jackson, Tenn.,1918 Dec. 5</title>
          <date when="1918-12-05">1918 Dec. 5</date>
          <author>
            <name type="person">James L. Dodds</name>
          </author>
          <extent>12 pages</extent>
          <note type="collection">Smith Family Papers</note>
          <note type="manuscript">1303</note>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
        <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
        <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
        <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as "turn page over" have been
						omitted.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy>
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="LCSH">
          <term>Jackson (Tenn.) -- History.</term>
          <term>Jackson (Tenn.) -- Social life and customs.</term>
          <term>Knoxville (Tenn.) -- History.</term>
          <term>Newton County (Ind.) -- Genealogy.</term>
          <term>Tennessee Volunteers (Football team).</term>
          <term>University of Tennessee, Knoxville.</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change when="2013" who="White, Park">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
      <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e38">
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_001303_000234_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e39"/>
        <p>James L. Dodds</p>
        <p>Truck Co # 8 = 23 Engis</p>
        <p>American Exp Force</p>
        <p>Miss Ellen Smith</p>
        <p>111 Hatton Street</p>
        <p>Jackson</p>
        <p>Tennessee</p>
        <p>U.S.A.</p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_001303_000234_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e57"/>
        <p>Dec 5 1918</p>
        <p>Dear Ellen:</p>
        <p>I received a letter from you to day dated Oct. 8  There is no use of me trying to tell you how glad I was to here from once more. I will say I was lucky though to ever get it if you were three days writing it.</p>
        <p>Well I have had a days rest I havent been out of the house except for my meals</p>
        <p>We have had several visitors boys from our old Company (L.) have been coming in all day  Was real glad to see them I have been gone from them over two months. </p>
        <p>And I am always</p>
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_001303_000234_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e71"/>
        <p>to see old friends, I had just come back from a three days trip up the Meuse river  I will tell you how I made the trip so you can look on the map and see for yourself if you want to</p>
        <p>I went by the way of Verdun and followed the Meuse river up close to Sedan  We started about 6 PM one night and drove most all night</p>
        <p>We always take our beds which is about four blankets and sleep on or under the trucks. But as usual was raining that night so had to sleep in the trucks.</p>
        <p>I thought I was going to get a trip over in Germany. But missed it.</p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_001303_000234_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e81"/>
        <p>Jno Cartmell started but turned back on account of not needing all the truck, I thank he was disappointed  He said he was going over and find him a German girl</p>
        <p>He couldnt talk to these French girls so he would try and see if he could do any good with the Germans</p>
        <p>I will tell you these soldiers will talk you girls almost to death when they get back for has been a long time since they had a good old chat with a lady</p>
        <p>I was coming in to camp the other evening and I found four Red Cross nurses walking up the road and they ask me to let them ride</p>
        <p>Well you know I couldnt refuse</p>
        <pb n="3" facs="0012_001303_000234_0005.jpg" xml:id="d4e93"/>
        <p>Of course they wanted to know all about what I had been doing and how long I had been over what I belong to and where I come from in the states and if I was anxious to get back home</p>
        <p>I told them I would walk five hundred miles backwards if that would get me home any quicker.</p>
        <p>I thank we are going to move from here pretty soon  I dont know just where we will go  But will be glad to leave here and get back where the roads are in better shape</p>
        <p>Truck driving around here is a pretty hard job. The roads have been torn up so bad </p>
        <pb n="4" facs="0012_001303_000234_0006.jpg" xml:id="d4e103"/>
        <p>from shell fire. Of course they are a lots better than they were when the drive first started you know this 23 Engineers have been working on them HaHa.</p>
        <p>And another thing I have been all over this part of the country and want to move to a new place. We have had a good chance to see this country for we have some long trips</p>
        <p>When I left the Larraine front we drove through the country which was a three days trip and when we leave here we will drive our trucks</p>
        <p>I do hope it is pretty weather  You said you hadnt heard</p>
        <pb n="5" facs="0012_001303_000234_0007.jpg" xml:id="d4e114"/>
        <p>from me in most a month  Will that is the time I didnt have time to write to any one. I wrote you once in about five weeks. </p>
        <p>I left the Larraine front and came up here and in a few days after we got here the drive started. I worked most day and night for a month. And we couldnt get paper to write on</p>
        <p>Well to make a long story short just didnt have time to write.</p>
        <p>You said you would like to ask me a lots of questions well go ahead I will try to answer any thing you</p>
        <pb n="6" facs="0012_001303_000234_0008.jpg" xml:id="d4e124"/>
        <p>want to know</p>
        <p>I told you in my last letter where I was and where I had been since coming across</p>
        <p>I know there was some celebration all over the states when this war was over  I would have liked to have been there and seen the fun  Well there was some time over here also.</p>
        <p>I believe you are a regular nurse for the children  I must say that is kind of you to stay at home and keep the kids while the rest celebrate.</p>
        <p>What do they say when Aunt Ellen goes to the country for a week  I know they miss you</p>
        <pb n="7" facs="0012_001303_000234_0009.jpg" xml:id="d4e136"/>
        <p>Now when I get home you will have to cut out that going to the country. But Linn and Harold will be back by that time and they wont need you on the farm.</p>
        <p>I see where all the aerial squadrons are going home soon so guess Linn soon be home. I know Peachie will be some glad to see him get home.</p>
        <p>Well how is Aunt Flossy?(Floy) by this time hope she is well again. I heard Everett had gone back to Memphis an that <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">un</unclear>
            </p>
        <p>No I never here from Esther I wrote to her and her husband but have never heard from</p>
        <pb n="8" facs="0012_001303_000234_0010.jpg" xml:id="d4e148"/>
        <p>them, I guess they are to busy loving to write to any one. Well what on earth could she have got mad at you about  I guess she will be alright before long.</p>
        <p>Well I wish I could be there to take you to a dance Myself  Well I dont know wheather I can dance or not has been over a year since I tried to dance Myself.</p>
        <p>I might learn you though if you was willing to learn  But you know the old saying you would have to learn to love your teacher. How about it?</p>
        <pb n="9" facs="0012_001303_000234_0011.jpg" xml:id="d4e156"/>
        <p>No I have never seen any of the Jaxan boys except Rufe Gregory. I told you about that some time ago</p>
        <p>The Jaxan boys have been fighting with the English in Belgium  I have never been close to them that I know of</p>
        <p>The Jaxan boys are in the 30 Div. I here they have started home or rather I saw in the paper where they were going home  Now I should have been in the 30 Div.</p>
        <p>I am sorry to here of George Miller death I remember him very well. What Div. was he in? I guess he was with the Tennessee boys though</p>
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_001303_000234_0012.jpg" xml:id="d4e166"/>
        <p>Well I have about run out of news and Jno Cortmell and Orr have up a big argument</p>
        <p>So if you run across any thing that dont sound just right you can know the reason.</p>
        <p>So here is wishing you a Merry Christmas and a happy New Year  And write me real often</p>
        <p>with lots of love from</p>
        <p>James L Dodds</p>
        <p>Truck Co # 8 = 23 Engis</p>
        <p>American Exp Forces</p>
        <p>Via N.Y.       France</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
