<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000599_000252_0000">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Letter,
					<name>Henry Brown</name>
				                     to Caroline M. Brown, <date>undated</date>
            </title>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
          <name>White, Park</name>
        </respStmt>
        <author>
          <name type="person">Henry Brown</name>
        </author>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
        <date>2013</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
        </availability>
        <idno type="SPC">0012_000599_000252_0000</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Letter, Henry Brown to Caroline M. Brown,</title>
          <date>undated</date>
          <author>
            <name type="person">Henry Brown</name>
          </author>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <note type="collection">Henry Brown Collection</note>
          <note type="manuscript">MS.599</note>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
        <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
        <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
        <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as "turn page over" have been
						omitted.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy>
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="LCSH">
          <term>Ohio -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives.</term>
          <term>Ohio -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.</term>
          <term>Soldiers -- Ohio -- Correspondence.</term>
          <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives.</term>
          <term>United States. Army. Ohio Infantry Regiment, 31st (1861-1865)</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change when="2013" who="White, Park">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
      <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e37">
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_000599_000252_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e38"/>
        <p>This to the boys  Dear Isaiah and george I would love to See You Soon if it was So I could I do Feel in hope that it will not be
				       long till That time will Come for i am not Fit for duty here  And i do not think I will be Soon if Ever  I feel afraid that i Will be 
				       trubled with The Dropsy the rest Of my days i may get will if i could get to come home</p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_000599_000252_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e42"/>
        <p>But if i have to Stay In the Service i will Die after a while with It it i am afraid but If i should never get Home i want you Boys to
				  be good boys TC your mother and The Neighbours for That is the way to Have friends in this World if i get to come Home i will
				  fetch one Of the best little that Is in the 31st regt now I am Sitting there Alone and feel verry Lonesome to if you Boys was here
				  to run in and out i would like it</p>
        <pb n="3" facs="0012_000599_000252_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e46"/>
        <p>I want to See you all The worst old way  And i want to See The Stock and see how You do up your farming And i want to see
				  The Neighbours too with The rest of you but you And your mother first  Of all I have seen Anough of this war  You had better
				  think If i get out of this It will take a pretty Man to get me in the Next you had better Think Now Boys i Want you to form Some
				  kind of a better</p>
        <pb n="4" facs="0012_000599_000252_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e50"/>
        <p>write soon  I will read it with Pleasure i tell i <unclear reason="illegible" resp="pw">bane</unclear>To hear from you boy As
				  well as your mother  Now write and dont Neglect it you must All write and tell Me how you got along with your harvest Any way
				  and how your Corn looks to And how your oats Are and all these Little things are out Thare such things  Looks verry Bad here
				  So good by to mother And boys and all</p>
        <p>Henry Brown to <unclear reason="illegible" resp="pw">his</unclear>Boys</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
