<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000060_000291_0000">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Letter,
					<name>Ramsey, J.G.M.</name>
				                   in New York, N.Y., to M.B.C. Ramsey in Mecklenburg, Tenn., <date when="1850-09-18">1850 September 18</date>
            </title>
        <author>
          <name type="person">Ramsey, J. G. M. (James Gettys McGready)</name>
        </author>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
          <name>Hogan, Josh</name>
          <name>Dyson-Smith, Bridger</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
        <date>2013</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
        </availability>
        <idno type="SPC">0012_000060_000291_0000</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Letter, Ramsey, J.G.M. in New York, N.Y., to M.B.C. Ramsey in Mecklenburg, Tenn., 1850 September 18</title>
          <date when="1850-09-18">1850 September 18</date>
          <author>
            <name type="person">Ramsey, J.G.M.</name>
          </author>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <note type="collection">James Gettys McGready Ramsey Papers, 1850</note>
          <note type="manuscript">MS.0253</note>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
        <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
        <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
        <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as "turn page over" have been
						omitted.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy>
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="LCSH">
          <term>Ramsey, J. G. M.,  (James Gettys McGready), 1797-1884</term>
          <term>Confederate States of America. Dept. of the Treasury.</term>
          <term>East Tennessee and Georgia Railroad Company</term>
          <term>Knoxville (Tenn.) -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.</term>
          <term>Mecklenburg Declaration of Independence.</term>
          <term>Overland journeys to the Pacific.</term>
          <term>Tennessee -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.</term>
          <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change when="2013" who="Hogan, Josh">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
      <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e43">
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_000060_000291_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e44"/>
        <p>
          <unclear reason="Illegible" resp="JH">Frm</unclear>
        </p>
        <p>J.G.M. Ramsey, P.M.</p>
        <p>Mecklenburg T.</p>
        <p>Mrs. M.B.C. Ramsey</p>
        <p>Mecklenburg</p>
        <p>Near Knoxville</p>
        <p>Tennessee</p>
        <p>
          <unclear reason="Illegible" resp="JH">Kindness of Mr. Pickle</unclear>
        </p>
        <p>P.S. With <unclear reason="Illegible" resp="JH">my</unclear> affectionate regards to all of your worthy family</p>
        <p>Ever your friend</p>
        <p><unclear reason="Illegible" resp="JH">John</unclear> Roberts</p>
        <p>Mrs. M.B.C. Ramsey</p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_000060_000291_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e78"/>
        <p>Irving House N.Y. Sep. 18. 1850.</p>
        <p>My Dear Wife</p>
        <p>I wrote hastily to you or Crozier three days ago &amp; mentioned then that I had arrived here well.  It has been a source of much anxiety to me that I have not received a line from any of you since Crozier wrote me at Nashville.  I must get a letter to day or my anxiety will be increased.  Even the Knoxville newspapers have not come to Yates &amp; the reading rooms.  Anything from Tennessee would be now so cheering &amp; acceptable.  I feel consoled by the hope that you &amp; the rest are all well.  I am quite so.  The weather here is pleasant &amp; since I have stoped travelling I am improving every way.  The night I left Nashville the stage was crowded &amp; they would have the blinds up &amp; as tobacco chewers must be next the windows I took cold &amp; never entirely overcome it till I got here.  It was not less a disappointment to me than I know it must have been to Liddy that I cold not go by Richmond &amp; see the poor child but I heard at Bardstown that the Ohio by the prevalent fogs &amp; low water could not be ascended to Pittsburg &amp; I at once determined to turn off to Louisville &amp; take the Lake route to this City.  I enjoyed the travelling pretty well but the voy</p>
        <pb n="3" facs="0012_000060_000291_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e86"/>
        <p>age was a little stormy.  We passed the wreck of the Griffin in which so many were lost.  I shall have a great deal to tell to our young folks about Ohio - Sandusky City Buffallo.  The falls of Niagara.  My sail down  Lake <unclear reason="Illegible" resp="JH">Sencha</unclear> &amp; the trip along the Erie Rail Road.  56 hours only are required to come from Cincinnati to N.Y.  Nearly four hundred miles are passed the last day.  Tell M.J. &amp; H. that I have not yet been to see the Swedish nightingale Jinny Lind - nor to hear the warblings of the best vocalist in the world.  I dont know that I will go.  I hear nothing else but her name every where Jinny Lind hats - bonnets - kanes - books - boots &amp; even sausages.  I believe as I told the brokers this morning that I will call my bonds Jinny Lind stocks - as nothing under any other name will sell now in N.Y.  Tell them that I have given into the prevailing mania only so far as to buy some Jinny Lind music for them.</p>
        <p>I cannot say when I will leave here - probably Friday.  I have made no sales &amp; received no offers that I will entertain.  I must stay a short time longer here &amp; at Philadelphia to feel the stock market.  If I can sell only enough to pay the duties on the first cargo of iron I will repair immediately to Charleston &amp; Savannah but will write you occasionaly before I reach there.  At present I think I will</p>
        <pb n="4" facs="0012_000060_000291_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e95"/>
        <p>be next Sunday 22nd in Philadelphia.  Sunday 29th in Charleston &amp; during the succeeding week be at Savannah.  Or if the first cargo comes to Charleston I will be with you soon after.</p>
        <p>I can say nothing about business at home.  I know our little managers there will do every thing that boys of their age can do about the farms - crops &amp;c. <gap resp="Hogan"/> I am more uneasy about sickness there than any thing else - but our kind heavenly parent can take care of &amp; protect us alike absent or together - at home &amp; abroad in sickness &amp; in health &amp; to his good Providence I commit you all.  Let Crozier stay with you as much as he can spare time <gap resp="Hogan"/> his business.  I think on account of the scarcity of corn some of our horses had better be sold if fair prices can be got for them.  I have no news from California that you do not see.  The next steamer takes out the Pacific Mail &amp; I will write by it to our wanderers.  I wrote to you all along the route but expect my letters may not have reached you.  They were left in the R.R. offices &amp; cabins of S.B. Captains &amp; written so hastily that you are as well without them.  Love to you my dear Peggy &amp; the children &amp; good wishes to all friends</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
