<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_001445_000200_0000">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Letter,
					<name>Sophema</name>
				                    in Nashville, Tenn., to her sister<date when="1874-03-20">1874 Mar. 20</date>
            </title>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
          <name>Mincey, Jennifer</name>
        </respStmt>
        <author>
          <name type="person">Sophema</name>
        </author>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
        <date>2013</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
        </availability>
        <idno type="SPC">0012_001445_000200_0000</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Letter, Sophema in Nashville, Tenn., to her sister1874 Mar. 20</title>
          <date when="1874-03-20">1874 Mar. 20</date>
          <author>
            <name type="person">Sophema</name>
          </author>
          <extent>2 pages</extent>
          <note type="collection">Nashville Cholera Letter</note>
          <note type="manuscript">MS.3135</note>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
        <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
        <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
        <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as "turn page over" have been
						omitted.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy>
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="LCSH">
          <term>Cholera -- Tennessee -- Nashville.</term>
          <term>Christianity -- Southern States.</term>
          <term>Nashville (Tenn.) -- History.</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change when="2013" who="Mincey, Jennifer">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
      <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e39">
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_001445_000200_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e40"/>
        <p>Nashville March the 20 1874</p>
        <p>My ever Dear Sister <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">Electa</unclear>
            </p>
        <p><unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">I no</unclear> you cannot think me very Dear in not writing, to you, but alass I cannot frame no excuse only negligence I cannot rember the last letter I rec from you but I believe it was about the time Uncle Ben David Died I do not remember wheather I have answered it or not, with me time flies fast that Is bearing me to my long home, but I do not wish to complain, nor wish my time long or short but hope to be <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">resined</unclear> to the will of God in all things, the Lord is &amp; has been very good unto me all the days of my life, therefore would I desire to be thanful myhealth is &amp; has been very good through the Summer &amp; fall during the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">Chollory</unclear> times I went up in the country on the Farm &amp; stayed some 3 or 4 weeks it was a very distressing &amp; alarming time all that could &amp; was able to get a way left for the country &amp; wattering places I cannot paint the seen to you but as I live close by 2 <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">underlakes</unclear> I had a great chance to see of its awafull <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">havoc</unclear> one day it was published that there was 1,27 died in one day &amp; doubtless that was not all every one felt the efect more or less some took provisions &amp; went to the woods as they could not find accomodations buisness of all kinds was suspeneded, it is called now healthy as is common, but times are called very hard &amp; dull in the Months of May I was more the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">Buisey</unclear> from Sept to Christmas</p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_001445_000200_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e67"/>
        <note type="transcription">The following text is a continuation of the second page of the letter.</note>
        <p>nothing in comparision to the joy in meeting you once more I often think of you &amp; wonder if you <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">gea</unclear> old like me my hair is quite gray &amp; I can see my facultys &amp; memory are failing me but still my health is good write to me &amp; let me hear from you your Sister <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">Sophema</unclear>
            </p>
        <note type="transcription">The preceding text is a continuation of the second page of the letter.</note>
        <p>I have kept 2 girls have one with me now a going to school we have had very interesting meetings this Winter I have enjoyed them the best I ever have since I have been hear Prayer Meetings hear are not conducted as they are where I used to be few are called onto Pray no one says anything but the Preacher, my past life more more then <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">surpriseth</unclear> me, I have no desire to live my life over again sometimes <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">I rejoice</unclear> that my days are so fast number my up then a gain I fear that I like Moses may never be permitted to enter <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">Canaan</unclear> the Promised land but God hat sed come unto me &amp; be ye saved Dear Sister how is it with you are you ready waiting &amp; prepared for the coming of the Son of Man we according to the corse of nature have not many years longer to live let us try &amp; live so we may meat each other in a better wourld - we have had a very pleasant winter no snow but once some got out these steds for sport but you could hear the grit &amp; gridn so they did not want not <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">maney</unclear> Bells the Peach trees are now in Bloom but I fear they may be frosts &amp; <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">inguse</unclear> them we are now having much rain I dont think this is much of a Farming country or it is subject to eather wet or dry but still the country is kept up still flourishes &amp; populates both with white &amp; Black, I wish you could come &amp; see me I would take all the pains I could in trying to show you the Southern Stile, but that would</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
