<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000091_000233_0000">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Letter,
					<name>David Jones</name>
				                    to his wife <date>undated</date>
            </title>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
          <name>Smither, Elizabeth</name>
        </respStmt>
        <author>
          <name type="person">David Jones</name>
        </author>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
        <date>2013</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
        </availability>
        <idno type="SPC">0012_000091_000233_0000</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Letter, David Jones to his wife</title>
          <date>undated</date>
          <author>
            <name type="person">David Jones</name>
          </author>
          <extent>2 pages</extent>
          <note type="collection">David Jones letters</note>
          <note type="manuscript">MS.2685</note>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
        <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
        <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
        <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as "turn page over" have been
						omitted.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy>
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="LCSH">
          <term>Jones, Anna</term>
          <term>Jones, David L.</term>
          <term>Nashville (Tenn.).</term>
          <term>Pennsylvania -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives.</term>
          <term>United States. Army. Pennsylvania Cavalry Regiment, 19th (1863-1866).</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change when="2013" who="Smither, Elizabeth">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
      <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e37">
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_000091_000233_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e38"/>
        <p>I dont know how the weather is with you there whether it is cold or Pleasant if safe in your opinion i would give the children Some Sulpher it is cold enough for an Overcoat here this morning although we have not a spark of fire in the house All our fellows nearly are out of money <unclear reason="illegible" resp="EMS">Snubbs</unclear> have not had a cent for a Long time even when he sends to his wife i give him stamp Do not let any one know this though Ill tell you a Joke on him him and some more fellows went to the wharf and they came a cross a Pittsburgh Boat and for their dinner there Snubbs ate to hearty and when he came back he was that bad that I thought he would have died but he got over it I dont know of anything else to write you about Just now </p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_000091_000233_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e45"/>
        <p>I have wrote you a great deal this week i shall try and manage in writing so as you will hear from me twice a week I cant expect you to write often to me though this morning is Just like a fair here some cleaning their guns some <unclear reason="illegible" resp="EMS">swearing</unclear> some singing  if some shaving Now i will close my letter as soon as I get that from the cap i shall send it you right away give my respects to all that enquires for me I do not know whether Jane is with you or not - Does Sharon ask of me Does Anna May make any effort of walking yet Tell the older ones to try and be good Kiss all the children for me while I remain yours faithfully </p>
        <p>David</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
