<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:id="ms0012_001303_000228_0000">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Letter,
					<name>James L. Dodds</name>
				                   in France to Ellen Smith in Jackson, Tenn.,<date when="1918-07-22">1918 July 22</date>
            </title>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
          <name>White, Park</name>
        </respStmt>
        <author>
          <name type="person">James L. Dodds</name>
        </author>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
        <date>2013</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
        </availability>
        <idno type="SPC">0012_001303_000228_0000</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Letter, James L. Dodds in France to Ellen Smith in Jackson, Tenn.,1918 July 22</title>
          <date when="1918-07-22">1918 July 22</date>
          <author>
            <name type="person">James L. Dodds</name>
          </author>
          <extent>3 pages</extent>
          <note type="collection">Smith Family Papers</note>
          <note type="manuscript">1303</note>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
        <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
        <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
        <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as "turn page over" have been
						omitted.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy>
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="LCSH">
          <term>Jackson (Tenn.) -- History.</term>
          <term>Jackson (Tenn.) -- Social life and customs.</term>
          <term>Knoxville (Tenn.) -- History.</term>
          <term>Newton County (Ind.) -- Genealogy.</term>
          <term>Tennessee Volunteers (Football team).</term>
          <term>University of Tennessee, Knoxville.</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change when="2013" who="White, Park">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
      <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e38">
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_001303_000228_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e39"/>
        <p>J.L. Dodds</p>
        <p>Co L 23 Engrs</p>
        <p>American Ex F.</p>
        <p>Miss Ellen Smith</p>
        <p>111 Hatton Street</p>
        <p>Jackson Tennessee</p>
        <p>U.S.A.</p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_001303_000228_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e55"/>
        <p>July 22 1918</p>
        <p>Some where in France</p>
        <p>Dear Ellen:</p>
        <p>This is my day to write you again so here I am feeling fine and dandy. Hope this will find you well and happy. Well another week has past and not a single letter from any one. I bet at least a dozen letter over here some where and I sure would like to get them.</p>
        <p>I will get them after they are about two months old I guess and that is to old to suit me. I would be glad to get one now though if it was old. Guess you are getting some good news out of the papers  I know it sounds good to me.</p>
        <p>Now believe me the French and American are making up with the Germans. I would like to be up there where they are having the big battle so I could get in it my self</p>
        <p>We are where it is quiet not murch going on here now like there was when we first got up to the front  But it might break out here any old time.</p>
        <pb n="3" facs="0012_001303_000228_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e71"/>
        <p>The time a fellow least expects is when they start a drive  So I may get a chance to get all I wont any day. How is the weather back home now? You should be over here to spend the summer. The weather here now is about like we have April and May, back home, except the nights are cooler</p>
        <p>Well I am still driving the truck guess this job will last for some time looks that way. I will tell you news is awful hard to find over here except war news and I am not allowed to write that and I know you get it out of the paper by the time I do so would be real old when my letter would get there if I was to write it</p>
        <p>So will close for this time and maybe some thing will happen so will have something to write about. Write me real soon for I enjoy your letter so much.</p>
        <p>with lots of love</p>
        <p>James L Dodds</p>
        <p>Co L 23 Engrs</p>
        <p>American Ex Force</p>
        <p>via N Y,  France</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
