<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000599_000249_0000">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Letter, 
					<name>Henry Brown</name>
				                     to Caroline M. Brown<date when="1862-04-27">1862 Apr. 27</date>
            </title>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
          <name>Henderson, Ian</name>
        </respStmt>
        <author>
          <name type="person">Henry Brown</name>
        </author>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
        <date>2013</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
        </availability>
        <idno type="SPC">0012_000599_000249_0000</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Letter, Henry Brown to Caroline M. Brown1862 Apr. 27</title>
          <date when="1862-04-27">1862 Apr. 27</date>
          <author>
            <name type="person">Henry Brown</name>
          </author>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <note type="collection">Henry Brown Collection</note>
          <note type="manuscript">MS.2117</note>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
        <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
        <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
        <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as "turn page over" have been
						omitted.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy>
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="LCSH">
          <term>Ohio -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives.</term>
          <term>Ohio -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.</term>
          <term>Soldiers -- Ohio -- Correspondence.</term>
          <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives.</term>
          <term>United States. Army. Ohio Infantry Regiment, 31st (1861-1865)</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change when="2013" who="Henderson, Ian">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
      <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e38">
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_000599_000249_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e39"/>
        <p>Camp Schiloh</p>
        <p>31th Reg OVUSD Volunteers,</p>
        <p>Company A</p>
        <p>April 27 1862</p>
        <p>Caroline M. Brown</p>
        <p>Dea wife I sit Down this Sabath morning to respond to your of the fourteenth I was truly Glad to hear from you once And to hear that you and the Boys ware well i cant brad of my health at present i have Binn very unwell for some 3 or 4 days with a diarea i am Some better today altho not Able for duty the regement have gone out <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">tucket</unclear> we are within 11 miles of the rebels breast works At Corrinth in mississippi</p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_000599_000249_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e56"/>
        <p>Now i will tell something about the battle ground the fighting was done mostly in the woods Altho it is cald the battle field the line of battle was about Six miles long and they fought About 4 miles in breadth from the river back was over a good part of the ground my self i saw any amount of graves it was a very hard fight the bushes ware all cut down with musket balls and trees as big as my body cut off 30 feet high with cannon ball it may be our Lot <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">nex</unclear> but i hope not we may get in a fight and come off safe I saw a yong man that went School to Joel Nuzum last winter he said that he was Hasty as a buck he also new the groves i expect to get to see</p>
        <pb n="3" facs="0012_000599_000249_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e63"/>
        <p>The boys they are about two miles From whare we are at this time And Thomas B. Martin also And the 63 regt. is here close Some of the boys are a finding Some of theirs old play mates I will just Say that Doctor Holdon was to see uson the 22 And we ware paid that day 26 Dollars Each and i Sent $5 Dollars home by him when you hear that he is at home you can go up and get it And as i have Said before you must do the best you Can with it Save Some to pay The Tax for i will not get Any more in time for you to pay it with i want you to keep Some for your own use I know you will want some Clothes i dont want you to</p>
        <pb n="4" facs="0012_000599_000249_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e67"/>
        <p>go like some old begger if I am away from you I am getting very tired we have no way to write Only to sit flat on the ground if i live to get home i will Try to tell you more about The battle of Pittsburg landing So it is cald i will close Now by Saying to you pray For me for i have many Temtations to bare with here I do hope and pray that we will be permited on Earth one more before I die iam doing the best i can good by to you for this time</p>
        <p>Write Soon</p>
        <p>Henry Brown</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
