<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_001591_000201_0000">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Letter, <name>Andrew Jackson Donelson</name> to Andrew Jackson at the Hermitage, Tenn. <date when="1844-01-02">1844 January 2</date>
            </title>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
          <name>Dunham, Elizabeth</name>
        </respStmt>
        <author>
          <name type="person">Andrew Jackson Donelson</name>
        </author>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
        <date>2013</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
        </availability>
        <idno type="SPC">0012_001591_000201_0000</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Letter, Andrew Jackson Donelson to Andrew Jackson at the Hermitage, Tenn. 1844 January 2</title>
          <date when="1844-01-02">1844 January 2</date>
          <author>
            <name type="person">Andrew Jackson Donelson</name>
          </author>
          <extent>3</extent>
          <note type="collection">Andrew Jackson Papers, 1840 April, 1844 January 2-October 7</note>
          <note type="manuscript">3228</note>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
        <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
        <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
        <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as "turn page over" have been
						omitted.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy>
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="LCSH">
          <term>Donelson, Andrew Jackson, 1799-1871</term>
          <term>Davidson County (Tenn.) -- History.</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change when="2013" who="Dunham, Elizabeth">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
      <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e38">
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_001591_000201_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e39"/>
        <p>Dr Uncle,</p>
        <p>I told Andrew that I would see Wm on the subject of the road this evening, but it was an hour in the night before I could get through the delivery of my pork to Mr. Smith + others.  So that I must put it off till tomorrow.</p>
        <p>Mr Fletcher would have risked the trial of the road case, but Mr Ward thru Mr. Washington asked + obtained a continuance.  Mr Fletcher acquiesced under a hope that it could be compromised, and believing that almost any compromise would be preferable to the failure of the application for damages, a result which was almost certin had the trial been had yesterday.</p>
        <p>I discover that the copy referred to by Mr. Fletcher corresponds with the original agreement respecting the route for the road: and, although it may not be a valid paper in law for the want of the signiature of all the parties, still it strengthens the opposition made to a claim for damage by the party agreeing to it.  The road can be stopped, possibly, by Mrs Ward because she did not sign the agreement, but I trust the agreement suggested by Andrew + William Donelson will be adopted by all the parties and thus all controversy be amicably settled before the meeting of the next court.</p>
        <p>I will come over as soon as I get</p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_001591_000201_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e51"/>
        <p>my breakfast and make out as nearly as I can the statement you desire.  I do not see however of what avail my statement may be in the explanation of the agreement.  I acted on first the Jury of damage and voted to allow Mrs Ward damage to the amount of $200.  I was not with the other jury.</p>
        <p>Yrs affectionately</p>
        <p>A J Donelson.</p>
        <p>Jany 2d 1844</p>
        <p>Genl Andrew Jackson</p>
        <pb n="3" facs="0012_001591_000201_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e63"/>
        <p>Genl Andrew Jackson</p>
        <p>Hermitage</p>
        <p>Maj. A J Donelson to Gen. Jackson on the road</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
