<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000599_000204_0000">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Letter,
					<name>Henry Brown</name>
				                   in camp near Elk River, Tenn. to Caroline M. Brown, <date when="1862-08-13">1862 Aug. 13</date>
            </title>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
          <name>White, Park</name>
        </respStmt>
        <author>
          <name type="person">Henry Brown</name>
        </author>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
        <date>2013</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
        </availability>
        <idno type="SPC">0012_000599_000204_0000</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Letter, Henry Brown in camp near Elk River, Tenn. to Caroline M. Brown, 1862 Aug. 13</title>
          <date when="1862-08-13">1862 Aug. 13</date>
          <author>
            <name type="person">Henry Brown</name>
          </author>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <note type="collection">Henry Brown Collection</note>
          <note type="manuscript">MS.599</note>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
        <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
        <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
        <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as "turn page over" have been
						omitted.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy>
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="LCSH">
          <term>Ohio -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives.</term>
          <term>Ohio -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.</term>
          <term>Soldiers -- Ohio -- Correspondence.</term>
          <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives.</term>
          <term>United States. Army. Ohio Infantry Regiment, 31st (1861-1865)</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change when="2013" who="White, Park">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
      <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e38">
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_000599_000204_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e39"/>
        <p>August 13th  62</p>
        <p>Camp Near Elk</p>
        <p>River</p>
        <p>Tennessee</p>
        <p>CAROLINE  M.  BROWN</p>
        <p>Our Flag and Our Country!</p>
        <p>Dear Caroline</p>
        <p>I received one of your old Letters This morning and Was glad that it came to Hand altho I had one of A later date
				       from you I Read with intrust and Saw you had bin on A visit up to rush creek  And you Stated that you Had got your
				       likeness Taken and would Send It to me if i wanted it  I will just Say that I do hope to See your Face Before long for I</p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_000599_000204_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e57"/>
        <p>Have not bin able for Duty for a grate while  My feet is not Swelld So bad as they ware Some time ago but they Are still
				  too big yet  I thought i would write A few lines to you by Leutenant Primrose  He Starts for home in The morning on a
				  Furlough for his health I do not feel much like writing i will Say That we go for Every thing we want Corn Chickens
				  Turkeys geese Sheep hogs Cattle horses mules and Negroes and honey  We just sweep the Every thing before us you had
				  better</p>
        <pb n="3" facs="0012_000599_000204_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e61"/>
        <p>Think you Stated in you Last letter that you Had Sold all the Sheep But Seven lambs if I get home you will Have to by
				       one or two Good ones for me mutton Is all I crave in the meet line and once And a while Some Fride Chicken and A
				       little frest pork And a little Cabage And Some unions And Some potatoes  I have 10 cents for one Dozen of them and
				       not verry big at that  I hope you will Have plenty of all Them things for me when i come home</p>
        <pb n="4" facs="0012_000599_000204_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e65"/>
        <p>If i get to Come home Any ways soon i hope you will have Some good pickels for me to Eat and melons and Some nice
				  Chickens To fry and plenty of Eggs and ham for we Do not get much Of that here we get good bacon and Pork that is
				  sides And shoulders  And Crackers <unclear reason="illegible" resp="pw">asusea</unclear>Do not look for me until 
				  you see me  Give my Love To all the friends And take Some your Self  Goodby</p>
        <p>To Caroline by</p>
        <p>HENRY  BROWN.</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
