<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000599_000202_0000">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Letter,
					<name>Henry Brown</name>
				                    in camp near Tuscumbia, Ala. to Caroline M. Brown,<date when="1862-07-15">1862 July 15</date>
            </title>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
          <name>White, Park</name>
        </respStmt>
        <author>
          <name type="person">Henry Brown</name>
        </author>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
        <date>2013</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
        </availability>
        <idno type="SPC">0012_000599_000202_0000</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Letter, Henry Brown in camp near Tuscumbia, Ala. to Caroline M. Brown,1862 July 15</title>
          <date when="1862-07-15">1862 July 15</date>
          <author>
            <name type="person">Henry Brown</name>
          </author>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <note type="collection">Henry Brown Collection</note>
          <note type="manuscript">MS.599</note>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
        <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
        <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
        <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as "turn page over" have been
						omitted.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy>
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="LCSH">
          <term>Ohio -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives.</term>
          <term>Ohio -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.</term>
          <term>Soldiers -- Ohio -- Correspondence.</term>
          <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives.</term>
          <term>United States. Army. Ohio Infantry Regiment, 31st (1861-1865)</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change when="2013" who="White, Park">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
      <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e38">
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_000599_000202_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e39"/>
        <p>July  15th  1862</p>
        <p>Camp Near</p>
        <p>Tuscumbia</p>
        <p>CAROLINE  M.  BROWN</p>
        <p>Most Dear wife I Sit down this nice morning to let you know how i am  This Morning my Health is not So good as It 
				       was when i wrote to You last my feet is very much Sweld again the Hurt me this time very much they look as though
				       They would burst open  It may be they will Send me home as Soon as we Are paid of again we are Looking for the
				       pay master On Every day now  To pay us we will be</p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_000599_000202_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e51"/>
        <p>Paid against the first of next month any way i do hope These fewe lines will find You in good health at least Better than
				  my health is At this time it has bin Some time Since i got a Letter from you we have Had 2 or 3 mails since i Got any
				  from you the Other boys gets letters From Hartley ville and me None i do not write as Often as Some of the Boys for i
				  do not feel Like writeing when i Am not well but i want you to write as Often as you can you Have a good chance to
				  Write Every Sunday If you want to do so</p>
        <pb n="3" facs="0012_000599_000202_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e55"/>
        <p>I think i have Answerd All your letters and more  To our regt went out to Ruselsville last Saturday And have not returnd
				   yet  We heard that they would Be back to morrow morning  They went out on a scout we heard that thearewas A squad
				   of rebels out in The mountains but they Could not find them  So we heard this morning John Hemery has bin quite
				   Sick but he is better now  He has bin at the hospicalle Ever since we have bin At this place he is here To day cooking 
				   Some Black berries but very weak the rest of the Boys are mostly well</p>
        <pb n="4" facs="0012_000599_000202_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e59"/>
        <p>Henry Strait are with us again he is not very well he has The yellow jondice he is at his quarters he Is not confined to his
				  Bed but is not able For duty at present now I have never said much About being tired of The Servise but i have Thought
				  agreat deal about It and i will omit Telling my thoughts for Awhile yet but it is not As i Exspected by along ways  at any
				  rate you may know that by the way i write to you this time i love the verri old house you Stand in</p>
        <p>So good by</p>
        <p>HENRY  BROWN.</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
