<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:id="ms0012_001303_000210_0000">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Letter,
					<name>James L. Dodds</name>
				                   in Camp Meade, Md., to Ellen Smith in Jackson, Tenn.,<date when="1918-01-14">1918 Jan. 14</date>
            </title>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
          <name>White, Park</name>
        </respStmt>
        <author>
          <name type="person">James L. Dodds</name>
        </author>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
        <date>2013</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
        </availability>
        <idno type="SPC">0012_001303_000210_0000</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Letter, James L. Dodds in Camp Meade, Md., to Ellen Smith in Jackson, Tenn.,1918 Jan. 14</title>
          <date when="1918-01-14">1918 Jan. 14</date>
          <author>
            <name type="person">James L. Dodds</name>
          </author>
          <extent>5 pages</extent>
          <note type="collection">Smith Family Papers</note>
          <note type="manuscript">1303</note>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
        <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
        <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
        <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as "turn page over" have been
						omitted.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy>
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="LCSH">
          <term>Jackson (Tenn.) -- History.</term>
          <term>Jackson (Tenn.) -- Social life and customs.</term>
          <term>Knoxville (Tenn.) -- History.</term>
          <term>Newton County (Ind.) -- Genealogy.</term>
          <term>Tennessee Volunteers (Football team).</term>
          <term>University of Tennessee, Knoxville.</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change when="2013" who="White, Park">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
      <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e38">
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_001303_000210_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e39"/>
        <p>Miss Ellen Smith,</p>
        <p>111 Hatton Street,</p>
        <p>Jackson,</p>
        <p>Tenn,</p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_001303_000210_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e49"/>
        <p>Camp Meade Md.</p>
        <p>Jan 14 1918</p>
        <p>Dear Ellen:</p>
        <p>Well I will write you this afternoon and tell you how to address My Mail. I will leave Camp Meade tomorrow  I dont know where I am going for sure but I thank will go to Laurel Virginia</p>
        <p>I have been asigned to Company L. I have just found out that it is Laurel Maryland enstid of Virginia. I am pretty sure we will go there.</p>
        <p>I had a letter from Esther at noon tell her I will write her just as soon as I get to where I am going</p>
        <p>And if you see any of Aunt</p>
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_001303_000210_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e65"/>
        <p>Annie folks tell them for me I wont have time to write to all of them  And tell them to tell the rest of My Aunts and Uncles there  If you will do this I will appreciate it very murch</p>
        <p>I will get the mail that is adds to Recruiting Detachment but will take a long time</p>
        <p>They are moving all the 23 Engineers out of this Camp they are sending 4 Companys to France in a few days and looks now like we will all follow them just as fast as Can get ready</p>
        <p>I dont think the first of March will find Me in good Old U.S.A. but across the pond by then.</p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_001303_000210_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e75"/>
        <p>I am glad I am leaving here. I have been in quarantine since the first of Jan and dont see any chance to get out as long as I stay here  Maybe I will have a little pleasure where I go</p>
        <p>I havent been any where at all since I have been here not out of Camp only on hike</p>
        <p>I havent spoke to a lady in a month. I would like to just say hello to one and see how I would feel  You know that dont suit Me at all but I have to do a lot of things in the Army I dont like</p>
        <p>The weather is some warmer here to day and believe Me I am</p>
        <pb n="3" facs="0012_001303_000210_0005.jpg" xml:id="d4e85"/>
        <p>glad to see it for I have all Most froze. I guess if the weather turns cold down at Laurel I will freeze for we will be in tents there</p>
        <p>The boys are all glad we are leaving here they are running around saying O boy O joy where do we go from here  That is a saying in the army</p>
        <p>I will write you again when we stop and if you will tell Auntie I will be oblige</p>
        <p>as Ever James L Dodds</p>
        <p>address like this</p>
        <p>23 Engineers, Company, L.</p>
        <p>Camp Meade</p>
        <p>Maryland</p>
        <p>They will send My Mail to me where ever I go with that address</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
