<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:id="ms0012_001303_000221_0000">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Letter,
					<name>James L. Dodds</name>
				                    in France to Ellen Smith, in Jackson Tenn., <date when="1918-05-23">1918 May 23</date>
            </title>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
          <name>Giles, Sheldon</name>
        </respStmt>
        <author>
          <name type="person">James L. Dodds</name>
        </author>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
        <date>2013</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
        </availability>
        <idno type="SPC">0012_001303_000221_0000</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Letter, James L. Dodds in France to Ellen Smith, in Jackson Tenn., 1918 May 23</title>
          <date when="1918-05-23">1918 May 23</date>
          <author>
            <name type="person">James L. Dodds</name>
          </author>
          <extent>3 pages</extent>
          <note type="collection">Smith Family Papers</note>
          <note type="manuscript">1303</note>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
        <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
        <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
        <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as "turn page over" have been
						omitted.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy>
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="LCSH">
          <term>Jackson (Tenn.) -- History.</term>
          <term>Jackson (Tenn.) -- Social life and customs.</term>
          <term>Knoxville (Tenn.) -- History.</term>
          <term>Newton County (Ind.) -- Genealogy.</term>
          <term>Tennessee Volunteers (Football team).</term>
          <term>University of Tennessee, Knoxville.</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change when="2013" who="Giles, Sheldon">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
      <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e38">
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_001303_000221_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e39"/>
        <p>James L. Dodds</p>
        <p>Co L 23 Engers</p>
        <p>American Ex Fr</p>
        <p>Miss Ellen Smith </p>
        <p>111 Hatton Street</p>
        <p>Jackson </p>
        <p>Tennessee</p>
        <p>U. S. A.</p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_001303_000221_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e57"/>
        <p>May 23 1918</p>
        <p>Some where in france</p>
        <p>Dear Ellen -</p>
        <p>Well I will write you again this P. M. I am feeling fine and hope you are also I havent heard from any one at home yet But guess the time seems longer
to me than it really is Will soon be two months since i left the states Say how did every body in Jackson hear we had</p>
        <pb n="3" facs="0012_001303_000221_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e67"/>
        <p>left the states. Carl had a letter from Lena Schwab and she said they heard we had left the states long before
the cards got there we are still having lots of fun loading the German big shells They have been falling in sight all day and real close to where 
some of the boys are working But listen I want to tell you something that will make you laugh I know. 
I am a cook can you believe such a thing. Well I didnt either but I am a cook just the same Well ever body has to learn so here goes I am trying any way
I am in a little town so the Germans dont shoot the town up. But they come real close some times The aeroplances fly over us ever day they are getting
so common I dont notice them much They have battles in the air here and the other day when we were eating dinner</p>
        <pb n="4" facs="0012_001303_000221_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e71"/>
        <p>They brought a German plane down. Lots of fun. We are between the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SG">us and them</unclear>
            
            and when the Americans get to shelling the Germans we have some noise believe me</p>
        <p>There was one night didnt any body sleep any I dont think, we shelled the Germans all night we are going to mop up with 
these Germans in time for me to get home and eat Christmas dinner with you and I will be awful hungry to</p>
        <pb n="5" facs="0012_001303_000221_0005.jpg" xml:id="d4e80"/>
        <p>So you will have to cook lots of Turkey Well what is going on in the city. Now much of any thing. I would guess But I wouldnt know how to act if I was to be 
turned aloose again and told to do as I wanted to. </p>
        <p> But some day I will and I can have a good time to. A lot easier than I could before I joined the army Do you ever hear from Ester
since she got married</p>
        <pb n="6" facs="0012_001303_000221_0006.jpg" xml:id="d4e86"/>
        <p>and left the city. Who do you get to go to town with you now? I cant think of any body that was as close as she was
what has become of Lynn? Is he still at Millington or has he moved a long  ways from home. 
They always get a fellow as far away from home as possible. Well write me a long letter and tell me all the news
I cant think of any thing else I can tell now so will quit. answer real soon </p>
        <p> a true friend</p>
        <p> James L. Dodds</p>
        <p>Co l 23 Engr</p>
        <p>American Ex Force</p>
        <p>Via New York France</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
