<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:id="ms0012_001303_000208_0000">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Letter,
					<name>James L. Dodds</name>
		         in Camp Meade, Md., to Ellen Smith, in Jackson, Tenn.,<date when="1918-01-05">1918 Jan. 5</date>
            </title>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
          <name>White, Park</name>
        </respStmt>
        <author>
          <name type="person">James L. Dodds</name>
        </author>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
        <date>2013</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
        </availability>
        <idno type="SPC">0012_001303_000208_0000</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Letter, James L. Dodds in Camp Meade, Md., to Ellen Smith, in Jackson, Tenn.,1918 Jan. 5</title>
          <date when="1918-01-05">1918 Jan. 5</date>
          <author>
            <name type="person">James L. Dodds</name>
          </author>
          <extent>6 pages</extent>
          <note type="collection">Smith Family Papers</note>
          <note type="manuscript">1303</note>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
        <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
        <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
        <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as "turn page over" have been
						omitted.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy>
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="LCSH">
          <term>Jackson (Tenn.) -- History.</term>
          <term>Jackson (Tenn.) -- Social life and customs.</term>
          <term>Knoxville (Tenn.) -- History.</term>
          <term>Newton County (Ind.) -- Genealogy.</term>
          <term>Tennessee Volunteers (Football team).</term>
          <term>University of Tennessee, Knoxville.</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change when="2013" who="White, Park">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
      <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e38">
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_001303_000208_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e39"/>
        <p>Miss Ellen Smith</p>
        <p>111 Hatton Street</p>
        <p>Jackson</p>
        <p>Tenn,</p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_001303_000208_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e49"/>
        <p>Camp Meade Md.</p>
        <p>Jan5 1918</p>
        <p>Dear Ellen:</p>
        <p>I received two letters from to day. So I will answer them to night.</p>
        <p>I dont know why you havent heard from me more than you have I have written you ever week  But some time I have a hard time finding time to write</p>
        <p>I am working most day and night and dont have time to even wash my face some days</p>
        <p>We get up at 5-15 ever Morning and dont have time to get our close on hardly until we are out in line for Mess(or breakfast) and then back and go to work or drill</p>
        <p>Well I have been out for most</p>
        <pb n="3" facs="0012_001303_000208_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e67"/>
        <p>an hour getting some equipment It looks just like harness for a horse. We carry all of our blankets dishes and some clean cloths</p>
        <p>Oh I wouldnt put that load on a horse, but I have got to put it on my back and walk about 22 miles tomorrow we are going to move again</p>
        <p>Are going to Glenburnie Md. about 6 Miles from Baltimore. So we will have to get up early in the morning and walk all the way. Ah some job I have got</p>
        <p>If you dont care what you say  We are going down there to get rifle practis</p>
        <p>I dont know wheather we will get to come back here</p>
        <pb n="4" facs="0012_001303_000208_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e79"/>
        <p>or not. Will I dont care  I take ever thing easy.</p>
        <p>I was talking to the Captin of our Company about getting a pass to come home and he told me there was nothing doing  That he thought we would be in France by the 15 of March</p>
        <p>I ask him for a pass from the first of March I ask him if I could go now and he said no So I wont get to come home until I go over and get the Kiser</p>
        <p>I sure would like to come home and see ever body and especialy you but guess I cant.</p>
        <p>I was over in Baltimore Sat night and Sunday I had</p>
        <pb n="5" facs="0012_001303_000208_0005.jpg" xml:id="d4e91"/>
        <p>some pictures made I will send you one as soon as I get them I had some post cards made but I will wait and send you a good one I sent Esther one of the post cards guess she will show it to you</p>
        <p>I am tickled to death to know you are sending Me some cake and candy I will eat it and thank of you all the time  I am afraid I will loose it though as I am going to leave here tomorrow</p>
        <p>I sure do hate to make that trip but will have to  I have the tent all fixed up and have got to go off and leave it</p>
        <pb n="6" facs="0012_001303_000208_0006.jpg" xml:id="d4e99"/>
        <p>I wont have time to write Aunt Annie to night you tell her I am getting along fine and will write her just as soon as I get a chance  I have written her two letters in the last ten days  I dont see why she hasnt heard from Me</p>
        <p>Well I have just got 15 minutes to get in bed guess I will have to close  Add My mail as you have been all the time  I guess I will get it  I will write you ever time I can find time</p>
        <p>With lots of love</p>
        <p>James L Dodds</p>
        <p>Co. L. 23 Engineers</p>
        <p>Camp Meade Md.</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
