<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000202_000200_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter, <name>Edward Summers</name> in Winchester, Tenn., to Mr. Arthur
                    Johnson <date when="1863-11-02">1863 November 2</date>
            </title>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>Rozema, Laurel</name>
               <name>Dyson-Smith, Bridger</name>
            </respStmt>
            <author>
               <name type="person">
                  <name type="person">Edward Summers</name>
               </name>
            </author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <availability status="restricted">
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_000202_000200_0000</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Letter, Edward Summers in Winchester, Tenn., to Mr. Arthur Johnson 1863 November 2</title>
               <date when="1863-11-02">1863 November 2</date>
               <author>
                  <name type="person">Edward Summers</name>
               </author>
               <title>[Letter] <date when="1863-11-02">November 2nd, 1863</date> Winchester,
                        Tennessee [to] Mr. Arthur Johnson</title>
               <date>2006-05-22</date>
               <author>
                  <name/>
               </author>
               <author>
                  <name type="person">Summers, Edward</name>
               </author>
               <date when="1863-11-02">November 2nd, 1863</date>
               <extent>4 pages</extent>
               <note type="abstract">This letter from Union Sgt. Edward Summers, Co. K. Kentucky
                        Calvary Regiment, is to his cousin Arthur Johnson on November 2, 1863.
                        Summers gives a detailed account of his unit&apos;s movements following his
                        enlistment on October 21, 1861 at Louisville, KY, including involvement in
                        the Battle of Chickamauga.</note>
               <note type="collection">Edward Summers Letter, 1863</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS.2714</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
						omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH"/>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013" who="Rozema, Laurel">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
         <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e99">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_000202_000200_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e100"/>
            <p>Winchester, Tennessee</p>
            <p>November 2nd, 1863</p>
            <p>Mr. Arthur Johnson,,</p>
            <p>Dear Cousen after my Very best Love to you, Mrs. Elizabeth Johnson and your
                    Little Offspring, I again take my pen in hand for the fourth time Without an
                    Answer to Let you know that I am Still On the Land amongst the Living. I Can
                    again Say I, am Well and hope those fiew Lines may find you all Enjoying Same
                    Blessing.. Peter, Mann,, Frank, Trueax,, F. W. Asbury,, Alexander, Curtis,, and
                    all of Our Bracken Boys, are well and harty.. I have But Little News of Intrust
                    at this time Every thing appears quiet Except Occasional Skermishes in the front
                    and a fiew Gurriller Bands through Tennessee We have Bin Expecting. a heavy
                    Battle for some two Weeks but it seams as if Bragg is incline to fall Back it
                    may be his Object is to Draw Our troops away from Chatanooga. I,am Not With my
                    Regiment at this time and I have a bad Chance of Gathering Information. I.am One
                    of the Guards With the 1st Cav. Divisions, Ordnance train and it is hear at
                    Winchester Tenn. Whaar it may in all probability Remain for Several Weeks My.
                    Regiment and in fact My Whole Brigade is Encamped at Jeffers Ferry on the
                    Tennessee River 2 Miles South of Stevenson Alabamia. I expect to Remain with
                    this train all Winter it is an Easy position. and my fair are good My quarters
                    are in a Neat Little Train House Near the Publick Squair I.Can See all that is
                    going on in town in the Day time and have as many Yellow Girles in my Room at
                    Night as I Wish but Enough of this</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_000202_000200_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e110"/>
            <p>I.Will Now give you a Short Sketch of my travels Since I was at your house. When
                    I.left home I went by the Way of Cynthaana and Georgetown to Lexington Ky I Was
                    then Ordered to Report at Point Pleasant in Virginia. I.left Lexington on the
                    22nd of Last Oct. one year ago and passed through. Paris Millersburg the Blue
                    Licks Washington, and On to Maysville Ky. I.their Crossed the Ohio River to
                    Aberdeen and passed through Decature, Westunion Salem Jackson, Sciotiville
                    Lucasville Galliopolis, and up the River to the mouth of the Big Kanawey River I
                    their Crossed the Ohio River into Point Pleasant Virginia Whar I Joined my
                    Command. We Drove the Enemy through Charlestown and Whiped them at Gawley Bridge
                    and Drove them through Ashbys Gap in the Blue Ridge Mountains. We then Receivd
                    Orders to Report at a point Near Vicksburg Misissippi. We Marched Back to Point
                    Pleasant and their took Steam Boats to Cincinnati Ohio the Infantry went to
                    Misissippi and Our Cavalry Was Ordered to Report at Lexington Ky We Bid a Due to
                    the Queen City of the West and passed through Covington Williamstown Georgetown
                    and On to Lexington Whar We Only Remained two Days to Rest from a Long and
                    toilsome march of over 700 miles. We left Lexington Ky the Garden spot of the
                    World with heavy hearts and marched,through Nicholassville Perryville Lebanon
                    Danville Bloomfield, Springfield and On to Louisville Ky. We Only Remained their
                    a Day or two to Rest Our Jaded horses We their took the Cars and passed through
                    many town and Vilages and though the Green River Country to Nashville Tennessee
                    the Capitol of</p>
            <pb n="3" facs="0012_000202_000200_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e114"/>
            <p>the State. We traversed the State all Over and,Over and Camped for a fiew Days
                    at. Brentwood Franklen Springhill Shelbyville Tullahoma Triune Murfreesboro
                    Winchester Fayattsville and many other towns after We had Skerged Tennessee Well
                    We Then marched all of Our Cavalry forces into Alabamia Our first trip was to
                    take Huntsville Ala. One of the finest towns I have Seen in Ala. We then took
                    Stevenson and Bridgeport and many Other Little town the Enemy Still held
                    Chatanooga. it is Situated on the Tennessee River about 2 1/2 miles from the
                    Georgia State Line. Our Next moove was to take Chatanooga Which We Done Easily
                    We then made a.Dashing Rade through Georgia tearing up the Rail Rode track
                    Burning Bridges and Depoes and Cutting up hell in General. and O, God, O, God,
                    the Scenes I have Witnessed. I have witnessed Some Dark and horrible Scenes Such
                    as has made my Blood Run Cold. I, have, Seen men hung Like Dogs in Cool Blood.
                    I, have Seen men Shot Down Like Broots in Cool Blood. I have Seen the flaming
                    torch applide to fine Mills Large factories and Stately Mansions I.have Seen
                    towns Raped in flames Besides innumerable Scenes of Disgust. I.have Seen the
                    Rich made poor in a fiew Short hours. I have Seen Enough of the Horrors of War
                    to Satisfy me and to Satisfy my mind that a Civil War Will Ruin any Nation under
                    the Canopy of Heavan, it will Ruin all Classes of man kind the Whole World is
                    Demoralized at this time and I.have underwent all the hardships Perils and
                    privations that Belongs to a Soldiers Life I.have went through frost and Snow,
                    through Rain and mud as well as the Scorching heat and bore it all. </p>
            <pb n="4" facs="0012_000202_000200_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e118"/>
            <p>as become a soldier I.have Bin in Nine Battles Besides a Number of Skermishes and
                    by the help of God am yet Spard to tell the memorable tale of this Campaign
                    I.have also Witnessed thousands and thousands of Most Butiful Sceneries Both
                    Natural and Strange that was well Calculated to Interest the Weary Soldier as he
                    passes by But the most Horrible Sight is the Battle field Yet, if you Could of
                    Bin presant and of Looked Over the Battle field after the Battle of Chickamauga
                    in Georgia and of Seen the Thousands apon top of thousands of Ded, Dying, and
                    mangled masses of human Souls weltering in their Blood it would of Chilled Every
                    Drop of Blood in your Veins wi the Whole face of the Earth appeard to be Covered
                    with the Ded and Gorged with Blood Many of my Brave Companions fell in that
                    memorable Battle By the Enemies fatal Ball and their Bones are left to Bleach
                    apon the Georgia Plains I am Sorry to Inform you that Our Ded was Not Buried the
                    Enemy took the field and held it Our Loss is Estimated at fifteen thousand and
                    the Enemies at twenty Eight thousand, a Large Number of Souls to fall in One
                    Battle and yet the War is Not at a Close Well Arthur I Shall have to Close for
                    this time Give my Love to all of the friends and Relation and Answer Immediately
                    Direct your Letter to Winchester Tennessee in the Care of Capt Wilson a.q.m. 1st
                    Cav. Division and believe me to be Your Ever affectionate Cousen till Deth</p>
            <p>Ewd. Summers</p>
            <p>pleas Send me a fiew Postage Stamps I can&apos;t get them hear</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
