<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000599_000226_0000">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Letter,
					<name>Henry Brown</name>
				                    in Camp Rock, Nelson County, Ky., to Caroline M. Brown,<date when="1862-02-23">1862 Feb. 23</date>
            </title>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
          <name>Wibking, Lyndy</name>
        </respStmt>
        <author>
          <name type="person">Henry Brown</name>
        </author>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
        <date>2013</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
        </availability>
        <idno type="SPC">0012_000599_000226_0000</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Letter, Henry Brown in Camp Rock, Nelson County, Ky., to Caroline M. Brown,1862 Feb. 23</title>
          <date when="1862-02-23">1862 Feb. 23</date>
          <author>
            <name type="person">Henry Brown</name>
          </author>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <note type="collection">Henry Brown Collection </note>
          <note type="manuscript">MS.2117</note>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
        <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
        <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
        <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as "turn page over" have been
						omitted.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy>
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="LCSH">
          <term>Ohio -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives.</term>
          <term>Ohio -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.</term>
          <term>Soldiers -- Ohio -- Correspondence.</term>
          <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives.</term>
          <term>United States. Army. Ohio Infantry Regiment, 31st (1861-1865)</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change when="2013" who="Wibking, Lyndy">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
      <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e38">
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_000599_000226_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e39"/>
        <p>Camp Rock</p>
        <p>Nelson County Ky</p>
        <p>February 23th 1862</p>
        <p>Dear belove wife And children I sit down this Sabath evening to inform you that we have orders to strike tents to morrow morning by seven oclock And be ready to march at half past They say we are going to louisville And go down the river some whare towards Tennisee but we do not know any thing about whare we will go  now i will just say if i should never see you any more i want you All to pray for me and i will for you i was to hear the chaplain preach and he gave us good advice he prayd for us all and gave us good</p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_000599_000226_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e49"/>
        <p>Incouragement he can beat them all alike to preach rite I was just thinking whare i left sitting if we we was there to night and this thing was settled and i was at home whare i could be with you Around the fire side withe you three i could be contented to stay with you as long as I would some of the of the officers seams to think that we will get home in a month or six weeks But it is hard to tell what we will be the fate of us we cant tell when we will draw the money for the work we have already done the Prospect is very poor for some time yet i it is verry Harde to do with out some</p>
        <pb n="3" facs="0012_000599_000226_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e53"/>
        <p>If you can get me two Dollars and send it to me in your  next letter i would be verry glad if you get it you may get me one Dollars worth of stamp and send me about 20 of them and keep the rest of them your self or get 20 and send and keep the money for yourself I sent my dress coat in a box with Henry Strait to his Father you can see my name on the lining of the coat if They ever get it Now i shall close by saying right soon Nnow remember me As your dear husband and companion good by my dear beloved wife To Caroline Brown down to Dixy we go</p>
        <p>Henry Brown</p>
        <pb n="4" facs="0012_000599_000226_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e59"/>
        <p>To the Dear little Boys</p>
        <p>Now now boys you are verry dear to me And i want to hear from you Every time i get a letter from home you I want you to be good to your mother and your Neighbours also you will never regret it you may gess i will have to close soon Isaiah you can writ pretty well you can write when you please so good by</p>
        <p>To Isaiah and George Brown God bless the boys</p>
        <p>Good by to you All</p>
        <p>Henry Brown</p>
        <p>your Father</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
