<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000599_000213_0000">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Letter,
					<name>Henry Brown</name>
				                    in Camp Dick Robinson, Ky to Caroline M. Brown, <date when="1861-10-15">1861 Oct. 15</date>
            </title>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
          <name>Hutson, Aaron</name>
        </respStmt>
        <author>
          <name type="person">Henry Brown</name>
        </author>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
        <date>2013</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
        </availability>
        <idno type="SPC">0012_000599_000213_0000</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Letter, Henry Brown in Camp Dick Robinson, Ky to Caroline M. Brown, 1861 Oct. 15</title>
          <date when="1861-10-15">1861 Oct. 15</date>
          <author>
            <name type="person">Henry Brown</name>
          </author>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <note type="collection">Henry Brown Collection 1861-1862</note>
          <note type="manuscript">MS.2117</note>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
        <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
        <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
        <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as "turn page over" have been
						omitted.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy>
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="LCSH">
          <term>Ohio -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives.</term>
          <term>Ohio -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.</term>
          <term>Soldiers -- Ohio -- Correspondence.</term>
          <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives.</term>
          <term>United States. Army. Ohio Infantry Regiment, 31st (1861-1865)</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change when="2013" who="Hutson, Aaron">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
      <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e38">
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_000599_000213_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e39"/>
        <p>October 15 1861</p>
        <p>Camp Dick Robinson</p>
        <p>Dear wife i take this time to inform you that i am well At this time and I do hope these few lines may find you all the same  Esq Alderman Is here to day and I thought that I would writ you A few lines to let you How I was and how the Times are down here All For union we have a great Visitor Every day and we have A small girl in the tennessee Troops That acts as leuteant She is drest in mens cloths she is from tennessee and she is a very nice looking</p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_000599_000213_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e47"/>
        <p>Girl too The Tennefsee Troops Are very Eager to git Back There to do the fighting they Say all they wants us to too Do is to go with them and They will do the fighting our Chaplain is Drake From <unclear reason="indecipherable" resp="AH">Rekobooth</unclear> preach s us A good sermon last Sunday we had sunday school in The afternoon and prayer meeting at night we have good time here and <unclear reason="indecipherable" resp="AH">mery</unclear> The kurnel says he thinks That will stay here this Winter But it is very Hard to tell where will go from here when we move when I think of my little Boys and you And phene haveing all the Chorse to do it make me Shed many years for</p>
        <pb n="3" facs="0012_000599_000213_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e57"/>
        <p>you all I hope you will Do the Best you Can with out me while i am Away from you i hope I will see you again before I die i want you to do the Best you Can if the Boys Cant Chop the wood you must get Sam body To help them that ax is to heavy for them it is more dark and we have no candle No more at present But Remain yours</p>
        <p>Remember me when This you see tho many miles we separate</p>
        <p>Henry Brown</p>
        <pb n="4" facs="0012_000599_000213_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e65"/>
        <p/>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
