<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:id="ms0012_001303_000213_0000">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Letter,
					<name>James L. Dodds</name>
				                   in Camp Laurel, Md., to Ellen Smith in Jackson, Tenn.,<date when="1918-03-09">1918  Mar. 9</date>
            </title>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
          <name>White, Park</name>
        </respStmt>
        <author>
          <name type="person">James L. Dodds</name>
        </author>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
        <date>2013</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
        </availability>
        <idno type="SPC">0012_001303_000213_0000</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Letter, James L. Dodds in Camp Laurel, Md., to Ellen Smith in Jackson, Tenn.,1918 Mar. 9</title>
          <date when="1918-03-09">1918  Mar. 9</date>
          <author>
            <name type="person">James L. Dodds</name>
          </author>
          <extent>10 pages</extent>
          <note type="collection">Smith Family Papers</note>
          <note type="manuscript">1303</note>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
        <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
        <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
        <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as "turn page over" have been
						omitted.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy>
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="LCSH">
          <term>Jackson (Tenn.) -- History.</term>
          <term>Jackson (Tenn.) -- Social life and customs.</term>
          <term>Knoxville (Tenn.) -- History.</term>
          <term>Newton County (Ind.) -- Genealogy.</term>
          <term>Tennessee Volunteers (Football team).</term>
          <term>University of Tennessee, Knoxville.</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change when="2013" who="White, Park">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
      <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e38">
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_001303_000213_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e39"/>
        <p>Miss Ellen Smith,</p>
        <p>11 Hatton Street,</p>
        <p>Jackson,</p>
        <p>Tenn,</p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_001303_000213_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e49"/>
        <p>From J.L.D</p>
        <p>Co L 23</p>
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_001303_000213_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e55"/>
        <p>Say if you know Esthers add give it to me for I never did write to her. I guess her husban wont shoot me</p>
        <p>Camp Laurel Md.</p>
        <p>March 9-1918</p>
        <p>Dear Ellen:</p>
        <p>Guess you thank I have forgotten you but I havent. I have been real busy for some time and havent had time to write</p>
        <p>I have been on guard and when that job comes around it keeps a fellow busy for a while  And yesterday I was out in the woods all day cutting wood for the Camp</p>
        <p>But it has been raining here to day so didnt have to do any thing  I am like a kid on the farm glad to see it rain so will get to rest and tomorrow is sunday</p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_001303_000213_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e71"/>
        <p>so thank I will catch up with my writing</p>
        <p>I got my weeks washing done this morning so tomorrow I hope I wont have any thing to do.</p>
        <p>But I bet will be my luck to have to work all day at some thing and if I do well I wont say it here just thank it</p>
        <p>I have quit shooting I guess I was such a sorry Marksman they thought the time was wasted so they put me to work.</p>
        <p>Well I should worry I dont want a rifle any way. I will give these men that can shoot my rifle and I will do the work for believe me they soon get heavy when we go no hikes</p>
        <p>We had a hike the other day had all that pack I was telling you about once before  Only it was heavy this time then it was before and we</p>
        <pb n="3" facs="0012_001303_000213_0005.jpg" xml:id="d4e85"/>
        <p>had rifles this time so all together the pack weighs 70 pounds</p>
        <p>Every one of us thought we were leaving for parts unknowne  They told us we were but they were only fooling we came back here and believe me the men were some sore about it   They want to leave here</p>
        <p>But I dont know when it will come I hope some time soon  I want to leave this place I have been here long enough  I dont care where we go I like to go to a new place </p>
        <p>I soon get tired of a place and more especially this place we are about 10 miles from no where out in the woods and I never see any one but soldiers</p>
        <p>I guess if I were to see a lady</p>
        <pb n="4" facs="0012_001303_000213_0006.jpg" xml:id="d4e97"/>
        <p>wood be afraid of her</p>
        <p>Well tomorrow is when Esther get married wish I could see the show  I guess they will leve Monday Morning for ther new home in Bhm. I hate to thank of it for when I come back home wont seem right for me not to see her running around in the front yard.</p>
        <p>Sure is a fine old girl if she get as good a husban as he does a wife they will be alright through this old world  Of course I dont mean to say he is not a good fellow I dont know anything about him  But I hope he will be good to her</p>
        <p>I know you will be lost with out her  Who will yu have for a girl friend  I cant think of any lady that ever</p>
        <pb n="5" facs="0012_001303_000213_0007.jpg" xml:id="d4e107"/>
        <p>close like she does</p>
        <p>I guess I will have to come home and keep you from getting lonesome  Oh there is Bob he can keep you from being lonesome</p>
        <p>Has Bob got his barbershop that he had before the went away  What has happened around Jackson that you thank would be news to me?</p>
        <p>Do they have any thing except picture shows to go and pass away the time? I sure would like to see a show I havent been to a show since I left home</p>
        <p>When I was in Baltimore that sunday ever thing was close up as tight as a jug</p>
        <p>And I have only been out </p>
        <pb n="6" facs="0012_001303_000213_0008.jpg" xml:id="d4e121"/>
        <p>of Camp twice since I enlisted once in Baltimore and the other time I was at a dance at Annapolis Md.</p>
        <p>I sure would like to get out of jail and see how I would feel. But I dont see any chance  Some time I have to stop and thank who we are at war with.</p>
        <p>I will be good when the time comes for us to go to France  I am going to try to transfer out of this regt. as soon as we get across</p>
        <p>I dont know what kind of luck I will have but I am going to do my best  I cant get in to any thing that will be any worse than this regt.</p>
        <p>I some times wish I had waited and let them draft Me  The drafted men get better treatment than we do. So they tell me</p>
        <p>I know they do get out of Camp some time and I dont</p>
        <pb n="7" facs="0012_001303_000213_0009.jpg" xml:id="d4e135"/>
        <p>I guess I had better hesh or I will wake up in the guard house  They censor all of the mail that leaves here  But when I get wound up I cant help it  Its in me and has got to come out</p>
        <p>I am in the tent all by self to night  All the other boys are on guard so I feel real lonesome with out them  But when they are here they talk so murch I can't write with any sense</p>
        <p>We have got a new bunch in the tent Orr Cortmell and My self are the only one of the old bunch left  Orr dont have any one to argue with now</p>
        <p>But after supper when the</p>
        <pb n="8" facs="0012_001303_000213_0010.jpg" xml:id="d4e145"/>
        <p>other bunch was together Orr would start an argument with a fellow by the name of Ralf and such a time they would have</p>
        <p>Say you tell Bernard if he dont send Orr his watch pretty soon he will curse enough to send him to ____ a dozen times</p>
        <p>He sent Dick Lane the money about a month ago to see Bernard and get his watch and send to him but it hasent come yet and we are expecting to leave here any day</p>
        <p>Well I thank I have told you ever thing I know  So will quit for this time  write me real soon and tell me all the news and all about Esthers Wedding</p>
        <p>with lots of love</p>
        <p>I am the same old boy</p>
        <p>J.L.Dodds</p>
        <p>Co L 23 Engr</p>
        <p>Laurel</p>
        <p>Md.</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
