<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000599_000203_0000">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Letter,
					<name>Henry Brown</name>
				                    in camp near Tuscumbia, Ala. to Caroline M. Brown,<date when="1862-08-01">1862 Aug. 01</date>
            </title>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
          <name>White, Park</name>
        </respStmt>
        <author>
          <name type="person">Henry Brown</name>
        </author>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
        <date>2013</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
        </availability>
        <idno type="SPC">0012_000599_000203_0000</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Letter, Henry Brown in camp near Tuscumbia, Ala. to Caroline M. Brown,1862 Aug. 01</title>
          <date when="1862-08-01">1862 Aug. 01</date>
          <author>
            <name type="person">Henry Brown</name>
          </author>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <note type="collection">Henry Brown Collection </note>
          <note type="manuscript">MS.599</note>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
        <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
        <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
        <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as "turn page over" have been
						omitted.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy>
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="LCSH">
          <term>Ohio -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives.</term>
          <term>Ohio -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.</term>
          <term>Soldiers -- Ohio -- Correspondence.</term>
          <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives.</term>
          <term>United States. Army. Ohio Infantry Regiment, 31st (1861-1865)</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change when="2013" who="White, Park">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
      <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e38">
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_000599_000203_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e39"/>
        <p>Camp Near Tuscumbia</p>
        <p>Alabama</p>
        <p>August</p>
        <p>First  62</p>
        <p>CAROLINE  M.  BROWN</p>
        <p>Dear wife, I.  Sit down To inform you whare I am at this time i am In the old camp our regt Left last mondy 
				       aweek Ago for tennessee but There is 35 of the 31st Here that was Sick and Lame together we Exspect To
				       leave to morrow we Get no letter here any More they go on to the Regt we have bin here Better than a
				       month And i have only got one</p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_000599_000203_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e53"/>
        <p>Letter since we have bin here And i think the time very Long i have wrote but One for i felt so bad I could not
				  think of Writeing but now i am Better i thought i would write a few lines to let you know how i am  I feel better
				  the Sweling Has left my feet and legs Pretty near but they are very week and sore yet  Robert Conn is Sitting By
				  my Side Eating his Breakfast he is all rite  I hope these few lines will Find you and the rest of The family all well
				  and Doing the best you can For your Selves it is not worth while Say any</p>
        <pb n="3" facs="0012_000599_000203_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e57"/>
        <p>Thing about the war for i Know nothing to say only It Still goes on down here we Know that much about it
				       As for comeing home it   It is a very dul chance  I think at the present Time we have our own fun with the
				       Nigroes when They come in camp to sell Fish and Eggs and chickens And pies corn bread and Such likes 
				       i went this Morning to get Some butter And they ask me 40 cts Per pound and i told them I would See 
				       their house Burn first  So i went back To camp with out it i have Paid at the rate of 75 cts per Dozen and
				       other things in Propotion our Sutters Sells</p>
        <pb n="4" facs="0012_000599_000203_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e61"/>
        <p>Salt at 15 Dollars a barrel  Flour at twenty Dollars We have to pay for Every Thing we buy down here  I 
				       tell you i can not Eat The crackers since i have been Sick we can buy bread At a dear rate  what you would
				       give a man for a Pice for 10 cents it is What we would call a Light cake at home and Small at that but verry
				       Good bread so you may Guess what we have To pay for our grub  Here now i shall have to Close by saying
				       that i would like to come home To See you all once more</p>
        <p>So good to you all for this Time</p>
        <p>write Soon</p>
        <p>HENRY  BROWN.</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
