<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:id="ms0012_001303_000220_0000">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Letter,
					<name>James L. Dodds</name>
				                    in France to Ellen Smith, in Jackson, Tenn., <date when="1918-07-01">1918 July 1</date>
            </title>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
          <name>Giles, Sheldon</name>
        </respStmt>
        <author>
          <name type="person">James L. Dodds</name>
        </author>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
        <date>2013</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
        </availability>
        <idno type="SPC">0012_001303_000220_0000</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Letter, James L. Dodds in France to Ellen Smith, in Jackson, Tenn., 1918 July 1</title>
          <date when="1918-07-01">1918 July 1</date>
          <author>
            <name type="person">James L. Dodds</name>
          </author>
          <extent>3 pages</extent>
          <note type="Collection">Smith Family Papers</note>
          <note type="manuscript">1303</note>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
        <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
        <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
        <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as "turn page over" have been
						omitted.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy>
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="LCSH">
          <term>Jackson (Tenn.) -- History.</term>
          <term>Jackson (Tenn.) -- Social life and customs.</term>
          <term>Knoxville (Tenn.) -- History.</term>
          <term>Newton County (Ind.) -- Genealogy.</term>
          <term>Tennessee Volunteers (Football team).</term>
          <term>University of Tennessee, Knoxville.</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change when="2013" who="Giles, Sheldon">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
      <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e38">
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_001303_000220_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e39"/>
        <p>Dodds</p>
        <p>23 Enger</p>
        <p>Ex Fr</p>
        <p>Miss Ellen Smith</p>
        <p>111 Hatton Street</p>
        <p>Jackson Tennessee</p>
        <p>U. S. A.</p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_001303_000220_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e55"/>
        <p>July 1 1918</p>
        <p>Some where in France</p>
        <p>Dear Ellen:</p>
        <p>At last I got a letter from you and I cant tell you how glad I was I feel a lots better and I read it. I know is is not your fault
as I have said before I know the reason for not getting any mail in so long a time. But cant tell you I think  everything will be alright
for a while any way. I dont see why you dont get my letters for I write you every week that comes. I dont do that well to any body else except mother
I always find time to writ you both once a week when I have had my supper and am feeling fine</p>
        <p>except I am real tired for I have been driving a big truck all day Mad 74 miles to day hauling big racks to build a road some of
the roads are</p>
        <pb n="3" facs="0012_001303_000220_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e67"/>
        <p>rough so you know what it is to drive a light car over rough roads and this thing I am driving is awful heavy
But if that helps to win the war I dont mind it a bit. Yesterday was Sunday so I went to town to look the place over. I drove the truck in with a 
bunch  of the men. We can go to town every sunday if we want to but I hardly ever go but yesterday was My day to drive so I had to go.
We take a time about as we have several trucks We are in a little town but the place here is a pretty good size place.
I saw some real nice looking girls there about the best looking I have seen in France.</p>
        <p>Good looking girls are scarce in France or at least I think so Well I hope you had a good time in Memphis I know I could if I was there
I could have a good time</p>
        <pb n="4" facs="0012_001303_000220_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e73"/>
        <p>in Oakfield if I was on there. I thin it is rreal nice for Lynn to be so close to home that preache can go and see him.
Does he think he will come across on the side or stay there? Well would be real nice to come across but I have been here as long as I want to stay.
The time passes pretty fast though  we will soon be over there Months dont seem that long. 
But we have something to think about over here (our work)  and we didnt in the states. I sure hope Uncle Robert dont get in trouble over 
running in the <gap reason="indecipherable" resp="Giles"/> engine</p>
        <p>I have got to write mother as I didnt get to write her yes-terday. And we are going to have a picture show as the 
Y M C A to night  Will close write me real soon and dont for get me</p>
        <p>With lots of love</p>
        <p>I also got a letter from aunt Annie today will set some</p>
        <p>James L  Dodds</p>
        <p>Co L 23 Enger</p>
        <p>American Ex fr</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
