<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000599_000205_0000">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Letter,
					<name>Henry Brown</name>
				                  in Convalesent camp near Nashville, Tenn. to Caroline M. Brown,<date when="1862-09-14">1862 Sept. 14</date>
            </title>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
          <name>White, Park</name>
        </respStmt>
        <author>
          <name type="person">Henry Brown</name>
        </author>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
        <date>2013</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
        </availability>
        <idno type="SPC">0012_000599_000205_0000</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Letter, Henry Brown in Convalesent camp near Nashville, Tenn. to Caroline M. Brown,1862 Sept. 14</title>
          <date when="1862-09-14">1862 Sept. 14</date>
          <author>
            <name type="person">Henry Brown</name>
          </author>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <note type="collection">Henry Brown Collection</note>
          <note type="manuscript">MS.599</note>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
        <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
        <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
        <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as "turn page over" have been
						omitted.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy>
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="LCSH">
          <term>Ohio -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives.</term>
          <term>Ohio -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.</term>
          <term>Soldiers -- Ohio -- Correspondence.</term>
          <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives.</term>
          <term>United States. Army. Ohio Infantry Regiment, 31st (1861-1865)</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change when="2013" who="White, Park">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
      <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e38">
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_000599_000205_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e39"/>
        <p>Convalesent Camp Near</p>
        <p>Nashville Tenn</p>
        <p>September</p>
        <p>CAROLINE  M.  BROWN</p>
        <p>14th  1862</p>
        <p>Dear Companion I Sit down This Sabath After noon To inform You how I am at this Time I am not verry well 
				       I tell you <unclear reason="illegible" resp="pw">how</unclear>I feel verry poorly With what i Sufer with
				       My feet and legs and The athsma has set in with the rest or Something Like it i have to coff A grate deal at
				       night And Some throught The day and i am Getting verry poor</p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_000599_000205_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e56"/>
        <p>And for getting home i See But a Slim chance For my part the old Papers are all lost and I cant tell when they will
				  get up any new Ones for us thar is one Thing i know and is This if i was at home I would be better cared For than
				  whare i am  My feet and legs are Not weld as much as They ware Some time Ago But pain me By Spells rite Smarte</p>
        <p>The Skin just above The ancle Was allmost Growed to the bone  it Feels like grisle Now If this to hand I do not
				  want you to greave</p>
        <pb n="3" facs="0012_000599_000205_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e62"/>
        <p>About my Situation For we are too far apart To help Each other at this Time altho i would Like to be with you And
				  the rest of the Family to in Joy peace And comfort once more To gether i think if i Was there now i would Not be
				  Excited gain  For i see i cant stand Any longer in the Servise  I am wore out with Hardships and Exsposier  I do hope 
				  these few Lines will find you all In good health I will Just we have not bin Paid any Since i sent you them 12 Dollars
				  there Is about Sixty dollars</p>
        <pb n="4" facs="0012_000599_000205_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e66"/>
        <p>Due me now if i had Some of that now i Could get thing that i Could Eat  you wanted To know whare you Should
				  Sow Some wheat If i did not get home In time you had better Try and get the corn Cut up as soon as it will do
				  atall and Sow that field that A <unclear reason="illegible" resp="pw">Svers</unclear>had  in and the Orchard
				  lot up as far As that row of peach Trees back of the house  you must do the best you can and Cook  Look for me
				  untill you see me comeing  No more yours untill Death good by</p>
        <p>HENRY  BROWN.</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
