<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000599_000206_0000">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Letter,
					<name>Henry Brown</name>
				                   in Convalesent camp near Nashville, Tenn. to Caroline M. Brown, <date when="1862-09-11">1862 Sept. 11</date>
            </title>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
          <name>White, Park</name>
        </respStmt>
        <author>
          <name type="person">Henry Brown</name>
        </author>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
        <date>2013</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
        </availability>
        <idno type="SPC">0012_000599_000206_0000</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Letter, Henry Brown in Convalesent camp near Nashville, Tenn. to Caroline M. Brown, 1862 Sept. 11</title>
          <date when="1862-09-11">1862 Sept. 11</date>
          <author>
            <name type="person">Henry Brown</name>
          </author>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <note type="collection">Henry Brown Collection 
</note>
          <note type="manuscript">MS.599</note>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
        <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
        <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
        <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as "turn page over" have been
						omitted.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy>
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="LCSH">
          <term>Ohio -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives.</term>
          <term>Ohio -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.</term>
          <term>Soldiers -- Ohio -- Correspondence.</term>
          <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives.</term>
          <term>United States. Army. Ohio Infantry Regiment, 31st (1861-1865)</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change when="2013" who="White, Park">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
      <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e38">
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_000599_000206_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e39"/>
        <p>September  11th  62</p>
        <p>Convalesent Camp</p>
        <p>CAROLINE  M.  BROWN</p>
        <p>Near Nashville  Tennessee</p>
        <p>Dear wife it is with regret that I seat myself To inform you whare I am I am in the camp Above mentioned about
				       One mile from Nashville Waiting my discharge and we that are here are used more like dogs than men  we only
				       get one third Rashons and that is not a Nought we have to buy Some Bread and potatoes and a little meat to keep
				       us along i think we will be Sent to Louisville Before Long and then home</p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_000599_000206_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e51"/>
        <p>After my respects to you your Father and mother and The boys I will just say That i got a few lines In jim Bones
				  letter And was truly glad to Hear from you for it Had bin a good before That i had any word From you it was the
				  26 of last month and Since That I received one dated The 8 of last month  From you and Jimmy Bloomer I was
				  verry Glad to hear that you All injoyed good health Alltho i am not Blest with the Same at present  I hope i will
				  be at Home before long to injoy with you all Some of the</p>
        <pb n="3" facs="0012_000599_000206_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e55"/>
        <p>Good thing you have laid up for me you must Not make your Self Unesy about me and you Must Excuse me for
				       not writing before this because I have bin moved to 3 Difernt places since i rote The last letter to you  And now 
				       i cant advis you To write to me for i cant Tell what day we may Be moved from this camp To Some other so i
				       shall Say for you not to write untill i write again to To you if we are moved To Louisville i shall come Home 
				       Shure my feet and Legs are not sweld so Bad as they ware some time ago but</p>
        <pb n="4" facs="0012_000599_000206_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e59"/>
        <p>So good By to you all  I cant walk to do any Good and dont know As i Ever shall any more N. B. John S. Hemery
				       Got wounded in the Thigh last mondy they ware going out on a Scout and the out line Of our pickets fired on
				       Them and wounded Him  now i will just Say that i will be at Home as soon as i can Get there you may bet my
				       legs achees while writeing these few Lines  there is 6 of co A waiting for their Papers  myself and R Scrivoner and
				       John McClurg and the other I need not mention</p>
        <p>HENRY  BROWN.</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
