<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:id="ms0012_001303_000243_0000">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Letter,
					<name>Dodds, James L.</name>
				                    in France to Ellen Smith in Jackson, <date when="1919-02-02">1919 Feb. 2</date>
            </title>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
          <name>Giles, Sheldon</name>
        </respStmt>
        <author>
          <name type="person">Dodds, James L.</name>
        </author>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
        <date>2013</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
        </availability>
        <idno type="SPC">0012_001303_000243_0000</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Letter, Dodds, James L. in France to Ellen Smith in Jackson, 1919 Feb. 2</title>
          <date when="1919-02-02">1919 Feb. 2</date>
          <author>
            <name type="person">Dodds, James L.</name>
          </author>
          <extent>5 pages</extent>
          <note type="collection">Smith Family Papers</note>
          <note type="manuscript">1303</note>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
        <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
        <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
        <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as "turn page over" have been
						omitted.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy>
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="LCSH">
          <term>Jackson (Tenn.) -- History.</term>
          <term>Jackson (Tenn.) -- Social life and customs.</term>
          <term>Knoxville (Tenn.) -- History.</term>
          <term>Newton County (Ind.) -- Genealogy.</term>
          <term>Tennessee Volunteers (Football team).</term>
          <term>University of Tennessee, Knoxville.</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change when="2013" who="Giles, Sheldon">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
      <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e38">
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_001303_000243_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e39"/>
        <p>J. L. Dodds</p>
        <p>T Co #8 23rd Engir</p>
        <p>American Exp forces</p>
        <p>Miss Ellen Smith</p>
        <p>111 Hatton Street</p>
        <p>Jackson Tennessee U. S. A.</p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_001303_000243_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e53"/>
        <p>Dear Ellen:</p>
        <p>Recieved your most welcome letter of Jan 4- yesterday I only got two letters last week one from you and the other from mother</p>
        <p>We have had a snow this week and is still on the ground The roads are slick as glass I am like one of the boys said last night. the only time I am in the road is when I cross from one side to the other
                                If I dont quit fussing so much abot the weather over here i know you will think I am a regular old grouch</p>
        <p>But I have just go to fuss about something so I take it out on the weather.</p>
        <pb n="3" facs="0012_001303_000243_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e63"/>
        <p>I hope your eyes are alright by this time. </p>
        <p>I know you called me out when they were hurting so bad and I dont blame you a bit. Well when I get home I sure will do some calling out for I have told my people to never have any of my letters
                                    published in the paper. </p>
        <p>I dont think my name looks good in the paper.</p>
        <p>I say there has been plenty of flue in the States. Looks like never will leave I am sure glad we didnt have it to contend with over here Maybe if the weather continues Cold will stop that awful flue. They must have put on quite</p>
        <pb n="4" facs="0012_001303_000243_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e73"/>
        <p> a show for <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SG">Dean</unclear>
            </p>
        <p>Say did he ever come accross over here. I dont see how he got home so quick if he did</p>
        <p>I saw Ernest Warlick the other day, I dont know wherether you know him or not. Say you know him anyway. 
				Company is here in town with me I found the company the othere day but he is in the hospital So I dont get to see him
				I was awful sorry for when I found out he was in town (or his company) I thought I would get to see him</p>
        <p>I didnt find out what was the matter with him. If he got back any way soon I will see him I guess. I hope so any way</p>
        <pb n="5" facs="0012_001303_000243_0005.jpg" xml:id="d4e85"/>
        <p>I can find out where Prvt Leroy is I have looked for the place on the map but havent found it yet. Must be a small town. Well news is real scarce so will quit for this time hopeing to here from you again real soon</p>
        <p>With lots of love</p>
        <p>James L. Dodds</p>
        <p>Truck Co #8 - 23rd Engir</p>
        <p>A. E., Th </p>
        <p>France</p>
        <p>P. S. You should hear the argument here now Some one has started the report that we will be on our way home in 60 days I dont know but dont think there is any truth to the report</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
