<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:id="ms0012_001303_000218_0000">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Letter,
					<name>James L. Dodds</name>
				                  in France to Ellen Clark Smith, in Jackson Tenn., <date when="1918-06-08">1918 June 8</date>
            </title>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
          <name>Sheldon Giles</name>
        </respStmt>
        <author>
          <name type="person">James L. Dodds</name>
        </author>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
        <date>2013</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
        </availability>
        <idno type="SPC">0012_001303_000218_0000</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Letter, James L. Dodds in France to Ellen Clark Smith, in Jackson Tenn., 1918 June 8</title>
          <date when="1918-06-08">1918 June 8</date>
          <author>
            <name type="person">James L. Dodds</name>
          </author>
          <extent>3 pages</extent>
          <note type="collection">Smith Family Papers Title</note>
          <note type="manuscript">1303</note>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
        <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
        <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
        <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as "turn page over" have been
						omitted.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy>
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="LCSH">
          <term>Jackson (Tenn.) -- History.</term>
          <term>Jackson (Tenn.) -- Social life and customs.</term>
          <term>Knoxville (Tenn.) -- History.</term>
          <term>Newton County (Ind.) -- Genealogy.</term>
          <term>Tennessee Volunteers (Football team).</term>
          <term>University of Tennessee, Knoxville.</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change when="2013" who="Sheldon Giles">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
      <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e38">
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_001303_000218_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e39"/>
        <p>James L Dodds</p>
        <p>Co L 23 Engrs</p>
        <p>American Ex Force</p>
        <p>Miss Ellen Clark Smith</p>
        <p>111 Hatton Street</p>
        <p>Jackson </p>
        <p>Tennessee</p>
        <p>U. S. A.</p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_001303_000218_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e57"/>
        <p>June 8, 1918</p>
        <p>Some where in France</p>
        <p>Dear Ellen:</p>
        <p>I recieved two letters from you yesterday and I cant tell you how glad I was to get them I was looking every day for a letter from you
So you can imagine how glad I was. I was cooking dinner when the mail came and when I got the two letters I quit frying stake to read them.
The other cook said he didnt want me to get any more mail when we were cooking dinner But I hope I can get it any time believe me 
welll things are a little quiet here now as I am getting use to the noise and things that go on here</p>
        <p>When I first got here every time I heard an aeroplane I would have to go out and look at it as long as I could see it and now 
I dont notice them half the time Unless I think there is going to be a fight in the air. I like to see that it is real entertaining</p>
        <p/>
        <p/>
        <pb n="3" facs="0012_001303_000218_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e71"/>
        <p>I think I told you about seeing the German plane come down in flames the other day Well that alway pleases me to see the 
                <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SG">WORD</unclear> Backs come down.</p>
        <p>But things are coming along nice now. We have some fun here with the boxing gloves the company shares them and in the 
evenings after supper some one put them on a go to it. We have some French soilders here and some times they put them on and then we have some fun
Soilders are just like kids always playing but we have to do some thing like that to amuse our selfs.</p>
        <p>Well I am sorry you didnt get to go to the dance. But I dont understand why you didnt tell Bob  you wanted to go 
I remember very well how you use to tell me what to do and more especially to go home pretty early do you remember it.
Well I guess Ester has to love Carl so</p>
        <pb n="4" facs="0012_001303_000218_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e83"/>
        <p>much she dont have time to write me. I think I will write them  night . If I have the time to write to mother on sunday
I can realize yet Ester is married. Miss Mary Ransom writes to us boys and send the interesting news out of the town of Jackson
Since I see in there also  that you have had several wedding back home.</p>
        <p>You said you would stash you letter because some one else wanted to read it. Well I am th eonly one that
has to read it and I dont get tired at all You dont know how much I enjoy I do enjoy getting letters from you But hope in the near future
we wont have to write to each other I will be home to talk to you Must close for this time write me real soon and dont forget me</p>
        <p>with lots of love</p>
        <p>James L. Dodds</p>
        <p>Co L 23 Engrs</p>
        <p>American Ex Force</p>
        <p>Via N. Y. France</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
