<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000599_000239_0000">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Letter,
					<name>Henry Brown</name>
				                    in Camp Shiloh Tenn., to Caroline M. Brown,<date when="1862-05-03">1862 May 3</date>
            </title>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
          <name>Wibking, Lyndy</name>
        </respStmt>
        <author>
          <name type="person">Henry Brown</name>
        </author>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
        <date>2013</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
        </availability>
        <idno type="SPC">0012_000599_000239_0000</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Letter, Henry Brown in Camp Shiloh Tenn., to Caroline M. Brown,1862 May 3</title>
          <date when="1862-05-03">1862 May 3</date>
          <author>
            <name type="person">Henry Brown</name>
          </author>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <note type="collection">Henry Brown Collection</note>
          <note type="manuscript">MS.2117</note>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
        <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
        <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
        <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as "turn page over" have been
						omitted.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy>
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="LCSH">
          <term>Ohio -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives.</term>
          <term>Ohio -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.</term>
          <term>Soldiers -- Ohio -- Correspondence.</term>
          <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives.</term>
          <term>United States. Army. Ohio Infantry Regiment, 31st (1861-1865)</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change when="2013" who="Wibking, Lyndy">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
      <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e38">
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_000599_000239_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e39"/>
        <p>Camp Shiloh</p>
        <p>Tennessee May 3th 62</p>
        <p>Caroline M. Brown</p>
        <p>Dear wife it is with much pleasure that I sit down this afternoon to let you know how i am At this time I feel verry well at present hopeing these few lines may find you and the Boys the same we are just Alaying here on our backs doing no good for no body we are campt in the woods the woods are trampt up like A door yard we have to sweep our quarters Every morning And we have a big yard to sweep to what you have at home we have about one half acre to sweep in the woods</p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_000599_000239_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e49"/>
        <p>At that anough of that now if i could tell you whare we would go from here i would be happy to do so but i cannot I feel a little afraid that we will have to go further South before we are set free i will just say that we get some good news with the bad as we go along i have nothing new to tell you at present as we are in the same place yet we still can hear from virginnia the army are in motion there and doing some work there now i think they will soon clean out the rebels I hear before long if so we will clean out the Mississippi value for them</p>
        <pb n="3" facs="0012_000599_000239_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e53"/>
        <p>Now we are going to have a verry poor chance to get a letter home they have what the call the letter blockade At Savannah to keep the letters untill news gets old and we cant help it they say that they will stay some two weeks Before they will send away But you can send as many as you want to me they will come rite on to the regment I want you to send one to me every week whether you get one or not i shall write to you once a week while i am here whether get them or not you must not get out of heart because you do not get my letters i want</p>
        <pb n="4" facs="0012_000599_000239_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e57"/>
        <p>to hear from you and the boys As often as i can and i would like you to get my letters the same way if some of the neighbors would send me a letter i would try and answer it the best i could i want <unclear reason="illegible" resp="LW">yount</unclear> you to still want you to send me some more stamp when this come to hand if you can get them handy I shall close my letter now hopeing to hear from you soon as this comes to hand I got a letter from Indiana since i heard from you and ware all well when it was written no more at prseent but still remain your true husband Henry Brown good by to you to day</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
