<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng"
type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng"
type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_001356_000209_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter, 
               <name type="author">Alfred Smith</name> in <name type="place">Nashville, Tenn.</name>, to <name type="person">Eliza Smith</name> in <name type="place">Binghamton, N.Y.</name>, 
               <date when="1865-05-14">1865 May 14</date>
            </title>
            <author>
               <name>Smith, Alfred</name>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>White, Park</name>
               <name>Lasley, Noah</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <availability status="restricted">
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
                  information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special Collections Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
            <idno>0012_001356_000209_0000</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Letter, 
                  <name type="author">Alfred Smith</name> in <name type="place">Nashville, Tenn.</name>, to <name type="person">Eliza Smith</name> in <name type="place">Binghamton, N.Y.</name>, 
                  <date when="1865-05-14">1865 May 14</date>
               </title>
               <date when="1865-05-14">1865 May 14</date>
               <author>
                  <name>Smith, Alfred</name>
               </author>
               <extent>3 digital images</extent>
               <note type="collection">Mary Francis (Fannie) Smith Family Papers</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS.3029</note>
               </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for The University of Tennessee Libraries
               Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Corrections have been applied to the text only where there is a high degree of
               certainty of an error and if the correct spelling is known.</p>
            <p>Corrections are represented by editorial tags.</p>
            <p>Quotation marks and apostrophes have been replaced by entity references.</p>
            <p>All unambiguous end-of-line hyphens have been removed.</p>
            <p>Names of persons, places, and organizations are indicated in the transcription when
               identifiable with a high degree of certainty.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Binghamton (N.Y.) -- History.</term>
               <term>Floods -- New York (State).</term>
               <term>Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865 -- Assassination.</term>
               <term>New York (State) -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.</term>
               <term>Soldiers -- New York (State) -- Correspondence.</term>
               <term>Soldiers -- Tennessee -- Correspondence.</term>
               <term>Tennessee -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.</term>
               <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Correspondence.</term>
               <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Engineering and construction.</term>
               <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Manuscripts.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-07-16" who="da">
            Added "idno" element, editorial declaration statement, subjects/keywords and abstracts 
            from EAD finding aid. Removed box and folder notes, reference declaration element. Changed the formatting for blank 
            pages. Added resp attributes to editorial changes, and added name tags.
         </change>
         <change when="2013-07-17" who="da">Deleted n= attribute of TEI element, updated availability statement to include hyperlink, updated pagination to reflect envelopes being changed to back matter, removed superscript markup.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter" xml:id="d2e209">
            <pb facs="0012_001356_000209_0001.jpg" n="1" xml:id="d2e211"/>
            
            <opener>
               <dateline>
                  <name type="place">Nashville</name> <date when="1865-05-14">May 14th</date><lb/>
               </dateline>
               <salute>My Dear mother</salute><lb/>
            </opener>
            
            <p>"The U. S. CHRISTIAN COMMISSION sends this sheet as a messenger between the soldier and his home. Let it hasten to those who wait for the tidings."</p>
            <p>it now with pleasure that I answere your kind and welcome letter wich I received of the 9th and to let you know that I am well and injoying good health.</p>
            <p>can you tell me how longe father expects to stay there  bussness is very dull here  they ar discharging men here at the rate of 50 to 100 a day and when they all get paid off  the mess house will break up  if it dont before the 14 I think I shall come
               
               <pb facs="0012_001356_000209_0002.jpg" n="2" xml:id="d2e238"/>
               home then you say that pat foly is down to owego to work  I suppose every thing is dull there in B.  you sayed in your letter you would like to have my photograph taken standing  I am short of money just now  I have not been paid since I have been here you need not send me any money but will you send me a few postage stamps  tell Mr hensdale that gene has got a job working in a wood yard in franklin 20 miles south of nashville and Mike cuningham to I suppose that Susan Cooley sent
               
            <pb facs="0012_001356_000209_0003.jpg" n="3" xml:id="d2e240"/>
               me those flowers because they were so early we have radishes onions when ever we want them and new potatoes and green pease we have peaches the 1 of next month. send my best respects to pat foly and steve peer and all the rest of my inquiring friends also give my best respects to sale allen and tell her she ought to send me her picture. tell Austin that this ringe I send is made from <choice><orig>mustle</orig><corr resp="nl">mussel</corr></choice> shell that I took out of the <name type="place">cumberland river</name> and also a shield to hange on his watch chain</p>
            
            <closer>
               <salute>yours respectfully<lb/>
                  from your son<lb/>
               </salute>
               <signed>Alfred</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
