<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000060_000261_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter, <name> J. Crozier Ramsey </name> in Nashville, Tenn., to Mrs. E.A.R. Breck
in Charlotte, N.C. <date when="1865-09-15"> 1865 September 15 </date>
            </title>
            <author>
               <name type="person">Ramsey, J. Crozier</name>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>Dyson-Smith, Bridger</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_000060_000261_0000</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more information,
            contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special Collections
                Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Letter, J. Crozier Ramsey in Nashville, Tenn., to Elizabeth Ramsey Breck in Charlotte, N.C. 1865 Sept. 15</title>
               <date>1865-09-15</date>
               <author>
                  <name>Ramsey, J. Crozier</name>
               </author>
               <extent>4 digital images; 4 pages</extent>
               <note type="abstract">1865 Sept. 15 J. Crozier Ramsey, Nashville, Tenn., to his sister, Elizabeth
Ramsey Breck, Charlotte, N.C. Having heard of the insulting treatment of
Confederate sympathizers in Knoxville, advises his family to remain in North
Carolina. Regrets that he must go to Knoxville on business. Praises
President Johnson as a friend to the South who deserves the support of the
Southern people. Mentions writing to Judge Patterson, Andrew Johnson&apos;s
son-in-law, concerning the return of Elizabeth&apos;s farm. Expresses hope of
finding a wife when he can earn enough to support a family. News of his
mother&apos;s brother, Arthur Crozier. </note>
               <note type="collection">J.G.M. Ramsey Papers 1790-1869</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS.253</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee Libraries
                Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
                omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Business and politics -- Tennessee -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Family farms -- Political aspects -- Tennessee -- Knoxville --History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Quality of life -- Tennessee -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Confederate States of America -- Politics and government -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Knoxville (Tenn.) -- Politics and government -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Ramsey, J. Crozier (John Crozier) d. 1868 -- Correspondence.</term>
               <term>Breck, E. A. R. (Elizabeth Alexander Ramsey), 1823- -- Correspondence.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-10-02" who="bds">Migrating from
                XML to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter" xml:id="d3e158">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_000060_000261_0001.jpg" xml:id="d3e159"/>
            <p>Nashville Ten Sept 15th</p>
            <p>My Dear Sister</p>
            <p>I received your very kind letter and was sorry to hear that Ma and Sue had been sick. I hope however they will soon be
restored to their usual health. I am glad that you all have gone to house keeping. I am now satisfied (from what I hear almost
daily from Knoxville) that you have acted wisly in remaining where you are. The outragious <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">sciens</unclear> taht are constantly transpiring there is disgraceful to humanity and civilisation and is
almost beyond description I however will be compelled to be there the third Monday in Oct I do not anticipate the trip</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_000060_000261_0002.jpg" xml:id="d3e174"/>
            <p>with pleasure. I have no fears at the result of my case - but the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">outside</unclear>
feeling is not so good but you need give yourself no uneasiness about my safety as I think I will come out with safety. I also
received Papas letter a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">five</unclear> days ago enclosing me a copy of his application
for pardon - As I had written to him about my arrest and return from Knoxville I have not yet answered it. I think he need have
no fears I think President Johnson will pardon him and all others soon. I was highly pleased with his speech - he made before
the Southern delegation you must get it and read it - he will come out all right as I knew he would - he will be the best
friend the</p>
            <pb n="3" facs="0012_000060_000261_0003.jpg" xml:id="d3e188"/>
            <p>South has and it <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">becomes</unclear> us all cordially to sustain him inorder that he
may be able to break down Black republicanism. I will write to Judge Patterson to day and see if he cant get the President to
order the return of your farm without you visiting Knoxville - if so we can rent it out for you. I am glad to hear that the
young folks are disposed to marry I hope they may all be able to find suitable companions I would like very much to be there and
form some acquaintances with the ladies - but that is impossible. I will have to do my courting by proxy and let you act as
my agent though I must first get through all my troubles and then try and make some money to support</p>
            <pb n="4" facs="0012_000060_000261_0004.jpg" xml:id="d3e199"/>
            <p>some good lady with - but if she had the money I think I would be a very good person to take care of it for her as I have
had much experience in having money and not having it. I would have sent you my Photograph with pleasure but my practice as yet
is quite limited and it takes all I make to keep up my necessary expenses I will however try and send you one soon. Say to Papa
that if he has my pocket book containing my notes - and has an opportunity of sending it - to send it to me - perhaps there may be
some of them that I can collect or make something out of them. I received a letter from Uncle Arthur a few weeks ago - he is at
Austin - his family is well but he has lost a great <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">eal</unclear> of property though not
as much as the rest of us - he speaks of moving to Arkansas - When I write to him I will advise him to come here I received a letter
from my Dear Sister Margaret J. (she is well) a few days ago. She sustains me in all my troubles when I am at Knoxville with a
devotion and affection that is unequaled and unprecidented by a Sister I dont see how I could get along without her - She (while
I lay in the jail) was there both late and early Uncle Williams has been very sick for the last week - but is some better to day - the
rest are all well. Remember me kindly to all - will be pleased to hear from you all at any time</p>
            <p>Yours truly</p>
            <p>J.C. Ramsey</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>