<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000060_000537_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter,
<name>John M. Lea</name>
 in Nashville, Tenn., to M.B.C. Ramsey in Knoxville, Tenn..<date when="1886-02-02">1886 Feb. 2</date>
            </title>
            <author>
               <name type="person">Lea, John M.</name>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>Roberts, Jason</name>
               <name>Williams, Sherry</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_000060_000537_0000</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more information,
            contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special Collections
                Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Letter, John M. Lea in Nashville, Tenn., to M.B.C. Ramsey in Knoxville, Tenn. 1886 Feb. 2</title>
               <date>1886-02-02</date>
               <author>
                  <name>Lea, John M.</name>
               </author>
               <extent>3 digital images; 1 envelope, 2 pages.</extent>
               <note type="abstract">1886 Feb. 2, John M. Lea, Nashville, Tenn., to M.B.C. Ramsey, Knoxville, Tenn. Reports that the Society has been left $5000 with which they can manage well and publish their proceedings. Regrets that J.G.M. did not live to see this. Mentions his own old age. 

</note>
               <note type="collection">James Gettys McGready Ramsey Papers</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS.0253</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee Libraries
                Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
                omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>History -- Sources -- Publishing -- Tennessee.</term>
               <term>Aging -- Physiological aspects.</term>
               <term>Gifts.</term>
               <term>Nashville (Tenn.) -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Tennessee -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Tennessee Historical Society -- Finance.</term>
               <term>Ramsey, J. G. M. (James Gettys McGready), 1797-1884 -- Appreciation.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-10-02" who="bds">Migrating from
                XML to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter" xml:id="d3e154">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_000060_000537_0001.jpg" xml:id="d3e155"/>
            <p>If not called for in 10 days</p>
            <p>Return To</p>
            <p>John M. Lea.</p>
            <p>Nashville, Tenn.</p>
            <p>Mrs. Margaret C. Ramsey</p>
            <p>Mecklenburg near</p>
            <p>Knoxville</p>
            <p>Tenn</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_000060_000537_0002.jpg" xml:id="d3e178"/>
            <p>43 North Vine Street,</p>
            <p>Nashville, Tenn., Feb. 2 1886</p>
            <p>Mrs. Margaret C, Ramsey,</p>
            <p>My Dear Friend,</p>
            <p>I sent you to-day a copy of the proceedings of a Meeting of the Historical Society recently held at Murfreesboro. I know that you take a deep interest in the Institution of which my friend, your most excellent and honored husband was for a long time the President and most efficient and useful member. His name and memory are held in veneration by every member of the Society, and we all feel the deep obligation that we owe to him. I wish he had lived to have known the price of good fortune which has happened by which our means of <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JR"> carefulness</unclear>will be increased. It was always a source of regret that our Treasury was so low that we could make no publications of our proceedings, and the efforts made by us to get help from the State never met with any success. A most worthy and public spirited gentleman who formerly lived in Tennessee -- whose death, I am grieved to say, was announced to me by a Telegram the night before last -- gave to the Society $5000, and the interest on this money coupled with the annual dues of the members will supply all our needs if economically managed. To many people those details would be uninteresting, but you will be pleased I know and whilst I write I feel almost as if I were talking to Dr. Ramsey. I take</p>
            <pb n="3" facs="0012_000060_000537_0003.jpg" xml:id="d3e197"/>
            <p>great pleasure in sending to you the first copy of any pamphlet printed by the Society with means not gathered from voluntary subscription.</p>
            <p>I hope that your health continues good and that you are far from the pain which often attends the aged even though not suffering from any real sickness. I too am getting old and have pretty much well accomplished every thing that I can do in this life. I have said to some of the Members that though I should be a good working member and never cease to take an interest in the success of the Society, I <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JR">must</unclear>be released from longer holding any official position. I am not so active as I was a few years ago and <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JR">must</unclear>be careful not to tax my strength.</p>
            <p>We had delightful weather till the beginning of the year and since that time there has scarcely been a clear day. Whilst I write it is snowing fast. Fifty five years ago such a snow would have caused a visit to &quot;Wilt&apos;s old friend,&quot; and to the grounds of your father around &quot;Aunt Edy&apos;s house,&quot; in quest of the rabbits, of which in that neighborhood, I recollect there were a great many, but my taste has changed, and now instead of hunting rabbits, I seek a warm fire and a cozy room.</p>
            <p>With kind regards to your family and best wishes for yourself</p>
            <p>Very Sincerely</p>
            <p>Your friend</p>
            <p>John M. Lea</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>