<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000060_000347_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter, <name>Francis A. Ramsey</name> at Swan-pond, Tenn., to J.G.M.
Ramsey, at Mount Ebenezer Academy, Knox County, Tenn. <date when="1813-03-25">1813 March 25</date>
            </title>
            <author>
               <name type="person">Ramsey, Francis A. (Francis Alexander), 1764-1820</name>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>Dyson-Smith, Bridger</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_000060_000347_0000</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more information,
            contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special Collections
                Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Letter, Francis A. Ramsey in Swan-Pond, Tenn., to J.G.M. &amp; W.B.A. Ramsey at Mount Ebenezer Academy, Knox County, Tenn. 1813 Mar. 25</title>
               <date>1813-03-25</date>
               <author>
                  <name>Ramsey, Francis A. (Francis Alexander), 1764-1820</name>
               </author>
               <extent>4 digital images; 4 pages</extent>
               <note type="abstract">1813 Mar. 25, Francis A. Ramsey, Swan-Pond, Tenn., to his sons, J.G.M. and W.B.A. Ramsey, students at Mount Ebenezer Academy, Knox County, Tenn. Greetings on J.G.M.&apos;s sixteenth birthday and advice for building a good character now that he has reached this &quot;very critical period.&quot;</note>
               <note type="collection">J.G.M. Ramsey Papers 1790-1869</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS.253</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee Libraries
                Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
                omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Moral exhortation -- History -- 19th century. </term>
               <term>Communication -- Moral and ethical aspects -- Tennessee -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Friendship -- Tennessee -- Sociological aspects -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Knox County (Tenn.)</term>
               <term>Ramsey, Francis A. (Francis Alexander), 1764-1820 -- Correspondence.</term>
               <term>Ramsey, J. G. M. (James Gettys McGready), 1797-1884 -- Correspondence.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-10-02" who="bds">Migrating from
                XML to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter" xml:id="d3e156">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_000060_000347_0001.jpg" xml:id="d3e157"/>
            <note type="transcription">The following text is a continuation of the fourth page of the letter.</note>
            <p>
               <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">N.B</unclear> Your grand Pa expected to go down but the rain
has prevented I will however keep this and send it to you the first opportunity Please to keep and
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">lay</unclear> by you for future perusal all my letters
and I will keep yours also - Billy will please to write to his Papa also - both of you write
occasionally to your <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Sissy</unclear> - she loves you both, and
it may be of service to write to her - </p>
            <note type="transcription">The preceding text is a continuation of the fourth page of the letter.</note>
            <p>Mr James G.My. Ramsey</p>
            <p>Student at Mount Ebenezzer Academy</p>
            <p>Knox County Tennessee</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_000060_000347_0002.jpg" xml:id="d3e183"/>
            <p>Swan-pond March 25th 1813</p>
            <p>My dearly beloved, and now my oldest Son,</p>
            <p>Sixteen years ago this day, I first seen your face, on that day, and on many days since I endeavoured
to give you to God, I almost dayly and hourly feel anxiety of mind about your happiness in this life and
in the life that is to come, you have now arrived at a very critical period of your life, a time when the
mind is very often formed as to the future character, the dispositions and habits formed about your present
age, and a few years after are such as is generally seen to accompany thro the whole course of life
afterwards, If this be true, then of what vast importance is it to set out right - Oh my son if you
knew, or could recognize how much my happiness, as well as your own depends on your good conduct, I
am sure you would still continue to try to add to my happiness, by guarding against youthful follies,
and now when you are coming near to mans years strive to &quot;put away childish things&quot;</p>
            <p>&quot;My Son, if thine heart be wise, my heart shall rejoice, even mine; yea, my reins shall rejoice,
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">when</unclear> thy lips speak right things.&quot; Prov. XXIII -
15.16</p>
            <p>&quot;I have no greater Joy than to hear that my children walk in Truth&quot; 3rd Epistle of John 4th
verse</p>
            <p>You will be careful to take all opportunities of storing your mind with useful and ornamental
knowledge <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">nad</unclear> such books as may be of most
advantage to you in this respect, and for this purpose I herewith</p>
            <pb n="3" facs="0012_000060_000347_0003.jpg" xml:id="d3e207"/>
            <p>Send you <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Beatties</unclear> Elements - which if I am not
mistaken is elegantly written, (but of this I am not a competent Judge) - I think it would be
advisable for you to make a small blank book in which you should write down your own observations on
every author you read, particularly noting the section page &amp;c - and if in any thing you are at
loss to understand your author - particularly note that, and write it down by way of interrogation,
and take some occasional opportunity of proposing it to your Uncle, or to any person whom you think
would be able to give you light on the subject - cultivate a disposition to reflect on, and apply all
you read, this is the way to make your reading profitable to you, and your life a pleasure to
your-self and to those connected with you - </p>
            <p>There is one thing my dear Son I think it my Duty to advise you about and to caution you respecting,
it is this - young men of ingenuous minds, and of a Friendly disposition, in the ardor of their Friendship
sometimes unintentionally injure the feelings or character of one Friend or associate in the mind of
another Friend or associate - I will give you an example - suppose I have two Friends A. and B -
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">with</unclear> whom I am intimate - and they are unacquainted
with each other - My Friend A. in the confidence of his Friendship with me, does some act before me,
or says something to me, that he would not wish to be known by any body else - I afterwards in the
confidence of my Friendship with B tell him</p>
            <pb n="4" facs="0012_000060_000347_0004.jpg" xml:id="d3e223"/>
            <p>about my Friend A. not intending any injury to A by telling B - yet you see at once that A is thereby
lessened in the eyes of B altho I have told nothing but what was true and in the ardor of my
Friendship for B - and at the same time not intending to act unfriendly to my Friend A. - this is an
evil that frequently arises among young Friends who are communicative, and the more Friends or
associates we have we are in the more danger of falling into this snare and still doing it in
the exercise of a Friendly disposition, I am the <unclear reason="gap" resp="bds">most</unclear> particular
in mentioning this as it is an error I have seen very many fall into, that they were not aware of
it - because they were unconscious of a design to injure any Friend, and as it only injures by
consequence and not of design.</p>
            <p>My Dear Son I am anxious that you should excel in every thing that is praise worthy, and ornamental
to the human character - you are naturally an Example to your dear little Brother Billy whose
naturally placid, and yielding disposition you may be very helpful to lead in the paths of Virtue,
Sobriety and Piety - this letter I design for you both but it was suggested principally from the
circumstance of this being your birthday - </p>
            <p>Let me exhort you in the words of an apostle &quot;The youthful lusts which war against the Soul&quot;
&quot;Let none despise thy youth, but be (both of you) an example to others&quot; &quot;<unclear reason="gap" resp="bds">Abstain from an appearance of evil&quot;</unclear> &quot;Pray without
ceasing&quot; I shall conclude with the words of Solomon &quot;My Sons, hear the instructions of
a Father,&quot; that you both may be disposed to walk in the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Fear</unclear> and Love of God, and to seek him now in the days of your youth is
the Earnest and constant prayer of my dear sons your affectionate Father</p>
            <p>F.A. Ramsey</p>
            <p>To J.G.My &amp; W.B.A. Ramsey</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
