<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000087_000200_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter, <name>
William J. Helsley
</name>
in Chattanooga, Tenn., to Mary Helsley in Southington, Ohio,
<date when="1864-07-23">
1864 July 23
</date>
            </title>
            <author>
               <name type="person">Helsley, William J.</name>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>Hogan, Josh</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_000087_000200_0000</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more information,
            contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special Collections
                Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Letter, William J. Helsley in Chattanooga, Tenn. to Mary Helsley in Southington, Ohio, 1864 July 23</title>
               <date>1864-07-23</date>
               <author>
                  <name>Helsley, William J.</name>
               </author>
               <extent>5 digital images; 0.1 linear feet; 1 envelope, 3 p.</extent>
               <note type="abstract">In this letter, dated July 23, 1864, William J. Helsley writes to his wife Mary Helsley, informing her that he has been given &quot;detached&quot; duty at a military bridge in Chattanooga, rather than being sent to the front. He also reports that General Sherman has captured Atlanta.</note>
               <note type="collection">William J. Helsley Letters, 1864</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS.1439</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee Libraries
                Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
                omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Soldiers -- Ohio -- Correspondence.</term>
               <term>Atlanta Campaign, 1864 -- Personal narratives.</term>
               <term>Georgia -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Campaigns.</term>
               <term>Tennessee, East -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.</term>
               <term>Sherman, William T. (William Tecumseh), 1820-1891.</term>
               <term>Helsley, William J. (William Jefferson) -- Correspondence.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-10-02" who="bds">Migrating from
                XML to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter" xml:id="d3e150">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_000087_000200_0001.jpg" xml:id="d3e151"/>
            <p>Mrs. Mary. Helsley.</p>
            <p>Southington,</p>
            <p>Trumbull,</p>
            <p>County, Ohio</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_000087_000200_0002.jpg" xml:id="d3e165"/>
            <p>August the 16th 64</p>
            <p>From Bill</p>
            <p>in haste</p>
            <p>and bring back</p>
            <p>a letter</p>
            <pb n="3" facs="0012_000087_000200_0003.jpg" xml:id="d3e181"/>
            <p>Chattanooga Tenn July the 23d</p>
            <p>Dear Mary</p>
            <p>After a delay of most two weeks I take up my pen to inform you whare I am and how I am getting along soon after my seckond letter that I wrote at Nashville I was sent back to this place to the convalecant camp and expected to go to the Regiment in a few days but instead of sending me to the front they put me on detached duty in Chattanooga at the Military Bridge over the Tenn River I have a good place to stay and plenty to eat and have not much duty to do and I think I will stay here a couple of weeks and I may stay longer I have got about well again and begin to feel like myself again we have good newes from Sherman this morning but no</p>
            <pb n="4" facs="0012_000087_000200_0004.jpg" xml:id="d3e193"/>
            <p>perticulars he has possession of Atlanta and the newes is that thare is a General fight coming of. the weathe has been very warm and it is getting very dry &amp; the roads are very dusty I was out in the country yesterday about four miles after Blackberries and found plenty of them five of us went out and in two hours we picked over a bushel I neve saw berries hang as thick and nearley all ripe.</p>
            <p>I have not heard from any of you since I left the Regiment and I am getting very anxious to hear from you I have been expecting a letter for some time but they have not come yet the letters that I had you send to Nashville I had them sent on to Chattanooga if they came thare. I found one of the Southington boys here a few days ago and had an old fashion visset the man was Harrison</p>
            <pb n="5" facs="0012_000087_000200_0005.jpg" xml:id="d3e203"/>
            <p>Eggleston he is a soldier and belongs to the 24th Ohio or did he is now with 18th Ohio and I saw James Hurd at Bridge Port when I came from Nashville here. I have wrote all I can think of this time and hope when it reaches you that it will find you well and I will</p>
            <p>Bid you Good Bye</p>
            <p>And Ever Remain</p>
            <p>Your Loveing Husband</p>
            <p>Wm J Helsley</p>
            <p>Write as soon as you can after you get this and send it to Chattanooga Tenn</p>
            <p>In care of the U.S. Christain Commission</p>
            <p>My Love to all</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>