<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000060_000259_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter, <name> J. Crozier Ramsey </name> in Nashville, Tenn., to M.B.C. Ramsey 
in Charlotte, N.C., <date when="1865-08-11"> 1865 August 11 </date>
            </title>
            <author>
               <name type="person">Ramsey, J. Crozier</name>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>Dyson-Smith, Bridger</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_000060_000259_0000</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more information,
            contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special Collections
                Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Letter, J. Crozier Ramsey in Nashville, Tenn., to M.B.C. Ramsey in Charlotte, N.C. 1865 Aug. 11</title>
               <date>1865-08-11</date>
               <author>
                  <name>Ramsey, J. Crozier</name>
               </author>
               <extent>4 digital images; 4 pages</extent>
               <note type="abstract">1865 Aug. 11 J. Crozier Ramsey, Nashville, Tenn., to his mother, M.B.C.
Ramsey, Charlotte, N.C. News of his father&apos;s brother, William B.A. Ramsey,
and of his family with whom Crozier is living. Tells of a visit with McNutt,
formerly a Federal officer and relays McNutt&apos;s impressions that Knoxvillians
would welcome the Ramseys with the exception of Robert. Urges his family to
return to Knoxville so that they can be near their grandchildren and have a
better chance of recovering their property. Mention of other Confederate
sympathizers returning to East Tennessee. </note>
               <note type="collection">J.G.M. Ramsey Papers 1790-1869</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS.253</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee Libraries
                Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
                omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Family life -- Southern States -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Refugee property -- Tennessee -- Knoxville -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Pardon -- Tennessee -- Knoxville -- History -- 19th century. </term>
               <term>Knoxville (Tenn.) -- Politics and government -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Southern States -- Politics and government -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Ramsey, J. Crozier (John Crozier) d. 1868 -- Correspondence.</term>
               <term>Ramsey, M. B. C. (Margaret Barton Crozier), 1802-1889 -- Correspondence.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-10-02" who="bds">Migrating from
                XML to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter" xml:id="d3e156">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_000060_000259_0001.jpg" xml:id="d3e157"/>
            <p>Nashville August 11th 1865</p>
            <p>My Dear Ma</p>
            <p>I received yours and Papas letters yesterday and was glad to hear that you were all well. I read all your letters
with great interest and my Uncle and his family who read them with great pleasure My Uncle and all of them are very kind
to me he is very comfortably situated and his two married daughters live near him they also have a Church near him and I
go to church every Sunday Mr <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Trimble</unclear> (their pastor) is a good preacher. I
think a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">greatest</unclear> about your situation and troubles I have taken great
interest about the state of feelings in East Ten and their is scarcely a day but what I see either a Union or Southern
man from there and I always make it my business to</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_000060_000259_0002.jpg" xml:id="d3e175"/>
            <p>enquire as to the condition of things with a view as to advise you all as to the propriety of returning I have no doubt
but the reports you hear from their are exagerated My own opinion based upon what I hear is that you could all return with
perfect safty (except Robert) without having the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">sbigent</unclear> fears of having
any personal harm done to Papa or Mack neither would you be subject to any insults of any kind. I met with Capt. John
McNutt (of the Fork and formerly of the Federal army) a few days ago I spent most of the day with him and took him out
and spent the night with us at my Uncles he has the kindest feeling for you all and from him I learned the particulars
as to the feeling about you all he says that all your old neighbors such men as Sam <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Bowman</unclear> and others are very anxious for you to return and instead of having any thing against you
they have</p>
            <pb n="3" facs="0012_000060_000259_0003.jpg" xml:id="d3e189"/>
            <p>great sympathy for you but would any thing in their power to serve you all John thinks you should all return at once. I
could give you many reasons why I should think it best for you to return if I could see you but I will only mention the most
important ones as they strike my mind you would be better satisfied if you move near your grandchildren where you could
take care of the poor motherless children although you could live comfortably where you are yet your anxiety for them
would always make you uneasy and still you would not be satisfied where you are Secondly by returning home the moral effect
would be good in getting back your property McNutt said that the public sentiment was very much against those that
purchased it and it might be that influences would be brought to bear (if you were all at home) that they would
surrender the property upon the money being refunded or upon some compromise that might be better than to commence a suit Aside
from this I believe that you could live cheaper and more comfortable and contented that where you are. You could live at
Margaret Janes place in town or at Lenoirs in <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">case</unclear>. Another reason when you
return if you should conclude not to remain there you would be in a better condition to select under the advice of your
friends a future home. I would therefore make Knoxville home (at least) for future <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">operations</unclear>
I would feel much more contented happy and less <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">solicitous</unclear> about you all if
you move back at your old home than for you all still to remain exiles that gives me more pain than my own condition if you go
to the trouble of getting a house and furnishing it and living there for a year yet I think it all unnecessary unless you
have made up your minds never to return then after surveying all</p>
            <pb n="4" facs="0012_000060_000259_0004.jpg" xml:id="d3e206"/>
            <p>facts and <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">sights</unclear> before me from this point. I would advise you that when the weather
gets cool and more pleasant for traveling (say the last of Sept or early in October) I would start for East Ten I suppose you
could get transportation for all by that time Papa will I hope receive his pardon I believe all will turn out well and that you
will all be glad that you have returned. The above is my candid advise but I leave the whole to your own better judgement you friends
at Knoxville may be able to give you a more correct view than I can. The last letter I received from Margaret Jane she and all of our
friends were well Aunt <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Hannah</unclear> and Aunt Mary had returned Uncle Frank
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Keller</unclear> was also at home <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">unmaserted</unclear>.
Frank Ramsey (Uncle Johns son had also returned and was living at home undisturbed. The corn crop in East Ten is very promising
James Cowan and family are all at home He or Mr <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Hismes</unclear> or Dr. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Lennox</unclear> could give Papa correct information as to the propriety of his
returning soon. Tell Papa that I expect to hear from Judge Patterson soon in regards to our applications and that I will
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">note</unclear> a while before I answer his letter. Do any of you know what had become
of Maj R.B. Reynolds I have heard nothing from him since I was captured. I heard that Maj Wallace was living in Athens Ga and that
he would be elected President of some Rail Road I hope he will if you all should go home soon perhaps he could give Robert a
situation on the road. All the refugees from Middle Ten are returning and received <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">kindly</unclear>
by the Union men When you all write write at different times and by that means I can get a letter from you once a week Will the mail
communication be open soon to Charlotte. Remember me kindly and affectionately to all Will be pleased to hear from you all
at any time</p>
            <p>Yours truly</p>
            <p>J.C. Ramsey</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>