<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000060_000228_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter, <name>J.G.M. Ramsey and M.B.C. Ramsey</name> in Charlotte, N.C., to Mrs. E.A.R. Breck,
in Liberty, V.A. <date when="1867">1867</date>
            </title>
            <author>
               <name type="person">Ramsey, J. G. M. (James Gettys McGready)</name>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>Dyson-Smith, Bridger</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_000060_000228_0000</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more information,
            contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special Collections
                Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Letter, J.G.M. Ramsey and M.B.C. Ramsey in Charlotte, N.C., to Mrs. E.A.R. Breck in Liberty, Va. 1867 undated</title>
               <date>1867</date>
               <author>
                  <name>Ramsey, J. G. M. (James Gettys McGready)</name>
               </author>
               <extent>2 digital images; 2 pages</extent>
               <note type="abstract">1867 Letters from J.G.M. Ramsey and wife, M.B.C. Ramsey, Charlotte, N.C., to their daughter, E.A.R. Breck in Liberty, Virginia. J.G.M. briefly mentions a long letter from son Crozier. Expresses details of family&apos;s prosperity and abundance of livestock/poultry and fresh fruits/vegetables. His wife expresses details of Sophie Alexander&apos;s wedding. Gives details of her own plans for traveling via buggy, and condition of her health.  </note>
               <note type="collection">J.G.M. Ramsey Papers 1790-1869</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS.253</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee Libraries
                Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
                omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Family life -- North Carolina -- Charlotte -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Elite (social sciences) -- North Carolina -- Charlotte -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Charlotte (N. C.) -- Social life and customs -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Ramsey, J. G. M. (James Gettys McGready), 1797-1884 -- Correspondence.</term>
               <term>Ramsey, M. B. C. (Margaret Barton Crozier), 1802-1889 -- Correspondence.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-10-02" who="bds">Migrating from
                XML to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter" xml:id="d3e151">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_000060_000228_0001.jpg" xml:id="d3e152"/>
            <p>another good &amp; long letter C. sent me three copies of the Commercial. When <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Progress</unclear> full out honest people used to get their own May be it will be so now. Nows 
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">serons.</unclear>, We are all well - have <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">luxuriated</unclear> on strawberries cream &amp; sugar for a month. They are almost but cherries &amp;
currants take their place. Our garden is fine &amp; the poultry yard is full of chickens ducks geese &amp; (20) young
turkeys. We have two fine cows &amp; of course plenty of milk &amp; butter &amp; a little money in th Bank. &amp; the
promise of a good crop. Love to all the rest &amp; a kiss to little <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Suzy</unclear>.
Has she forgotten me? Your Ma will add a line J.G.M. Ramsey</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_000060_000228_0002.jpg" xml:id="d3e172"/>
            <p>My dear Daughter, your Pa has written so fully on every subject there is buy little for me to say. Sophia Alexander
was married last wednesday morning to Dr Lamples an old flame he is 57 - she is 30 they left immediately for Memphis where
he resides a number of the clan were present most of whom it is said were not invited - none of our set were invited but
Capt Johnson &amp; Mr Holliday, not even Davidson A., of course they are teased by the rest, especially by the ladies.
Lue. &amp; Mc were at Ms H. the evening before Old Ms H. is there, she begged them to stay all night, &amp; she would
have an opposition breakfast. When the throng of wash is over I will go up to Roberts he will send his buggy for me, it
will be a long ride for me, if I am well can go, last week I was not well. Write often and tell us all the news of Tenn. I
am very uneasy about Crozier. I received a letter last week from Nannie, they were all well and seem much pleased with
their new home. Give my love to your Aunt Mary tell her when she moves again had better come to N.C. your aff Ma</p>
            <p>M.B. Ramsey</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
