<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000060_000336_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter, <name>J. Ramsey</name>, <date>undated</date>
            </title>
            <author>
               <name type="person">Ramsey, J. G. M. (James Gettys McGready), 1797-1884</name>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>Dyson-Smith, Bridger</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_000060_000336_0000</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more information,
            contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special Collections
                Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Letter, 1819?,  J. Ramsey (Philadelphia?)</title>
               <date>1819-01-01</date>
               <author>
                  <name>Ramsey, J. G. M. (James Gettys McGready), 1797-1884</name>
               </author>
               <extent>2 digital images; 2 pages.</extent>
               <note type="abstract">Letter, 1819?, from J. Ramsey (Philadelphia, Pennsylvania) describing the medical college faculty and lectures he attends. Notes the effect of Dr. Rush&apos;s death on the &quot;fame of this University.&quot; (Written on a &quot;Philadelphia, Nov. 15, 1819 circular&quot; by Jospeh M. Sanderson.)</note>
               <note type="collection">J.G.M. Ramsey Papers 1790-1869</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS.253</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee Libraries
                Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
                omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Medical colleges -- Pennsylvania -- Philadelphia -- Faculty -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>College teachers -- Pennsylvania -- Philadelphia -- History -- 19th century. </term>
               <term>Lectures and lecturing -- Pennsylvania -- Philadelphia -- History -- 19th century. </term>
               <term>Philadelphia (Pa.) -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Ramsey, J. G. M. (James Gettys McGready), 1797-1884 -- Correspondence.</term>
               <term>Rush, Benjamin, 1746-1813.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-10-02" who="bds">Migrating from
                XML to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter" xml:id="d3e149">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_000060_000336_0001.jpg" xml:id="d3e150"/>
            <p>I have hitherto <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">deferred from</unclear> writing to you from
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">the</unclear> expectation that a time would arrive when I
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">should</unclear> have more leisure than I have yet found - But
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">such</unclear> a time I believe will not arrive during the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">continuance</unclear> of the Lectures - Indeed I never viewed my time
as worth more than it now is - The Lectures are becoming daily more interesting because they are becoming
daily more practical (Doctor Chapman who Lectures on the Theory and Practice of Medicine and Clinical
Practice having finished physiology &amp; Pathology has just entered on the causes symptoms &amp; treatment
of diseases) - He has <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">adapted</unclear> a nomeclature <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">&amp;</unclear> arrangement wholly different from any other
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">no<gap resp="Dyson-Smith"/>ologist</unclear>
            </p>
            <p>Dr <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Gosce</unclear> has got through his speculations on the Modus
Operandi &amp; the Quo modo of medicine is beginning to <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">show</unclear>
their application to the removal and prevention of diseases. Instead of the theories of inflammation 
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">lemon</unclear> huge Old with which his first lectures abounded Dr.
Gibson Prof. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Lus.</unclear> has begun to exhibit the Principles and
Practice of Operative Surgery. And even the speculations for which the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Chair</unclear> Dr. J Jills is distinguished are giving way to the</p>
            <p>Owing in part to the present pecuniary <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">embarrassment</unclear> of
the Country as well as perhaps to the increasing celebrity of the rival institutions <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">there</unclear> is in this University a much smaller class than has been for many years -- The
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">speculation</unclear> of this school as far as I can learn is fast
sinking -- The death of Rush and more lately of <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Niston</unclear> &amp;
the removal of Doctor <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Physia</unclear> from the Surgical to the
anatomical chair have contributed very much to lessen the fame of this University -- The present
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">however</unclear> is said to be the best course of lectures that has been
delivered since the decease of Rush Dr. C. is <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">propenent</unclear> of the
Theory &amp; Practice &amp; Clinical Practice -- he is every way a very superior man but distinguished
especially for the Industry of his research Theraputics -- source of <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">eliscan</unclear> classification -- <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Physick</unclear> is
the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">idol</unclear> of the City and is indisputablely a very eminent
operative surgeon. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Butand</unclear> though his inventions and
improvements in this branch of the profession manifest a great degree of ingenuity &amp; <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">inventi<gap resp="Dyson-Smith"/>
               </unclear> I cannot think him equal to many of the professors. He is <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">escepively raecin</unclear> &amp; austere &amp; supremely self-sufficient
- and though an accurate &amp; <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">correct</unclear> administrator in
Anatomy he is very far from a ready one - and as might be <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">expected</unclear>
from one who so long taught Surgery he is constantly takes occasion to introduce that subject in his Anatomical
Lectures - And he never fails to mention any improvement he may have suggested in that branch <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Gore</unclear> is certainly more learned and independent than any in the school and
is perhaps a man of the deepest research - I have said he is the most independent I might have said intrepid - For
such</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_000060_000336_0002.jpg" xml:id="d3e254"/>
            <p>indeed he is He has <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">revived</unclear> the antiquated <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">doctoring</unclear> of the humoral pathology. To have intimated such an opinion - 
opposing as it does the writings of <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Cullen Davison</unclear> and all the
modern authors and the doctrine that has been taught in this school since its first institution requires no
ordinary degree of prowess - In justice to Dr. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Gore</unclear> I must
add that he does not carry the system to its extreme - I think he has indeed satisfactorily proved that the
rejection of that theory in toto was unwarranted - A student of the immortal Rush he very tenacious of the 
peculiarities of that great teacher - And in mentioning the applications of <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">remidies</unclear> he always recommends a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">successence</unclear>
to the Lancet - he often warns us like his preceptor not prescribe for the name but for the symptoms of the
disease - Dr <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">He</unclear> has taken nearly the same arrangement for his
lectures that <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Chapm</unclear> has in his <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">theraputics</unclear> - I say nearly for his first grand division differs - <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">He</unclear> divides the Materia Medica into two grand classes
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Sedantia &amp; Incitantia</unclear> - according very well with his
views and definition of health &amp; disease Health is what has been said of disease a unit consisting in
a harmony of <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">action</unclear> of all the parts of the animal
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">machine</unclear> - disease is but an excess or defect of this action
This is only a modification of Browns theory Dr. Gibson I hear with a great deal of interest and attention - his
remarks are always practical and he illucidates them by a selection of cases of which his extended experience gives
him a full supply - on wounds he is much more full and lengthy as well as in <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">absess</unclear> in which you wel know <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Dorsey&apos;s</unclear>
Surgery which is here called Physicks is very defective. The Students say that Dr <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Ham</unclear> the Lecturer on Chemistry is more proper than one that has preceeded him on that chair - 
He has given a new edition of <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Hansy</unclear> with notes by himself but I believe
his improvements are inconsiderable Doctor James lectures excite great attention and are certainly very instructive - Rush
&amp; Nisten are never mentioned in the Lecture rooms but with the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">brightest</unclear>
applause and sentiments of the deepest respect - The City was never healthier - the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Resurrection man</unclear> - My own health - (intensity of the weather) - <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Rather</unclear> be <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Hyh chandrenal</unclear> in <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">H.</unclear>
than in R - <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Formal for segument</unclear> - Dr. Ely - (attend
six lectures - takes notes <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Studium</unclear> give
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">coloms sommisum</unclear>) Present my warmest friendship
to all <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">&amp; send not </unclear> of your family &amp; accept
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">the as.</unclear> of my high respect &amp; esteem</p>
            <p>J. Ramsey</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
