<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000060_000338_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter, <name>Andrew Russell</name> in Abingdon, Va., to Francis A. Ramsey,
in Knox County, Tenn. <date when="1820-06-15">1820 June 15</date>
            </title>
            <author>
               <name type="person">Russell, Andrew, III</name>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>Dyson-Smith, Bridger</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_000060_000338_0000</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more information,
            contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special Collections
                Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Letter, Andrew Russell in Abingdon, Va., to Francis A. Ramsey in Knox County, Tenn. 1820 June 15</title>
               <date>1820-06-15</date>
               <author>
                  <name>Russell, Andrew, III</name>
               </author>
               <extent>4 digital images; 1 envelope, 3 pages</extent>
               <note type="abstract">1820 June 15 Andrew Russell, Abingdon, Va., to his new brother-in-law, Francis A. Ramsey, Knox County, Tenn.</note>
               <note type="collection">J.G.M. Ramsey Papers 1790-1869</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS.253</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee Libraries
                Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
                omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Family life -- Tennessee, East -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Travel -- Social aspects -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Abingdon (Va.) -- Description and travel -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Tennessee, East -- Social life and customs -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Russell, Andrew, III -- Correspondence.</term>
               <term>Ramsey, Francis A. (Francis Alexander), 1764-1820 -- Correspondence.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-10-02" who="bds">Migrating from
                XML to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter" xml:id="d3e152">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_000060_000338_0001.jpg" xml:id="d3e153"/>
            <p>For Dr <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">F.A.M.</unclear>
            </p>
            <p>Dec. 19, 1876 with Love</p>
            <p>of his Brother</p>
            <p>J.G.M.R.</p>
            <p>Colo. Francis A. Ramsey</p>
            <p>Knox County</p>
            <p>Tennessee</p>
            <p>mail</p>
            <p>They arrived last evening all well June 16 1820.</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_000060_000338_0002.jpg" xml:id="d3e180"/>
            <p>Abingdon June 15th 1820.</p>
            <p>Dear Sir,</p>
            <p>Your favor of the 24th <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">recd.</unclear> was handed to me on Tuesday
last by the Revd. Glenn who is now in our village or its vicinity - He informed me Mr. Saunders had gone to
Mr. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">McHenrys</unclear> Springs in the county of Scott where he would
spend some time. Should he call on me I will extend to him such civilities as I can.</p>
            <p>Altho I was not consulted either by my sister Margaret or yourself on the subject of your matrimonial union,
yet presuming that the match was founded on prudent considerations, as well as on pure conjugal affection, I
entertained from the first moment I heard it was intended, the strongest hopes that it was to be the means
of promoting the comfort &amp; happiness of you both, and also that of your families. I could not fail being
pleased, and therefore now tender to you as well as to my sister my sincere congratulations on an event, with
which I am persuaded you have both reason to be pleased - Be assured Sir, it affords me much pleasure to avail
myself of the present occasion, to acknowledge and receive you as a brother.</p>
            <pb n="3" facs="0012_000060_000338_0003.jpg" xml:id="d3e200"/>
            <p>Mrs. Russell and myself have experienced much anxiety for some time past waiting the arrival of our charming
Grand daughter together with her parents on a visit from Lynchburg - The last intelligence from them by letter
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">leaving</unclear> date on the first inst. informed us they then calculated
on leaving home on the Wednesday following, or at any rate within a day or two afterwards - My wife has grown
quite impatient that their arrival has been delayed so long - she has been looking for them since last Monday
evening. By the arrival of the Eastern Mail tomorrow we hope to hear from them should they not get here before. The
Grand daughter Frances Ann, and her mother will spend the summer with us, but her father will return in a few days
after they come, to Lynchburg, to attend to his business there.</p>
            <p>My friend Captain Craig, Mr. William Smith his son in law, and daughter Mrs. Hamilton and Harriett, started on
Tuesday last intending to go by the way of Jonesboro, Greensville and Dandridge to Knoxville to visit their friends
in Tennessee and may probably give you a call on their way. Mrs. Hamilton is one of my very particular female friends,
so is Mr. Smith and his lady. Should they call on you, I have no doubt you will find them</p>
            <pb n="4" facs="0012_000060_000338_0004.jpg" xml:id="d3e213"/>
            <p>quite agreeable - Harriett is remarkable for her literary acquirements and intelligence - Mr. Smith is a plain
genteel person, and quite sociable and agreeable - Should Sarah Craig conclude to travel for her health they can
afford her a convenient and easy mode of conveyance in Mr. Smiths carriage - It will give me pleasure to use any
means within my power to have Sarah restored to health again, and shall be happy to see her at my house. I expected
before this to have received a letter from my young friend Margaret <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Cowan</unclear>
 - I fear now she is determined not to write to me - Have I offended her - It is impossible - assure her if I
have that I did not intend it.</p>
            <p>I am Dear Sir your friend</p>
            <p>Andrew Russell</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>