<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_lite.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_001564_000205_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter, 
               <name type="author">Robert A. Ragan</name> near <name type="place">Greeneville, Tennessee</name>, to Emeline Ragan, 
               <date when="1863-10-29">1863 October 29</date>
            </title>
            <author>
               <name>Ragan, Robert A.</name>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>White, Park</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <availability status="restricted">
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
                  information, contact the Special Collections Library.</p>
            </availability>
            <idno>0012_001564_000205_0000</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Letter, 
                  <name type="author">Robert A. Ragan</name> <name type="place">Greeneville, Tennessee</name>, to Emeline Ragan, 
                  <date when="1863-10-29">1863 October 29</date>
               </title>
               <date when="1863-10-29">1863 October 29</date>
               <author>
                  <name>Ragan, Robert A.</name>
               </author>
               <extent>4 digital images</extent>
               <note type="collection">Robert A. Ragan Letters</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS.0743</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for The University of Tennessee Libraries
               Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Corrections have been applied to the text only where there is a high degree of
               certainty of an error and if the correct spelling is known.</p>
            <p>Corrections are represented by editorial tags.</p>
            <p>Quotation marks and apostrophes have been replaced by entity references.</p>
            <p>All unambiguous end-of-line hyphens have been removed.</p>
            <p>Names of persons, places, and organizations are indicated in the transcription when
               identifiable with a high degree of certainty.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Knoxville (Tenn.) -- History -- Siege, 1863.</term>
               <term>Soldiers -- Tennessee -- Correspondence.</term>
               <term>Tennessee -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.</term>
               <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Religious aspects.</term>
               <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-06-17" who="nl">Updated earlier transcription from the old TEI.2 system to anticipate and resolve difficulties and issues with re-formatting letters from this collection into TEI-P5 lite.</change>
         <change when="2013-07-15" who="nl">Added "idno" element, 
            editorial declaration statement, subjects/keywords and abstracts 
            from EAD finding aid. Removed box and folder notes, reference 
            declaration element. Changed the formatting for blank pages. 
            Added resp attributes to editorial changes, and added name 
            tags.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter" xml:id="d2e175">
            <pb facs="0012_001564_000205_0001.jpg" n="1" xml:id="d2e177"/>
            
            <opener>
               <dateline>Near
                  <choice><orig><name type="place">Greenville</name></orig><corr resp="pw"><name type="place">Greeneville</name></corr></choice>
                  <date when="1863-10-29">Oct. 29th 1863</date>
               </dateline>
               <salute>Dear Wife</salute>
            </opener>
            
            <p>I received Your letter this morning and I was glad to here from You but when you hear from me You will nodoubt be Surprised, I am now at at <name type="place"><choice><orig>Greenville</orig><corr resp="pw">Greeneville</corr></choice></name> or Near there we left <choice><orig><name type="place">Jonesboro</name></orig><corr resp="pw"><name type="place">Jonesborough</name></corr></choice> yesterday morning and we traveled 22 miles.  I am very near brake down.  I think we will go on down the Country I am afraid I am worse out of heart this morning than I have binn Sence this war began It is becaus we are going down the country  I am Sceard this morning I am a frade we will retreet back to <name type="place">Knoxville</name>  If we do then my trouble sets in  I dont want you to be troubled  You must bare It the best you can.</p>
            <p>I Could not help Shed tears when I red your letter  You no I will excuse you  I no you will write as often as you can  I wish you had bin home when Laura went up to</p>
            
            <pb facs="0012_001564_000205_0002.jpg" n="2" xml:id="d2e223"/>
            <p>See you: Jo Winters came up yesterday and Father came up Last Night  I begin to think I was not going to get any letter but debusk came this morning and brought me two letter for the first I have got but I was proud to get then you dont no how much good It done me to get a letter from you.  but I am afrad It is a going to be So I Cant hear from you, nor ya cant hear from me.  I was pond you sent me then things but I am a frade I cant get them things for you.</p>
            <p>Oh If I Could get to come home I would giv all this wourld If I had It but I cant come now I am coming when I toled Ya I would If not befor  but If there is any chance in the world I will com before that time.  do the best ya can I am <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">shops</unclear>we wont go far down the Coutry.  If we dont I will come  good by and write soon and as often as you can you <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">affetud</unclear>husband R A R</p>
            
            <pb facs="0012_001564_000205_0003.jpg" n="3" xml:id="d2e238"/>
            <p>If Jo Winters brings anything to William you send me something to Eat  Send me some Chees and butter  If we stay here I will bring that black boy home to sow my Wheat, and you get that corn from John Fresh.  I think If we stay here a few days I will come home and If we go on down the Country It will be doubteful.</p>
            <p>I will bring my few Lins to a close give my Respect to all of the familey</p>
            
            <closer>
               <salute>Your affectinat husband</salute>
               <signed>
                  <name>R A Ragan</name>
               </signed>
            </closer>
            
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
