<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000060_000262_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter, <name> J. Crozier Ramsey </name> in Nashville, Tenn., to J.G.M. Ramsey 
in Charlotte, N.C. <date when="1865-10-12"> 1865 October 12 </date>
            </title>
            <author>
               <name type="person">Ramsey, J. Crozier</name>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>Dyson-Smith, Bridger</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_000060_000262_0000</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more information,
            contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special Collections
                Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Letter, J. Crozier Ramsey in Nashville, Tenn., to J.G.M. Ramsey in Charlotte, N.C. 1865 Oct. 12</title>
               <date>1865-10-12</date>
               <author>
                  <name>Ramsey, J. Crozier</name>
               </author>
               <extent>5 digital images; 4 pages, 1 envelope</extent>
               <note type="abstract">1865 Oct. 12 J. Crozier Ramsey, Nashville, Tenn., to his father, J.G.M.
Ramsey, Charlotte, N.C. Informs his family that his case has been postponed
until the next term of the court in Knoxville. Explanation of why he did not
flee before his certain arrest. Relays news from Margaret Jane of happenings
in Knoxville. Discusses his hope of recovering J.G.M.&apos;s property for him. </note>
               <note type="collection">J.G.M. Ramsey Papers 1790-1869</note>
               <note type="manuscript">253</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee Libraries
                Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
                omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Court congestion and delay -- Tennessee -- Knoxville -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Right of property -- Tennessee -- Knoxville -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Business and politics -- Tennessee -- Knoxville -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Knoxville (Tenn.) -- Politics and government -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Ramsey, J. Crozier (John Crozier) d. 1868 -- Correspondence.</term>
               <term>Ramsey, J. G. M. (James Gettys McGready), 1797-1884 -- Correspondence.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-10-02" who="bds">Migrating from
                XML to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter" xml:id="d3e156">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_000060_000262_0001.jpg" xml:id="d3e157"/>
            <p>Dr J.G.M. Ramsey</p>
            <p>Charlotte</p>
            <p>N.C.</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_000060_000262_0002.jpg" xml:id="d3e169"/>
            <p>Nashville Ten Oct 12th</p>
            <p>Dear Sir</p>
            <p>I received your letter Mas and Lizzies a day or two ago and <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">posponed</unclear>
answering until I heard whether I would have to go to Knoxville I received this morning a letter from Uncle <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Dreadrick</unclear> stating that the Attorney General had agreed to have my cases continued
until the next Term of the Court waiving my appearance at this Term - So you see that I am released from taking the trip
I have so much dreaded. I have now not the slightest fears of my cases as all will be quiet at the the next Term of the Court
I will <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">flank</unclear> them badly</p>
            <pb n="3" facs="0012_000060_000262_0003.jpg" xml:id="d3e190"/>
            <p>when that time comes. All of my friends here when I was released advised me to leave on account of these cases. I knew that
I would in all probability be arrested - it mattered not where I would go and I disliked to be a fugitive from justice or rather
from persecution - I told my friends that I would have to meet the cases some time or nother and I might as well meet them now
as any other time - and while I appreciated their advice I had concluded to stand my ground and fight them out - I think I was
right about it. I received a letter from Margaret Jane a few days ago - she was well and things were more quiet - but a large
number of citizens were leaving - the Campbells</p>
            <pb n="4" facs="0012_000060_000262_0004.jpg" xml:id="d3e198"/>
            <p>of the Fork had to leave and a number of good Union men. As I am released for some time about my cases - I will now turn my
attention to the investigation of your property I would have liked very much to have examined the Records of your cases and to
have examined for myself the exact condition of yours and the rest of your childrens property - (for I have not yet understood
the condition of the cases to form a correct legal opinion of your defences or right to recover) this I can not do - but will
have to rely upon the opinion of other Lawyers I expect to write in a few days to Judge Brown and get him to examine correctly
all the principles involved in your cases and also to consult Col Nelson</p>
            <pb n="5" facs="0012_000060_000262_0005.jpg" xml:id="d3e206"/>
            <p>as to his opinion as to your right to recover - if they should think you can recover. I think they should be the proper ones
to undertake the business - as I have confidence in their judgment. If they think you can <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">recoversuits</unclear> should be instituted at once. I fear however that they will be long and tedious suits - but
still if their is any possibility of a recovery - it is worth a trial - Sneed has commenced suits for the recovery of his property - I
think his chances are better than yours - as the principles are different and on a better basis. I wrote you soon after my return
from Washington Did you get the letter - All are well at Uncle Williams - Love to all - will be pleased to hear from all of
you at any time</p>
            <p>Yours truly J.C. Ramsey</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>