<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_001560_000202_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>
               <name>Henry R. Pippitt </name>Diary, <date from="1865-01-01" to="1865-09-16">1865 January 1-September 16</date>
            </title>
            <author>
               <name type="person">Pippitt, Henry R.</name>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>Deane, Christine H.</name>
               <name>Dyson-Smith, Bridger</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_001560_000202_0000</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more information,
            contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special Collections
                Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Henry R. Pippitt Diary, 1865 January 1-September 16</title>
               <date>1865 January 1-September 16</date>
               <author>
                  <name>Pippitt, Henry R.</name>
               </author>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee Libraries
                Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
                omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Civil War Diaries</term>
               <term>Pippitt, Henry, 1842-1927--Diaries</term>
               <term>United States. Army. Ohio Infantry Regiment, 104th (1862-1865)
              Company G.</term>
               <term>United States. Army. Ohio Infantry Regiment, 104th (1862-1865) --
              Personal narratives.</term>
               <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Regimental
              histories.</term>
               <term>Ohio -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Regimental
              histories.</term>
               <term>Jordan, Thomas, 1819-1895.</term>
               <term>Sherman, William T. (William Tecumseh), 1820-1891.</term>
               <term>Fort Fisher (N.C.)--1860-1870.</term>
               <term>Fort Anderson (N.C.)</term>
               <term>Chesapeake Bay (Md. and Va.)</term>
               <term>Raleigh (N.C.)</term>
               <term>Greensboro (N.C.)</term>
               <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Blockades.</term>
               <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Naval
              operations.</term>
               <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Prisoners and
              prisons.</term>
               <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Military
              life.</term>
               <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Campaigns &amp;
              battles.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-10-03" who="bds">Migrating from
                XML to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="diary" xml:id="d4e167">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_001560_000202_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e171"/>
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_001560_000202_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e175"/>
            <p>Henry R. Pippitt. Comp. G 104th. Reg. O.U.J. Brig. 3rd Div. 23rd Army Co 2/03</p>
            
            <pb n="3" facs="0012_001560_000202_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e186"/>
            <p>Pocket Diary 1865. Willy Wallach, No. 43 John Street, New York</p>
            
            <pb n="4" facs="0012_001560_000202_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e197"/>
            <p>November 1865 December Moon Phases. A Table of Stamp Duties</p>
            
            <pb n="5" facs="0012_001560_000202_0005.jpg" xml:id="d4e208"/>
            <p>Stamp Duties</p>
            
            <pb n="5" facs="0012_001560_000202_0006.jpg" xml:id="d4e219"/>
            <p>Stamp Duties. A Table of Stamp Duties on Demand and Time Notes</p>
            
            <pb n="6" facs="0012_001560_000202_0006.jpg" xml:id="d4e230"/>
            <p>Rates of Postage. Sunday, January 1, 1865. In camp near Columbia. The day was clear and
          cold. Two inches of snow on the ground. Received orders to be ready to march. Did not
          march. The order was countermanded. Orders come at midnight to march at six Oclock in the
          morning</p>
            
            <pb n="7" facs="0012_001560_000202_0007.jpg" xml:id="d4e241"/>
            <p>Monday, January 2, 1865. Left Columbia this morning took the Mount Plesant Pike, marched
          about one mile South of town. The whole Dis<gap resp="Deane"/> forteen mile. Passed the residence of
          Reble Gen Polk who was woulned and killed on the Georgia Campaign. He was a Piscapalian
          and had a church on his own premises. Had a splendid residence and my thing to
          correspond</p>
            <p>Tuesday, January 3, 1865. Marched out from Camp near Mount Pleasant at daylight marched
          eight mile and stoped for dinner marched about six mile after dinner and camped for the
          night at four Oclock. Marched Southwest course all day on a bridle path through the
          woods</p>
            
            <pb n="8" facs="0012_001560_000202_0008.jpg" xml:id="d4e256"/>
            <p>Wednesday, January 4, 1865. Lay in Camp until two Oclock then drew rations and marched.
          Marched untill Ten Oclock at night; forded Buffalo creek three times water cold enough to
          freeze ice and over knee deep. Got into Camp plenty of nails and oats in the sheaf for a
          bed; go supples and got to bed by One Oclock. Distance marched about forteen miles</p>
            <p>Thursay, January 5, 1865. Resumed our march at eight Oclock in the morning marched until
          one Stoped and took dinner and then marched to Naynes Burro and Camped for the night. The
          country through which we marched was all a wild <unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">snep</unclear>. Had been considerable of Charcoal <unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">burntalm</unclear>. Sound future day. Dis marched Fifteen mile</p>
            
            <pb n="9" facs="0012_001560_000202_0009.jpg" xml:id="d4e275"/>
            <p>Friday, January 6, 1865. Left Haynesboro at nine Oclock in the morning. The 104th were
          train guards. Put all our baggage on the wagons. Rather a rough country through which we
          paped all timber land marched within three mile of the Tenn River and went into camp. Dis
          forteen mile</p>
            <p>Saturday, January 7, 1865. In Camp near the River. In the afternoon a detail was sent to
          Police a new Camp</p>
            
            <pb n="10" facs="0012_001560_000202_0010.jpg" xml:id="d4e288"/>
            <p>Sunday, January 8, 1865. Nine Oclock we moved camp about one eight of a mile fixed up a
          good bunk of lumber. No preaching today To much <unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">businefs</unclear> on hand</p>
            <p>Monday, January 9, 1865. In Camp. It is a very wet and disagreeable day. The Transports
          are shipping traspo to East Point Mississippi as fast as transportation can be
          furnished</p>
            
            <pb n="11" facs="0012_001560_000202_0011.jpg" xml:id="d4e304"/>
            <p>Tuesday, January 10, 1865. Still in Camp a Squal of twenty five men returned which had
          been sent out to rescue some of our Boys which wer lost and could not get to Camp on
          account of the guirrilla. They found two the other three wer killed or wounded. The squad
          wer fired into none hurt. Returned to Camp all safe</p>
            <p>Wednesday, January 11, 1865. In Camp at Clifton Tenn All quiet</p>
            
            <pb n="12" facs="0012_001560_000202_0012.jpg" xml:id="d4e317"/>
            <p>Thursday, January 12, 1865. Nothing of interest transpired to day</p>
            <p>Friday, January 13, 1865. To day Leander Barnaby and I went a forageing got one boy
          weighing about one hundred</p>
            
            <pb n="13" facs="0012_001560_000202_0013.jpg" xml:id="d4e330"/>
            <p>Saturday, January 14, 1865. To day I went a squirrel hunting had a gay time but did not
          get but one squirrel</p>
            <p>Sunday, January 15, 1865. In Camp at Clifton Tenn. All quiet religious services to day by
          the Chaplain</p>
            
            <pb n="14" facs="0012_001560_000202_0014.jpg" xml:id="d4e343"/>
            <p>Monday, January 16, 1865. To day I went a squirrel hunting. About eight Oclock we struck
          tents went to the River and got aboard of the Swallow where we lay until day light</p>
            <p>Tuesday, January 17, 1865. At day light we pulled out. Rain all night and reached
            <unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">Pedwele</unclear> day light. Passed Fort Henry
          distance from the march of the Tenn to Pedwele two hundred mile. Took passage on the
          Swallow</p>
            
            <pb n="15" facs="0012_001560_000202_0015.jpg" xml:id="d4e359"/>
            <p>Wednesday, January 18, 1865. Left Pedwele at day light. Reached Evansville at day light
          of the 19th</p>
            <p>Thursday, January 19, 1865. Left Evansville about eight Oclock. Passed where they fired
          three Salutes and we responded three cheers for the Hoosiers</p>
            
            <pb n="16" facs="0012_001560_000202_0016.jpg" xml:id="d4e373"/>
            <p>Friday, January 20, 1865. Reached Lousiville about dary. Did not stop pushed on for
          Cincinatti</p>
            <p>Saturday, January 21, 1865. Reached Cincinatti at dark but there was to much fog could
          not land. Lay on the Boat all night</p>
            
            <pb n="17" facs="0012_001560_000202_0017.jpg" xml:id="d4e386"/>
            <p>Sunday, January 22, 1865. Left Cincinatti at one Oclock took the Daton and Hamilton road.
          Corp Kennedy deserted us in Cincinnati this 22nd of Jan 1865</p>
            <p>Monday, January 23, 1865. Left Newark at Seven Oclock passed Jamesville. Reached Ballair
          at midnight and <unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">crufsed</unclear> the river.
          Plenty of coffee ready made where we got on the side</p>
            
            <pb n="18" facs="0012_001560_000202_0018.jpg" xml:id="d4e402"/>
            <p>Tuesday, January 24, 1865. Got on the Baltimore and Ohio roads at <unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">Benarwrun</unclear> to Grafton got that coffee the
          weather is very cold</p>
            <p>Wednesday, January 25, 1865. To day we run to Cumberlan where we got hot coffee and soft
          bread</p>
            
            <pb n="19" facs="0012_001560_000202_0019.jpg" xml:id="d4e418"/>
            <p>Thursday, January 26, 1865. We came into Martins Burgh at two Oclock in the morning got
          hot coffee and soft bread come through Harpers ferry, which is situated at the foot of the
          Maryland Hights. Reached Washington about nine Oclock at night. Got our suppers at the
          soldiers nest and put in barrucks for the night</p>
            <p>Friday, January 27, 1865. Got breakfast at the Soldiers nest as soon as breakfast over I
          went to the Capital was over the principle past of the building we then left the city and
          went to camp stoneman and went into Barracks</p>
            
            <pb n="20" facs="0012_001560_000202_0020.jpg" xml:id="d4e431"/>
            <p>Saturday, January 28, 1865. In the Barracks the three company that wer on another Boat
          come up to day we are laying side of some of Hancocks veterans, who are a little to strict
          to be decent</p>
            <p>Sunday, January 29, 1865. In Stoneman Barracks Stroch Woolmen come to the city to take
          John Moore home and culled around to Lee the Butlar Boys</p>
            
            <pb n="21" facs="0012_001560_000202_0021.jpg" xml:id="d4e444"/>
            <p>Monday, January 30, 1865. To day I went to the city First went to Navy Yard and from
          there to the Capital and from there to the Patent Office. The day passed to quick I longed
          for the <gap resp="Deane"/> to be a week. I see Enoch Woolmen who was clever enough to lend me some
          money</p>
            <p>Tuesday, January 31, 1865. Left Camp Stoneman at 8 oclock passed through Washing City
          crossed the Potomac and reached Alexand about two Oclock. Lay on the commons until sun set
          and then went to the convalescent home barracks where we lay for the night</p>
            
            <pb n="22" facs="0012_001560_000202_0022.jpg" xml:id="d4e459"/>
            <p>Wednesday, February 1, 1865. Encamped in the Connel moved the Horse out and the 104 and
          16th Ky. took there places. The weathe is cole But the Tug Boats keep the Channel of the
          River open</p>
            <p>Thursday, February 2, 1865. To day I was over Alexander there are a great many hard wamer
          live there Still in the Hors stabbles. I was to see John Moore but he left yesterday and
          went to Washington en rout for home</p>
            
            <pb n="23" facs="0012_001560_000202_0023.jpg" xml:id="d4e472"/>
            <p>Friday, February 3, 1865. To day we left the Conel and got aboard of The Steamer called
          the Star of the South lay at the wharf all night</p>
            <p>Saturday, February 4, 1865. Pulled out from the wharf at four Oclock in the morning just
          before leaving one of Co B of 100 was shot dead while a sleep on deck. It was a glancing
          shot from the wharf Sailed until dark and for the night. Anchored about 20 mile from the
          mouth of the Potomac River</p>
            
            <pb n="24" facs="0012_001560_000202_0024.jpg" xml:id="d4e485"/>
            <p>Sunday, February 5, 1865. Still sailing to day we are in Chesapeak Bay some of the Boys
          are sea sick. Reached Fortres Monroe at dusk cast anchor out in the Stream</p>
            <p>Monday, February 6, 1865. Drew anchor at day light and continued our journey. Passed
          Albamoral and Paniev Sounds and Cape Hatteras. The sea was very rough many of the Boys are
          sick</p>
            
            <pb n="25" facs="0012_001560_000202_0025.jpg" xml:id="d4e498"/>
            <p>Tuesday, February 7, 1865. This morning it is Stormy and the sea is very rough. The whole
          reg was sick. I never felt so disagreeable in my life. Our Captain get lost on account of
          a heavy fog. The sea was saw so high that we wer abliged to lay out at Sea all day and at
          dusk we cast anchor</p>
            <p>Wednesday, February 8, 1865. Lay out at Sea all day. The Scoonners wer busily engaged in
          landing Portions of our Camps but we did not get off wer ordered three different times to
          land but countermanded each time</p>
            
            <pb n="26" facs="0012_001560_000202_0026.jpg" xml:id="d4e511"/>
            <p>Thursday, February 9, 1865. This mornign we changed boats twice before landing. After
          landing we passed Fort Fisher. Captured Eighty-six large guns beside a number of small
          guns. One two hundred lb Armstrong gun mounted on mahogany was presented to the Rebles by
          the Brittish blockade runners. Our men captured some twenty five hundred prisoners. Gen.
          Terry <unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">Comdg</unclear> the land forces and Poster
          the Fleets</p>
            <p>Friday, February 10, 1865. To day we are laying in Camp on <unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">Cafse</unclear> fear River. I went to take a Stroll over Fort Fisher which
          fell on the 15th of Jan 1865. I see one of Armstrongs guns mounted on mahogany carriage a
          one hundred and fifity lb presented to the Rebles by the Brittish blockade runners. They
          had one of Robisons and Cottum make London. It shoots one hundred and twenty to times. A
          britch lauding sifted gun and not over <unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">fans</unclear> feet long</p>
            
            <pb n="27" facs="0012_001560_000202_0027.jpg" xml:id="d4e534"/>
            <p>Saturday, February 11, 1865. To day the 1st Brig went out in a Resognoiter moved about
          one mile, lay all day and camped there for the night</p>
            <p>Sunday, February 12, 1865. Lay still until noon then went to the landing and drew three
          days rations got back at dusk. Struck tents and went five miles up the coast with the
          prospect of cropping an Inlet, but did not crop could not lay the Pontoons came back to
          our old Camp about Eleven Oclock at night</p>
            
            <pb n="28" facs="0012_001560_000202_0028.jpg" xml:id="d4e547"/>
            <p>Monday, February 13, 1865. Lay in Camp, no demonstrations made during the day. All quiet
          at night. Maj Gen Whitting was comdg and had been for four years at Fort Fisher, he was
          wounded and afterwards surrendered the Fort. The Armstrong gun weighed fifteen thous
          <gap resp="Deane"/> and seven hundred and thirty seven pounds and cost $13,000 in gold</p>
            <p>Tuesday, February 14, 1865. Went to the landing distance four miles and drew rations
          Issued them to the men at the landing come back and at dark struck tents and went up to
          the Inlet but did not offset a crossing. Returned to our old camp it being two Oclock in
          the morning</p>
            
            <pb n="29" facs="0012_001560_000202_0029.jpg" xml:id="d4e562"/>
            <p>Wednesday, February 15, 1865. Did not get up until half past eleven and would not of then
          but the water run in our tent three inches deep. In the afternoon I went to the river
          where they wer swimming. One draw they caught ten bushel. I got enough for supper</p>
            <p>Thursday, February 16, 1865. Struck tents at Eight Oclock marched down to the landing got
          aboard the Eliza Hancock and went down the river eight mile to Smithville and landed
          camped there for the night; I went for oysters got a fine mep of them. Received a letter
          from Jo Ray, Is at Jefferson Hospital had had a rough time with the gangrene in his leg
          but is doing well now</p>
            
            <pb n="30" facs="0012_001560_000202_0030.jpg" xml:id="d4e575"/>
            <p>Friday, February 17, 1865. Left Smithville at Eight Oclock in the morning advanced some
          six mile in the direction of fort Anderson before we come to the Reble outpost. Our forces
          drove them some two miles then camped for the night putting up works. A little firing from
          our gun boats at Fort Anderson</p>
            <p>Saturday, February 18, 1865. To day we moved out one mile to the front and found the
          Rebles fortified and artillery in position. We then went back to the rear and took another
          road to get their flank. We advanced some three miles, come to gum Swamp where the Rebs
          wer fortified on the opposite. Our Reg charged half of it on skirmish and the balance
          supporting Lt. Reid and Snider of Co. J wer slightly wounded. Serg Gibbons Co. A wounded
          and Heammand Co E killed, Orderly Co. J wounded</p>
            
            <pb n="31" facs="0012_001560_000202_0031.jpg" xml:id="d4e588"/>
            <p>Sunday, February 19, 1865. Drew rations and at noon marched and at night camped some five
          miles north of Fort Anderson. The Rebles evacuated fort Anderson the night before at
          twelve Oclock leaving eleven guns</p>
            <p>Monday, February 20, 1865. Left camp at sunrise moved to the right and turned the Rebs
          flank. Closed in on them and at sunset charged them taking four hundred and thirty
          prisoners and two peices of artilery.Co C. lost eleven in all. H. Six and one killed. G.
          two slight : Co. K one. Camped for the night on the Spot. Captured a boat-load of sweete
          potatoes and hard cider</p>
            
            <pb n="32" facs="0012_001560_000202_0032.jpg" xml:id="d4e601"/>
            <p>Tuesday, February 21, 1865. A Company of the 177 took the prisoners to fort Anderson an
          dour command moved on toward Wilmington moved some five mile put up works and camped for
          the night. At two Oclock in the morning packed up marched back three mile about faced and
          came back and went to bed. It wa five Oclock AM slept until morning</p>
            <p>Wednesday, February 22, 1865. To day Colonel Jordon wa appointed Provost marshall of the
          City of Wilmington and the 104th to do Provost duty. We crossed Cape fear river and passed
          into the City the Band struck up Yankee doodle. The streets wer crowded with citizens and
          danys. We went to the outskirts of town and we out into barracks. There eight of our men
          prisoners here who starved to death and two who are just alive.</p>
            
            <pb n="33" facs="0012_001560_000202_0033.jpg" xml:id="d4e614"/>
            <p>Thursday, February 23, 1865. To day one busy cleaning up the Barrack</p>
            <p>Friday, February 24, 1865. To day I went a fishing. Rather a poor day for fishing did not
            <unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">cuth</unclear> any</p>
            
            <pb n="34" facs="0012_001560_000202_0034.jpg" xml:id="d4e630"/>
            <p>Saturday, February 25, 1865. Nothing of interest going on</p>
            <p>Sunday, February 26, 1865. All quiet to day. We sighed the pay roller to day</p>
            
            <pb n="35" facs="0012_001560_000202_0035.jpg" xml:id="d4e643"/>
            <p>Monday, February 27, 1865. All quiet to day. This Evening Bill Kelly come to see Kink
          Whitoose and myself. He has been a prisoner for 8 months and just been <unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">pasalld</unclear> almost naked for the want of
          clothes</p>
            <p>Tuesday, February 28, 1865. To day we wer mustered for two months more pay. Escaped and
          paroled prisoners are coming in continually</p>
            
            <pb n="36" facs="0012_001560_000202_0036.jpg" xml:id="d4e659"/>
            <p>Wednesday, March 1, 1865. To day we received four months pay. Bunny Kink called to see
          son today was paroled</p>
            <p>Thursday, March 2, 1865. All moving off lively. Still doing duty in Wilmington</p>
            
            <pb n="37" facs="0012_001560_000202_0037.jpg" xml:id="d4e672"/>
            <p>Friday, March 3, 1865. This is the last days duty in Wilmington are to be releaved by the
          24th. Corps to night we had a dance at our Barracks. Had a gay time all to our selvs. Two
          fiddlers and a banjo picker</p>
            <p>Saturday, March 4, 1865. This morning we wer releaved and croped the Wilmington and
          Weldon R.R. and Camped Schofield <unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">comdgs</unclear>the Dept Couch the Corps, reilly the Dive and Cocks Military goo of
          N.C</p>
            
            <pb n="38" facs="0012_001560_000202_0038.jpg" xml:id="d4e689"/>
            <p>Sunday, March 5, 1865. To day we drew five days rations and have orders to get ready for
          the front. Duke got into a fight go stabbed not able to go with</p>
            <p>Monday, March 6, 1865. Left Camp at 8 Oclock marched 15 mile in the direction of Newburn
          and camped for the night. Sterl Comdgs the Brig</p>
            
            <pb n="39" facs="0012_001560_000202_0039.jpg" xml:id="d4e702"/>
            <p>Tuesday, March 7, 1865. Marched at day light; went 15 mile and camped for the night very
          little open country. Mostly pure forest</p>
            <p>Wednesday, March 8, 1865. Left camp at seven Oclock marched twelve and camped for the
          night. It rained the greater part of the afternoon</p>
            
            <pb n="40" facs="0012_001560_000202_0040.jpg" xml:id="d4e715"/>
            <p>Thursday, March 9, 1865. The 16th Ky and our Reg was on train guard. It rained part of
          the day did not get to camp until one Oclock wading mud and water all day and as soon as
          we reached camp got orders to issue one days rations and march at five Oclock. I did not
          get to sleep any</p>
            <p>Friday, March 10, 1865. Left camp at five Oclock, mud and water ankle deepe all day, went
          into camp about four Oclock. At ten drew rations and be ready to march at two. No sleep
          for me this night</p>
            
            <pb n="41" facs="0012_001560_000202_0041.jpg" xml:id="d4e728"/>
            <p>Saturday, March 11, 1865. Pulled out at two Oclock marched some two mile and come to a
          large stream waded it and went on mud and water knee deep; About as rough marching as we
          ever done. This night we form a junction with Gen Cox near Kingston</p>
            <p>Sunday, March 12, 1865. To day we moved some two mile and camped. Camp any G went on
          picket. All quiet</p>
            
            <pb n="42" facs="0012_001560_000202_0042.jpg" xml:id="d4e741"/>
            <p>Monday, March 13, 1865. Lay still in Camp our company was relieved at four Oclock. The
          Boys are bring in plenty of forage such as pork and <gap resp="Deane"/>
            </p>
            <p>Tuesday, March 14, 1865. Orders to move at 8 Oclock marched two mile and camped a detail
          was sent to get out ties for the Rail road</p>
            
            <pb n="43" facs="0012_001560_000202_0043.jpg" xml:id="d4e755"/>
            <p>Wednesday, March 15, 1865. Pulled out at five Oclock went to the river one mile and
          camped. It rained very hard</p>
            <p>Thursday, March 16, 1865. Lay in camp near the Neuse R<gap resp="Deane"/>. The Boys are not relieved
          that went to get out ties</p>
            
            <pb n="44" facs="0012_001560_000202_0044.jpg" xml:id="d4e770"/>
            <p>Friday, March 17, 1865. Still in Camp on the Banks of the Neuse River. The Boys are a
          getting out ties for the R. R.</p>
            <p>Saturday, March 18. 1865. To day we had inspection, all went off smooth</p>
            
            <pb n="45" facs="0012_001560_000202_0045.jpg" xml:id="d4e783"/>
            <p>Sunday, March 19, 1865. Preaching at Ten Oclock. Three vessals came up the river to day
          loaded with rations</p>
            <p>Monday, March 20, 1865. To day we marched twelve mile toward Galesborro and camped for
          the night</p>
            
            <pb n="46" facs="0012_001560_000202_0046.jpg" xml:id="d4e796"/>
            <p>Tuesday, March 21, 1865. Marched at 7 Oclock marched all day and until two oclock next
          morning when we reached Galesborro went to bed</p>
            <p>Wednesday, March 22, 1865. Did not get up until ten Oclock got dinner and then moved camp
          west of town and put up works 12 ft at the base and 9 at the top worked all knight. Henry
          C Wisner of Co G. died at Wilmington this date</p>
            
            <pb n="47" facs="0012_001560_000202_0047.jpg" xml:id="d4e809"/>
            <p>Thursday, March 23, 1865. Lay still in camp. Sherman made conection with us to day his
          army are passing into town</p>
            <p>Friday, March, 24, 1865. In camp. To day the 17th Corps came into town all quiet to the
          front</p>
            
            <pb n="48" facs="0012_001560_000202_0048.jpg" xml:id="d4e822"/>
            <p>Saturday, March 25, 1865. Nothing transpired of importance; wer lively putting in pickets
          in front of our works</p>
            <p>Sunday, March 26, 1865. In Camp at Goldsboro N.C. nothing of interest going on</p>
            
            <pb n="49" facs="0012_001560_000202_0049.jpg" xml:id="d4e836"/>
            <p>Monday, March 27, 1865. In camp behind our works</p>
            <p>Tuesday, March 28, 1865. All quiet went down to the Neuse River and took a canoe and
          paddled up and down the river a fishing</p>
            
            <pb n="50" facs="0012_001560_000202_0050.jpg" xml:id="d4e849"/>
            <p>Wednesday, March 29, 1865. All quiet to day at the front</p>
            <p>Thursday, March 30, 1865. To day one of the 12 New York Calvary was shot for commiting a
          rape on an elderly lady at Kinston NC. Drew five days rations came the 30th</p>
            
            <pb n="51" facs="0012_001560_000202_0051.jpg" xml:id="d4e862"/>
            <p>Friday, March 31, 1865. In camp all quiet commenced drilling 3 hours a day</p>
            <p>Saturday, April 1, 1865. In camp; no drill an <unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">Liutus</unclear> day</p>
            
            <pb n="52" facs="0012_001560_000202_0052.jpg" xml:id="d4e878"/>
            <p>Sunday, April 2, 1865. In camp church at two Oclock</p>
            <p>Monday, April 3, 1865. There is a revival in town having a pretty good time</p>
            
            <pb n="53" facs="0012_001560_000202_0053.jpg" xml:id="d4e891"/>
            <p>Tuesday, April 4, 1865. Regular drill nothing of importance transpired. Rec four Recruits
          all but Cap <unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">Faweets</unclear> some are strangers.
          Their names are as follows, Griswold Hall, Christian Fawsett and Dillion. JW Derr returned
          from the Hosp. Wm Davis died at Beuford N, C, this day. Richman fell</p>
            <p>Wednesday, April 5, 1865. All quiet to day. Regular drill at the usual hours. H.
          Greenswalt returned from Hosp</p>
            
            <pb n="54" facs="0012_001560_000202_0054.jpg" xml:id="d4e907"/>
            <p>Thursday, April 6, 1865. Rec the news of the fall of Richmond. Great cheering and
          rejoicing generly</p>
            <p>Friday, April 7, 1865. Griswold went to the Hospital. The Officers are on a small drunk
          over the fall of Richmond</p>
            
            <pb n="55" facs="0012_001560_000202_0055.jpg" xml:id="d4e920"/>
            <p>Saturday, April 8, 1865. To day Wm Dubbs come up from the hospital was wounded in the
          hand at a change made at Fawn Creek N. C. Feb 20th Great rejoicing generly throwing rocket
          and the Boys are making all noise imaginable a shooting and</p>
            <p>Sunday, April 9, 1865. All quiet to day. Preaching on the camp ground. Aaron Moore come
          up to the Co from Kingston Tenn. Was detaile as Div wagon master. Gen Lee surrendered to
          Grant. Conditions wer stuck arms park trains and artillery. Pare the men and officers.
          Officers keepe their side arms</p>
            
            <pb n="56" facs="0012_001560_000202_0056.jpg" xml:id="d4e933"/>
            <p>Monday, April 10, 1865. This morning Shermans whole army moves for the front. Our Brigade
          moved ½ a mile and then wer sent back to camp to guard the train. Lay in camp for the
          nights was up town. Hope I may never forget the 10th of April</p>
            <p>Tuesday, April 11, 1865. Rec orders to march at six Oclock but did not leave camp until
          noon wer waiting for the train. The 1st Brig are train guards moved five miles in the
          direction of Raleigh and camped for the night. Rec a letter from home all well </p>
            
            <pb n="57" facs="0012_001560_000202_0057.jpg" xml:id="d4e946"/>
            <p>Wednesday, April 12, 1865. Still guarding the train. Marched some seven and camped with
          the train for the night. A dispatch came to us that Lee had surrendered his Army. Cheers </p>
            <p>Thursday, April 13, 1865. Marched along with the train. Croped the Neuse River on
          pontoons (the river being burnt) and camped for the night. Gen Lees surrender was
          confirmed by a dispatch from Gen Sherman. Drew three days rations</p>
            
            <pb n="58" facs="0012_001560_000202_0058.jpg" xml:id="d4e959"/>
            <p>Friday, April 14, 1865. Left the banks of the Neuse river on train guard marched some
          fifteen miles and camped for the <gap resp="Deane"/> The Rebs dashed on the train cut loos the mules of
          16 wagons and burnt three. We <unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">cupd</unclear> two
          of the Rebs. Pres Lincoln was shot at Fords Theater W, DC at half ten and died about ten
          the next day</p>
            <p>Saturday, April 15, 1865. Left camp early in the morning wer in advance of the Brig and
          train. Reached Raleigh about five Oclock. Our advance is pushing Johnson <unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">clustly</unclear>
            </p>
            
            <pb n="59" facs="0012_001560_000202_0059.jpg" xml:id="d4e979"/>
            <p>Sunday April 16, 1865. Camped at the outskirts of town. Sherman and Johnson are
          communicating together</p>
            <p>Monday April 17, 1865. Sherman and Johnson are still communicating together. To day the
          news of Lincoln’s death reached the Army. The authorities put on a heavy guard to Keepe
          the Soldiers from destroying Raleigh</p>
            
            <pb n="60" facs="0012_001560_000202_0060.jpg" xml:id="d4e993"/>
            <p>Tuesday April 18, 1865. To day we moved camp to the North side of Raleigh and prospects
          bid fair for us to remain here until we start home</p>
            <p>Wednesday April 19, 1865. Fixing up in camp all pickets wer with drawen to day at three
          Oclock and Hostilities have ceased. The daily standard came out in mourning for President
          Lincoln</p>
            
            <pb n="61" facs="0012_001560_000202_0061.jpg" xml:id="d4e1006"/>
            <p>Thursday April 20, 1865. Laying in camp near Raleigh N. C. preparing for a review by
          Sherman tomorrow. At this time our Navy consists of six hundred and eighty three. Sixty
          four Iron Clads have been added in this past year</p>
            <p>Friday April 21, 1865. To day the 23rd Corps was reviewed by Gen Sherman. They made a
          fine display on the Streets of Raleigh</p>
            
            <pb n="62" facs="0012_001560_000202_0062.jpg" xml:id="d4e1019"/>
            <p>Saturday April 22, 1865. This morning our Reg met for the purpose of Ellecting
          Representatives to nominate Delegates to the State Convention. Lm Shafer and Clark of Co
          F. wer ellected. The 20th Corps was reviewed and played the past of good soldiers. I went
          in the afternoon to visit the deaf dumb and blind asylum. It was interesting to see them
            <unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">secite</unclear>
            </p>
            <p>Sunday April 23, 1865. Nothing of interest. C. L. Heaton came back to the company just
          from home</p>
            
            <pb n="63" facs="0012_001560_000202_0063.jpg" xml:id="d4e1034"/>
            <p>Monday April 24, 1865. In camp near Raleigh all quiet</p>
            <p>Tuesday April 25, 1865. Received orders to march at six this morning, was countermanded
          and all quiet</p>
            
            <pb n="64" facs="0012_001560_000202_0064.jpg" xml:id="d4e1047"/>
            <p>Wednesday April 26, 1865. In camp All quiet</p>
            <p>Thursday April 27, 1865. In camp at Raleigh NC All quiet</p>
            
            <pb n="65" facs="0012_001560_000202_0065.jpg" xml:id="d4e1060"/>
            <p>Friday April 28, 1865. No news of interest. Shermans Army consisting of the 20, 14, 15
          and 17th Cosps left Raleigh for Richmond</p>
            <p>Saturday April 29, 1865. All quiet. Nothing of Interest</p>
            
            <pb n="66" facs="0012_001560_000202_0066.jpg" xml:id="d4e1073"/>
            <p>Sunday April 30, 1865. Wer mustered to day for two months more pay</p>
            <p>Monday May 1, 1865. Still at Raleigh</p>
            
            <pb n="67" facs="0012_001560_000202_0067.jpg" xml:id="d4e1086"/>
            <p>Tuesday May 2, 1865. Left Raleigh at 7 Oclock this morning for Greensboro arrived about
          four Oclock. Many of Johnson Army met us at the Station some of them seem to be in a good
          humor and others wer very <unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">cously</unclear> Camped
          near the Station for the night our guards relieved the Reble guards immediately</p>
            <p>Wednesday May 3, 1865. Moved camp in to a grove. The <unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">9BBJ</unclear> came from Raleigh to help garrison the place; all passes off
          quietly and Rebles are as thick as flys in August</p>
            
            <pb n="68" facs="0012_001560_000202_0068.jpg" xml:id="d4e1105"/>
            <p>Thursday May 4, 1865. Paroling is going on speedily and one train load after another are
          leaving all goes on quietly. The Rebs are a sore set of people</p>
            <p>Friday May 5, 1865. More troops arriving constantly. Citizens both men and women come for
          miles to see the Yankees seem much pleased</p>
            
            <pb n="69" facs="0012_001560_000202_0069.jpg" xml:id="d4e1118"/>
            <p>Saturday May 6, 1865. The <unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">ralonn</unclear> come
          came from Raleigh to day, Kilpatericks command come in. I see Andy Seall from Laudonville
          had quite a confab with him</p>
            <p>Sunday May 7, 1865. The balance of the 1st Brigade come up to day. The weather is very
          warm preaching to day</p>
            
            <pb n="70" facs="0012_001560_000202_0070.jpg" xml:id="d4e1134"/>
            <p>Monday May 8, 1865. The Brig moved camp the 104th are detached and doing duty in
          Greensboro. The weather is very warm and every thing is in full bloom</p>
            <p>Tuesday May 9, 1865. To day we moved camp to a grove on the outskirts of town. I made a
          purchase of 9 ½ yd of Reble cloth and two reble blankets </p>
            
            <pb n="71" facs="0012_001560_000202_0071.jpg" xml:id="d4e1148"/>
            <p>Wednesday May 10, 1865. D C Boutwell and E. S. Kentner returned from Wilmington to the
          Company. No good feeling in the Co toward him. Colonel Pritchard of the fourth <unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">michcun</unclear> with 130 men captured. Jeff Davis near
          Irwinsville Irwins Co Georgia. Mrs Davis remarked to Col Hardens after the excitement was
          over that the men had better not pranke the Pres or he might hurt some of em</p>
            <p>Thursday May 11, 1865. Doing duty in Greensboro. The Citizens like the Reg very well and
          desire that we may remain</p>
            
            <pb n="72" facs="0012_001560_000202_0072.jpg" xml:id="d4e1164"/>
            <p>Friday May 12, 1865. Was up town to guard mounting. The Reg make a fine display</p>
            <p>Saturday May 13, 1865. all quiet in camp nothing of interest transpired during the
          day</p>
            
            <pb n="73" facs="0012_001560_000202_0073.jpg" xml:id="d4e1177"/>
            <p>Sunday May 14, 1865. Regular guard mount. Dress parade quite a contrast to what took
          place one year ago to day the battle of Resacea</p>
            <p>Monday May 15, 1865. All quiet. The Reg had Dress parade</p>
            
            <pb n="74" facs="0012_001560_000202_0074.jpg" xml:id="d4e1190"/>
            <p>Tuesday May 16, 1865. In camp nothing of interest transpired</p>
            <p>Wednesday May 17, 1865. Drew rations for five days. All quiet</p>
            
            <pb n="75" facs="0012_001560_000202_0075.jpg" xml:id="d4e1203"/>
            <p>Thursday May 18, 1865. All quiet. Doing Provost duty in Greensboro</p>
            <p>Friday May 19, 1865. Colonel Jordon put a guard acrop the road to prevent the Boys from
          town most of the Reg went went to town for spite</p>
            
            <pb n="76" facs="0012_001560_000202_0076.jpg" xml:id="d4e1216"/>
            <p>Saturday May 20, 1865. All quiet to day. The Reg drew clothing</p>
            <p>Sunday May 21, 1865. Sunday Inspection at one Oclock. Jordon still comes down on the Boys
          for going to town</p>
            
            <pb n="77" facs="0012_001560_000202_0077.jpg" xml:id="d4e1229"/>
            <p>Monday May 22, 1865. Ration day drew for five days</p>
            <p>Tuesday May 23, 1865. Nothing of interest. The citizens are beginning to bring in produce
          cherries and everything seem to be in a proper condition</p>
            
            <pb n="78" facs="0012_001560_000202_0078.jpg" xml:id="d4e1242"/>
            <p>Wednesday May 24, 1865. All is quiet. Nothing of interest</p>
            <p>Thursday May 25, 1865. The assassins of Pres Lincoln are now being tried at Washington
          City. There wer one couple <unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">murrice</unclear> in
          Greensboro this night. The guards preserved order</p>
            
            <pb n="79" facs="0012_001560_000202_0079.jpg" xml:id="d4e1258"/>
            <p>Friday May 26, 1865. A picknick a couple of miles from town the Band are in attendance.
          Rained greater part of the day and stormed very hard in the night</p>
            <p>Saturday May 27, 1865. The weather is very gloomy and cold. All kind of grapevine rumors
          afloat in regard to our going home</p>
            
            <pb n="80" facs="0012_001560_000202_0080.jpg" xml:id="d4e1271"/>
            <p>Sunday May 28, 1865. Clear day all quiet. Church at 2 Oclock by our Chaplains</p>
            <p>Monday May 29, 1865. Nothing of interest. Done my weeks washing to day</p>
            
            <pb n="81" facs="0012_001560_000202_0081.jpg" xml:id="d4e1284"/>
            <p>Tuesday May 30, 1865. All quiet. Nothing of interest. David O Boutwell died at the 3rd
          Div Hospital to day buried this Eve at five Oclock</p>
            <p>Wednesday May 31, 1865. To day is ration day drew rations for five day</p>
            
            <pb n="82" facs="0012_001560_000202_0082.jpg" xml:id="d4e1298"/>
            <p>Thursday June 1, 1865. Mer Thomas and myself went to Friendship to a Union Military a
          distance of ten mile all poped off quietly</p>
            <p>Friday June 2, 1865. Returned to camp about ten Oclock was very tired. Jack Cosemain and
          wife are here. He (Cosemain) is running for Lt Governor of Ohio his friends are few and
          far between in the 104 <unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">O U J</unclear>
            </p>
            
            <pb n="83" facs="0012_001560_000202_0083.jpg" xml:id="d4e1313"/>
            <p>Saturday June 3, 1865. Wm Widdoes returned to the Co has been home on furlough</p>
            <p>Sunday June 4, 1865. Church to day at two Oclock. Nothing of interest</p>
            
            <pb n="84" facs="0012_001560_000202_0084.jpg" xml:id="d4e1326"/>
            <p>Monday June 5, 1865. Drew five days rations. The commanders are busy makes my clothing
          returns and many rumors about going home</p>
            <p>Tuesday June 6, 1865. All quiet in camp</p>
            
            <pb n="85" facs="0012_001560_000202_0085.jpg" xml:id="d4e1339"/>
            <p>Wednesday June 7, 1865. The Boys played out taking knapsack to town on guard. Jordon sent
          them back to get them put two men under arrest</p>
            <p>Thursday June 8, 1865. This morning the Boys all come out without Knapsacks</p>
            
            <pb n="86" facs="0012_001560_000202_0086.jpg" xml:id="d4e1352"/>
            <p>Friday June 9, 1865. In camp at Greensboro N.C</p>
            <p>Saturday June 10, 1865. All quiet. Nothing of interest</p>
            
            <pb n="87" facs="0012_001560_000202_0087.jpg" xml:id="d4e1365"/>
            <p>Sunday June 11, 1865. Church at two Oclock P.M</p>
            <p>Monday June 12, 1865. All quiet. Still talk of going home</p>
            
            <pb n="88" facs="0012_001560_000202_0088.jpg" xml:id="d4e1378"/>
            <p>Tuesday June 13, 1865. In camp at Greensboro N.C</p>
            <p>Wednesday June 14, 1865. Talk of being relieved but no relief com</p>
            
            <pb n="89" facs="0012_001560_000202_0089.jpg" xml:id="d4e1391"/>
            <p>Thursday June 15, 1865. No relief come as yet</p>
            <p>Friday June 16, 1865. Relieved from duty at Greensboro N.C. by the 17 Mass Strong talk of
          going home</p>
            
            <pb n="90" facs="0012_001560_000202_0090.jpg" xml:id="d4e1404"/>
            <p>Saturday June 17, 1865. Gen Cox Inspected the 3rd Div at Greensboro to day. Did not get
          off</p>
            <p>Sunday June 18, 1865. Left Greensboro at five Oclock. Reached Danville at eleven Oclock.
          Dis 48 mile loaded on the train for Birksville</p>
            
            <pb n="91" facs="0012_001560_000202_0091.jpg" xml:id="d4e1417"/>
            <p>Monday June 19, 1865. Left Danville at daylight and reached Birksville at two Oclock
          distance eighty five mile. Left Birksville at three oclock and arrived at Petersburg at
          seven Oclock distance eighty six mile. Left for City Point at Seven distance ten mile got
          on board of Columbia where we lay for the night </p>
            <p>Tuesday June 20, 1865. Left City Point at daylight went down the James River to Fort
          Manne reached there about two Oclock. Left for Baltimaore got to the mouth of the York
          River and the appearance of an approaching storm run up 12 mile to York town and anchored
          for the night. Quite a number of us went on a swimming. Sweet from Co. D prety near
          drowned</p>
            
            <pb n="92" facs="0012_001560_000202_0092.jpg" xml:id="d4e1430"/>
            <p>Wednesday June 21, 1865. Pulled out from York town at day light and journeyd on for
          Baltimore. Reached the harbor at twelve Oclock at nigh. Did not go in until morning. From
          City Point to Baltimore 280 mile</p>
            <p>Thursday June 22, 1865. Pulled into the Wharf at Six A M marched through Baltimore 1 ½
          miles to the Pa Central <unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">soad</unclear>. Lay until
          twelve Oclock. Took the train run to Hanesburg Dis 84 mile from there to Marysville at the
          crossing of the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">Susqurebranna</unclear> River
          changed locomotives. Arrived at Altona about 8 Oclock next morning</p>
            
            <pb n="93" facs="0012_001560_000202_0093.jpg" xml:id="d4e1450"/>
            <p>Friday June 23, 1865. Left Altona at ten A. M. Arrived at Pittsburg ½ past five. The
          Pittsburg Band escorted us to the town Hall where we wer furnished a good supper. Then we
          marched to the Depo and go aboard of the Canes. Soldiers could not of been treated better
          than we wer by the citizens of Pittsburg especially by the Ladies. Harrisburg to Pittsbugh
          140 mile. Run to Wellsalle Dis 50 M <gap resp="Deane"/>
            </p>
            <p>Saturday June 24, 1865. Passed through Alliance about six Oclock on to Atwater, Roxanna,
          Hudson and arrived at Cleveland about two Oclock. Stoped at the station and washed marched
          through the City to the park where a good substantial dinner awaited us. One the citizens
          give up short and appropriate reception speech then took dinner and marched to the
          barracks met J. R. Ray and Serg Maj WB Elston when we arrived</p>
            
            <pb n="94" facs="0012_001560_000202_0094.jpg" xml:id="d4e1464"/>
            <p>Wednesday June 28, 1865. May I never forget the 28 of June</p>
            
            <pb n="95" facs="0012_001560_000202_0095.jpg" xml:id="d4e1475"/>
            <p>Thursday June 29, 1865. Left Cleveland 4 Oclock forty minutes for home</p>
            
            <pb n="96" facs="0012_001560_000202_0096.jpg" xml:id="d4e1486"/>
            <p>Wednesday July 19, 1865. Left Laudonville for Salem to day. Arrived at noon and took
          dinner with Uncle Danny Boulton. Went out home with Ner G. Burns</p>
            <p>Thursday July 20, 1865. Remained with New all day and night had a pleasant time</p>
            
            <pb n="97" facs="0012_001560_000202_0097.jpg" xml:id="d4e1499"/>
            <p>Friday July 21, 1865. Went to Kinks, helped them hall hay stayed the night. It rained
          very hard</p>
            <p>Saturday July 22, 1865. Went to Salem. Stayed all night with Wm Turner</p>
            
            <pb n="98" facs="0012_001560_000202_0098.jpg" xml:id="d4e1512"/>
            <p>Sunday July 23, 1865. Visited the semmetry took tea at Mrs Bets and spent the night
          there</p>
            <p>Monday July 24, 1865. Was in town and spent the night with A.A. Thomas</p>
            
            <pb n="99" facs="0012_001560_000202_0099.jpg" xml:id="d4e1525"/>
            <p>Tuesday July 25, 1865. Left Salem and went out to Uncle Isaacs, Roberts, and Thomases</p>
            <p>Wednesday July 26, 1865. Still with Uncle</p>
            
            <pb n="100" facs="0012_001560_000202_0100.jpg" xml:id="d4e1538"/>
            <p>Thursday August 31, 1865. Farm for Sale. Farm of 77 Acres situated 3 ½ miles SW of Salem.
          Lies well a good roomy house, barn, wagon house and other out buildings. Two wells of
          water and a good orchard of the choicest fruit</p>
            
            <pb n="101" facs="0012_001560_000202_0101.jpg" xml:id="d4e1549"/>
            <p>Saturday September 16, 1865. Valuable Farm for sale. Farm of 77 acres owned by Joseph
          Pippitt situated 3 ½ miles S.W. of Salem, Lies well a <gap resp="Deane"/>
            </p>
            
            <pb n="102" facs="0012_001560_000202_0102.jpg" xml:id="d4e1564"/>
            <p>General Mower Command the 20th Corps</p>
            <p>Jeff C. Davis Commands the 14th Corps</p>
            <p>Gen Slocum Commands the two Corps and is called the Army of Georgia</p>
            <p>Frank Blair commands the 17th Corps</p>
            <p>John Logan the 15th Corps</p>
            <p>Gen Howard the two and is called the army of Tenn</p>
            <p>Gen Cox com the 23rd Corps</p>
            <p>Gen Terry the 10th Corps and Gen Schofield the two called the Depot of Ohio</p>
            <p>Dr M L Bynne</p>
            <p>Box 4669 P O</p>
            <p>New York City</p>
            <pb n="103" facs="0012_001560_000202_0103.jpg" xml:id="d4e1593"/>
            <p>One Dram of Nitrite of Silver one of Aqmmonia</p>
            <p>Apply with Brush</p>
            <p>Commenced work for Robert Carr Aug 25</p>
            <pb n="104" facs="0012_001560_000202_0104.jpg" xml:id="d4e1605"/>
            <p>
               <unclear reason="illegible" resp="LW">L L</unclear> Fort Pemberton New Jersey</p>
            <pb n="105" facs="0012_001560_000202_0105.jpg" xml:id="d4e1615"/>
            <p>Feb</p>
            <p>J D Peters 49</p>
            <p>40</p>
            <p>9</p>
            <p>J D Peters 20</p>
            <p>10</p>
            <p>10</p>
            
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
