<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_002414_000223_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Power of Attorney,
					<name>Walter Bowne</name>
				                    in New york, N.Y., to Thomas McEuen,<date when="1804-01-25">1804 Jan. 25.</date>
            </title>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>White, Park</name>
            </respStmt>
            <author>
               <name type="person">Walter Bowne</name>
            </author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <availability status="restricted">
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_002414_000223_0000</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Power of Attorney, Walter Bowne in New york, N.Y., to Thomas McEuen,1804 Jan. 25.</title>
               <date when="1804-01-25">1804 Jan. 25.</date>
               <author>
                  <name type="person">Walter Bowne</name>
               </author>
               <extent>2 pages</extent>
               <note type="collection">Insurance Company of North America Records, 1792 December 1-1843 February 18 </note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS.1184</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
						omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Adams, John Quincy, 1767-1848</term>
               <term>Insurance Company of North America.</term>
               <term>Madison, James, 1751-1836</term>
               <term>Morris, Robert, 1734-1806</term>
               <term>Webster, Daniel, 1782-1852</term>
               <term>Insurance companies -- United States.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change who="White, Park">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
         <change when="2013-10-03" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_002414_000223_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e39"/>
            <p>Walter Bowne</p>
            <p>Power to</p>
            <p>Thomas Mc Euen</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_002414_000223_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e47"/>
            <p>KNOW all Men by these Presents, That I Walter Bowne of New York do make, constitute and appoint Thomas Mc Euen
				      of Philadelphia my true and lawful Attorney irrevocable, for me and in my Name to sell assign and transfer to any
				      Person or Persons Two hundred and thirty two shares of </p>
            <p>Stock standing in my Name in the Books of the Insurance Company of North America  with Power also an Attorney or
				      Attornies under him for that Purpose to make and substitute ; and to do all lawful Acts requisite for effecting the
				      Premises ; hereby ratifying and confirming all that my said Attorney or his Substitute or Substitutes shall do therein by
				      Virtue hereof. IN WITNESS whereof I have hereunto set my Hand and Seal the Twenty Fifth Day of January in the Year
				      of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and four</p>
            <p>Sealed and delivered in the Presence of</p>
            <p>Jno Keese</p>
            <p>Chas Reese</p>
            <p>Walter Bowne</p>
            <p>State of New York, sso</p>
            <p>BE IT KNOWN, That on the twenty fifth Day of January one thousand eight hundred and four before me, JOHN KEESE,
				       Notary Public in and for the State of New-York, duly commissioned and sworn, came and appeared Walter Bowne</p>
            <p>within named, and acknowledged the above Letter of Attorney to be his Act and Deed. IN TESTIMONY whereof I have
				       hereunto set my Hand, and affixed my Seal of Office, the Day and Year last aforesaid.</p>
            <p>Jno Keese</p>
            <p>Public Notary</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
