<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000070_000203_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter, <name> Welcker, A.G.</name> in Cleveland, Tenn. to O.P. Temple in Knoxville,
     Tenn. <date when="1864-06-17">1864 June 17</date>
            </title>
            <author>
               <name type="person">Welcker, A.G.</name>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>Williams, Nancy</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_000070_000203_0000</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more information,
            contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special Collections
                Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Letter, A.G. Weckler in Cleveland, Tenn., O.P.Temple in Knoxville Tenn., 1864 June
      17</title>
               <date>1864-06-17</date>
               <author>
                  <name>Welcker, A.G.</name>
               </author>
               <extent>4 digital images; 4 pages</extent>
               <note type="abstract"> Letter June 17, 1864 from A.G. Welcker in Cleveland, Tenn., to O.P.
      Temple in Knoxville, Tenn. Brings up questions as to existence or nullification of &quot;our
      judicial positions;&quot; goes into situation at length, especially Welckers own case. </note>
               <note type="collection">The O.P. Temple Papers, 1864</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS.0021</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee Libraries
                Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
                omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Knoxville (Tenn.) -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 </term>
               <term>Tennessee, East -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865</term>
               <term>Welcker, A. G. (Albert Gallatin), 1823-1868 -- Correspondence</term>
               <term>Temple, Oliver Perry, 1820-1907 -- Correspondence</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-10-02" who="bds">Migrating from
                XML to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter" xml:id="d3e153">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_000070_000203_0001.jpg" xml:id="d3e154"/>
            <p>Cleveland, June 17th 1864</p>
            <p>Col O.P. Temple</p>
            <p>Knoxville, Tenn.</p>
            <p> Herewith find the bill which has been so long coming to hand. The deed was not with it.</p>
            <p>Being called on to perform an official act reminds me of my peculiar condition &amp; I have
     concluded to address you on the subject &apos; beg your &quot;Kind Offices.&quot;</p>
            <p>Are our judicial offices vacant? Is my <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NW">fial</unclear> a
     nulity? Do I commit an offense by performing official duties? Alas Gov. Johnson intened to
     appoint Judges &amp; Chancellors, or issue new commissions to those who have been elected by
     the people? These questions are much talked of among us &amp; all seem to form opinions from
     what they conjecture to be the opinion of Gov. Johnson I have deemed it proper to perform my
     official duties until some action is had by the Governor. </p>
            <p>I have advices from Nashville that Gov. Johnson had procured from the President a special
     pardon for Judges Gant &amp; Patterson &amp; Ch. Luckey; and Judge Gant tells me that he has
     such a paper. I am the only otherJudge in E. Tenn elected at the same time. The omission to
     include me look, a little ominous. Judge Gant tells me that he intended for me &amp; others
     have done so. but the Judge perhaps was a little embarassed himself by certain letters &amp;
     speeches during past troubles; nor have we many other prominent men of the Union party in our
     district who remained at home. And those who left were perhaps displeased with my early</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_000070_000203_0002.jpg" xml:id="d3e177"/>
            <p>opposition to the proposed seperation of E. Tenn; and although all parties at present approve
     my views on the subject as appears from the action of the late convention at Knoxville it is
     possible that the displeasure remains &amp; is operating against me, while the cause of it is
     forgotten. I am left to conjecture the difficully in my case; nor am I willing to believe it
     arises out of my subsequent canvass for congress when my failure resulted from the charge of my
     union affliliations, &amp; it soon became sufficient cause for an arrest &amp; in some cases
     long imprisonment to prove that a man had voted for me. But if that canvass caused the
     difficulty, I may ask why should I be held to so harsh a scrutiny when in the general effort of
     the original union men to make peace with the military, letters, speeches &amp; manifestoes
     became so common? If others who were then on the Bench &amp; by their position might with some
     show of prosperity have remained quiet are to be excused for their letters &amp; speeches on
     the ground that they were forced to make such manifestations, why should I not receive the same
     leniency for speeches made while a private citizen &amp; therefore in a more exposed condition?
     Had they been more active than I in their opposition to succession? Or is it intended as a
     compliment to my courage in not being awed by the military; or to my integrity in holding
     boldly to my opinions under all curcumstances?</p>
            <p>I apprehend that some one has impressed the Governor against me &amp; no doubt others would
     like to </p>
            <pb n="3" facs="0012_000070_000203_0003.jpg" xml:id="d3e187"/>
            <p>to keep up the fuding. Nothing that I could say or do would be likely to operate on his &amp;
     in these days of trouble &amp; general suspicion when every one seems afraid to speake above
     their breath, I hardly know how to approach any one on a matter of interest to myself. The time
     was when I should not have hesitated to refer to a long list of friends in Knoxville -
     Yourself, Maynard, Heiskell, <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NW">Dickerson </unclear>,
     Rogers, Luttrell, Jackson, Baxter, Flemming &amp; others too numerous to mention. But whether
     you have taken interest enough in matters in this district to form an idea of my course as to
     be able to speake a good word for me is a matter unknown to me. If you have &amp; will be kind
     enoughto get a few friends to join you, I have no doubt you can easily turn the scale in my
     favor, &amp; at all events, you will place me under many obligations-</p>
            <p>Please pardon me for unexpectedly illustrating in the present instance the old adage that
     self as the subject generally produces a long epistle. </p>
            <p>Yours Truly</p>
            <p>A. G. Welcker</p>
            <pb n="4" facs="0012_000070_000203_0004.jpg" xml:id="d3e204"/>
            <p>A G Welcker</p>
            <p>A June 24/64</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>