<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_002414_000302_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter,
					<name>Elliston Perot &amp;John Perot</name>
				                   in Abington to Charles Pettit., <date when="1799-09-24">1799 Sept. 24</date>
            </title>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>White, Park</name>
            </respStmt>
            <author>
               <name type="person">Elliston Perot &amp;John Perot</name>
            </author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <availability status="restricted">
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_002414_000302_0000</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Letter, Elliston Perot &amp;John Perot in Abington to Charles Pettit., 1799 Sept. 24</title>
               <date when="1799-09-24">1799 Sept. 24</date>
               <author>
                  <name type="person">Elliston Perot &amp;John Perot</name>
               </author>
               <extent>4 pages</extent>
               <note type="collection">Insurance Company of North America Records, 1792 December 1-1843 February 18</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS.1184</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
						omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Adams, John Quincy, 1767-1848</term>
               <term>Insurance Company of North America.</term>
               <term>Madison, James, 1751-1836</term>
               <term>Morris, Robert, 1734-1806</term>
               <term>Webster, Daniel, 1782-1852</term>
               <term>Insurance companies -- United States.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change who="White, Park">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
         <change when="2013-10-03" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_002414_000302_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e39"/>
            <p>Charles Pettit Esqr. Presidt.</p>
            <p>of The Insurance Office of No. America</p>
            <p>Philadelphia</p>
            <p>Septr  24th  1799</p>
            <p>E &amp; J  Perot</p>
            <p>E &amp; J. Perot  24 Sept.</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_002414_000302_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e53"/>
            <p>Ansd. 15 warled. Danish B &amp; <unclear reason="illegible" resp="pw">Oor</unclear>
            </p>
            <p>More -- as hestates it</p>
            <pb n="3" facs="0012_002414_000302_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e61"/>
            <p>Abington 24 Septemr. 1799</p>
            <p>Gentn.</p>
            <p>We want to make Insurance at and from St. Thomas to Leghorn upon the Brig Triton Capt. Andreas Frederickson &amp; Cargo.
				       You will Oblige us by mentioning by the return of the bearer what will be the premium say, 20000 Dollars to be Insured on both</p>
            <p>The following information is given us in a letter Dated St. Thomas 25 August 1799. on which Day the Triton began to take her Cargo
				       on board in which there will be nothing counterband and expected she would sail within the next fortnight.</p>
            <p>&quot;This vessel is Philadelphia built of Live oak &amp;cedar by the famous Penrose formerly belonged to John Crag _ and was 
				       insured at your Office in 1795 by James Fard, and in 1796 by Messieurs Odier and Bosquet Brothers her other Insurances have been
				       made in Copenhagen  she has been regularly in the Streights Trade from hence ever since  has been taken examined and suffered
				       to pass _ by French &amp; English and was once carried into there detained a long while and after the Strictest Investigation was
				       released,  she has had the same Captain and almost the same Crew for several years,  the first ever since the purchase was made of
				       her from Mr. Crag.  The papers under which she now sails are not of the West Indies,  but from Copenhagen with the most ample
				       Certificates of</p>
            <pb n="4" facs="0012_002414_000302_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e73"/>
            <p>Of Neutrality certified and confirmed at different periods by Consular Signatures.  The Triton moreover Sails well and is in Excellent
				       Order.  As the papers were originally taken out and have been regularly kept in the Name of Mr. John Dunlop of St. Croise it has been
				       thought adviseable to continue them the same, tho: Mr. Dunlop has sold out and I have become the purchaser it is with Mr. Dunlop&apos;s
				       approbation that they should be thus continued  &quot;</p>
            <p>The Gentleman for whom this Insurance is intended to be made wishes it to be made as explicit as possible and says of late Policies
				       have been filled up with the following conditions.   Vos</p>
            <p>&quot; That the Captains Protest be considered Sufficient proof of Loss and the policy Sufficient proof of Property&quot;</p>
            <p>In order that we may meet his wishes let us know if you will Comply with it in case we write you to make the Insurance.</p>
            <p>We are respectfully </p>
            <p>Your <unclear reason="illegible" resp="pw">Assured</unclear>Friends</p>
            <p>Elliston  &amp; John Perot</p>
            <p>Charles Pettit Esqr. President of the Insurance Co. of No. America</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
