<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000060_000260_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter, <name> J. Crozier Ramsey </name> in Nasville, Tenn., to J.G.M. Ramsey 
in Charlotte, N.C. <date when="1865-08-31"> 1865 August 31 </date>
            </title>
            <author>
               <name type="person">Ramsey, J. Crozier</name>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>Dyson-Smith, Bridger</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_000060_000260_0000</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more information,
            contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special Collections
                Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Letter, J. Crozier Ramsey in Nashville, Tenn., to J.G.M. Ramsey in Charlotte, N.C. 1865 Aug. 31</title>
               <date>1865-08-31</date>
               <author>
                  <name>Ramsey, J. Crozier</name>
               </author>
               <extent>4 digital images; 4 pages</extent>
               <note type="abstract">1865 Aug. 31 J. Crozier Ramsey, Nashville, Tenn., to his father, J.G.M.
Ramsey, Charlotte, N.C. Account of his arrest, his removal to Knoxville, and
his week&apos;s imprisonment there. Mentions indictments which are pending
against him. Praises Margaret Jane for her kindness to him in his troubles.
Anticipates future troubles in clearing himself of the accusations against
him. Reference to their applications for pardons and suggests that probably
all the family except Robert could return to Knoxville. </note>
               <note type="collection">J.G.M. Ramsey Papers 1790-1869</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS.253</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee Libraries
                Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
                omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Indictments -- Tennessee -- Knoxville -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Imprisonment -- Tennessee -- Knoxville -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Knoxville (Tenn.) -- Politics and government -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Ramsey, J. Crozier (John Crozier) d. 1868 -- Correspondence.</term>
               <term>Ramsey, J. G. M. (James Gettys McGready), 1797-1884 -- Correspondence.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-10-02" who="bds">Migrating from
                XML to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter" xml:id="d3e154">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_000060_000260_0001.jpg" xml:id="d3e155"/>
            <p>Nashville Ten August 31st</p>
            <p>Dear Sir</p>
            <p>I wrote Ma a letter about two weeks ago - and supposed that I would have got a letter from some of you before this time. For
fear you may have heard of my arrest and be alarmed about it - I thought I would write you. When I was released at Louisville
in June and returned to this place I know of the indictments pending against me at Knoxville both in the State and Federal Court - 
but I know that if I remained in the U.S. I would have to <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">met</unclear> the case some time
or another I then made up my mind to stand my ground and met the cases and have them disposed of at court. I then met the</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_000060_000260_0002.jpg" xml:id="d3e170"/>
            <p>the Sheriff of this country and the Marshal and had an interview with them and told them that I expected <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">capiases</unclear> would be sent to them from Knoxville for my arrest and that I did not intend
to avoid them - but that I desired before entering into business to make an arrangment with them not to arrest me until court and
then I would go with them - they agreed to it - and then I commenced business - after remaining here some six weeks a diferent set of
circumstances arose and the Sheriff felt it his duty to arrest me and take me to Knoxville where I was bailed upon a writ of
Habeas Corpus and returned to this place and have again resumed business. I do not reflect upon the Sheriff for making the arrest - 
Maj <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Dick McCarson</unclear> a citizen of this place was <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">provisionaly</unclear>
            </p>
            <pb n="3" facs="0012_000060_000260_0003.jpg" xml:id="d3e186"/>
            <p>arrested and taken to Knoxville and the Sheriff felt that it would not be right for him to have a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">capies</unclear> in his pocket for me and not serve it - When Dick was arrested and placed in jail upon the same
charge - So you see that I am not yet through with all my troubles and trials - but do not allow them to trouble you or give you
any uneasiness about them. I will come out of them all right - but it will put me to some trouble and expense - So you fully may
understand the case I send you an article taken from the Nashville Gazette which gives a correct <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">version</unclear> of the facts of the case and the legal principles that ought to control the case I was
imprisoned at Knoxville (which was a week) I met with several of my friends and frequently with my dear Sister - her devotion to
me which in all my troubles is unequaled and she was of</p>
            <pb n="4" facs="0012_000060_000260_0004.jpg" xml:id="d3e200"/>
            <p>great service to me and I can never forget her kindness and attachment to me (not only on this occasion but in all my troubles - 
the sentiment is still bad there - when I was released on bail I remained in prison until the cars started and then I was
accompanied with a guard to the Depot. I think it was unnecessary but my friends advised it and I thought it best to take their
advice. I have to return the third Monday in Oct. I think things will be better by that time I at least dont apprehend any
difficulty I read yesterday your letter to my Uncle - Glad to hear you are all well and that you have got a place for the
next year - perhaps it is best for you to stay there for another year - though I still think as I wrote to Ma that you could all
return (except Robert) with safety - I wrote Judge Patterson yesterday another letter inregard to our applications. I hope
we will get them soon - you might write to him also - his given name is David T. - he resides with the President - All our friends
and relatives at Knoxville are well and all are well here - Love to all and will be pleased to hear from all of you often - Uncle
William received a letter from Uncle Arthur he is living at Austin and has also suffered in property greatly by the war</p>
            <p>Yours truly</p>
            <p>J.G. Ramsey</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>