<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_002414_000328_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter,
					<name>John Wethered</name>
				                    in Wilmington, Del. to Charles Pettit in Philadelphia, Pa., <date when="1804-05-09">1804 May 9</date>
            </title>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>White, Park</name>
            </respStmt>
            <author>
               <name type="person">John Wethered</name>
            </author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <availability status="restricted">
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_002414_000328_0000</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Letter, John Wethered in Wilmington, Del. to Charles Pettit in Philadelphia, Pa., 1804 May 9</title>
               <date when="1804-05-09">1804 May 9</date>
               <author>
                  <name type="person">John Wethered</name>
               </author>
               <extent>2 pages</extent>
               <note type="collection">Insurance Company of North America Records, 1792 December 1-1843 February 18</note>
               <note type="manuscript">.MS.2414</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
						omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Adams, John Quincy, 1767-1848</term>
               <term>Insurance Company of North America.</term>
               <term>Madison, James, 1751-1836</term>
               <term>Morris, Robert, 1734-1806</term>
               <term>Webster, Daniel, 1782-1852</term>
               <term>Insurance companies -- United States.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change who="White, Park">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
         <change when="2013-10-03" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_002414_000328_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e39"/>
            <p>Charles Pettit, Esquire</p>
            <p>Agent or Commissioner</p>
            <p>for the Insurance of</p>
            <p>Houses against Fire &amp;a</p>
            <p>Philadelphia</p>
            <p>John Wethered</p>
            <p>9th May 1804</p>
            <p>Insurance on buildings at Trinidad</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_002414_000328_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e57"/>
            <p>Wilmington, Delaware  9th. May 1804__</p>
            <p>Sir</p>
            <p>I this day Recd. a Letter from my Son Lewin, who is in the Mercantile line in Baltimore, informing me that my Kinsman Mr. Thomas Wethered,
				       who is in the Customs of Trinidad, also Paymaster to the Army &amp;ce. had Requested him to have insured at Baltimore all his Dwellings,
				       Offices &amp;a. Rather near than in the Town, all Wood &amp;Nearly New for Which he Receives a Very high Rent from the Commissary, I
				       have also Reced. a Letter from Mr. T. Wethered dated 15th. April 1804. Requesting that I yod. Refresh the Memory of Lewin Respecting the 
				       Insurance this I find unnecessary, as Lewin in his Letter informs me that it cannot be effected in the Office at Baltimore as the Charter Prevents
				       them extending the insurance beyond Ten Miles from Town, he then Mentions the Office in Philada. extending the Policies. Which I find is
				       Correct.   Mr. Thomas Wethered is a Prudent Young Man has made his property by Attention &amp;Prudence, &amp;Wishes to insure his
				       House in this Peaceable happy Country,  he desires Fifteen hundred pounds Sterling may be insured for one Year, in Order to give You Every
				       Satisfaction, I Recommend it to You to make Enquiry of any Gentleman who traded to Martinique while it was in possesion of the British
				       Government.  Mr. T. Wethered, being a Custom House Officer there must be well Known.  Since the Evacuation he has Acted at Trinidad in
				       the Same Character as he had done at Martinique_ he has Made Money, Built handsomely &amp;wishes Insurance.  After You Make Every 
				       Necessary Enquiry, Please to Write to me &amp;Let me Know on What Terms fifteen hundd. pound. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="pw">S?</unclear>
				       Insurance can be had for one Year_ Which Will Oblige Your</p>
            <p>Most Obed. Servt.</p>
            <p>John Wethered.</p>
            <p>P.S</p>
            <p>Any Gentleman from Trinidad can give You a full Acct. of both Thos. Wethered, Esquire, and his Large New Buildings.  J.W.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
