<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_001560_000201_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>
               <name>Henry R. Pippitt </name>Diary, <date from="1864-04-01" to="1864-12-20">1864 April 1-December 20</date>
            </title>
            <author>
               <name type="person">Pippitt, Henry R.</name>
            </author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <date>2013</date>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_001560_000201_0000</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more information,
            contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special Collections
                Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
          <sourceDesc>
              <bibl>
                  <title>Henry R. Pippitt Diary, 1864 April 1-December 20</title>
                  <date>1864 April 1-December 20</date>
                  <author>
                      <name>Pippitt, Henry R.</name>
                  </author>
              </bibl>
          </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Civil War Diaries</term>
               <term>Pippitt, Henry, 1842-1927 -- Diaries</term>
               <term>United States. Army. Ohio Infantry Regiment, 104th (1862-1865)
              Company G.</term>
               <term>United States. Army. Ohio Infantry Regiment, 104th (1862-1865) --
              Personal narratives.</term>
               <term>United States -- History--Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Regimental
              histories.</term>
               <term>Ohio -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Regimental
              histories.</term>
               <term>Horton, Marcus C.</term>
               <term>Polk, Leonidas, 1806-1864.</term>
               <term>Hood, John Bell, 1831-1879.</term>
               <term>Knoxville (Tenn.)</term>
               <term>Nashville (Tenn.)</term>
               <term>Pulaski (Tenn.)</term>
               <term>Columbia (Tenn.)</term>
               <term>Spring Hill (Tenn.)</term>
               <term>Franklin (Tenn.)</term>
               <term>Franklin (Tenn.), Battle of, 1864.</term>
               <term>Atlanta (Ga.)</term>
               <term>Atlanta Campaign, 1864.</term>
               <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Prisoners and
              prisons.</term>
               <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Military
              life.</term>
               <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Campaigns &amp;
              battles.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-10-03" who="bds">Migrating from
                XML to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="diary" xml:id="d4e145">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_001560_000201_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e149"/>
            
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_001560_000201_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e154"/>
            <pb n="3" facs="0012_001560_000201_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e158"/>
            <pb n="4" facs="0012_001560_000201_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e162"/>
            
            <pb n="5" facs="0012_001560_000201_0005.jpg" xml:id="d4e168"/>
            
            <pb n="6" facs="0012_001560_000201_0006.jpg" xml:id="d4e174"/>
            <p>September 7th 1864. We marched back to the rear
          of the Decator road marched about ten mile &amp; Camped for the night</p>
            <p>Wednesday 8.
          Reached Deeden at nine oclock and took position on the line for a rest. So here ends the
          Campaign commencing May 7th 1864 &amp; ending Sept 8th 1864</p>
            <p>Thursday 9. Lay in Camp.
          Our Band come up which effords <unclear reason="illegible" resp="R.M.">myoh</unclear>
          company in camp; had our first <unclear reason="illegible" resp="R.M.">Inesparad</unclear>
            </p>
            <pb n="7" facs="0012_001560_000201_0007.jpg" xml:id="d4e194"/>
            <p>September 10, 1864. All quiet in camp and it
          seems almost like home.</p>
            <p>September 11, 1864. In camp nothing of interest
          transpired.</p>
            <p>September 12, 1864. To day some of the boys went <unclear reason="illegible" resp="R.M.">a<gap />
               </unclear>forageing. Frank Baugh of Col H Col Cook
          &amp; was captured.</p>
            
            <pb n="8" facs="0012_001560_000201_0008.jpg" xml:id="d4e213"/>
            
            <p>May 13, 1864. Marched to Snake Gap which is
          completely blockaded with troops and supply trains. Marched to the front &amp;took our
          position; no fighting on our lines, but heavy cannonading on our right.</p>
            <p>May 14,
          1864. Heavy skirmishing all the fore part of the day and at one oclock the fighting began;
          fought hard until dark. Our Reg. was in the second line of battle. Drove them out of their
          second line of breastworks.</p>
            <p>Sunday, May 15, 1864. Skirmishing commenced this
          morning; heavy firing during the day. Took a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="R.M.">beiltsy</unclear> of five peaces. Our members red two hundred and eighty six Dead
          Rebles.</p>
            
            <pb n="9" facs="0012_001560_000201_0009.jpg" xml:id="d4e231"/>
            
            <p>May 16, 1864. Could not find Jo Johnson. He
            <unclear reason="illegible" resp="R.M.">setsealed</unclear>towards Atlanta. Our Divi
          crossed the Cursaw river and are in hot pursuit.</p>
            <p>May 17, 1864. Marched to River;
          drew rations and at dark started on the march; marched until three Oclock in the morning
          &amp; camped</p>
            <p>May 18, 1864. Started at seven Oclock A.m. &amp; marched until four
          Oclock P.m. camped for the night distance forteen miles</p>
            <p>May 19, 1864. Marched to
          Cassville and camped for the night</p>
            <p>May 20, 1864. Marched from Cassville to to
          Carters Station camped for the night. The Rebles destroyed a good but of property before
          leaving</p>
            <p>May 21, 1864. Camped at Carters Station. Slight skirmishing going at the
          front</p>
            
            <pb n="10" facs="0012_001560_000201_0010.jpg" xml:id="d4e256"/>
            
            <p>May 22, 1864. Still at Carters Station doing
          washing &amp; cleaning up generally</p>
            <p>May 23, 1864. Left Carters Station and marche to
          the fight until we reached High Tower river &amp; camped for the night</p>
            <p>May 24, 1864.
          Took up the line of march in the morning and crossed the river on Pontoons, marched also 8
          miles skirmishing with the Enemy as we went</p>
            <p>May 25, 1864. Lay in camp until dark and
          then marched about six miles and then stoped (it rained all the time) until twelve Oclock
          &amp; then marched on</p>
            <p>May 26, 1864. marched until daylight and then stoped for
          breakfast. The 20the Corps on the 25th lost about 1000 men by charging a masked battesy.
          Took our position on the left</p>
            <p>May 27, 1864. Lay in line of battle all night heavy
          skirmishing all day. Two <unclear reason="illegible" resp="R.M.">men</unclear>of Company A
          of the 104th wounded.</p>
            
            <pb n="11" facs="0012_001560_000201_0011.jpg" xml:id="d4e281"/>
            
            <p>May 28, 1864. Heavy skirmishing all day and
          night. Capt. Horton of Co. D. killed instantly.</p>
            <p>Sunday May 29, 1864. Heavy firing
          day and night. The Rebs made several changes but repulsed every time</p>
            <p>Monday May 30,
          1864. Heavy skirmishing all night Rebs made three charges wer repulsed every time heavy
          loss of the Rebs</p>
            <p>Tuesday May 31, 1864. Still behind our breastworks. An attack made
          by the Rebles; considerable canonading all day</p>
            <p>Wednesday June 1, 1864. Laying behind
          the breastworks; heavy skirmishing and canonading all day. Was relieved by the 14th corps
          at 12 oclock that night. Went to the rear and lay till morning.</p>
            <p>Thursday June 2,
          1864. Took breakfast and marched to the left of our line. Commenced skirmishing with the
          enemy in the afternoon. Our Brig charged &amp; took their first line of rifle
        pits</p>
            
            <pb n="12" facs="0012_001560_000201_0012.jpg" xml:id="d4e303"/>
            
            <p>Friday June 3, 1864. Laying behind our
          breastworks. Supported by the 20th Corps no attack by the Reble <unclear reason="illegible" resp="R.M.">Hooys Divi</unclear>come the flank movement on <unclear reason="illegible" resp="R.M."/> wer compelled to fall back &amp; evacuate their forts
          and rifle pits</p>
            <p>Saturday June 4. Our forces moved up and took possession of their
          Breastworks</p>
            <p>Sunday June 5. Still behind the Reble breastworks. Our Brigade went on a
          reconoitering expedition. Went some two miles and found nothing but evacuated forts and
          rifle pits</p>
            <p>Monday June 6. All Quiet in Camp. The troops from the right are all
          moving to the left. Heavy musketry in that direction.</p>
            <p>Tuesday June 7. Drew one days
          ration on the 6th &amp; it had to last three. We wer hungry Boys still behind the Reble
          Breastworks</p>
            <p>June 8. No movement as yet. Still hold our old
        position</p>
            
            <pb n="13" facs="0012_001560_000201_0013.jpg" xml:id="d4e330"/>
            
            <p>June 9. Laying still behind the breastworks
          drew one days ration to last one (that is if we can get rations)</p>
            <p>June 10. Picked up
          our traps and moved to the left some three miles and commenced skirmishing</p>
            <p>June 11.
          Held our position and built breastworks. No movements of notice heavy canonading on our
          left</p>
            <p>June 12, 1864. Laying behind the breastworks all quiet except
          skirmishing</p>
            <p>June 13. Still in our rifle pits. Heavy canonading on the left with
          thirty two pounders</p>
            <p>June 14. Shelled the Rebles off of a strong position. Gen. Polk
          was killed.</p>
            
            <pb n="14" facs="0012_001560_000201_0014.jpg" xml:id="d4e352"/>
            
            <p>June 15, 1864. Shelled the Rebs out of another
          line of breastworks &amp; the 23rd &amp; 20th corps advanced and took posession of their
          evacuated works.</p>
            <p>June 16. Took position to the front about two hundred yards from
          the Reble works and fortified the right swung around and the Rebs evacuated at three
          oclock of the 16th</p>
            <p>June 17. Skirmish line advanced the Rebs done some shelling at
          which time our forces charged them drove them two mile into another line of rifle pits.
          Here they shelled us but killed one man.</p>
            <p>June 18. The Rebs still hold their works
          but it is under ganling fire of artilery</p>
            <p>June 19. Early in the morning they
          evacuated their line of works and we pushed forward</p>
            <p>June 20. Our Brigade was in the
          front but the 104 was on the reserve skirmishing continualy</p>
            
            <pb n="15" facs="0012_001560_000201_0015.jpg" xml:id="d4e375"/>
            
            <p>June 21. Holding the second line of works.
          Heavy firing on our left &amp; slight skirmishing in front We ar on the extreme
          right</p>
            <p>June 22. Took the front and drove the Rebles one mile and put up a heavy line
          of works</p>
            <p>June 23. Laying behing our breastworks all quiet in front except a little
          skirmishing Heavy fighting on the left.</p>
            <p>June 24. No movement on the right but heavy
          fighting on the left at Kenasaw Mountain</p>
            <p>Saturday June 25. All quiet in front save a
          little skirmishing. Hard fighting at Kenasaw Mountain</p>
            <p>Sunday June 26. Left our
          fortifications and advanced on the enemy drove them one mile &amp; run on their works
          &amp; was obliged to stop</p>
            
            <pb n="16" facs="0012_001560_000201_0016.jpg" xml:id="d4e397"/>
            
            <p>June 27. The 23 2nd battery &amp; the 15th 2nd
          battery got into position and routed the enemy out of their works. We advanced one mile
          and built breastworks. The Rebs had a masked ball in front</p>
            <p>June 28. Built
          breastworks and nothing of interest transacted</p>
            <p>June 29. Laying behind our works.
          Slight skirmishing on the front. Issued some Blouses shirts Drawers &amp; socks</p>
            <p>June
          30. All quiet on our front. Regular muster day.</p>
            <p>July 1. Behind our works. Haskels
          Div. moved &amp; took position to our right &amp; Cox filled up the gap between Bird and
          Haskell</p>
            <p>July 2. Still behind our works. The 15th Corps moved to our right. no
          fighting.</p>
            
            <pb n="17" facs="0012_001560_000201_0017.jpg" xml:id="d4e419"/>
            
            <p>July 3. Lay behind our works. The Rebs are fast
          on the retreat for Atlanta &amp; our ford at their heels</p>
            <p>July 4. A long dreary day,
          nothing of interest during the day</p>
            <p>July 5. The 15th &amp; 16th Corps post moving
          toward the river. Our Div moved 2 mile to the front and halted for the night</p>
            <p>July 6.
          Revalee at four Oclock and marched to the railroad, here there are strong Reble Earth
          works and presents a spat of ground which has been heartily contested</p>
            <p>July 7.
          Marched 5 mile toward the river and went into Camp. Policed the ground all clear &amp;
          left next morning for the river</p>
            <p>July 8. Marched within 1 1/2 miles of the river
          &amp; here lay while the 2nd Div forded &amp; then we lay the Pontrans &amp; crossed the
          river. The 2nd Div charged &amp; took one Pace of <unclear reason="illegible" resp="R.M.">antiters</unclear>
            </p>
            
            <pb n="18" facs="0012_001560_000201_0018.jpg" xml:id="d4e443"/>
            
            <p>July 9. moved one mile to the front and took a
          position &amp; fortified. Worked about half the night</p>
            <p>July 10. Company G went on
          skirmish, and the rest of the Reg lay behind the works</p>
            <p>July 11. Co. G Came off
          skirmish in the morning and Reg got orders at four oclock to pack up &amp; be ready to
          move. Moved across on another ridge</p>
            <p>July 12. Cleared up Camp and put up tents
          &amp;stayed for the day</p>
            <p>July 13. Laying in Camp</p>
            <p>July 14. Still in Camp a very
          heavy rain and wind Blew down a tree &amp; killed the Adjutant of <gap />and one pretty
          near killed one of Co Ks Boys &amp; wounded another</p>
            
            <pb n="19" facs="0012_001560_000201_0019.jpg" xml:id="d4e467"/>
            
            <p>July 15. All quiet laying in camp on the
          River</p>
            <p>July 16. Lay in Camp marched at seven oclock marched some six mile driving the
          Enemy before us. Camped for the night Sarg Jackson of Co H shot himself accidental in
          crossing a creek</p>
            <p>July 17. Advanced some two mile to cross Keys Where we intersected
          the newly laid out railroad running to Richmond</p>
            <p>July 19. We advanced upon the Enemy
          Coming in from a different direction from that they wer expecting</p>
            <p>July 20. Advanced
          &amp; skirmished with the Enemy &amp; at night got into position three mile from Atlanta
          and built breast works Company G went on skirmish line which was a
        <gap />
            </p>
            
            <pb n="20" facs="0012_001560_000201_0020.jpg" xml:id="d4e487"/>
            
            <p>July 21, 1864. Heavy skirmishing all along the
          lines Occasional shots are being <unclear reason="illegible" resp="R.M">throwen</unclear>
          into Atlanta. Co G releaved at dark. M Jinnyerman was shot through the left shoulder
          &amp;died in a few hours</p>
            <p>July 22. The first Brig. moved within three quarters of a
          mile of Atlanta &amp;was soon ordered two miles to the rear to guard a train. There was
          hard fighting on our left. Gen McPherson was killed</p>
            <p>Saturday 28. The first Brigade
          are laying two miles to the rear of Atlanta a guarding the train. There is some canonading
          going on at the front</p>
            <p>Sunday 24. Laying behind our works guarding the
          train</p>
            <p>July 25. Nothing of interest. Still guarding the train</p>
            <p> Tuesday July 26.
          Moved within half mile of the front line &amp;took posession of the Reble works &amp;are
          now fronting both ways &amp;have the train &amp;Hosfertals
        between</p>
            
            <pb n="21" facs="0012_001560_000201_0021.jpg" xml:id="d4e512"/>
            
            <p>July 27. Strengthened the works. Heavy
          canonading on the front line</p>
            <p>July 28. Occasional canonading Throwing shell into the
          Oily Strengthening the works</p>
            <p>July 29. The 1st Brigade went around the south side of
          Atlanta on a rcoinoiter and a few Reble Cavalry returned in the Evening</p>
            <p>July 30. Lay
          in Camp Considerable of canonading on the right of the line</p>
            <p>Sunday July 31. Sunday
          inspection All quiet in front Col. J.W. Reilly Promoted to Brigadar General</p>
            <p>August
          1. Lay in Camp until Evening. Struck tents and marched around toward the right. traveled
          until one oclock at night and camped</p><pb n="22" facs="0012_001560_000201_0022.jpg" xml:id="d4e532"/>
            
            <p>August 2. Marched five mile on the right and
          took position building strong works </p>
            <p>August 3. Completed the works and rested the
          balance of the day. In the afternoon the Rebs shelled but done no damage</p>
            <p>August 4.
          Moved to the front to support the 14th Corps where we lay during the day Four of our Reg
          was wounded by stray balls</p>
            <p>August 5. Ten Oclock moved to the right one mile and lay
          on the supporting line. The 14th Corps took the Reble skirmish line three times to over a
          hundred in all</p>
            <p>August 6. Moved on the Reble works The skirmish line changed twice
          and the ballance of the Brig. charged but did not carry the works. The Brig loss 330
          killed &amp;wounded; retired at night</p>
            <p>August 7. lay to the rear of our front line
          until afternoon and then moved to the right &amp;took postion built fortifications all
          night </p>
            
            <pb n="23" facs="0012_001560_000201_0023.jpg" xml:id="d4e554"/>
            
            <p>August 8. Completed the work. Wm Siple was
          wounded through both legs braking his left. The same ball went through my
          tent</p>
            <p>August 9. Moved our position to the right to give room for the 15th 2nd Battery
          The Rebs works &amp;ours are close enough to shoot across It makes it unhealthy to the
          rear of our works</p>
            <p>August 10. In our old position skirmishing continualy William
          Siple died a few minutes before twelve to day his death was caused by the amputation of
          his leg</p>
            <p>August 11. Nothing of interest transpired to day Continual
          skirmishing</p>
            <p>August 12. Wer relieved by the 2nd Div of the 14th Corps. The 3rd Div
          went to the right to effect a cuting of the East Point road. Did not sucseede and come
          back and camped to the rear of our old position</p>
            <p>August 13. Laying in Camp on the Sam
          town road. Some of the Boys went a forageing for Corn. The Rebs fired on them Killed one
          and wounded two</p>  <pb n="24" facs="0012_001560_000201_0024.jpg" xml:id="d4e574"/>
            
            <p>August 14. In Camp to the rear of 3rd Div of
          23rd Corps</p>
            <p>August 15. Laying in Camp as above stated</p>
            <p>August 16. Moved about
          two miles to the right and commenced to fortify Built the works twelve feet thick. Cap
          Saulhworth was killed by a tree falling him</p>
            <p>August 17. Finished the works I went a
          foraging about three mile found Apples, Corn &amp;potatoes Returned to Camp at noon well
          loaded</p>
            <p>August 18. Started at half past twelve Oclock and went</p>
            <p>August 19. The
          3rd Div advanced to the right moved about one mile took posession of a ridge and built
          works</p>
            
            <pb n="25" facs="0012_001560_000201_0025.jpg" xml:id="d4e596"/>
            
            <p>August 20. The Reg went on a reconoiter
          returned after dark. Wer supporting the skirmish line</p>
            <p>August 21. No movement. All is
          quiet Laying behind our works. D. C Boutrrell come up had been back sick since the siege
          at Knoxville</p>
            <p>August 22. In Camp Behind our works nothing worth notice passed during
          the day</p>
            <p>August 23. In Camp all quiet frequent skirmishing nothing worth
          notice</p>
            <p>August 24. Behind our breastworks No movement to day</p>
            <p>August 25. All
          quiet to day</p>  <pb n="26" facs="0012_001560_000201_0026.jpg" xml:id="d4e617"/>
            
            <p>August 26. Laying in Camp All quiet in
          front</p>
            <p>August 27. All quiet until noon at which time we received orders to pack up
          &amp; be ready to move Did not move for Post was at work on the works how I pity him the
          blistered his left hand. Poor thing</p>
            <p>August 28. Received orders to be ready to march
          at day light did not move until three Oclock. Moved about two miles &amp; a half put up
          temporary works for the night</p>
            <p>August 29. Moved to the right of the 14th Corps halted
          deployed skirmishers lay two hours then withdrew the skirmishers and advanced about three
          mile from where we started in the morning. Fortifyed for the night</p>
            <p>August 30.
          Marched about three mile and fortifyed across the Montgomery railroad lay for the
          night</p>
            <p>August 31. Got up at two Oclock got breckfast and struck for the Macon road
          reached it about five Oclock in the Eve. Commenced destroying the track Marched about
          eight mile</p>
            
            <pb n="27" facs="0012_001560_000201_0027.jpg" xml:id="d4e639"/>
            
            <p>September 1. This morning we commenced
          destroying the track both ways. After completing the work we moved down the real road
          &amp; are now some fifteen mile south of Atlanta</p>
            <p>September 2. Moved out and lay near
          the train until one Oclock and then followed the retreating enemy until nine Oclock at
          night then camped having come about 8 mile Passed a great many wounded
          Rebles</p>
            <p>September 3. The first Brigade lay in the rear guarding train etc. I went a
          forageing got two bushel of sweet potatoes. In the Eve our train left for Atlanta loaded
          with sick &amp; wounded to bring up rations</p>
            <p>Sunday September 4. The first Brigade
          occupy the same positions as here to fore stated Nothing of note transpired during the
          day. An order for full rations was issued to day</p>
            <p>September 5. In the Evening got
          orders to fall back. The trains all moved out &amp; our Brig did not get started until
          eleven Oclock at night. Marched alll night it raining most of the time and halted for
          breakfast at 8 Oclock</p>
            <p>September 6. Here we lay all day the 28th A.C. wer in the
          rear</p>
            
            <pb n="28" facs="0012_001560_000201_0028.jpg" xml:id="d4e661"/>
            
            <p>September 7. Left Knoxville at four Oclock A.M.
          for Cumberlan Gap. Marched twenty one miles and Camped for the night. Burnside and Staff
          accompanied the Brigade consisting of the 44th 4th Ohio Battery and the 104th
          O.V.</p>
            <p>September 8. Revalie at three Oclock marched thirty miles and Camped at
          Tazwell; twelve mile from the Gap at this time we have marched fifty two miles; doing it
          in forty hour including time for sleep and meals</p>
            <p>September 9. Left Tazwell after
          daylight and reached Camp at noon being two mile from the gap Burnside sent in a flag of
          truce; at first they would not surrender to the second flag they did surrender There was
          four Reg &amp; peaces of artilery </p>
            <p>September 10. Our Company was posted at the Gap;
          and wer busy Confiscating property all day There was three thousand prisners in all that
          surrendered</p>
            <p>September 11. Started back to Knoxville marched eighteen miles and
          camped for the night. On the south we passed through Tazwell a small town which had been
          partly burned in the year 1862</p>
            <p>September 12. Revalie at half past four; crossed the
          Clinch river and took dinner Marched to Maynardsville and Camped for the
        night</p>  <pb n="29" facs="0012_001560_000201_0029.jpg" xml:id="d4e681"/>
            
            <p>September 13. Nothing going on worth notice
          There was a large mail to day &amp; among it was one in which I got the awful coming down
          I ever want to get</p>
            <p>September 14. Nothing going on policeing of a new
          Camp</p>
            <p>September 15. To day we moved Camp It is a nice position for
          Encamping</p>
            <p>September 16. Policeing and cleaning up of Camp building of Bunks
          etc.</p>
            <p>Sep. Saturday 17. This Evening Lt Gen Humasan took command of Company g 104
          <gap />. Pv Ray come up being back since spring last</p>
            <p>September 18. Nothing of
          interest transpired. Building breast works</p> <pb n="30" facs="0012_001560_000201_0030.jpg" xml:id="d4e703"/>
            
            <p>September 19. To day the draft comes off.
          Another victory in the Shanondoa valey by Sheridon completely routing the enemy driving
          them 12 mile</p>
            <p>September 20. All quiet today. This Evening we signed the Payroll for
          six months pay</p>
            <p>Wednesday September 21. Nothing of interest To day I received a
          letter from Tid Kelly</p>
            <p>September 22. To day it is wet and rainy still working on the
          Breast works</p>
            <p>September 23. It rained very hard at diferent showers during the day I
          have been writing off a copy of a Board of <unclear reason="illegible" resp="R.M.">Su</unclear>held over the property of Cap AJ Saulhworth Diseased</p>
            <p>Saturday
          September 24. At work on the Breastworks They are heavy works Forteen feet at the base
          &amp; a ditch eight feet wide &amp; four feet deep in front</p>
            <pb n="31" facs="0012_001560_000201_0031.jpg" xml:id="d4e728"/>
            
            <p>Sunday September 25, 1864. Brigade Inspection
          and Brigade Dress parade which was attended by Generals Cox Rielly &amp; Paymaster
          Janes</p>
            <p>Monday September 26. Nothing of Interest transacted to day Boys all on the
          works</p>
            <p>Tuesday September 27. To day we wer payed for six months. I sent $(100) one
          hundred dollars home</p>
            <p>Wednesday September 28. to day the Rebs attacted a forage train
          surrendered it. The Boys cut out lost one man out of 60 2nd. The Rebs lost 12
          killed</p>
            <p>Thursday September 29. At work on the works</p>
            <p>September 30. All quiet in
          Camp Still at work on the works</p>  <pb n="32" facs="0012_001560_000201_0032.jpg" xml:id="d4e748"/>
            
            <p>October 1. Nothing going on</p>
            <p>Sunday
          October 2. Sunday inspection nothing of interest</p>
            <p>October 3. Received orders to move
          at one Oclock Just finished the works at twelve The order was countermanded</p>
            <p>Tuesday
          October 4. Marched at six Oclock Marched all day and camped about one hour after dark. One
          mile from the North Side of the Chattahoochee R</p>
            <p>Wednesday October 5. Continued our
          march until dark &amp; camped 3 mile North of Maryetta</p>
            <p>Thursday October 6. Continued
          the march to Big Shanty It reained most part of the day The roads are very
        bad</p>  <pb n="33" facs="0012_001560_000201_0033.jpg" xml:id="d4e768"/>
            
            <p>Friday October 7. The Reg went on some
          <gap />four mile in the Direction of <gap />Returned<gap />three Oclock <gap />attacted the
          Enemy &amp; whiped them</p>
            <p>Saturday October 8. Ordered to leave <gap />&amp; was
          <gap />Left at four Oclock <gap />through <gap />which was plundered &amp;Destroyed. Camped
          at Altona</p>
            <p>October 9. I was <gap />wounded Rebles &amp; one which is a female wounded
          in the flesh part of her leg They fought hard and <gap />whiped</p>
            <p>Monday October 10.
          Left Altona in the morning went to Cartersville &amp; took dinner Distance 7 mile went on
          to Cosville 6 mile &amp; camped for the night</p>
            <p>Tuesday October 11. Left Cassville
          Early in the morning marched to Kingston Dis 6 mile and camped one mile <gap />Kingston
          Where we voted for the State Election</p>
            <p>Wednesday October 12. Left for Rome Dis
          1<gap />mile reached there at four Oclock &amp; camped for the night The Rebled are only
          one mile from the town; Strength 30 <gap />
            </p> <pb n="34" facs="0012_001560_000201_0034.jpg" xml:id="d4e813"/>
            
            <p>Thursday October 13. To day our Div went out on
          a <gap />left the train to the rear. They returned in the Eve the 4th U.S. &amp; wilders
          Brig of <unclear reason="illegible" resp="R.M.">Cov. Cap <gap /> &amp; the
          <gap />
               </unclear>Rebs have left &amp; going North</p>
            <p>Friday October 14. Started for
          Calhoon the 4 &amp; 14th Corps &amp; train are in the advance Marched 11 mile &amp; Camped
          for the night Rebs reported to be at Resacca 11 mile</p>
            <p>Saturday October 15. To day we
          marched to Resacca and Camped for the night the Rebs are Reported to have taken Dalton
          &amp; 2 Reg of Inf.</p>
            <p>Sunday October 16. To day we left Resacca passed through snake
          creek gap five mile through &amp; camped &amp; camped 1/2 miles on this side</p>
            <p>October
          17. To day we lay and rest. the Baggage of the 4 &amp; 14th Corps are passing; Just came
          up from Atlanta</p>
            <p>October 18. Started on the road leading to Rome. Marched about 18
          miles and Camped for the night. We passed over some of the best plantation that we have in
          the State</p>
            
            <pb n="35" facs="0012_001560_000201_0035.jpg" xml:id="d4e843"/>
            
            <p>October 19. Passed through Tredaway Gap;
          marched five mile &amp; camped for the night</p>
            <p>Thursday October 20. Marched to
          Gaylisville Dis. 8 mile &amp; camped for the night. The Rebs are Reported to be at Decater
          Alabama Crossed the Alabama line</p>
            <p>October 21. Laying in camp all quiet</p>
            <p>October
          22. In Camp near Gaylisville</p>
            <p>Sunday October 23. Sunday Inspection In
          Camp</p>
            <p>October 24. Moved 1/2 a mile and camped for the night All seems to be quiet in
          front</p>
            
            <pb n="36" facs="0012_001560_000201_0036.jpg" xml:id="d4e865"/>
            
            <p>October 25. moved camp crossed the Cusa river
          went to Cedar Bluff Dis 3 1/2 mile and camped. The 3 Div. went to Centerville on a
          recinoyter Dis 8 mile made no discoveries</p>
            <p>October 26. Laying in Camp at Cedar Bluff,
          received a mail</p>
            <p>October 27. Sill in Camp no movements of notice</p>
            <p>October 28. At
          noon received orders to march croassed the <gap />and marched 8 mile in an NorthEast
          Direction from Centerville and Camped for the night</p>
            <p>October 29. Left at six Oclock
          A.M. crossed the Alab line about three Oclock, marched <gap />to spring and Camped Dis 19
          mile; This is a beutiful little village</p>
            <p>October 30. Marched five mile North of Rome
          &amp; Camped for the nigth Dis about nineteen (19) miles</p>
            <pb n="37" facs="0012_001560_000201_0037.jpg" xml:id="d4e892"/>
            
            <p>October 31. Marched to Calhoon Dis. 20 mile and
          camped for the night</p>
            <p>November 1. Marched to Resacca took dinner and from there to
          Tilton Dis 13 mile &amp; camped with the prospect of going on the train but did
          not</p>
            <p>November 2. marched to Dalton Dis 7 mile it was very wet &amp; muddy camped with
          the prospect of taking the train</p>
            <p>November 3. Still wating on the train but did not
          get off this day</p>
            <p>November 4. Wating on the train</p>
            <p>November 5. not off
        yet</p>
            
            <pb n="38" facs="0012_001560_000201_0038.jpg" xml:id="d4e914"/>
            
            <p>November 6. Took the Cars at five Oclock &amp;
          went to Chattanooga. Stoped about Eleven Oclock &amp; drew rations</p>
            <p>November 7. Moved
          on reached Nashville about two Oclock in the morning Raining constantly</p>
            <p>Tuesday
          November 8. To day is Presidential Election the Boys are all gay. Some whisky <gap />the
          track. Our <gap />Poled 414 votes &amp; 13 <gap />
            </p>
            <p>Wednesday November 9. At Franklin
          18 mile South East of Nashville moved 9 mile futher to a little town called Spring hill
          &amp; camped the R.R. bridge being destroyed</p>
            <p>November 10. Laying in Camp Feasting on
          freash Pork &amp; Potatoes</p>
            <p>November 11. In Camp</p>
            <pb n="39" facs="0012_001560_000201_0039.jpg" xml:id="d4e941"/>
            
            <p>November 12. A detachment went some six mile on
          a Reconnyter returned in Evening</p>
            <p>Sunday November 13. Left Spring Hill for Columbia
          Arrived at Columbia about four Oclock &amp; camped for the night</p>
            <p>November 14. Left
          Columbia &amp; marched to Minville Dis 16 mile &amp; camped for the night</p>
            <p>November
          15. Marched to within two mile of Polaski &amp; camped Dis 12 mile</p>
            <p>November 16. In
          camp near Polaski</p>
            <p>November 17. In camp near Polaski</p>
            <pb n="40" facs="0012_001560_000201_0040.jpg" xml:id="d4e963"/>
            
            <p>November 18. In Camp near Polaski, wet, cold,
          and rainy</p>
            <p>November 19. In Camp near Polaski wet &amp; rainy</p>
            <p>November 20. Near
          Polaski got orders to draw five days rations &amp; be in readiness to march</p>
            <p>November
          21. Left Polaski early in the morning and marched to Minville by 12 Oclock Halted took
          dinner &amp; camped for the night Dis 12 mile</p>
            <p>November 22. Near Polaski under
          marching orders ^This is for the <gap />&amp; what is wrote in Pag 22 is for
          22nd</p>
            <p>November 23. Left Minville about four Oclock in the Eve marched 9 mile toward
          Columbia camped at 8 Oclock It was very cold &amp; has been for the past three days &amp;
          nights I did not sleep any It was to cold Pardney on Picket</p>
            <pb n="41" facs="0012_001560_000201_0041.jpg" xml:id="d4e987"/>
            
            <p>November 24. Left camp before day Hood Reported
          to be as near as Columbia as we reached Col. about 8 Oclock AM The Rebs wer driving our
          Cavalry Our Brig Repulsed them &amp; put up works</p>
            <p>November 25. To day the Rebs are
          trying our strength, drove our skirmishers a short Dis. considerable of canonading in the
          afternoon 2 Oclock at night our Brig crossed the River</p>
            <p>Novemebr 26. The Rebs come
          into town but could not cross Dusk river. Brisk skirmishing all day</p>
            <p>Sunday November
          27. Lay half a mile to the rear of the river Considerable of skirmishing all
          day</p>
            <p>Monday November 28. Moved down near the river and built works. Received a good
          shelling but did no damage</p>
            <p>November 29. Still behind our works considerable of of
          firing on both sides Retreated to Franklin reached there four Oclock
        AM</p><pb n="42" facs="0012_001560_000201_0042.jpg" xml:id="d4e1007"/>
            
            <p>November 30. Put up works At four Oclock the
          Rebs 2 Div strong charged our works the firing continued some four hours Cleborns Div was
          badly cut up. Crossed Haspeth River &amp; retreated 8 mile</p>
            <p>December 1. Marched to
          Nashville <unclear reason="illegible" resp="R.M.">Promiscuously</unclear>
          Encamped</p>
            <p>December 2. Moved behind works Rebs are forming their lines some two mile
          from the city But no demonstration made by the Rebs</p>
            <p>December 3. Still behind our
          works Considerable of skirmishing in front</p> <pb n="43" facs="0012_001560_000201_0043.jpg" xml:id="d4e1026"/>
            
            <p>December
          15. Our Div. moved out and filled the works with convalescents. Moved to our right &amp;
          broke the Rebles left Cavalry in our advance <gap />&amp; took six peaces of artilery. We
          took position &amp; <gap />works wet &amp; rainy</p>
            <p>December 16. All quiet until two
          Oclock when the 16th Corps broke their line on the left center &amp; our Brigade charged
          took 8 peaces of Artilery completely demoralizing the Rebs Captured some three thousand.
          Campin in their works Raining</p>
            <p>December 17. Orders to march at 8 Oclock but was
          delayed by the train marched some 3 mile &amp; done most of that after dark The worst
          marching our Brig ever done Raining</p>  <pb n="44" facs="0012_001560_000201_0044" xml:id="d4e1045"/>
            
            <p>December
          18. Marched to the Franklin pike one mile Issued rations &amp; moved on to within one mile
          of Franklin &amp; camped Wet &amp; Raining</p>
            <p>December 19. Marched in the afternoon
          &amp; camped to the left of the battle ground at Franklin. The Reble left fifteen hundred
          wounded Rainy</p>
            <p>December 20. Marched to Spring Hill Dis 12 mile camped for the night
          Raining</p>
            
            <pb n="45" facs="0012_001560_000201_0045.jpg" xml:id="d4e1061"/>
            <p>
               <gap />Hallie P. Beadley</p>
            <p>
               <gap />
            </p>
            <p>
               <gap />Carr, May 28th</p>
            <p>P.E. Bull, June
          24th 1894</p>
            <p>L.M. Bull, June 28th</p>
            <p>W.C. Pippitt, July 11th</p>
            <p>J.B. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="R.M.">R</unclear>, July 14th</p>
            <p>W.C. Pippitt, July
          23rd</p>
            <p>J. Pippitt, July 25th</p>
            <p>T. B. Eagle, July 28th</p>
            <p>E. J. Bull, Aug
          3rd</p>
            <p>E.J. Bull, Aug 7th</p>
            <p>Fred Buckhemer, Aug 9th</p>
            <p>Jacob Sedinger, Aug
          9th</p>
            <p>W.C. Pippitt, Aug 12th</p>
            <p>L.M. Bull, Aug 23rd</p>
            <p>W.C. Pippitt, Aug
          25th</p>
            <p>Jonnie Bull, Aug 23rd</p>
            <p>W.C. Pippitt, Sep 10th</p>
            <p>F. Burckhemer, Sep
          13th</p>
            <p>D.P. Straun, Sep, 12th</p>
            <p>E.J. Bull, Sept 14th</p>
            <p>Letters</p>
            <p>W.C.
          Pippitt, Sep 16</p>
            <p>J. Pippitt, Sep 14th</p>
            <p>F. Birckhemer, Sep 28th</p>
            <p>W.C.
          Pippitt, Sep 30th</p>
            <p>W.C. Pippitt, Oct 12</p>
            <p>E.J. Bull, Nov 10</p>
            <p>W.C. Pippitt,
          Nov 10</p>
            
            <pb n="46" facs="0012_001560_000201_0046.jpg" xml:id="d4e1139"/>
            
            <table rows="22" cols="8">
               <row role="data">
                  <cell>CASH ACCOUNT.--DECEMBER. CASH ACCOUNT.--DECEMBER.</cell>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell>Date.</cell>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell>Received.</cell>
                  <cell>Paid.</cell>
                  <cell>Date.</cell>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell>Received.</cell>
                  <cell>Paid.</cell>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell>Jan/62</cell>
                  <cell>One pr of Pants</cell>
                  <cell>2.50</cell>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell>Articles</cell>
                  <cell>Prices</cell>
                  <cell/>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell>Oct/63</cell>
                  <cell>One shirt</cell>
                  <cell>1.53</cell>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell>Hats</cell>
                  <cell>1.65</cell>
                  <cell/>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell>Jan/64</cell>
                  <cell>Two pr of Socks</cell>
                  <cell>00.64</cell>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell>Caks</cell>
                  <cell>.58</cell>
                  <cell/>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell>Feb/64</cell>
                  <cell>One Artilery Jacket</cell>
                  <cell>5.30</cell>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell>Dress Coats</cell>
                  <cell>7.00</cell>
                  <cell/>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell>June 64</cell>
                  <cell>One Pr of shoes</cell>
                  <cell>1.48</cell>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell>Jackets</cell>
                  <cell>5.30</cell>
                  <cell/>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell>Nov 6</cell>
                  <cell>one Poncho</cell>
                  <cell>1.75</cell>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell>Pants Ca</cell>
                  <cell>3.55</cell>
                  <cell/>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell>May 12</cell>
                  <cell>one Pr Shoes</cell>
                  <cell>1.48</cell>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell>Pants Inl</cell>
                  <cell>2.50</cell>
                  <cell/>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell>June 30</cell>
                  <cell>1 Shirt, 1 Pants</cell>
                  <cell>4.03</cell>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell>Blouses</cell>
                  <cell>2.35</cell>
                  <cell/>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell>Jn 30</cell>
                  <cell>1 Canteen</cell>
                  <cell>.90</cell>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell>Shirts</cell>
                  <cell>1.53</cell>
                  <cell/>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell>Sep 17th</cell>
                  <cell>1 pr Shoes</cell>
                  <cell>1.86</cell>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell>Drawers</cell>
                  <cell>.90</cell>
                  <cell/>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell>&quot; Knit</cell>
                  <cell>1.08</cell>
                  <cell/>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell>Boots Swued</cell>
                  <cell>2.05</cell>
                  <cell/>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell>&quot; Pegged</cell>
                  <cell>2.82</cell>
                  <cell/>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell>Shoes Swued</cell>
                  <cell>2.05</cell>
                  <cell/>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell>&quot; Pegged</cell>
                  <cell>1.48</cell>
                  <cell/>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell>Socks</cell>
                  <cell>.32</cell>
                  <cell/>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell>OverCoat Cav</cell>
                  <cell>8.95</cell>
                  <cell/>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell>Overcoat Inf</cell>
                  <cell>7.30</cell>
                  <cell/>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell>Blankets</cell>
                  <cell>3.25</cell>
                  <cell/>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell>Rubber &quot;</cell>
                  <cell>1.08</cell>
                  <cell/>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell>Ponchos</cell>
                  <cell>2.73</cell>
                  <cell/>
               </row>
            </table>
            <pb n="47" facs="0012_001560_000201_0047.jpg" xml:id="d4e1430"/>
            <table rows="13" cols="4">
               <row role="data">
                  <cell>MEMORANDA.</cell>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell>Date.</cell>
                  <cell/>
                  <cell>Dolls.</cell>
                  <cell>Cts.</cell>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell>2</cell>
                  <cell>A.C. Null</cell>
                  <cell>15.</cell>
                  <cell>00</cell>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell>2</cell>
                  <cell>W.W. Dulls</cell>
                  <cell>15.</cell>
                  <cell>00</cell>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell>1</cell>
                  <cell>F. Berckhemer</cell>
                  <cell>15.</cell>
                  <cell>00</cell>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell>2</cell>
                  <cell>E.J. Hall</cell>
                  <cell>12.</cell>
                  <cell>00</cell>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell>2</cell>
                  <cell>J.G. Post</cell>
                  <cell>12.</cell>
                  <cell>00</cell>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell>3</cell>
                  <cell>G. Beery</cell>
                  <cell>15.</cell>
                  <cell>00</cell>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell>3</cell>
                  <cell>W.J.G. Erstill</cell>
                  <cell>15.</cell>
                  <cell>00</cell>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell>5</cell>
                  <cell>John R. Strattan</cell>
                  <cell>21.</cell>
                  <cell>00</cell>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell>29.</cell>
                  <cell>N.G. Kirk</cell>
                  <cell>0.</cell>
                  <cell>50</cell>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell>25.</cell>
                  <cell>John W. Faweell</cell>
                  <cell>0.</cell>
                  <cell>50</cell>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell>March</cell>
                  <cell>W.J. Bentley</cell>
                  <cell>1.</cell>
                  <cell>00</cell>
               </row>
               <row role="data">
                  <cell/>
                  <cell>L. Barnaby one Pr of Socks</cell>
                  <cell>.</cell>
                  <cell>32</cell>
               </row>
            </table>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
