<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000649_000201_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>
               <name>Tilghman Blazer</name> Journal, 
					<date when="1864-04-26">April 26, 1864</date>
            </title>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>White, Park</name>
            </respStmt>
            <author>
               <name type="person">Tilghman Blazer</name>
            </author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <availability status="restricted">
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_000649_000201_0000</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Tilghman Blazer Journal, April 26, 1864</title>
               <date when="1864-04-26">April 26, 1864</date>
               <author>
                  <name type="person">Tilghman Blazer</name>
               </author>
               <extent>86 pages</extent>
               <note type="collection">Tilghman Blazer Papers</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS.2174</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
						omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Nashville (Tenn.) -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.</term>
               <term>Tennessee -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives.</term>
               <term>Tennessee -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Regimental Histories.</term>
               <term>Tennessee -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.</term>
               <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Campaigns.</term>
               <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Regimental histories.</term>
               <term>United States. Army. Tennessee Infantry Regiment, 8th (1862-1865).</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change who="White, Park">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
         <change when="2013-10-03" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="journal">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_000649_000201_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e34"/>
            <p>[Front Cover]</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_000649_000201_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e38"/>
            <p>[Front Cover Verso]</p>
            <p>Salicylic acid</p>
            <pb/>
            <pb/>
            <pb n="5" facs="0012_000649_000201_0005.jpg" xml:id="d4e52"/>
            <p>Transactions of the United States forces in the South West under Gen W.T. Shareman comencing the 26th April 1864, the army under Gen Schofield, left Bulls Gap
				   E. Tenn  Hawkins Co  on the night of the 26th Apr/64 for Charleston Tennessee at which place we arrived on the 28th Inst and remaned hear till May the 3rd at
				   5 O cl A M we moved out toward Cleavland Tenn  marched 16 miles which put us 5 miles below Cleavland on the camping ground of the 4th Corps at 1, o,cl P.M.</p>
            <p>May the 4th army moved out and marched one mile beyond Red Clay Dep. one mile into Georgia and went into camp at 11, A.M. which was a march of 10 miles</p>
            <p>May the 5th no moove to day but Issued 5 days rations</p>
            <p>May 6th no moove to day</p>
            <p>May the 7th the army mooved in the direction of Tunel Hill 6 miles thence to the left 1 mile toward Dalton Ga and went into camp  Skirmishing pretty brisk</p>
            <pb n="6" facs="0012_000649_000201_0006.jpg" xml:id="d4e64"/>
            <p>Fedrel army taken Tunel Hill to day</p>
            <p>May the 8th no moove to day</p>
            <p>May the 9th the army mooved 4 miles to the Buzzard roost Valley heavy Skirmishing and canonading to day.  5 killed and 12 wounded in our Brigade</p>
            <p>May the 10th  Skirmishing and canonading  Federal Army retired and changed its front when firing ceased</p>
            <p>May 11th no moove to day</p>
            <p>May 12th mooved out at daybrake marched through Tunel hill and on toward the rear of Dalton and went into camp</p>
            <p>May the 13th mooved out at 2, A.M. marched through Sneak creek Gap South East of the mountains near Resaca where heavy Skirmishing was gowing on  we marched
					on in line of Battle but did not get in any engajement</p>
            <p> May 14th mooved out this morning to where the enemy was fortified where a heavy Battle was fought wich I Shall ever remember for the gallantry of our Troops</p>
            <p>May the 15th mached 2 miles to the left but did not</p>
            <pb n="7" facs="0012_000649_000201_0007.jpg" xml:id="d4e84"/>
            <p>get in an engajement though a heavy Battle was fought on the 15th by the 20 Corps  a compleate Victory gained by our fources</p>
            <p>May the 16th the enemy in full retreat our Corps which was the 23rd Corps under Genl Schofield mooved out at 11 A M marched 10 miles.</p>
            <p>May 17th crossed the Canasoga River marched 6 miles and halted and drew Rations and mooved out at dark and crossed the Coosawattee River and marched 9 miles till 3 ocl before day</p>
            <p>May the 18th Marched 11 miles and camped</p>
            <p>May the 19th Marched 10 miles near Cassville Ga  hear we drove the enemy with but little loss.</p>
            <p>May the 20th Marched 8 miles to Carcersville with Skirmishing in our front</p>
            <p>May the 21st no moove to day</p>
            <p>May the 22nd our Brigade mooved 4 miles up the Eastanola River and burnt a forge and a Rolling mill and a grist mill then returned to camp at Cartersville</p>
            <p>May the 23rd marched</p>
            <pb n="8" facs="0012_000649_000201_0008.jpg" xml:id="d4e104"/>
            <p>down the River 6 miles and camped  </p>
            <p>May the 24th crossed the River and marched 8 miles with considerable Skirmishing  Rebels ran in our rear and captured 23 waggans and burnt them</p>
            <p>May 25 no moove to day with our Brigade till 6 P.M. mooved out 4 miles and halted till 2 O Cl before day  very rainy night and dark so that we could not See a man before us
				   heare we remained till about 3 before day when we mooved out through the mud marched 6 miles whears a whears a Battle was fought on the 24th  hear we halted and got breakfast
				   which was May the 26th  after breakfast we moved out in line of Battle Skirmished till night and lay down till morning</p>
            <p>May 27th lay behind brestworks all day</p>
            <p>May 28th advanced on the enemy and built works heavy Skirmishing the enemy Shelling to night</p>
            <p>May 29th heavy firing to day of musketry and</p>
            <pb n="9" facs="0012_000649_000201_0009.jpg" xml:id="d4e118"/>
            <p>Artillery this place is what we called the 7 days breastworks near the Altony Mountain Paulding Co, Ga,</p>
            <p>May the 30th our Brigade yet in front the enemy charged our works but was repulsed</p>
            <p>May the 31st a continual firing of musketry and artillery  2 charges by the enemy on the night of the 31st Rebels repulsed with dead and woonded left on the ground hear the
				   enemy lost 30 killed 60 prisioners</p>
            <p>June the 1st 1864 our division commanded by Gen. Cox moved to the left out of the 7 days Breastworks at 11 in the night marched one mile and lay down till morning</p>
            <p>June the 2nd marched in the direction of the enemy got in contact with the enemy at 10 A M  a charge was made hear by our forces took 8 lines of works from the enemy  captured
				   one Major and Some prisioners very wet and disagreeable to night, Cob, Co. Ga</p>
            <pb n="10" facs="0012_000649_000201_0010.jpg" xml:id="d4e130"/>
            <p>June the 3rd Skirmishing and canonading up to 9 A M two Shells thrown in a few feet of wheare I was siting Slightly woonding a Horse, yesterday the 2nd Lt Cal George Lo Devergne
				   of our Regt was Shocked by a Shell</p>
            <p>June the 2nd very rainy this morning not much firing up to 1/2 past 6 A M, 20 mins after 11 A M left camp marched to the enemyes works which had been evacuated during the night,
				   very wet and rainy to night</p>
            <p>June the 5th very wet and rainy Rebels bushwacking our Regt left camp on a Scout to return at night after finding the desired place the enemy had left and left there dead and
				   woonded on the ground</p>
            <p>June the 6th on gard to day our Regt detailed to guard a amunition train  went in camp at 3 P M</p>
            <p>June 7th left camp this morning guarding Amunition train went in camp at 2 P M</p>
            <pb n="11" facs="0012_000649_000201_0011.jpg" xml:id="d4e142"/>
            <p>June the 8th all quiet and no moove to day</p>
            <p>June the 9th Cavalry mooving toward the front</p>
            <p>June the 10th Sent a leter home by Samuel Blazer mooved out 2 1/2 miles and Struck tents 2 hours till night</p>
            <p>June the 11th all quiet no moove to day very wet and unpleasant</p>
            <p>June the 12th very wet Some Shooting to day News From Tennessee that Fry had captured a No of Rebels at Greenville Tennessee</p>
            <p>June the 13th very wet and mudy to day Some firing to day and through the night cars came to Acworth to day  Rebel Jo Johnston under arrest for retreating</p>
            <p>June the 14th very coald this morning for the time of the year  mooved out at 1/2 after 6 A M marched two miles and got diner at 10 A M and drawed Rations  Our Battery
				   playing on the enemy heared from Tennessee to day by John S Haro  Rebels in Tenn in small forces  Rebel Gen Polk</p>
            <pb n="12" facs="0012_000649_000201_0012.jpg" xml:id="d4e159"/>
            <p>Killed to day the 14th our Regt on picket to day  our army advanced on the enemy to day and a heavy engagement and firing all night</p>
            <p>June the 16th the enemy retreating our army advancing hear we drew one days Rations of beacon</p>
            <p>June the 17th Marched near the Battle field Jessey S. Reeve Adjt was Shot through the body and lodged in G A Easterly, Reeve died the next day</p>
            <p>June the 18th Near Merrietta and a heavy Battle to day very wet and mudy</p>
            <p>June the 19th Mooved out 3 miles and built works and remained till the 20th and then mooved 300 yds and built works all night</p>
            <p>June 21st heavy fighting on our left to day all quiet to night</p>
            <p>June the 22nd a heavy Battle between us and Twin Mountain the 8th Tenn charged the enemy and Repulsed them  hear we built Strong works</p>
            <pb n="13" facs="0012_000649_000201_0013.jpg" xml:id="d4e175"/>
            <p>and tore down Negro Houses to get range at the enemy</p>
            <p>June the 23rd all quiet in our works but Skirmishing to Some extent</p>
            <p>June the 24  18 miles from Atlanta expecting an attack by the enemy but no engagement. Hookers forces geathered 69 dead Rebels and berried them on the
				   extreme left near Twin Mountain</p>
            <p>June 25 all quiet to day with little Skirmishing all quiet to night</p>
            <p>June 26th the army mooved out 1/2 mile and formed a line of Battle Bullets flying all around us advancing in line of Battle toward the enemy and very
				   warm and dry for water but all Standing firm and at there post</p>
            <p>June the 27 heavy firing with canon and musketry advanced toward the enemy 3 miles and built works all quiet to night</p>
            <p>June 28 building heavy works all day and night and Soldiers very tired</p>
            <p>June 30  Still working at works all day and night</p>
            <pb n="14" facs="0012_000649_000201_0014.jpg" xml:id="d4e193"/>
            <p>Skirmish fighting all day</p>
            <p>July 1st  formed a line of Battle at 4 this morning expecting an attact by the enemy  our army advancing toward the enemy a heavy charge at 20 minutes
				   after 4 P.M.</p>
            <p>July 2  heavy canonading on our left comenced at day light</p>
            <p>July 3  no moove with us to day but other troops from big hill passing toward Atlanta</p>
            <p>July 4  15th Corps passing to day</p>
            <p>July 5  mooved 1 1/2 miles and halted for the night</p>
            <p>July 6  mooved toward the enemy and found a long line of works evacuated by the enemy and crossed the Rail Road between Marrietta and Atlanta</p>
            <p>July 7  Our Brigade mooved 3 miles toward Atlanta and camped and an Order came at 12 in the night to be ready to march at 4 in the morning</p>
            <p>July 8  mooved out at daylight marched 4 miles near the</p>
            <pb n="15" facs="0012_000649_000201_0015.jpg" xml:id="d4e213"/>
            <p>Chattahoochee River and halted till the Pontoon Bridge was put across the River we then mooved out after the Bridge was across and crossed the Chattahoochee
				   at 9 in the night and took a posision on a high hill till daylight, here on this hill we captured 1 Rebel gun.</p>
            <p>July 9  mooved out on the bluff of the Chattahoochee for Picket duty and not much to eat</p>
            <p>July 10 building works to day So fighting near us to day  Capt R A Ragan in comd of the Regiment weather very warm</p>
            <p>July 11 all quiet to day</p>
            <p>July 12 Our Regt ordered back to the River to build a bridge across the Chattahoochee.</p>
            <p>July 13 at work at the Bridge.</p>
            <p>July 14 all quiet at the Bridge  the Bridge was built in two days</p>
            <p>July 15 all quiet and we have a fine time playing in the River</p>
            <pb n="16" facs="0012_000649_000201_0016.jpg" xml:id="d4e231"/>
            <p>a mess of fish for Supper to night</p>
            <p>July 16 all quiet on the Chattahoochee Col F A Reeve Resigned to day great confusion in the Regt about who shall be the comander in chief</p>
            <p>July 17 F.A. Reeve left us to day, no mooves to day, mooved out at dark and marched 6 miles and lay down</p>
            <p>July 18 marched to day to the newly graded Rail Road and halted for diner apple pie for diner to day</p>
            <p>July 19 mooved out at 6 A M toward Decator Ga the town was captured to day before we got there we then turned toward Atlanta and camped in an
				   oald field</p>
            <p>July 20 advanced one mile and formed a line of Battle. Skirmishing to day heavy on both Right and left an in the center troops advancing Rapidly
				   toward the enemy the 3rd Tenn</p>
            <pb n="17" facs="0012_000649_000201_0017.jpg" xml:id="d4e245"/>
            <p>Captured 40 Rebels in a charge at 4 P M  heavy canonading and musketry all night</p>
            <p>July 21 heavy Skirmishing on our right this morning  Engines active around Atlanta. Signal Corps in the top of poast-oak tree in plain view of Atlanta
				   Balls flying in every direction, heavy Skirmishing all night the enemy retreating.</p>
            <p>July 22 marched in one mile of Atlanta where we halted and I climed a Red Oak tree and had a view of the City</p>
            <p>July 23 heavy canonading to day the enemy made a charge on our men at Decator to day and our men fell back a Short distanceand took a posision and
				   repulsed the enemy  Our Brigade was ordered to Decator but when we got in 1 1/2 miles of the town our men had retaken the town and we halted till dark
				   and then went one mile</p>
            <pb n="18" facs="0012_000649_000201_0018.jpg" xml:id="d4e255"/>
            <p>back toward Atlanta and lay down and Stayed till morning</p>
            <p>July 24 no moove to day our cavalry returned from Covington to day dooing Important execution they burnt a large Bridge and burnt $ 3 00000.00 worth
				   cotton and captured a number of horses and mules and wagans 75 Boxes tobacco 200 Prisoners and Some Negroes and tearing up the Rail Road and destroyed
				   a quantity of other stores of all kind</p>
            <p>July 25 heavy Musket firing and canonading this morning in the direction of Atlanta</p>
            <p>July 26 no moove to day but heavy canonading around Atlanta  Mooved out after dark firing all night</p>
            <p>July 27 heavy canonading at 5 this morning on till 12 to day</p>
            <p>July 28 all quiet till 12 to day when heavy firing comenced and continued all night</p>
            <pb n="19" facs="0012_000649_000201_0019.jpg" xml:id="d4e269"/>
            <p>July 29 heavy canonading to day our Brigade out on reconoisance left there tents at the diches to return at night firing all night</p>
            <p>July the 30 a heavy engagement this morning on the right near Atlanta and continued all night</p>
            <p>July 31  all quiet this morning up to 10 A M</p>
            <p>August 1st 1864  a heavy Battle on our right this morning at day light near Atlanta, two hours till Sundown firing comenced again moved out 3 miles to night
				   and lay down at 12 in the night</p>
            <p>Aug 2  mooved out at 6 A M and marched till 11 A M and halted one hour for diner and then marched to the front on the South west Side of Atlanta and built
				   works light Skirmishing all night</p>
            <p>Aug 3  all quiet till late in the eavning when an engagement comenced with Artillery at the rate of 100 Shots in 4 minutes which lasted</p>
            <pb n="20" facs="0012_000649_000201_0020.jpg" xml:id="d4e283"/>
            <p>about one hour light Skirmishing all night</p>
            <p>Aug 4  all quiet up to. 8. A.M  we mooved 2 miles toward the front when an engagement with artillery lasted one hour Shot and Shell flying all around us firing
				   Seased at dark</p>
            <p>Aug 5  Rapid firing this morning on our right at 5, O, Cl a charge made this morning at 9 by our men captured about 200 Rebels our loss not yet Known mooved by
				   the right flank at 12 A M and halted at 3 P M and halted for the night  Skirmishing all night</p>
            <p>Aug 6th  a charge at 5 A M a charge at 9 A M a charge at 1 P M with dreadfull Slaughter on our Side  our Regt the 8th Tennessee lost 83 men in the charge also
				   there collers and coller bearers among the wounded was Wm Winter Co. B. Daniel Rader Co. B. who died during the night</p>
            <pb n="21" facs="0012_000649_000201_0021.jpg" xml:id="d4e293"/>
            <p>Jos. A Eatherton, Co. K  one Lt was Killed of Co. A. one 1st Lt Co. G. leg broken by a Shot and was amputated the next day the 8th Tenn charged manfully till in a
				   few Steps of the works where they was ordered to fall back but the fire was So heavy the men lay down and cralled off the best they could  heavy canonading at the
				   rate of 50 Shots a minute a heavy rain fell during the night which our poor woonded men was compelled to take without any Shelter  Skirmishing all night</p>
            <p>Aug 7  Skirmishing this morning up to 9 too Charges by  our men out at 2 P M and at 3 P M Rebels repulsed heavy Skirmishing all night.</p>
            <p>Aug 8th  2 1/2 miles from the Rail Road on the South west Side of Atlanta heavy Skirmishing all night</p>
            <pb n="22" facs="0012_000649_000201_0022.jpg" xml:id="d4e301"/>
            <p>Aug 9th  Skirmishing to day up to 12 A M our forces advancing by the right flank 2 Batteryes oopened on the enemy at 6 this eavning 2 1/2 miles from the Rail Road
				   and 6 from Atlanta.  We remained here till the 12th when we was ordered to the right</p>
            <p>Aug 13 &amp; 14 all quiet</p>
            <p>Aug 15th  all quiet</p>
            <p>Aug 16  mooved 2 miles to the right and built Strong works</p>
            <p>Aug 17  all quiet and the boy&apos;s out foraging</p>
            <p>Aug 18  mooved out at 12 to day and marched by the right flank and built works</p>
            <p>Aug 19th  all quiet to day</p>
            <p>Aug 20  all quiet to day</p>
            <p>Aug 22nd  Capt R A Ragan  R Kelly and Myself put up a bank to day</p>
            <p>Aug 23  Tea for diner to day by R A Ragan and T Blazer  George Frist  and Robt Kelly out foraging and brought in Some fine roastnears  all quiet to day</p>
            <pb n="23" facs="0012_000649_000201_0023.jpg" xml:id="d4e324"/>
            <p>August 24 Some canonading to day at 9 A.M.</p>
            <p>Aug 25  not well to day</p>
            <p>Aug 26  not well to day and very weak  Some fighting to day on our left</p>
            <p>Aug 27  not well to day.  Some fighting to day</p>
            <p>Aug 28  Some better this morning, mooved 3 miles and formed a line of Battle</p>
            <p>Aug 29th Mooved out at 7 A.M. marched 1 1/2 miles forward then 1 mile by the left Flank and formed a line of Battle  The 8th Tenn and 104 Ohio guarding the
				   Junction in the rear of the line of Battle</p>
            <p>Aug 30  Marched at 6 A M to the Mobile Rail Road and halted for diner then marched in 4 miles of East Point and built works  Bought a Bucket full of honey
				   this eavning for 50 cents and 2 corn cakes for one quart Sugar.</p>
            <p>Aug 31st  Marched toward the Macon Rail Road and got to the Road 30 minutes after 11 in the eavning our Skirmishers almost captured a train of cars</p>
            <pb n="24" facs="0012_000649_000201_0024.jpg" xml:id="d4e342"/>
            <p>we fortified all night heavy canonading all night</p>
            <p>Sept 1st 1864  heavy firing this morning on our right  we are now 13 miles below Atlanta near Eeastport where we destroyed the Rail Road toward East port
				   the army returned from destroying the road at 9 A M  while the boys was gone I grated corn and baked Bread for diner  we then mooved out at 1, ocl P M in
				   the direction of Macon  Struck the Rail Road 4 miles from Jonesborough where the Road was all destroyed   Gen Haskels Division Passing while we are resting
				   heavy canonading at 6 this eavning, we camped for the night in a large cornfield where we had plenty of roastnears</p>
            <p>Sept 2nd  too miles from Jonesborough  Marched at 1/2 after 9 A M in the direction of Atlanta then by the left flank on the South Side of Jonesborough  a
				   heavy Battle on our right at 6 P M</p>
            <pb n="25" facs="0012_000649_000201_0025.jpg" xml:id="d4e350"/>
            <p>we marched till 11 in the night</p>
            <p>Rebels left Atlanta on the night of the 2nd Sept 1864 burning Several trains of cars with Guns and a large quantity amunition  The burning of the amunition
				   took place about 12 or 1 ocl in the night which caused much excitement for we thought it was a heavy engagement had taken place  The explosions lasted about
				   one hour  we passed the Rebel Hospitle to day in the woods below Jonesborough where the enemy was forced to leave there dead and woonded in the woods without
				   any Shelter and a heavy rain fell during the night</p>
            <p>Sept 3rd  Battery oopened on the enemy at 7 A M  we are now 36 mls below  Atlanta,</p>
            <p>Sept 4th  all quiet except light Skirmishing</p>
            <p>Sept 5  Skirmishing and a canon Shot occasionally up tom 7 A M.  4 Ocl P M waggans and ambulance train Started Back</p>
            <pb n="26" facs="0012_000649_000201_0026.jpg" xml:id="d4e362"/>
            <p>toward Atlanta, a heavy rain fell this eavning, we packed up to move toward Atlanta but did not moove out till 12 in the night  very mudy and dark and
				   unpleasant marching  we marched till 4 in the morning and halted till day light,</p>
            <p>Sept 6  Mooved out at daylight and marched till 8 A M and went into camp</p>
            <p>Sept 7  we recieved news news this morning that the Rebel John Morgan was killed at Greenville Tennessee  the army mooved out at 10 A M and went into camp at
				   5 P M 6 miles from Atlanta</p>
            <p>Sept 8  Marched at daylight toward Decator Ga  we arived at Decator at 12 to day and marched through with music and colors to the Brass  we went into camp
				   one mile from Decator</p>
            <p>Sept 9  all quiet</p>
            <pb n="27" facs="0012_000649_000201_0027.jpg" xml:id="d4e374"/>
            <p>Sept 10 all quiet and resting from the toils of many long days and nights</p>
            <p>Sept 11 all quiet up to the 15th</p>
            <p>Sept 15 mooved camp to day across the Rail Road and put up tents in regular Millitary form</p>
            <p>Sept 16 all quiet up to the 17th</p>
            <p>Sept 17 R A Ragan Resigned to day all quiet up to the 20th</p>
            <p>Sept 20/64  R A Ragan Started home to day</p>
            <p>Sept 21 all quiet up to the 25</p>
            <p>Sept 25 a great victory in the Shenadoah Valley 2000 prisioners captured</p>
            <p>Sept 26 all quiet</p>
            <p>Sept 27 forage train attacted by the enemy</p>
            <p>Sept 28 all quiet</p>
            <p>Sept 29 8 Tenn with forage train to day but returned at night</p>
            <p>Sept 30 the 8th Tennessee Payed to day</p>
            <p>Oct 1st 1864  all quiet</p>
            <p>Oct 2  horserace to day, we are now ordered to be ready to march at 1 P M</p>
            <pb n="28" facs="0012_000649_000201_0028.jpg" xml:id="d4e407"/>
            <p>all ready at 1 P M but the order countermanded</p>
            <p>Oct 4th  mooved out at 6 A M and crossed the Chattahooche River in the eavning 7 miles from Atlanta and near the Rail Road Bridge and marched up
				   the valey of the Chattahoochee and camped for the night</p>
            <p>Oct 5th  while our army was wating for the train to get in front I proseeded to the high posision in view of all the country for Several miles and
				   in view of the Chattahoochee winding through its channel toward the great Mississipi  a Pleasant view could be seen of the many thousand troops and
				   waggans moving up the vealey of the Chattahoochee toward Marrietta  we mooved out at 10 A M and passed through Marritta at half after 4 P M and
				   halted at dark and camped for the night  it rained during the night and the water ran through our tents</p>
            <pb n="29" facs="0012_000649_000201_0029.jpg" xml:id="d4e415"/>
            <p>Oct 6th here we have a view of the Kiney-Saw Mountain and the Rebel works where Some heavy Battles was fought  we moved out at 7 A M and the road very
				   mudy we marched 10 miles to day and went into camp at dark</p>
            <p>Oct 7  Report this morning that the enemy is mooving toward Tennessee  Some canonading to day on the South Side of our lines  no moove to day all quiet
				   during the night</p>
            <p>Oct 8th  all quiet this morning  we mooved out at 2 P M passed through Acworth and on toward Altony Station</p>
            <p>Oct 9  all quiet this morning  we had a view of the woonded Rebels that was woonded on the 5th Inst in a charge they made on our Supplies at Altony
				   Station  Many of them was Shot down with a cracker box on there Shoulder for they was all most Starved to death, and awfull Seen to look at the many amputated</p>
            <pb n="30" facs="0012_000649_000201_0030.jpg" xml:id="d4e425"/>
            <p>Legs and armes that was lying on the ground not yet berried  no moove</p>
            <p>Oct 10th  mooved out at 8 A M marched through Altony Station and on to Cartersville  we crossed the Etowah River before we got to Cartersville and from
				   Cartersville we marched to near Cassville and camped for the night</p>
            <p>Oct 11  mooved into Cassville and halted till 9 A M here the 8th Tennessee was detailed to guard a waggan trane to Kingston Ga</p>
            <p>Oct 12th  marched to Rome Ga to day from Kingston to Rome is 16 miles  Rome is a nice City between too Rivers and Eastanola the other name I did not learn</p>
            <p>Oct 13  mooved out at 8 A M marched through Rome and crossed the Eastanola River on Pontoon and mooved toward the Allabama line but did not go but 6 miles
				   where we got into a fight with the enemy</p>
            <pb n="31" facs="0012_000649_000201_0031.jpg" xml:id="d4e437"/>
            <p>we routed the enemy and captured 3 Guns and horses with 30 prisioners  the horses very poor and not any Service to the Federal army after the fight  we
				   returned to Rome in the eavning and camped on the same ground that we occupied the previous night</p>
            <p>Oct 14  we mooved out at 6 A M and marched in the direction of Dalton we went into camp 1 1/2 hours after dark</p>
            <p>Oct 15  mooved out at 6 A M and marched to Calhoon till 12 A M a distance of 10 miles and halted for diner then to Resacca 6 miles from Calhoon and 22 miles
				   from Rome  we crossed the Coosa River at Sundown and marched through Resacca and camped till morning</p>
            <p>Oct 16th  mooved out at daylight in the direction of Sneak creek Gap.  we arrived at the Gap where we found the Road was blockaded with timber by the enemy</p>
            <pb n="32" facs="0012_000649_000201_0032.jpg" xml:id="d4e447"/>
            <p>to check our advance on them  whilst they was marching toward Tennessee the Road was oopened and we passed through the Gap at 3 P M and camped on a high
				   gravly Ridge</p>
            <p>Oct 17  mooved out toward Sumerville in the direction of Allabama</p>
            <p>Oct 18  our march still toward Sumerville</p>
            <p>Oct 19  mooved out at 9 A M crossed the Chattaooga River at 11 A M passed in Sight of Sumerville at 12 A M and went into camp at 5 P M near the State line
				   between Ga and Allabama</p>
            <p>Oct 20th  mooved out at 7 A M and crossed the Georgia and Allabama line at 9 ocl where our Band played away down in the Allabam  we marched on through Galesville
				   Allabama and marched 1 1/2 miles and camped on the bank of the Chattooga River</p>
            <pb n="33" facs="0012_000649_000201_0033.jpg" xml:id="d4e459"/>
            <p>Oct 21st  all quiet to day and no moove to day  our men fixing the bridge across the Chattooga.</p>
            <p>Oct 22  no moove to day</p>
            <p>Oct 23  no moove to day</p>
            <p>Oct 24  mooved one half mile toward Galesville and camped in a field where we built a framed tent and was well fixed with comfortable quarters and Several
				   large pumpkins that we got where the cavalry troops had left</p>
            <p>Oct 25  mooved to Cedar Bluff Alla on the bank of the Coosa River</p>
            <p>Oct 26  the Boys out on a Scout to day but returned at night</p>
            <p>Oct 27  Started a Leter home to day by D.R.B Winniford  Recd a leter from E J Williams at 12 ocl in the night and one from home on the night of the 25th</p>
            <p>Oct 28  mooved out at 12 A M and crossed the Coosa River and marched 7 miles through a forest of Pine timber the finest that I ever Saw, camped at 5 P M</p>
            <pb n="34" facs="0012_000649_000201_0034.jpg" xml:id="d4e478"/>
            <p>Oct 29th  mooved out at 6 toward Rome Georgia left cavo pring this morning for Rome Ga</p>
            <p>Oct 30  Passed through Rome after crossing the Eastanolia River and camped too miles from Rome.</p>
            <p>Oct 31st  Started a package of leters home by Lt Hines  we mooved out at 7 A M toward Calhoon Ga and camped in 1/2 mile of Calhoon in a large field where there
				   was a large quantity of apricots</p>
            <p>Nov 1st  we mooved out at 6 A M and passed through Calhoon at 7 and on toward Resacca at 10 in the morning and marched one mile and halted for diner  we then
				   marched to Tilton Station below Dalton Ga and camped till morning</p>
            <p>Nov 2  mooved out at 12 A M and marched to Dalton Ga  the Road very mudy and heard marching</p>
            <pb n="35" facs="0012_000649_000201_0035.jpg" xml:id="d4e490"/>
            <p>we arrived at Dalton at 5 in the eavning and camped in the rewined City  heare we was compelled to throw old houses down to make fire for we had no other chance
				   for wood and the weather wet and coald</p>
            <p>Nov 3  we was ordered to be ready to take the trane to night for Chattanooga Tennessee but did not moove,</p>
            <p>November 4  all quiet and we remained here till the 6th Inst  when we mooved out and got on the Trane the trane left Dalton 20 min after 10 A M and arrived at
				   Chattanooga at 5 in the eavning and Stoped one hour for Rations  when we left Chattanooga and traveled all night</p>
            <p>Nov 7th passed through Tulahoma to day but was detained at this place too or three hours  here we bought apples and pies and enjoyed our Selvs first  first rate
				   we arived at</p>
            <pb n="36" facs="0012_000649_000201_0036.jpg" xml:id="d4e500"/>
            <p>Nashville Tenn about too  hours before day and remained on the trane till daylight,</p>
            <p>Nov 8th 1864  to day was a day of Pleasure with the Soldiers  we voted for President to day and every thing Seemed to be working right  the Streets was crowded
				   all day with Ladies Selling apples and cakes and pies to the Soldiers that had So gallantly fought throug and over the planes of Georgia and this the only day
				   of much pleasure during the Ga Campaign.  The Streets of Nashville was very mudy and it Rained most all day.  we left Nashville at 7 in the night on the trane
				   we arrived at Franklin Tenn before day and Stoped till daylight</p>
            <p>Nov 9  we left Franklin at 1 P M and rolled on to near Spring hill</p>
            <pb n="37" facs="0012_000649_000201_0037.jpg" xml:id="d4e508"/>
            <p>where the Engine was thrown off and three boxes of the trane  here we was detained about 3 or 4 hours  another trane was brought and we mooved our baggage on the
				   other trane and got to Spring hill at 8 in the night,</p>
            <p>Nov 10  all quiet to day</p>
            <p>Nov 11  me and Lieut Alexander Ragan making paroles to day at a private house where we had Some good times by a Lady on the Piano</p>
            <p>Nov 12  Recd a leter from home and one from E J Williams date Oct 23</p>
            <p>Nov 13  mooved out on the Pike leading to Pulaski Tenn at 7 in the morning marched to Columbia and camped on the bank of Duck River</p>
            <p>Nov 14  we crossed Duck River at 8 A M and marched through Columbia and halted at 3 P M for diner and then we mooved on to Linville</p>
            <pb n="38" facs="0012_000649_000201_0038.jpg" xml:id="d4e522"/>
            <p>and camped till morning  This Village is nearly all burnt and not much remanes here but the Chimneys of the burnt houses</p>
            <p>Nov 15  mooved out at daylight and marched to near Pulaski Tenn  heare we remained till the 22nd when we Started back toward Nashville  on the eavning of the 22
				   we arived at Linville and the eavning was very coald  we camped here till 4 in the eavning of the 23 when we mooved out toward Columbia  we marched till a late
				   hour in the night when we laid down tired and weary without any Supper  On the morning of the 24 we mooved out at daybrake and marched for Columbia for the enemy
				   was trying to cut off our retreat  we arived near Columbia at 8 on</p>
            <pb n="39" facs="0012_000649_000201_0039.jpg" xml:id="d4e528"/>
            <p>the morning of the 25 Nov and the enemy forcing our Cavalry to retreat  here a line of Battle was formed and a few Shells Soon mad the enemy retreat  a line of
				   works was Speedily thrown up  we worked during the night and was ready for the enemy on the morning of the 26th  we crossed the River at 2 in the night and and
				   took a posision on the North Side of the River  the 8th Tennessee was placed at the ford to prevent the enemy from puting pontoon across the River  heavy Skirmishing
				   was all the fighting that occured here and on the South Side of the river till the 28th Nov when the enemy got range at the 8 Tenn that was guarding the ford and
				   Shelled them out there works  the 8th fell back a Short distance</p>
            <pb n="40" facs="0012_000649_000201_0040.jpg" xml:id="d4e532"/>
            <p>and held the ford till before day on the morning of the 29 when the 8th Tenn was releaved and rested the 29th till dark  heavy canonading and musketry firing was
				   kept up all day  the 4th Corps mooving toward Franklin and the 23 Corps in the rere  we left a rere guard behind and the 23 Corps mooved out at dark for Franklin
				   and Passed Spring hill at 12 or 1 ocl in the night and all most tired out for we had not Slept much for Several nights  and the enemy expecting to capture the 23 Corps
				   we was hurried to Franklin at which place we arived about one hour before day</p>
            <p>November the 30  we was ordered to form a line of Battle at daylight which Speedily don and good works was</p>
            <pb n="41" facs="0012_000649_000201_0041.jpg" xml:id="d4e538"/>
            <p>thrown up before our works was compleated  the enemy was in view of our works on a high hill in our front  at one Ocl the enemy began to form there lines for the expected
				   charge  but did not Charge till 3 or 4 Ocl in the eavning  when they charged our works with there columns but was repulsed.  the enemy mad 7 charges in the center but was
				   beaten back evry time with heavy loss both killed woonded and prisioners  a most desperate Slaughter of the enemy was to be Seen here  the Battle lasted till after dark
				   the firing almost Seased and we mooved out for Nashville  the 8th Tennessee had Some 30 or 40 prisioners  the most of which was lying on the ground in front of our works
				   to escape the heavy fire that was pooring in to there ranks from our works when the firing</p>
            <pb n="42" facs="0012_000649_000201_0042.jpg" xml:id="d4e542"/>
            <p>Seased we crossed the works and brought thos not woonded over and as before Stated proseeded to Nashville at this Glorious Victory we captured 30 Rebel flags the enemy lost
				   in killed woonded and captured near 7000 our loss was about 2000 in all  we arived at Nashville on the 1st Decr/64 after a toilsome march from Franklin for the Road was
				   crowded with waggans, Artillery and ambulaces and the Road was allmost impassable for the Infantry  after arriving at Nashville our Baggage trane came up and we put up tents
				   and enjoyed a good nights rest for we was all most worn out for we had not had but very little rest Since we left Pulaski  on the 22nd Nov the enemy continued there vigorous
				   pursuit to near Nashville where they</p>
            <pb n="43" facs="0012_000649_000201_0043.jpg" xml:id="d4e546"/>
            <p>was halted by our forces that was well prepared for the reception of the hostile Rebel General Hood and his army that had been badly defeated at Franklin.  Several days
				   passed off around Nashville with no fighting except Skirmishing on the 15th December 1864.  a portion of the army made the attact on the left and center of the Rebel line
				   and the 4th and 23 Corps mooved by the right flank with a large force of Cavalry on the eavning of the 15 the Cavalry dismounted and charged a Rebel Fort <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">fefon</unclear>
				   the Infantry could get up with them,  the fort was captured with a No of Prisioners &amp; 4 peaces of Artillery that was turned and fired on the retreating enemy as they left,
				   and the fort  the Old Stars and Stripes was Soon hoisted on</p>
            <pb n="44" facs="0012_000649_000201_0044.jpg" xml:id="d4e553"/>
            <p>On the Fort  the whole line now Seemed to be engaged and we could hear nothing but loud cheering and the loud belching Canon, and a continual firing of musketry  the enemy
				   was now in full retreat and we was closely pursewing them, the enemy beeing So closely pursewed in order to Save there trane made a Stand to check our advance  our line was
				   formed in about 400 Yds of the enemy and works was thrown up by both armies  we worked all night and only a Shot once and while was heared on the picket line which was about
				   400 Yds apart  the works was compleated by day light</p>
            <p>December the 16th  to day was a dangerous day for the too amies being in Gun Shot of each other  a man was in danger to rase his head above the works</p>
            <pb/>
            <p>The enemy had a posision more than equal to ours, but Seemed Inclined to want to Save there amunition as much as possible, our Artillery played on the enemies line all day
				   tearing the timber down over there heads and lifting the head logs off there works  only a few Shots of artillery was given from the enemy during this, althoug they had the
				   best ground but did not reply to our Batteries, a charge was ordered by Gen Thomas which was gallantly don with but little loss  the charge was made at 5 in the eavning and
				   the enemy retreated leaving there guns and equipments haver Sacks Canteens and Blankets on the ground with 4 peaces of artillery in front of the 8th Tenn before the charge
				   here Several hundred prisioners was taken one whole division or the most of it</p>
            <pb n="46" facs="0012_000649_000201_0046.jpg" xml:id="d4e564"/>
            <p>Surrendered with but little resistance  another Victory to our gallant boys was now to be Seen.  the night of the 16th was miserable for our wearied Soldiers it rained all
				   night,</p>
            <p>Decr 17th  we mooved out on the Granny white Pike it rained and was very unpleasant and the road So mudy the army could heardly march  we marched but a Short distance till
				   night we marched till a late hour in the night and the road became allmost empassable  we had to march through mud up to our knees in many places, we arrived at camp and the
				   most of us lay down with out any tent, and it was drizling rain and the ground very wet</p>
            <p>Decr 18  we mooved out early this morning our Rations having given out and we had no breakfast  we marched to the left and got on the Franklin Pike where our train</p>
            <pb n="47" facs="0012_000649_000201_0047.jpg" xml:id="d4e572"/>
            <p>was waiting for us in order to give us Rations, here we drawed rations and had breakfast and a large no  of Prisioners passed us here that our forces had captured on there
				   retreat  after breakfast we mooved out toward Franklin</p>
            <p>Decr 19th  marched to Franklin to day and viewed the Battlefield of the 30th Nov  we went into camp at 5 P M it was wet and coald all night and we had but little rest on
				   account of the coald,</p>
            <p>Decr 20th  we mooved out at 8 A M and marched to Spring Hill and camped</p>
            <p>Decr 21  no moove to day</p>
            <p>Decr 22  no moove to day but very coald</p>
            <p>Decr 23  we mooved at at 8 A. M. and marched near Columbia Tenn and camped</p>
            <p>Decr 24  no moove to day, official report of the number of Rebel officers captured on the 15-16 and 17 was 311  the No of officers from each State was as follows</p>
            <pb n="48" facs="0012_000649_000201_0048.jpg" xml:id="d4e588"/>
            <p>From   Tennessee   31</p>
            <p>&quot; Alabama     34</p>
            <p>&quot; Mississippi 42</p>
            <p>&quot; Georgia     31</p>
            <p>&quot; Louisiana   12</p>
            <p>&quot; Arkansas     8</p>
            <p>&quot; Florida     11</p>
            <p>&quot; S. Carolina  3</p>
            <p>and the others from Texas  Missouri  Kentucky and N Carolina</p>
            <p>Decr 25  no moove to day</p>
            <p>Decr 26  we mooved out at daylight crossed duck River at 8 A M and marched through Columbia and went into camp one mile South of Columbia  here we remained till
				   Jany 2nd 1865  the weather was very coald during the time we Stayed here  on the</p>
            <p>2nd day of January  we mooved out at 7 A M toward the Tennessee River  we passed through Mount pleasant at # A M an camped too miles from Town</p>
            <pb n="49" facs="0012_000649_000201_0049.jpg" xml:id="d4e615"/>
            <p>Jany 3  we mooved out at daylight and left the Pike and traveled through a Poor and usettled part of Tennessee  we went into camp about 1 1/2 hours before night.</p>
            <p>Jany 4th  we mooved out at 12 to day after drawing Rations and marched down Rock house creek and on to Buffalou River  we had to wade the River and before fires
				   could be erected the men was allmost froze  it was 10 in the night when we crossed the River and camped on the Bank</p>
            <p>Jany 5  we mooved out at daylight and marched through Ashland and on to 48 creek a beautiful Stream of water as I ever Saw  we marched through Hainesborough and
				   camped on a high hill</p>
            <p>Jany 6  we mooved out at daylight and marched through the Coaling-Ground near the Tennessee Ironworks</p>
            <pb n="50" facs="0012_000649_000201_0050.jpg" xml:id="d4e625"/>
            <p>when many hundred acres of timber had been cut off for the Support of the Tennessee Ironworks  here we Struck the Pike leading to the Tennessee River we marched
				   in 3 miles of the Tennessee River and camped, Snow and very coald  at 3 in the eavning,</p>
            <p>Jany 7  no moove to day</p>
            <p>Jany the 8  mooved Camp to day across the Road</p>
            <p>Jany 9  no moove</p>
            <p>Jany 10  the 8th Tennessee was detailed tonight to go to the River to unload a Steam boat and returned in three hours,</p>
            <p>Jany 11  we remained here till the night of the 16 when we mooved to the River  on the 14th Inst  I Received a leter from E J Williams date Decr 5/64  on the night
				   of the 16th we got on the Steamer Bertha at 11 in the night and mooved off at 4 in the morning</p>
            <pb n="51" facs="0012_000649_000201_0051.jpg" xml:id="d4e639"/>
            <p>Jany 17th  our fleet Numbered 14 vessels with one Gunboat as our Pilote, which left us at Paducha on the night of the 17 and turned up the Ohio River  we arived at
				   Louisville  Kentucky on the 20th at 7 in the morning here  I Started a leter home by Lieut David Green of the 8 Tenn Co B.  also one to E J Williams  Passed Madison
				   Indiana at 9 in the night</p>
            <p>Jany 21  arived at Cincinnatti at 8 this morning, here we left the Boat and took the trane  at dark we arrived at Columbus Ohio before day and remained till daylight
				   and got Breakfast  the ground was covered with Snow and very coald and no fire on the trane  we Suffered very much.  from Columbus we rolled for Bellare on the Ohio
				   River and arrived at Bellare at 3 in the night</p>
            <pb n="52" facs="0012_000649_000201_0052.jpg" xml:id="d4e645"/>
            <p>and crossed the River on a Steam Boat in to Brentwood in to Virginia  here Coffey was made for us, we then passed on and arrived at Cumberland City Maryland at 6 in the
				   eavning and halted about one hour and passed on,</p>
            <p>Jany 24  we arrived at Harpersferry at 5 in the morning, and coffey and Soft Bread was furnished us at point of Rocks five miles from Harpersferry</p>
            <p>Jany 25  we passed through Washington City at 8 in the night and arrived at Alexandria at 9 on the night of the 25  we left the trane and went to the Soldiers rest where
				   we remained the remainder of the night</p>
            <p>Jany 26  in Soldiers rest on the night of the 27 I was</p>
            <pb n="53" facs="0012_000649_000201_0053.jpg" xml:id="d4e655"/>
            <p>From the time we got on the Boat at Clifton Tennessee on the night of the 16,</p>
            <p>Jany /65  I was very unwell all the time till we arrived at Alexandria Va on the night of the 25  and on the night of the 26 I was taken to the Christian commission
				   Hospital where I remained till the 1st day of February when I was taken to the United States Hospitle, called Washington Street Hospt where I have been under the care of
				   Dr Dunning U. S. Surgeon up to the preasant date  March the 16th 1865  Alexandria Va</p>
            <p>The 23rd Corps left Alexandria Va on the 4th Feb 1865</p>
            <p>Tilghman Blazer</p>
            <p>8th Tenn V Inftry</p>
            <p>1st Brig 3rd Div 23 A C</p>
            <pb n="54" facs="0012_000649_000201_0054.jpg" xml:id="d4e669"/>
            <p>Alexandria Virginia  March the 17th 1865</p>
            <p>Mar 17     New York  Gold                      $169 1/2</p>
            <p>Mar &quot; at 12, O,Cl: A.M. New York  Gold     163</p>
            <p>Mar 18     New York  Gold                       160</p>
            <p>Mar 23     New York  Gold                       152 1/2</p>
            <p>Mar 31     New York  Gold                       152 3/8</p>
            <p>April 1st  New York  Gold                       151</p>
            <p>Apr 2nd    New York  Gold                       154</p>
            <p>April 3rd  Capture of Richmond this morning
				   at 15 min after 8 ocl A M</p>
            <p>Apr 3rd    New York  Gold                       146 3/4</p>
            <p>Apr 4th    New York  Gold                       147 3/4</p>
            <p>Apr 3rd    United States forces entered
				   Petersburg this morning at 3 O Cl A.M.</p>
            <p>April 5    New York  Gold                       152 3/4</p>
            <p>Apr   6    New York  Gold                       150 1/2</p>
            <p>Apr   8    &quot;    &quot;                     147 1/8</p>
            <p>Ap   10    &quot;    &quot;                     144 7/8</p>
            <p>Apr  11    &quot;    &quot;                     145</p>
            <pb n="55" facs="0012_000649_000201_0055.jpg" xml:id="d4e706"/>
            <p>Mr  Eligah Lemay</p>
            <p>Chamberlain Po office</p>
            <p>Indiana  Allen  co</p>
            <p>Apr  12th   New York  Gold                      145 3/4</p>
            <p>Apr  13     &quot;    &quot;                    146</p>
            <p>Apr  21     &quot;    &quot;                    150 1/4</p>
            <p>Apr  22     &quot;    &quot;                    149 1/2</p>
            <p>Apr  25     &quot;    &quot;                    150 3/4</p>
            <p>Apr  27     &quot;    &quot;                    149 3/4</p>
            <p>Apr  29     &quot;    &quot;                    14  1/2</p>
            <p>May   2     &quot;    &quot;                    141 1/2</p>
            <p>May   3     &quot;    &quot;                    141 3/4</p>
            <p>May   4     &quot;    &quot;                    142 3/4</p>
            <p>May   6     &quot;    &quot;                    143</p>
            <p>May   8     &quot;    &quot;                    137 1/8</p>
            <p>May   9     &quot;    &quot;                    136 1/4</p>
            <p>May  10     &quot;    &quot;                    129 3/8</p>
            <p>May  11     &quot;    &quot;                    130</p>
            <p>May  12     &quot;    &quot;                    132 3/8</p>
            <p>May  13     &quot;    &quot;                    130 1/8</p>
            <p>May  15     &quot;    &quot;                    131 1/4</p>
            <pb n="56" facs="0012_000649_000201_0056.jpg" xml:id="d4e752"/>
            <p>April the 26th 1865.</p>
            <p>Joseph E Johnson  Rebel General commanding confederate forces in North Carolina, Surrenders to Gen Sharman commanding United States forces in N. Carolina</p>
            <p>The No of men Surrendered by Johnson to Gen Sherman was 27 400</p>
            <p>May the 3rd 1865  Important news to day the Surrender of Rebels to the U S forces is daily ading to the list of the many thousands already Surrendered</p>
            <p>May the 5th 1865  Jeff Thompson Surrendered his entire army on the 2nd Inst to Capt Mitchell in the western department, Memphis News,</p>
            <p>May the 5th  <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">nonion</unclear>transportation for Rebel deserters or reffugees at D. C.</p>
            <pb n="57" facs="0012_000649_000201_0057.jpg" xml:id="d4e769"/>
            <p>April the 9th 1865</p>
            <p>Surrender of R. E. Lee and his army to Lieut Gen U S Grant commanding United States forces</p>
            <p>April the 11th 1865  a Salute to day For the Surrender of Gen R E Lee and his armey</p>
            <p>April the 14th 1865</p>
            <p>Abraham Lincoln late President of the United States was Assassinated this eavning at half past 9 O,cl P M</p>
            <p>Mobile</p>
            <p>April the 9th  at 2 15 minute before day United States forces taken Spanish Fort and Ft Alexandria with over twenty peaces of artillery and near
				   1000 prisioners  also the City of Mobile with a large quantity of comissary and other Stores</p>
            <pb n="58" facs="0012_000649_000201_0058.jpg" xml:id="d4e785"/>
            <p>April the 28th 1865, War department D C</p>
            <p>Order No 77 all Soldiers in Hospitles to be honorably discharged Imediatly with all pay due them,</p>
            <p>Mobile</p>
            <p>Immence captures by our forces they include 215 heavy guns and 2,000 bales of cotton 75,000 Barrels of Rossin hidden in the Swamps  10,000 Rebel
				   Straglers give them Selves up.</p>
            <p>April 19/65  Dick Tayler offers to Surrender but the high waters has prevented his Surrender to the U. S. forces. Gen Canby beeing the commander of Federal forces
				   contending against Tayler,</p>
            <p>May the 10th 1865</p>
            <pb n="59" facs="0012_000649_000201_0059.jpg" xml:id="d4e799"/>
            <p>April the 19th 1865</p>
            <p>Washington D C.  Funeral Procession of Abraham Lincoln.</p>
            <p>Heavy Gun at Alexandria Va
				                Weighing   49 549 lbs
				          Weight of ball      400 lbs
				     Six other Guns each      200 pounds</p>
            <p>May the 4th 1865</p>
            <p>President Lincoln was conveyed to Oak Ridge Cemetery Springfield Ill. and confirmed to the Tomb.</p>
            <pb n="60" facs="0012_000649_000201_0060.jpg" xml:id="d4e811"/>
            <p>April the 25th 1865  Alexandria Va  John Wilkes Booth was Shot 15 minutes past 3 O,cl this morning and died 10 min Past 7, O,cl A M.  he was
				   killed in St Maryes county Maryland near Port Royal</p>
            <p>May the 4th 1865</p>
            <p>Proclamation by President Johnson  $100 000 reward offered for Jeff Davis, $25 000 for Clement C. Clay  $25 000 for Beverly Tucker  $10 000
				   for William C Clay of Clement C Clay late clerk  $25 000 for George N Saunders  $25 000 for Jacob Thompson late of Mississippi</p>
            <p>Gen Wilsons expedition on the 2nd April 1865 he captured Salem Ala by assault taken 32 peaces of artillery in posision and 75 in arsenal. all
				   public property was destroyed  the Rebels burnt</p>
            <pb n="61" facs="0012_000649_000201_0061.jpg" xml:id="d4e821"/>
            <p>85 000 bales of Cotton 5 Steamboats  63 cars  1 locomotive</p>
            <p>Montgomery was entered without opposision on the 12 of April 1865</p>
            <p>Columbus was captured on the 16th Apr by assault on the heavy field works  1,200 prisioners taken 53 Guns in posision 1 Gunboat mounting 6 - 7
				   inch rifles 100 000 bales cotton 13 Locomotives and 100 cars  While there a portion of the column made a detour to West Point and Captured the
				   works by assault  the attack was made by dismounted Cavalry  they took 4 Guns and 350 prisioners  the Rebel Gen Tyler was killed  15 Locomotives
				   and 200 cars was taken  all the captured property was destroyed</p>
            <p>Macon was taken without assault on the 20th Apr  the Rebel Generals Harvel Cobb G.W. Smith  M Robertson and McCall with</p>
            <pb n="62" facs="0012_000649_000201_0062.jpg" xml:id="d4e831"/>
            <p>a large Number of officers of all Ranks 1600 prisioners in all. </p>
            <p>Gen Wilsons forces had travelled 481 miles in 20 days  they took in all 182 guns in position and in the field and 200 Guns in arsenals  A large number
				   of Rolling mills and Iron foundries were destroyed  Naval foundries powderworks  Magazines Supply depots &amp; <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">c</unclear>
            </p>
            <p>Salem itself was 240 miles from the base of opperations, there is Scarcely an officer on the Staff who has not made personal captures of prisioners during
				   the expedition  the army is made up mostly of Western troops  our loss in all the engagements amount to less than 350  the enemys loss at Salem was 500</p>
            <p>May the 2nd 1865</p>
            <p>the Tennessee Senate has passed a Resolution offering $5 000 for I G Harris</p>
            <pb n="63" facs="0012_000649_000201_0063.jpg" xml:id="d4e845"/>
            <p>Alexandria Virginia May 6th /1865</p>
            <p>Bought at Alexandria to day one dress for Wife 10 yds 8 yds woost goods lining hooks and eyes Two hats amounting to     11 00
				   One pare pants One Short Coat  Two Shirts  One pare lady Shoes amounting to                                             14 00</p>
            <pb n="64" facs="0012_000649_000201_0064.jpg" xml:id="d4e851"/>
            <p>May the 10th 1865  Capture of Jeff Davis this morning at daylight at Irwinsville Ga in Irwin County, he attempts to escape with one of his
				   Wifes dresses, but in running toward the woods his large Boots Showed to the yankee boys that he was not a Woman, Davis attemped to fight with
				   a well made Bowie Knife, but when he Saw Coalts Revolvers presented at him he Submited, the 1st Wisconsin and 4th Michigan made the capture
				   Mrs Davis remarked to Col Harden that the men had better not provoke the President or he would hurt Some of them</p>
            <pb n="65" facs="0012_000649_000201_0065.jpg" xml:id="d4e855"/>
            <p>Going home      L.M.  May 9th 1865</p>
            <p>Alexandria va</p>
            <p>1        My heavanly home is bright and fair
				            Nor pain nor death can enter there
				            Its glittering towers the Sun outshine
				            That heavenly mansion Shall be mine
				   Chorus,  I&apos;m going home I&apos;m going home
				            I&apos;m going home I&apos;m going home
				            To die no more to die no more
				            I&apos;m going home to die no more
				   2        My Fathers house is built on high
				            Far Far above the Starry Sky
				            When from this earthley prison free
				            That heavanly mansion mine Shall be
				   Chorus
				   3        Let others Seek a home below
				            Which flames devour our waves overflow
				            Be mine the happier lot to own
				            A heavenly mansion near the throne
				   Chorus
				   4        Then fail this earth let Stars decline
				            And Sun and moon refuse to Shine
				            All nature Sink and cease to be
				            That heavenly mansion Stands for me
				                       Chorus</p>
            <pb n="66" facs="0012_000649_000201_0066.jpg" xml:id="d4e863"/>
            <p>May the 16th 1865</p>
            <p>May 16   New York  Gold     130 1/4</p>
            <p>Washington D. C. May 23rd 1865  left Washington at 8 1/2 for Baltimore arrived at Baltimore and remained till 3 1/2 then for Harrisburg Pa  arived at
				   Harrisburg at dark and remained till 1.15 when I left for Pittsburg Pa  arrived at Pittsburg at 12 and left at 3.40 for Columbus Ohio where we arrived
				   at 3 1/2 A M  left Columbus at 6 1/2 for Cincinnati  arived at Cincinnati at 11 A M and left at 3 1/2 for Seymour Ky</p>
            <p>Arived at Knoxville Sunday at 6 P. M. on the 28th May 1865</p>
            <pb n="67" facs="0012_000649_000201_0067.jpg" xml:id="d4e874"/>
            <p>June the 3rd 1865</p>
            <p>arived at home at 12 at night</p>
            <p>Expences from Washington D.C. home from Washington to Baltimore  $ 1 50
				                                      from Baltimore to Louisville   15 50
				                                      from Louisville to Nashville    3 80
				                                      from Nashville to Knoxville    10 50
				                                                                    $31 30</p>
            <p>From Knoxville to Greenville <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">fru</unclear>Arived home <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">gim</unclear>the
				   3rd at 12 in the night</p>
            <p>September 1851 Lend from Sisk to Boyer</p>
            <pb n="68" facs="0012_000649_000201_0068.jpg" xml:id="d4e892"/>
            <p>Peech Seed 1872</p>
            <p>1st Coopens Mamoth
				   2   Stokley
				   3   Abel
				   4   Kenyon
				   5   Mckay  Late
				   6   Mckay
				   7   Eisinhour
				   8   Blazer</p>
            <p>April the 24th 1879 Planted new ground</p>
            <p>May the 17th planted Clover field</p>
            <pb n="69" facs="0012_000649_000201_0069.jpg" xml:id="d4e902"/>
            <p>Names of fruit Trees Ohio Nursery</p>
            <p>1st Apple trees
				   3   King of Tomkins <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">fleo</unclear>
				   3   York Stripe
				   3   Fall Pippin
				   4   Northern Spy</p>
            <p>Peach Trees
				   1st  1  Crawfords Late
				        1  Crawfords Early
				        1  Coopers Mamoth</p>
            <p>Cherry
				        2  Bell Magnifiquese</p>
            <p>Pare
					    2  Louisa Bon <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">lyensey</unclear>$10 15</p>
            <p>Somerow 10. Queen Pippin 4. Tennessee green 1  Somerow 3</p>
            <pb n="70" facs="0012_000649_000201_0070.jpg" xml:id="d4e922"/>
            <p>Fruit Trees From Richmond Va Nursery  Nov 15th 1873</p>
            <p>Appletrees
				   1  Yates Bud
				   1  Rawles gennete
				   2  Early Ripe
				   2  Shockley
				   2  Early Harvest
				   2  Johnsons Fine Winter
				   2  Pilott
				   2  <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">lsnley</unclear>N.C
				   2  Wine Sap
				   2  Red Astrachan</p>
            <p>Peach
				   1  Harkers Seedling
				   1  Halles Early
				   1  Large Early York
				   1  Susquihanna
				   Cost of Trees          $5 50</p>
            <pb n="71" facs="0012_000649_000201_0071.jpg" xml:id="d4e933"/>
            <p>Oct the 4th 1883</p>
            <p>Catalog of Peech Seed planted
				   1st  Ottinger firn free stone
				   2nd  firm white &amp; red free stone
				   3rd  Indian plum</p>
            <p>2nd Row beginning next the house
				   1st  Late white
				   2nd  Late Red
				   3rd  September peech</p>
            <p>1866  Time to Set out <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">Apeltnees</unclear>the 1st day of the new moon in February</p>
            <p>1889  Cattalog of Peach trees begining at gate
				   1st  LaRue  2nd Stokley  3 Templin  4 Yellow <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">Jae</unclear>A B  5 Early White</p>
            <pb n="72" facs="0012_000649_000201_0072.jpg" xml:id="d4e951"/>
            <p>Date of Aplication for Pension
				   August 30th 1879</p>
            <p>Examined by Dr Nelson
				   Sept 1881</p>
            <p>Examined by Dr Henry P. Coile
				   Decr 1882</p>
            <p>Examined Sept 24th 1884
				   at Knoxville by Examining Board</p>
            <p>No of Clame 339 732</p>
            <pb n="73" facs="0012_000649_000201_0073.jpg" xml:id="d4e963"/>
            <p>Georgia Campaign 1864</p>
            <p>W. T. Shermans Army numbered 98 797 effective men</p>
            <p>Moved November the 5 1880</p>
            <p>This July 1st 1892.</p>
            <pb n="74" facs="0012_000649_000201_0074.jpg" xml:id="d4e973"/>
            <p>Address Montgomery Ward &amp; Co.</p>
            <p>111  112  113  114 Michigan Ave
				                      Chicago Ill
				   Enclose 10 ct Stamp</p>
            <pb n="75" facs="0012_000649_000201_0075.jpg" xml:id="d4e979"/>
            <p>Amt Paid to Margaret Blazer  June 5</p>
            <p>June 5    1885   Paid by Regestred letter               10.00
				   Aug 27th  1886   Paid to Margaret Blazer               $10.00
				   Decr 13   1886   by Regestered letter                   10.00
				             1887   Paid by Register letter for Shares      2.00
				             1887   sent by Mr Boman                        5.00
				   Jan 9th   1888   sent by Registered letter              10.00
				   Oct 23rd  1888   &quot;&quot;&quot;&quot;               10.00
				   July 23rd 1889   Paid in hand                            5.00
				   Sept 20th 1890   Paid by Regt letter    Settled         10.00
				   May 19    1892   Paid by Regt letter                    10.00</p>
            <pb n="76" facs="0012_000649_000201_0076.jpg" xml:id="d4e985"/>
            <p>Oct 29th 1890  Was examined at Morristown by Drs. Dice, Hale, &amp; Lensing</p>
            <pb n="77" facs="0012_000649_000201_0077.jpg" xml:id="d4e989"/>
            <p>August 8th 1891  Sent Mill $15.</p>
            <pb/>
            <pb/>
            <pb/>
            <pb/>
            <pb/>
            <pb n="83" facs="0012_000649_000201_0083.jpg" xml:id="d4e1014"/>
            <p>F. M. Raid commenced Boarding</p>
            <p>Nov 3rd 1886.  ||||/ ||||</p>
            <p>Less dec 21. 186.</p>
            <p>Returned Jany, 14  187.</p>
            <p>||||</p>
            <pb/>
            <pb n="85" facs="0012_000649_000201_0085.jpg" xml:id="d4e1030"/>
            <p>[Back Cover Recto]</p>
            <pb n="86" facs="0012_000649_000201_0086.jpg" xml:id="d4e1034"/>
            <p>[Back Cover]</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
