<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000079_000200_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter, <name>
Joseph Linn King
</name>
in Knoxville, Tenn., to John Bracklesby in Hartford, CT,
<date when="1865-09-30">
1865 September 30
</date>
            </title>
            <author>
               <name type="person">King, Joseph Linn</name>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>Hogan, Josh</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_000079_000200_0000</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more information,
            contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special Collections
                Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Letter, from Joseph Linn King in Knoxville, Tenn. to John Bracklesby in Hartford, Conn., 1865 September 30</title>
               <date>1865-09-30</date>
               <author>
                  <name>King, Joseph Linn</name>
               </author>
               <extent>3 digital images; 0.1 linear feet; 1 envelope, 2 p.</extent>
               <note type="abstract">In this letter, dated September 30, 1865, from Joseph Linn King in Knoxville, Tenn. to John Bracklesby in Hartford, CT, King discusses politics and legal cases in post-Civil War Knoxville. King describes Knoxville as &quot;improved materially recently and I observe a more moderate tone in the late 2 mos. of the Knoxville Whig also.&quot; He also talks about a case in which the judge sentenced a man to six years in prison for &quot;intimidating and takeing [sic] from one of his neighbours 2 sides of Bacon.&quot; The judge &quot;in his charge stated to the jury that a rebel stood before the law the same as a Union man, and that there was no law that allowed one citizen to rob another because of his political opinions.&quot; King also mentions that he has made arrangements to move his family and business to Atlanta by November 1.</note>
               <note type="collection">The Joseph Linn King Letter, 1865</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS.2226</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee Libraries
                Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
                omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Reconstruction (U.S. history, 1865-1877) -- Tennessee, East.</term>
               <term>Equality before the law -- United States -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>United States -- Politics and government -- 1865-1900.</term>
               <term>Tennessee, East -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Economic aspects.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-10-02" who="bds">Migrating from
                XML to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter" xml:id="d3e145">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_000079_000200_0001.jpg" xml:id="d3e146"/>
            <p>[Envelope - Includes postmark, dated Oct 4, from Chattanooga, Tenn.]</p>
            <p>Mr Jno Brocklesby</p>
            <p>Hartford</p>
            <p>Connecticut</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_000079_000200_0002.jpg" xml:id="d3e160"/>
            <p>Knoxville Sept. 30/65</p>
            <p>Jno. Bracklesby Esq.</p>
            <p>Hartford Ct.</p>
            <p>Dear Sir -</p>
            <p>Absence from home, has prevented an earlier reply to your letter in relation to the note you hold vs WC Kain. His property here is involved in litigation so that I am unable to see how you could do anything to accomplish your purpose, and in an interview with him today he suggested it would be best to postpone any action for the present.</p>
            <p>Some time since I recd a letter from Cousin May, your good Lady, which I designed to have answered promptly, but mislaid her letter, and must crave her pardon for the seeming neglect - and plead the business mans ready excuse, press of business &amp;c. Claibourn is still healthy cheerful &amp; hopeful and I think anxious for the day of trial. He has not yet recd the argument expected from Mr Curtis and is getting anxious about it. I have written to him to day, and perhaps it would</p>
            <pb n="3" facs="0012_000079_000200_0003.jpg" xml:id="d3e178"/>
            <p>be well for you to write him also.</p>
            <p>The temper of this community I think has improved materially recently - and I observe a more moderate tone in the last 2 mos. of the Knoxville Whig also. I understand Judge Hall sent a man to the Penitentiary this week from an adjoining County for 6 years for intimidating and takeing from one of his neighbours 2 sides of Bacon, and in his charge stated to the jury, that a rebel stood before the law the same as a Union man, and that there was no law that allowed one citizen to rob another because of his political opinions - this of course has always been the law, but the other has been the practice recently. But the charge is regarded as very favourable to order as against the mob.</p>
            <p>I have made my arrangements to remove my family &amp; business to Atlanta Geo. and expect to do so by the 1st Nov. next.</p>
            <p>With love to all.</p>
            <p>Hastily yours</p>
            <p>Jos. L King</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>