<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_001496_000200_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>
               <name>Eleanora Willauer </name>Diary, <date from="1862-10-01" to="1869-11-09">1862 October 1-1869 November 9</date>
            </title>
            <author>
               <name type="person">Willauer, Eleanora</name>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>NH, PW, IH, KC, SS, RG, SJ</name>
               <name>Deane, Christine H.</name>
               <name>Dyson-Smith, Bridger</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_001496_000200_0000</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more information,
            contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special Collections
                Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Eleanora Willauer Diary, 1862 October 1-1869 November 9</title>
               <date>1862 October 1-1869 November 9</date>
               <author>
                  <name>Willauer, Eleanora</name>
               </author>
               <extent>222 digital images; 222 pages</extent>
               <note type="abstract"> Eleanora Willauer lived in Cumberland Furnace, Tennessee, during the Civil
War. She wrote this diary primarily between the ages of 18 and 23. </note>
               <note type="collection">Eleanora Willauer Diary</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS.2940</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee Libraries
                Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
                omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Willauer, Eleanora</term>
               <term>Tennessee -- History -- Civil War, 1862-1869 -- Personal Narratives,
Confederate.</term>
               <term>Tennessee -- History -- Civil War, 1862-1869</term>
               <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1862-1869 -- Women</term>
               <term>Women -- Tennessee -- Diaries</term>
               <term>Civil War and Reconstruction (1850-1877)</term>
               <term>1862-1869</term>
               <term>Cumberland Furnace, Tennessee, 37051</term>
               <term>Corinth, Miss.</term>
               <term>Giles County, Tennessee</term>
               <term>Dixon County, Tennessee</term>
               <term>Nashville, Tennessee</term>
               <term>Civil War Diaries</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-10-02" who="bds">Migrating from
                XML to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="diary" xml:id="d3e164">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_001496_000200_0001.jpg" xml:id="d3e165"/>
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_001496_000200_0002.jpg" xml:id="d3e170"/>
            <p>[Blank page.]</p>
            <pb n="3" facs="0012_001496_000200_0003.jpg" xml:id="d3e177"/>
            <p>Strictly Private</p>
            <p>
               <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SJ">J. Wayne. Willauer</unclear>
            </p>
            <p>Cumb <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SJ">@</unclear> Furnace</p>
            <p>Aug 1-20th 1862</p>
            <p>Presented by <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SJ">the</unclear> above <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SJ">his</unclear>
            </p>
            <p>Eleanora Willauer</p>
            <p>Oct. 1, 1862</p>
            <p>Cumberland Furnace</p>
            <p>Dixson County</p>
            <p>Tennessee</p>
            <p>Confederate States of</p>
            <p>America</p>
            <pb/>
            <p>[Blank page.]</p>
            <pb n="5" facs="0012_001496_000200_0005.jpg" xml:id="d3e224"/>
            <p>&quot;Journal. 1862.&quot;</p>
            <p>Wednesday Oct 1. 62</p>
            <p>Having written through the old book in which I kept my journal I now after a long pause
recommence</p>
            <p>It is still very warm and our beautiful soft fall weather has not yet commenced. Neither have the
trees put on their gorgeous Autumn dress; but from the heavy clouds which now darken the landscape,
and now <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SJ">sendding</unclear> before the upper currents, sink
behind the hills I think there will soon be rain after which I hope our Fall, which consists any
thing but &quot;melancholy days&quot; is our beautiful climate, will come.</p>
            <p>The poet must indeed have that sadness with in which makes the outer world look sad, who could
say our Autumnal days were &quot;saddest of the year&quot; for though they at times create a sort of
gladness in which there is deepest <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SJ">pretense</unclear> and
zest, yet this is that happiness with which some great minds have <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SJ">thought</unclear> approached nearest to the joy of the Redeemed, here after.</p>
            <p>Cousin Robert has just returned from Nashville. Every thing there looks very gloomy _ and the
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="SJ">Northern</unclear> invaders</p>
            <pb n="6" facs="0012_001496_000200_0006.jpg" xml:id="d3e254"/>
            <p>are excercising their ill gotten power to the fullest extent to which tyrant spirits prompt them.
May our God soon free our Country from the pollution of their fool spirits!</p>
            <p>I recieved a letter by Bob from my darling cousin Florence which though more than a month old was
still most welcome news coming from her. She is still merry and is happy. She has I think been
reading spirits constantly since we parted, now almost a year since, &amp; I think I can discover
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">a rich</unclear> womanly <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">murmur</unclear> in the ripple of her life stream which was not there when last I listined to its
music. &quot;Would I were with the&quot; Florence darling. I recieved a note from Mary who is stay
out there with Florence. They are both as gay and happy as youth and pleasant company and
surrondings can make them.</p>
            <p>I have neer known a sorrow, yet my life is not a happy one for I am and have been for a year - so
lonely and there is deepest sadness in that word at all times save when we have been surfeited with
company or when sadness pressed heavily on the soul and we would cast the</p>
            <pb n="7" facs="0012_001496_000200_0007.jpg" xml:id="d3e271"/>
            <p>load at the feet of a loving Redeemer. Still I try to be contented with my lot for as my favorite
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Tupper</unclear> says - Consider whatever be thy fate that it
might and ought to have been worse For ye all are <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">pensioners</unclear> of God And none may choose or refuse the cup His wisdom <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">wrath</unclear>. _ and I try not to envy those who have a happier fate
for &quot;We know the worst of ourselves but the secrets of others cannot see.&quot;</p>
            <p>Cumberland Furnace - Furnance - Dickson Co. Tenn. CSt.</p>
            <p>Furnance Oct 3 1862</p>
            <p>Nothing has happened of interest since I last wrote, no changes of any kind have taken place even
the weather is the same - still dry and very sultry. Life here is one dull routine - arise with the
Sun in the morning - which would be exceedingly pleasant if our first <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">waking</unclear> thoughts turned to some </p>
            <p> occupation for which the stay would <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">scarce</unclear>
suffice which thought would rouse the sleeping <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">faculties and
cause</unclear> a quick spring from the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">crack</unclear> which
from that minute had become <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">awesome</unclear>
            </p>
            <pb n="8" facs="0012_001496_000200_0008.jpg" xml:id="d3e310"/>
            <p>but one cannot have this happy feeling of interest when there is no company no books no new music
no rambles no rides no roses no new scenes no new any thing where the day is spent in eating a
disagreeable breakfast, all alone, going up and arranging your room - sitting down to a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">stupid</unclear> history if you are so fortunate as to have borrowed
one - or darning stockings or mending clothes or some such highly intellectual employment</p>
            <p>The history is much the most preferable of them all and the one I have now. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">D&apos;Au</unclear> - big <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">ni</unclear>
Reformation would be really very interesting if I only had a little refreshing poetry to read now
and then by way of contrast to its sober style <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Waverly</unclear> or a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Bulmer</unclear> would do.</p>
            <p>Still I am very glad to get the history and shall feel always much obliged to my kind friend Mrs.
Bell for having furnished me with so much valuable instruction. While <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">we are as if were are thus</unclear> dreaming of <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">action</unclear> - The <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">world</unclear> our country - our
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">stand and</unclear> convulsed at with the terrible sectionism
in which </p>
            <pb n="9" facs="0012_001496_000200_0009.jpg" xml:id="d3e348"/>
            <p>
               <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">fiercest</unclear> War has involved our country - Tennessee
the beloved state of my nativity the home of freedom honor and justice is now bowed down under the
rod of the tyrany of the North.</p>
            <p>When the history of this War is written impartially there will be scenes to record of atrocity
and inhumanity <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">unequalled</unclear> save in the barbarous
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">may doc</unclear> of the darkest ages of the world. Scenes
here in Tennessee which will call forth scalding tears from the eyes of the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">gentlest</unclear> and cause the hearts of her strong and free sons
almost to burst with indignation. God grant that the day may soon come when the invader driven from
our sacred soil, we may again fling the bright <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">barred</unclear> bonnet to our joyous breezes made joyous by the shouts of liberation and and
thanks and greetings of her then happy sons and <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">daughters</unclear> and may greet our gallant soldiers back to their native soil- Theirs then
indeed since they will have won it so nobly from a powerful foe.</p>
            <p>Florence has bcome quite a heroine out in <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Manry</unclear>.</p>
            <pb n="10" facs="0012_001496_000200_0010.jpg" xml:id="d3e379"/>
            <p>Mamma gave me a scolding this morning for being cutting and sarcastic in my manner. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">towards</unclear> Bob she says I am not gentle enough in my speech. I
feel this to be time and I pray to be better and more like the high ideal which I have formed of a
perfect woman, but it seems impossible for the more I strive the more I seem to get.</p>
            <p>I am now eighteen and a woman of that age should be joyous. but modest and yet self possessed and
she will this be fitted to gain esteem and respect of those by whom it is her fortune to be
surrounded.</p>
            <p>It is I find an exceedingly bad plan to strive to please by leveling yourself with those below
you in to whose <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">serenity</unclear> you are known yet you
should not put on airs of superority for this is indeed lowering yourself but be always pleasant yet
not familiar - <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">treat</unclear> people in a kind way to keep
their distance in short be dignified not stiff not too free. EW</p>
            <p>After Dinner - Jim Walles is here! I do not intend to see him if I can help it. Jim Walles has
gone - I saw him - wrote a note by him to Mrs. Walkins as she wanted to hear the news.</p>
            <pb n="11" facs="0012_001496_000200_0011.jpg" xml:id="d3e401"/>
            <p>Jim says Mr. Baxter and Dora were coming up here today but Bill heard last evening that the
Yankees were in Clarksville and he has to go on duty with the company in which he is first
Lieutenant consequently he and Dora could not come. I should have liked so very much to have seen
them.</p>
            <p>It somehow seems to me that I should never see him again - I hope the poor fellow may not be
killed.</p>
            <p>Beckie is in Clarksville. She has a new beau - a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Mer.</unclear> Frank Phillips a widower.</p>
            <p>I expect cousin <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Flo</unclear> here before long as Bob said
he was coming down to try to get up a company</p>
            <p>Furnance Sunday Oct 5 /62</p>
            <p>It is the holy day yet naught of holiness have me, no church nor prayers nor anything to remind
one that it is Sunday - Yet there is some thing for there is that calm which God seems to have order
for the Sabbath &amp; which I have ever found it to possess even in the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">bussiest</unclear> scenes.</p>
            <pb n="12" facs="0012_001496_000200_0012.jpg" xml:id="d3e429"/>
            <p>The wind has a far off sound as if <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">were</unclear> the
rustle of the millions of angel wings that fan the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">air so
fraught</unclear> with praise to Our Father.</p>
            <p>Oh how I wish that we all were better that the evil passions of man would be <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">subdued</unclear> and that he were a being worthy of this beautiful
beautiful World in which a God of Infinite love has placed him. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">has</unclear> that sin should have made if a heart sigh &quot;that it is a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">weary</unclear> world &quot; where all might be so good and happy!</p>
            <p>The negroes are having a grand time today. They have a number of colored visitors from
Raimey&apos;s &amp; from Mr. Vernon. </p>
            <p>They have all put on their Sundays and gone over the Creek to Church. </p>
            <p>I heard yesterday taht some man saw and shook hands with Major Roberson and Captain <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">J. H. Beaumoukin&apos;s</unclear> Chattanooga the other day. Nearly all
the Tennesseeans are there - The poor dear fellows are in fine spirits have plenty of arms but
numbers of them are barefooted - Until they are well clothed</p>
            <pb n="13" facs="0012_001496_000200_0013.jpg" xml:id="d3e462"/>
            <p>I trust they will be back here before cold weather and that we will be able to supply them with
shoes. I wonder if the first Regiment is there? - Ah poor fellows! all I know of its number may be
cold and blood-stained corpses - those happy young and manly faces may be lying upturned to the sky
whence their spirits have fled with not a tear shed over them, save those tears of the stars, cold
drops of dew.</p>
            <p>May the aching hearts at home soon hear certainly from you, for any thing is better than<unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">suspence</unclear>.</p>
            <p>I sorrow for you - yet I have not anyone to sorrow for - I almost envy those who have - for what
a high privelege it must be know that the near and dear are so noble and devoted.</p>
            <p>Debarred from so noble a career by my sex I have no one to fight my battles for me.</p>
            <p>Old Mrs. Hughes was here until after dinner yesterday I went over home with her and <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Mattie&apos;s</unclear> and little <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Bettie Harris&apos;s</unclear> who came for her. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Nannie&apos;s</unclear> Harris</p>
            <pb n="14" facs="0012_001496_000200_0014.jpg" xml:id="d3e489"/>
            <p>was there - she is very pretty - she looks much better than she did in the early part of the
Summer.</p>
            <p>It is reported that since the last Yankee proclamation the east Tennesseans are all turning out
for the South- <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">prate</unclear> on Oh ye Yanks! Of your
&quot;loyal East Tennesseans&quot; - we can agree with you now. I thought they were only misguided.
I knew none of our fellow states men would prove renegade to her interest when they knew what that
interest was.</p>
            <p>Andy Johnson death or exile awaits you - ask your conscience - if that has not been deadened long
ago - if you do not richly deserve both.</p>
            <p>Monday Oct 6 1862</p>
            <p>&quot;Southern <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">News</unclear>&quot;</p>
            <p>Mr. Nicks met a man known here as Mr Bailey on the Clarksville road and he being a discarged
Southern soldier gives authentic news from <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Hence</unclear> -
His brigade in which are the 1st. 3rd &amp; 14th Tenn were all in the battle at Sharpsburg,</p>
            <pb n="15" facs="0012_001496_000200_0015.jpg" xml:id="d3e516"/>
            <p>Our boys have had an opportunity at last of distinguishing themselves - alas! how many have been
laid in the soldiers graves but I must not think of such things. They are all in the best of spirits
and have more than enough arms <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">ic</unclear> captured from the
Yanks. in the late battles which <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">no one supposed</unclear>
were complete Southern <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">victoires</unclear>. There were 160,000
Southerners at Sharpsburg and from 260,000 to 300,000 Yanks. Beauregard has recovered and is
defending Charleston with a large force. The railroad is open all the way from Virginia to
Murpheesboro. Every one South in high hopes for Our future. It&apos;s not <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">sigh</unclear> and say ah poor <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Secession</unclear> but Our Gloreous Confederacy both now and &quot;For Ever&quot; with a loud
huzza.</p>
            <p>I was reading last night and found in an old magazine Hood&apos;s &quot;Bridge of Sighs&quot;
which I copied off this morning - Dear Hood I should so much like to have all of his works.</p>
            <p>I but rarely thik of him but I also think of friend Thamas Beau</p>
            <pb n="16" facs="0012_001496_000200_0016.jpg" xml:id="d3e542"/>
            <p>mont who first introduced me to him last Summer in Tylney Hall. Poor Captain - I liked him
exceedingly and it pains me much to hear that he has proven himself very weak when the months of
trial came- how strange that one so cooly and calmly brave in the direst <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">extremetris</unclear> of War should be morally must I say it? - a coward - apostalised too
they say but I have one friend at least who is yet most brave, and <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">true</unclear> and <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">pure</unclear> God grant that it
may never be other wise.</p>
            <p>(1863 Both are dead - bravely bravely - at Chickamanga.)</p>
            <p>Wednesday Oct 8 1862</p>
            <p>Read a whole book of D&apos;Anbigne yesterday, which kept me so busy that I did not have time to
write, even if I had possessed any topic to write about. Mer Nicks <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">states</unclear> that there is a rumor that poor Mr. Rose or rather Rolls is killed he
belonged to Minor&apos;s Geurilla&apos;s - they were decoyed by a pretended Southerner in to the
Yankees&apos; power. I was reading yesterday an account of the diet at Augsburg</p>
            <pb n="17" facs="0012_001496_000200_0017.jpg" xml:id="d3e568"/>
            <p>and the Confession of the Protestant princes - I was glad to hear from my old acqunaintance
Charles the Fifth who was introduced to me summer before last by Prescott.</p>
            <p>I was reading last night by way of vacation a treatise on the Social standing of my sex - it is a
difficult thing to be perfect or even make an approximation towards perfection - and yet we are
expected by men to be angels - and I am afraid we women think that men are far better and <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">pures</unclear> and more manly - in the highest and holiest sense of
the word - than we ever will find them in our contacts with them through life</p>
            <p>There is a sad lacking in most men of that delicacy and con - what I scarscely know - but which
is cultivated in woman to <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">such an extent</unclear> that it
makes her exceedingly unhappy to be <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">known</unclear> with those
who do not possess it - God give us - poor weak creatures - strength to bear and for bear the sorrow
and anguish of our lot</p>
            <pb n="18" facs="0012_001496_000200_0018.jpg" xml:id="d3e588"/>
            <p>Put thy trust in God&quot;</p>
            <p>My prayer, and it should be that of every honerable woman is protects me from slander.</p>
            <p>I wish I could form a better and clearer idea of the human character - at times when only under
the influence of my own bright hopefulness and inexperiance I think that there many be sinfulness in
the world but it does not seem to me that I shall ever come in contact with it - All those whom I
know seem pure and good.</p>
            <p>But then at other times when under the influence of the suspicion of age - I doubt almost every
one- Yet it is almost impossible for me not to think those sincere who seem so- who when in my
company seem always striving to lead one higher intellectually and morally- in many cases though, I
have been told that their lives do not correspond to their teachings- how very sad! I can not bring
myself though, to look at the dark side of life save at a very few short intevals - it will seem
bright to my </p>
            <pb n="19" facs="0012_001496_000200_0019.jpg" xml:id="d3e601"/>
            <p>hopeful heart. it is all one - ah how glorious! dream of happiness- poverty and toil and care may
come and I trust if they do that I shall be enabled by a loving Father in Heaven to bear them all
right gallantly- but they will not come to me- life will be joyous - God has given me this high
hopefulness and I will not stifle its joyous cries.</p>
            <p>Saturday Oct. 11. 1862</p>
            <p>Vanleer came down in a hack Thursday from Nashville- the hackman only staied an hour- I wrote to
Pa and to Cookery - Ma sent up some eatibles.</p>
            <p>There was a gentleman here from North Ala. Wednesday night Mer. Ross he knows <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">M. F.V. McKrirnam</unclear>.</p>
            <p>The Hughes girls came over in the evening and staied until after supper.</p>
            <p>Mer <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Collier</unclear> is here today - came yesterday
morning soon after breakfast and as it has rained ever since he can not go home. I have just slipped
up stairs while he smokes his segar. I expect he will go soon as it is after dinner and has not
rained since early</p>
            <pb n="20" facs="0012_001496_000200_0020.jpg" xml:id="d3e625"/>
            <p>this morning though it is still very cloudy.</p>
            <p>Mr Ward has returned from the army- he is released on account of a lame foot I know Cousin Eunice
was glad. I should like so much to see some of them from Harpeth Hall so that I could hear from my
soldier friends.</p>
            <p>When Van came I saw the hack and ran down to the gate in the full expectation of seeing and
folding in my arms- my darling cousin Florence. I was so disappointed- I expect she and Mary are
seeing a happier time than ever now for beside Jo they have the Southerners, and such girls as they
and Antionette are will always draw around them the best and bravest.</p>
            <p>Later - Mr. Collier has gone - Wayne has exchanged his beautiful horse for an ugly mule -
Farewell Thom. Johnson. I am so sorry. Van Hickman was put out at <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Cracker&apos;s at White&apos;s Crube to</unclear> school but he would not stay - I feel so
sorry for him for I know he will regret his <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">want of
education</unclear> so much when he is grown - it will be so much the worse for</p>
            <pb n="21" facs="0012_001496_000200_0021.jpg" xml:id="d3e644"/>
            <p>him for every one will know that Anthony Vanleer&apos;s grandson will have had the opportunity of
gaining a splendid education, if he has had the will and the mind. Van is a bright boy but so rude
and <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">untutored</unclear>
            </p>
            <p>From the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Sultriest</unclear> of weather it has suddenly
become so very cool that <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">fire is</unclear> indispensible. Waye
has made an appointment with Mr. Collins to go down to Smith <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Muling</unclear> house to old mr Batson&apos;s Funeral - perhaps I shall go with them,- I believe
Mr. Collier is in love with Florence - as deeply as he is capable of loving- I dont know what to
think of him - he is smart as a business man- so the old gentlemen say - indeed he is spoken of very
highly by everyone - he is very handsome - dresses well and will perhaps inherit a large fortune yet
none <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">scarcely</unclear> of the young ladies like him - though
he is one of the best <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">mahired</unclear> fellows in the
world</p>
            <p>I like him very well - yet it is no pleasure whatever for me to talk to him - now I know this
is</p>
            <pb n="22" facs="0012_001496_000200_0022.jpg" xml:id="d3e672"/>
            <p>no fault of mine for I do <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">dearly</unclear> love to talk to
some gentlemen- for instance Captain Beaumont- there is scarcely any thing which I have enjoyed more
than an evening with him- he seems to expand the mind. To be ever leading the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">thoughts/mind in</unclear> upward and onward to some newer and broader
field of thought. And though M. C&apos;s superior in mind yet he alas ! is not near so moral - ah!
how I wish and pray - ay! pray Capt Beaumont that you may over come this sinful weakness,- which
will bury all those noble talents, all the rest of your morality, unitil having become a thing so
vile that purity will shudder to touch you, you will sink down in to the grave, a sad, sad example
to all the gay, and gallant, and gifted who - have but too deeply drained the drunkard&apos;s bowl;
and your soul, the immortal part which even intoxication cannot destroy, where will it go.-</p>
            <p>They say Mr. Snowden has been made Colonel- I am very glad for he is worth of admirement - if he
has not greatly changed. It is as cold up here that I can not write anymore.</p>
            <pb n="23" facs="0012_001496_000200_0023.jpg" xml:id="d3e688"/>
            <p>Sunday Oct. 12 . 1862.</p>
            <p>Another week has glided almost imperceptably by. It is very cloudy though it has not rained today
This morning the Sun shone out for some time- it has moderated too - and it is very pleasant now as
regards temperature. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Hanmmer</unclear> &amp; I took a walk up
to the mill this morning to get warm. Met Van who took us <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">round</unclear> to the stable to see his new horse which he has named &quot;Dora&quot; - for Dora
Hawkins, I believe, he opened the stable and she got out, - he caught her after a while and then we
went up to the dam to look at his canoe. - We went into the mill. I had not been in it before since
I was a little child. It is a picturesque old place with its broad smooth dam flanked on one side
with a steep rocky bluff all covered over and crowned with <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">verdure</unclear> or rather <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">foliage</unclear> for it is all
crimson and golden now with the white rocks gleaming through - on the other side is a low bank
covered over with willows, which</p>
            <pb n="24" facs="0012_001496_000200_0024.jpg" xml:id="d3e710"/>
            <p>swayed gracefully to and fro in homage to the wind, making beautiful mosaic on the thick cover of
grass beneath with the shadows of their tiny leaves.</p>
            <p>The mill itself like all old mills is picturesque - the never ending play of water, wearing off
the roughness and angularity, which makes the new mill ugly.- The old rotting timbers, however
dangerous to walk over, are ever pretty to look at as rather pleasing - yet saddening.</p>
            <p>
               <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">I I</unclear> read some this evening and ever since have
been sitting in the rocking chair down in the parlor dreamily looking out on the clouded landscape,
or half sleepily dreaming one of my interminable irregular dreams - which by the way are <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">at once</unclear> my delight and my bane.</p>
            <p>It is very, when lonely, difficult to struggle successfully against a propensity - of this kind.
It is so delightful to have all gay and bright - and all <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">terrible</unclear> and grand things waiting on our call to throng around us.</p>
            <pb n="25" facs="0012_001496_000200_0025.jpg" xml:id="d3e731"/>
            <p>But I know that it is dangerous to indulge the &quot;ideality&quot; too much.-</p>
            <p>&quot;Woe to the youth whom fancy gains.&quot;</p>
            <p>&quot;Winning from reason&apos;s hands, the rains&quot;</p>
            <p>I know some of these simple, matter of fact country people here would vote for having me sent to
the asylum if they could see me deeply affected by the dreariness, or joy and beauty of the things
and scenes which Fancy calls before me from my &quot;chateau en Espagne&quot; - ah what a lovely
chateau it is all floating in a golden hued atmosphere which illumines its turrets of silver and
diamonds - it is a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">&quot;cloud&quot;</unclear> - no one, by
myself will ever read you, my only confidante!, my journal! so I need not fear that any sinister
mind will turn my airy palace into a wish for wealth. - no I never thought of that and it was only
on having to describe it that I ever thought any thing of the material - it was only all pure and
bright</p>
            <p>Cumberlan Furnace</p>
            <p>Dickson Co. Tenn</p>
            <p>CSA</p>
            <pb n="26" facs="0012_001496_000200_0026.jpg" xml:id="d3e753"/>
            <p>Wednesday Oct. 15. 1862.</p>
            <p>I have not writen since Sunday but not because I have had nothing to write about for there has
really been a great deal. Monday after dinner - Wayne, Van, &amp; I went down to Hickerson&apos;s
store to buy a calico dress for Mamma and myself - we also went to Mr. Dority&apos;s - we were then
very close to <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Louisa</unclear>. As we came home we saw the
corps of a negro man belonging to Mr. Ward - they were taking it home to Mr. Ben Robertson&apos;s, -
Mr. Abernathy to whom the man was <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">kinid</unclear> shot him
unintentionally I believe. When we had eatten supper Mr. Ward and Benny Robertson came here to stay
all night on their way to &quot;<unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Harpeth</unclear> Hall&quot;.
I was so glad to see them and hear from my friends, Mr. Ward is a small man and looks like Mr.
Beaumont who by the way is Lieut. Col. Beaumont now. Mr. W. is not as good looking as &quot;friend
B.&quot;</p>
            <pb n="27" facs="0012_001496_000200_0027.jpg" xml:id="d3e772"/>
            <p>Cousin Chris is still Major. Yesterday at dinner we were all talking about the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Dierson&apos;s</unclear> - not very favorably - as we had heard of
their having said some very scandalous things about us - one thing was that we were
&quot;Union&quot; - nothing can make me angrier than that - when too we have always shown ourselves
so favorable to every thing southern - I am a southern born, and southern raised, and educated woman
and I shall always feel proud of being a Southerner at heart. -- well we were talking about them
when Wayne promised me 25 dollars if I would never call one of them cousin again. I said I never
would- we were just going on in that strain when who should ride up <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">out</unclear> the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">old</unclear> Col. - he went away
this morning.</p>
            <p>Just before dinner a man rode up and asked us to feed his horse and give him dinner. he said he
was a southern soldier but he talks just exactly like a Yank. &amp; I believe he is a spy</p>
            <pb n="28" facs="0012_001496_000200_0028.jpg" xml:id="d3e790"/>
            <p>he says he will be back in four or five days - and then we shall find out who and what he is.-
Some of them are afraid that he will bring some Yankee Cavelry here.- I only hope they may have
spoken untruly &amp; that he spoke the truth when he said he was a Southerner.</p>
            <p>Buck and his wife are over the creek - they will come over here for a while I expect this
evening.</p>
            <p>Night before last one year ago - Cousin Chris staied here all night &apos;twas the last time he
was here.</p>
            <p>How many changes have take place in his life since then. I wonder if he really loves Florence -
he likes her - if he does I only hope she returns it for I know of no one so worthy of a
woman&apos;s love. Noble Cousin Chris! I should like to have you for a cousin in reality</p>
            <p>I had the toothache all yesterday evening and only recovered in the night.</p>
            <pb n="29" facs="0012_001496_000200_0029.jpg" xml:id="d3e805"/>
            <p>My face is swolen some today. God, my Heavenly Father guard and guide me! I am such a rash,
imprudent girl. Thou alone O Father! can <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">keep</unclear> me
from harm. I would give my life I believe for a lively faith and trust in my God.</p>
            <p>Sunday Oct. 19. 1862.</p>
            <p>Friday evening late two men rode up to our back gate and inquired if they could stay all night
one had on a military cap. they had just arrived when who should come but Felix Smith of Nashville
with whom I am very well acquainted, - also another young man <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Linus</unclear> Topp. They are all four members of Our Army.- <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Fee</unclear> Smith is Captain the other two gentleman were - Col. Ross and Dr. Conwell, a
regimental Surgeon, they came out here for the purpose of consolidating troops. Col Ross &amp; the
Docter went Saturday morning to Clarksville- Topp and <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Fee</unclear> left this morning. Topp is a very smart young man I think. Fee took Florence&apos;s
picture I could not make him leave it. They say they are going out to Columbia - ha!ha!</p>
            <p>Ah Felix I see you are in love!</p>
            <pb n="30" facs="0012_001496_000200_0030.jpg" xml:id="d3e831"/>
            <p>Tuesday. Oct 21. 1862.</p>
            <p>Yesterday there were four travellers took dinner here. Mamma did not come down - I acted lady of
the house - and Wayne charged them for their dinner! I was so mortified - I cried for a long time
after dinner. The boys think it is a good joke - but I dont - it made me miserable for a while- I am
a proud girl though few peple know it - I felt so degraded to be placed in the position of a
bar-maid. Wayne says it is false pride perhaps it is but if I ever am mistress of a house-
hospitality - shall never, if I can prevent it, be violated. - One of the men was a German - he
seemed very much interested in me - as he stopped <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Tucks</unclear> on the road - so W. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">says,</unclear> to
enquire who I was. They are all southern in sentiment and three from Georgea.</p>
            <p>Van was down at Louisa last week and Mrs. Watkins sent word to me to come down Wednesday as some
young ladies were coming out</p>
            <pb n="31" facs="0012_001496_000200_0031.jpg" xml:id="d3e849"/>
            <p>from Clarksville with Beckie. Florence Johnson is among the number. Fe Smith knows her, and told
me several things to ask her. I expect I shall go down tomorrow evening, if nothing prevents.</p>
            <p>I wonder what kind <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">I</unclear> girls I shall find them- one
of them I have heard is very wild- and very beautiful- Nannie Garland. I used to go to school with
her- but do not remember her - she and Mary <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Nachol</unclear>
are great friends. Nannie Tyler is very pretty they say.</p>
            <p>We have had glorious news, if it were only true but there have been so many conflicting reports
that we have no hope of getting to the true on. Among other things &apos;tis reported that the
&quot;Links&quot; are evacuating Nashville. Oh! if it were only true!!! wouldn&apos;t it be
&quot;Glorious&quot;!</p>
            <p>Nov. 14 or 15</p>
            <p>Friday</p>
            <p>Oh! I have been having such a glorious time ever since I wrote in here last. I did go down to
Louisa. Nannie Tyler - Darling Nannie Tyler - and Beckie - my sweet little sister came up for me</p>
            <pb n="32" facs="0012_001496_000200_0032.jpg" xml:id="d3e873"/>
            <p>the illustrous Frank Phillips came with them - they took dinner and Van and I went back with
them. Wayne went part of the way and rode with Nan. Phillips rode with me. I do not admire him much
and I am glad that I can think Beckie does not either. We got to Louisa late and found Florence
Johnson and the Watkins family there. Nannie Garland&apos;s health was too bad for her to come out.
They think she has consumption - poor girl. We spent a very pleasant time at Louisa for nearly a
week, when who should come but the two Lieut&apos;s Baxter. I was very glad to see Bill. We all went
over to Tennessee Furnace that evening excepting Nannie. Will rode with me.</p>
            <p>
               <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Nan</unclear> came over next day and we had a grand time
rarely ever retiring until two or three and riding nearly all day. There was great rivalry as to who
should receive the greatest attention from Lieut. Baxter.</p>
            <pb n="33" facs="0012_001496_000200_0033.jpg" xml:id="d3e884"/>
            <p>Nannie distanced us all I think that time. The Lieut had to return to camp though and we all
returned to Louisa and came from there up here. Nan, Beckie, Dora and I came first and the next day
or so Florence and Mrs. Watkins and Mrs. Jackson came. We stopped at Hickerson&apos;s on the way up
and there we met a young man from Woodward&apos;s Mr. Grimes. Nan and I wrote a note just for
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">fun</unclear> to Lieut. Bill, and Beckie wrote to Charlie
Tyler, Nan&apos;s brother - a Capt. in Woodward&apos;s sending him a pair of socks.</p>
            <p>Our time we spent I hope quite pleasantly I hope as Mr. Collier and Mr. Phillips were here, and
we danced every night, and greatest of all Maj. Robertson - Cousin Chris my dear friend and brother
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Beta</unclear> came - he being at home on furlough - Oh! I was
so glad to see him! I always liked him so much. He seemed perfectly smitten with Nan and I believe
Nan also liked him. I forgot to state that Madame <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Finley</unclear> was of the party.</p>
            <pb n="34" facs="0012_001496_000200_0034.jpg" xml:id="d3e903"/>
            <p>We all returned to Louisa at the expiration of a week and heard that Woodward&apos;s whole
command was camped at <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Autrock</unclear> only 6 miles from
Louisa - It was on Friday very cold and snowing; we were so glad to hear it and Nannie was so
anxious to see her brother that we all jumped on our horses and rode down. We met some of them at
Raimey&apos;s a mile from Louisa and one of them rode down to camp with me. Wayne and Collier rode
down with us also. We arrived at Camp and found Capt. Tyler gone. Lieut Baxter however was there and
he took us down and we were all introduced to the celebrated Woodward.</p>
            <p>He had given orders that no man should leave camp but Nannie begged him so hard that he at last
promised to let us all have a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">bean</unclear> apiece to take
home to stay all night. I knowing no one, chose a friend of Beckie&apos;s Lieut Ben Rogers. the
others chose - Lieut Baxter (Bill) Lieut Reaves. Capt. Charlie <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Billingsly</unclear>. &amp; I do not remember</p>
            <pb n="35" facs="0012_001496_000200_0035.jpg" xml:id="d3e921"/>
            <p>who else, as there were quite a number who came afterwards among those whom I remember were Capt.
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Cypret</unclear> Lieut. Wilkinson and Mr. Forbes of whom more
anon.</p>
            <p>When we arrived at Louisa who should be there but &quot;Cousin Chris&quot; and my old friend his
cousin Captain Hills Gould every one was delighted to see them. We had a glorious time that night,
danced until very late, and of course, there being so few ladies, we were all belles, and as
sequence were all well pleased. At one time there being a scarcity chairs there were several
gentlemen kneeling around me and Mr. Bill Baxter in his funny way came and dropped down before me
everyone laughed. It is so dark. I can not write so I will write the remainder hereafter.</p>
            <p>After Supper</p>
            <p>Next Morning, Saturday, we had a very pleasant time as they did not go until dinner time. Beckie
decorated Capt. Billingsly&apos;s hat with a plume and star. I decorated Lieut. B&apos;s with a gold
and black cord &amp; acorns and tacked it up on the side with a gold button and black and gold
tassel.</p>
            <pb n="36" facs="0012_001496_000200_0036.jpg" xml:id="d3e937"/>
            <p>It looked quite pretty and was very becoming to the handsome face of its wearer, I think. After
the soldiers had left excepting <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Meorj</unclear> Robertson and
Capt. Gould who should ride up but Col. Woodward - also his surgeon Dr. Wood; we were all delighted
to see Woodward and tried to be very facinating &amp; I think we must have succeeded, as he only
came to stay five minutes said when we proposed dancing that he could only dance a set and would not
take off his sword; - but he did take off his sword and did dance more than one set - for he staid
all day and all night and next day until nearly dinner time. He played game and danced and
masqueraded and had magnificent time. We were playing blind man and I caught Woodward by his long
hair. I let go in a hurry. He danced and in order for no one to dance with Woodward <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">most</unclear> we danced <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Irish
woman</unclear> instead of <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Freshman</unclear>, it was so
funny!</p>
            <pb n="37" facs="0012_001496_000200_0037.jpg" xml:id="d3e956"/>
            <p>I am afriad cousin Christi was shocked and disgusted with my conduct, and if that be so I would
rather have never seen Woodward. He (the Major) and Capt. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Wills</unclear> went soon after the Col. left. I forgot to say that while they were at the Furnace
the whole command passed on their way to Charlotte one mile from which they are now encamped. We all
went down to the side of the road to see them pass, and as if was quite cool Woodward put the famous
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Clainket</unclear> that he wears for a coat, round Beckie and
myself. It was Sunday and they had all just left when Florence&apos;s father came for her. She was
loth to leave, and we were so sorry to part with her.</p>
            <p>Tuesday</p>
            <p>Nov. 17. 62.</p>
            <p>Wednesday we came up here and met at <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Storks</unclear> an
escort of friends who were to meet us here. They were on their way to Louisa thinking the weather
too bad for us to venture out. The party consisted of Capt. Billingsly</p>
            <pb n="38" facs="0012_001496_000200_0038.jpg" xml:id="d3e979"/>
            <p>Lieut. W. Baxter, Lieut. Rob. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">McClure</unclear>. Lieut.
McGuire. Mr. McCall and his brother formerly of the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">fist</unclear> We had a glorious time that night danced until very late. The Maj. and Capt. G. were
here, so were a number of others</p>
            <p>The girls went home Friday I believe, after having spent, I hope, a very pleasant time.</p>
            <p>I was left all alone and was just setting down in to the old routine when Saturday just after
dinner Beckie Dora Nannie, Mrs. Finley and the often heard of Charlie Tyler came. They came back so
that Nan could be with Charlie on Sunday. Sunday he came after having spent the night at camp, and
who should come with him but &quot;Cousin Chris, by the way I have promised to write to him when the
mails are opened. he told me something too about those rings. Dear Cousin Chris, I may never see you
again. They all left <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Monday</unclear> evening.</p>
            <pb n="39" facs="0012_001496_000200_0039.jpg" xml:id="d3e999"/>
            <p>Charlie Tyler asked me to name his horse. A very handsome wounded soldier - one of the beaux of
Clarkesville stopped here for a while - he was on crutches - Capt. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Creeman</unclear> - also Lieut. Mitchell. Lieut. Rogers, who named his horse for me came
to see me yesterday - I like him right well. The men in his company not being able to master her
name call her &quot;Eleanora <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">Wildfire</unclear>&quot; (the
horse)</p>
            <p>Lieut. McGuire staied here Sunday night. There is a sick soldier here. a common farmers son - I
feel so sorry for the poor fellow. He has typhoid fever. There is some fear of Yankees I believe.
The camp is only three miles from here. We will be likely to suffer should there a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NH">force</unclear> come up to attack it. Woodward has returned from
Murpheesboro with arms and ammunition. Van says he is going to </p>
            <pb n="40" facs="0012_001496_000200_0040.jpg" xml:id="d3e1017"/>
            <p>join the Regiment. I do not think he really intends it. I have been doing all I can to prevent
him from going if he really intends to do so; he is such a bad boy that I think perhaps the Army is
in truth the best place for him. I almost despair of his ever making a man that one would not blush
to <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">own</unclear> as a relation Poor Florence, I pity her.</p>
            <p>Saturday 23</p>
            <p>I have been having such pleasant visitors I hope Woodward will not move soon. Mr. Phillips has
been here with a great many of the soldiers. A Captain English came a widower, he seemed quite
smitten with_ &quot;E.W. sent me word by some gentle men who came to spend the evening that he did not
wish me to dispose of myself in any way without consulting him. The gentlemen was my old friend
Lieut. Mc Guire and his Cap.</p>
            <pb n="41" facs="0012_001496_000200_0041.jpg" xml:id="d3e1031"/>
            <p>The renowned &quot;handsomist Man in Woodward&apos;s&quot;. Capt Elliott, he is very tall and is
straight and slender has very dark hair and eyes and is exceedingly fair, he has a perfectly
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">Laeian</unclear> side face and a heavy line of black eye_brow
extinding all across his face. That is, not <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">Acviaell</unclear>
over the nose; he has a beautiful mouth with the most beautiful teeth that I ever seen. He is twenty
two or three but look much younger, in <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">indeed</unclear> he
would look boyish if it were not for a slender black mous- tach, and the dark signs of heavy wiskers
which all shaved away; he is perhaps a little singular in manner, but I like him; he always smiles
when speaking.</p>
            <p>He complimented me highly on the way in which I sang &quot;Thy name was <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">anu</unclear> the magic spell. Though it was but a questionable compliment since Lt. Mc G.
says he cant tell one time from another. By the way, there is the greatest possible difference
between these two friend Elliott and McGuire. The latter is small has light hair and light whiskers
blue eyes and a rather sad expression</p>
            <pb n="42" facs="0012_001496_000200_0042.jpg" xml:id="d3e1052"/>
            <p>He is a dear little fellow. I like him very much.</p>
            <p>Charlie Tyler was here last night he came in the evening but would not have his horse put up as
he only intended staying a short time. He staid all night and seemed to not be very anxious to go
this morning. He likes to hear me sing.</p>
            <p>Van has gone down to camp, they will not swear him but he will go with them. We have done all we
could to prevent him from going and of course there is nothing to be done but let him go.</p>
            <p>Van came up while Capt Tyler was here. Just before Charlie came in Six or seven of the soldiers
came in to hear some music. I did not know them but complied and they departed.</p>
            <p>I like Captain Tyler very much. he is handsome, he is about five feet eleven, has brown hair,
blue eyes, and good skin; all of his features are exceedingly good, and except that he is too thin a
little I think him so good looking _ and then he is such a nice fellow, so pleasant</p>
            <pb n="43" facs="0012_001496_000200_0043.jpg" xml:id="d3e1067"/>
            <p>in every way, and moral and sincere, Lieut Rogers and Lieunt W. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">Barstis</unclear> sent me word they would be up to night. How military I am becoming. I
know no one of late but soldiers from <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">Genl. doron</unclear>!
Woodward is brigadiers now.</p>
            <p>December 6. 1862.</p>
            <p>Rare, brilliant snow clothes the earth. It was snowing rapidly all yesterday morning and the
consequence is there is about three inches of snow covering hill and glen. Lawrence Washington was
here, has just gone. Sergeant T. C. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">Depoyster</unclear> left
day before yesterday having been here a week; he&apos;s badly wounded, but would go on to the
Regiment with a friend of his. Mr. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">Hiden</unclear> from
Billingsly Company.</p>
            <p>The Regiment made a raid over into Ky. returned and have now gone to Columbia where they have
been joined by Forrest. Capt Billingsly was here to see me one day, while officer of the day. When
he returned to Camp Woodward had him arrested Also <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">Gresit
Sheaperd</unclear>who came</p>
            <pb n="44" facs="0012_001496_000200_0044.jpg" xml:id="d3e1096"/>
            <p>with him. Capt Tyler has been here a time or two. I like him so much. Lieut Mc Guire was here,
quite sick; I felt so sorry for him. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">Dupoyster</unclear> is a
nice little fellow; as mischevious, just five days younger than I <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">J anlur</unclear> went into Ky with Woodward last time. He has now gone out to Ashwood to
see his sisters he went in full soldiers guise alone. I hope he may not get hurt.</p>
            <p>Bill Baxter has passed here several times but did not come in, he must be angry or perhaps does
not enter out of regard for me giving that, I might become hopelessly attached of <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">hronrn</unclear>too <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">frequently</unclear> on to his facinating company. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">Jonie
Jonie</unclear> that last sentance was ill named and you should not be guilty of such.</p>
            <p>I fear Eleanora you are loosing your silf control and you know my darling, that, &quot;He that
hath no will over his own spirit is like a city that is broken down and without walls.&quot; You are
growing so vain and egotistical.</p>
            <pb n="45" facs="0012_001496_000200_0045.jpg" xml:id="d3e1123"/>
            <p>vain what have you to be vain of? You are not pretty, you used to be right good looking but you
grow uglier evry day. You are not facinating, you have no winning ways. You are in most cases
sincere, but you are in some instances affected. You have in fact no originality but apear the
actions and manners and slang of those by whom you are surrounded.</p>
            <p>Saturday night, Dec. 6, 1862.</p>
            <p>The moon is full and it shines so brilliantly down on the pure white snow. The trees look
singularly beautiful bending down under their snow wreaths and bathed in pure silken moonlight.</p>
            <p>It is winter in earnest, and that reminds me that it is only 19 days till Christmas. I wonder
what kind of a X-Mas I will spend. Beckie &amp; I made an engagement to spend it to gather. I hope
we may.</p>
            <p>Mr L. T. Hughes has gone to Nashville. I am anxious for him to get back as I am very anxious</p>
            <pb n="46" facs="0012_001496_000200_0046.jpg" xml:id="d3e1139"/>
            <p>to hear from thence. I am afraid that Nashville will have to be sacraficed to a foe or
flames.</p>
            <p>There is a tremendous army at Murfreesboro. I am expecting an attack daily. It is Braggs fault
that Our City is not now in the hands of the Confederates.</p>
            <p>Tuesday. Dec 9 / 62</p>
            <p>Mr Hughes has returned from Nashville and brings news, both good and bad. Uncle is not well, and
seems almost to have entirely lost his mind. Poor old man. I feel so very sorry for him</p>
            <p>Mr H. saw Mary <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">jrakol</unclear> who had just come in from
Maury. Van had reached there in safety, Maj. Robertson and Capt. Charlie Tyler had been out there.
The Maj. so they said, was on his way home on sick leave_looking dreadfully. I have not seen or
heard from him yet. Some one said that the whole family had gone South &amp; taken furniture and
everything</p>
            <pb n="47" facs="0012_001496_000200_0047.jpg" xml:id="d3e1158"/>
            <p>with them. I do most sincerely hope it may be untrue. That pleasant home stead was one of the
bright spots, to which my thoughts often turned, in my hours of lonliness. Though age may crown our
heads with snow yet none of us may ever meet again. God grant we may.</p>
            <p>Pa sent me two gold pens and a ring. I am writing with one of the pens now. Pa is quite will.
Every- thing looks I think very favorable to our Southern cause; even the northen papers acknowledge
this. The South seems to have the Sympathy of the world.</p>
            <p>Thanks to our Heavenly Father, we may now once again at least hope for peace and prosperity,
though not perhaps until after a long dark and bloody Winter. Cousin Chris thinks it will be the
darkest ever known in Tennessee. Woodward and Forrest are reported in Charlotte, do not credit us
the report as some of the soldiers would have</p>
            <pb n="48" facs="0012_001496_000200_0048.jpg" xml:id="d3e1169"/>
            <p>passed <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">een</unclear>this.</p>
            <p>One of the negroes met Dupoyster on the Clarksville road this evening, he was going towards
Clarksville. Wayne was at Old Tennessee this morning to see Mr Jackson. I sent the socks I knit him,
he was not at home. Mrs. Jackson promised to deliver them. Wayne is going down again tomorrow. I
should like for Beckie to up, but we have no sugar and can get none. I have been busy sewing all day
on a dress I bought before the War, but never made up a plain green &quot;<unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">delarn</unclear>.&quot; The ring that Pa sent me has C K D on it. I
wait papers coming to know its history. Mr H says Mary N. seems quite facinated with Capt. Tyler.
Selfishness whispers to me, that old E W would be very sorry to hear that the CWT was facinated with
Mary in like style. But my friend E W</p>
            <pb n="49" facs="0012_001496_000200_0049.jpg" xml:id="d3e1184"/>
            <p>says Selfishness whispers untruely. May future developments prove that E. W. is not so very
ungenerous. She likes friendship, but is willing that others shall share it, or have more if the
friend wishes.</p>
            <p>Mamma got a nice letter from pa, written almost as much to me. He states that Ellen Grace Hillman
is dead. I am so so sorry, everyone always spoke so highly of her. I feel so sorry for her Father
and Sister and brothers. That is the third death in that immediate family since Spring, A Mother,
and two daughters, the youngest and the oldest. Grace was just budding into womanhood.</p>
            <p>Good night friend, you are the only one I have to talk to when I please and so I am ever both to
part or converse but hurriedly as I have tonight.</p>
            <p>Thursday Dec 11.</p>
            <p>It is after supper and I have just come up from supper and am in my room all alone</p>
            <pb n="50" facs="0012_001496_000200_0050.jpg" xml:id="d3e1200"/>
            <p>&quot;Cousin Chris&quot; has been here! He came first while we were eating dinner. I was so
happy, and rather surprised to see him after hearing that they had moved away. They have not gone
nor do they intend going; I am so very glad. He is not sick, looks very well_ came back on
Regimental business, is going away in a few days though I hope I Shall see him again before he goes.
As every parting I think it is the last perhaps, but a kind providence ever causes a reunion.</p>
            <p>I promised to go and see Cousin Eunice soon and I will try to go. He had a black ring on his
little finger that answers to the description of one he made for me and did not give to me. I wonder
if it is the same? He went quite early, had to attend to some business to morrow, early, and could
not stay. Old Mrs. Hughes was here, spent the day. The girls have not been over for a long time and
their Grand-ma told us today that</p>
            <pb n="51" facs="0012_001496_000200_0051.jpg" xml:id="d3e1209"/>
            <p>they were angry at some foolishness that they had heard about our inviting them to laugh at
them.</p>
            <p>The Major had ever so much to tell about Florence darling Florence, how I wish I could see her!
She is anxious to get down &quot;Cousin&quot; says; - if you only were here, my darling, what a
grand time we would have.</p>
            <p>Wayne has just gotten back from &quot;Louisn&quot;. I expect he has some news. From almost the
severest of weather it had become quite pleasant</p>
            <p>I have seen Wayne, he brings me the dearest note from my dear little &quot;Sister Beckie&quot;.
She scolds me for having had Capt Billingsly arrested. Mrs Batson is going to give a party
Christmas. I am invited down. Bell and Mc Call are coming up tomorrow.</p>
            <p>Woodward is disbanded. I am so sorry. The portion of the Regiment that was willing to serve for
the War have formed into a Company with Woodward for Captain. Capt Elliot for first Lieut. and
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">Haion</unclear>
            </p>
            <pb n="52" facs="0012_001496_000200_0052.jpg" xml:id="d3e1226"/>
            <p>
               <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">imus</unclear> 3rd. Lieut Mc Guire is 4th Coporal. I am so
sorry that any difficulty should have occured to cause them to disband. I must stop, and go to
Sewing as I want my dress to wear tomorrow if I can finish it.</p>
            <p>Friday 12, 1862.</p>
            <p>They killed their pork today and as a sequence every_body was very busy. Mamma has been having
the room opposite the parlor downstairs fixed up for herself. we will stay in there this Winter. I
expect this is the farewell night in this &quot;old room&quot;. May tonight&apos;s sleep be fraught
with pleasant dreams.</p>
            <p>Bill Baxter and Mc Call passed today and stopped at the office. I did not see them, they are
going south I believe. I think there must be some reason why Bill does not come in to see me now.
Perhaps he is angry at something I have done. They are enforcing the Conscript here now, at least
they are making out the muster rolls.</p>
            <pb n="53" facs="0012_001496_000200_0053.jpg" xml:id="d3e1241"/>
            <p>Numbers of the citizens they say have gone over in to Ky: and else where to escape it. It is in a
few cases, a sad thing, but it is necessary for the Southern success and, We must succeed. I am
willing for the women to be called if we have not men enough. I would have I would go willingly if
it were absolutely necessary. Sex, and our natural gentleness, and timidity should be conquered and
we should, fight. It&apos;s horrible to think gentle females fighting. if such a cause as Ours would
be gained by it.</p>
            <p>Cousin Christi says things are looking very dark in Mississippi. May our Heavenly Father shield
and guide our soldiers there. May our Tennesseeans there keep up the honor of her deathless name and
win laurels as nobly as their fellow statesmen did at Perryville. General Bragg has ordered
&quot;Perryville&quot; to be written on all his battle flags and on those of <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">Tenn</unclear> two <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">little</unclear> cannon in addition as a mark of distinction.</p>
            <p>It is warm tonight but very windy. The</p>
            <pb n="54" facs="0012_001496_000200_0054.jpg" xml:id="d3e1258"/>
            <p>Wind whistles mourn fully round the house corners and through the cedar tops. I hope no one I
love is out in such a dreary night as this; there is some thing so irrepressably mournful in the
low, heavy coughing of the wind; The sound always reminds me of some old forgotten legends I have
read_of some deeds of darkest horror and crime, committed on just some such night as this. Capt
Tyler has left the Regiment and gone home. The Yanks are thick and there I am afraid they will get
him prisoner as well as the remainder of Woodwards who have gone home over there.</p>
            <p>When &quot;Cousin Chris&quot; was here he gave such a laughable account of his bivouac one night
when out alone lately. The cows &amp; pigs disputed his bed with him ! The idea of his having to
sleep in that fashion, reared in luxury ! I am very sleepy so good night friend journal.</p>
            <p>E W.</p>
            <pb n="55" facs="0012_001496_000200_0055.jpg" xml:id="d3e1269"/>
            <p>Cumberland Furnace Sunday</p>
            <p>December 14. 1862</p>
            <p>Lieut Sheapherd was here yesterday to dinner, promised to be back today. So I have been dressed
up all day in my &quot;new green&quot; to receive him _ has not come as yet. He says I may expect
Captain Billingsly in a day or two as his company are ordered to reorganize at Charlotte A man here
today from Nashville brings a short business letter from Pa to Wayne. Messrs. Morgan has again
successfully encountered the &quot;Yanks&quot; according to their own papers ! Jos. E. Johnston in
Command of the Army of Tennessee&quot; _ at Murfreesboro.</p>
            <p>They Yank by this own account have armed the Negro !_ they speak of this &quot;bravery and dash
in battle&quot; and advocate _ &quot;letting them finish the war themselves.&quot; Since they are
&quot;confederate from their Gentle Manly bearing that they would do it and not treat either Women
and Children badly&quot; !! _ How such things make my blood boil !</p>
            <pb n="56" facs="0012_001496_000200_0056.jpg" xml:id="d3e1284"/>
            <p>&quot;Not treat women badly&quot; __ splendid judges they must be of that, who advocate
Butler&apos;s exceedingly humane, just and enlightened not to say strictly Christian proclamation,
at New Orleans. Christian ! Can guardian angels remain in such a time as this with even the good and
pure ? It seems as if contact with so vile a human nature would contaminate even these children of a
brighter world.</p>
            <p>We pray God to let it cease and cease too so that &quot;Our South&quot; may never be united with
a land that could give birth to such hearts.</p>
            <p>The idea of strong able men being &quot;Conscripted&quot; in such a Cause! God grant that the day
may soon come when I shall see our &quot;South&quot; with her arms spred wide, I rejoice, with a
smile of gratitude and joy lighting up the beautiful face now so darkly o&apos;er shadowed with a
warcloud ! It is getting very dark so dark that I cannot write much longer</p>
            <pb n="57" facs="0012_001496_000200_0057.jpg" xml:id="d3e1295"/>
            <p>Monday will soon be here. _ perhaps Cousin Christi will come. I think he will though Mamma does
not. I shall be so disappointed if he does not come to say good_bye before starting South. Maj. I
would rather spend a few hours with you whom I can consider a sincere friend. Than days with the
casual admirers with whom I am usually thrown.</p>
            <p>Monday Dec 15</p>
            <p>Rain ! rain ! rain ! it has done nothing else all day _ it has not stopped for a single instant
today</p>
            <p>I have been sitting in here sewing all alone with my own thoughts all Morning _ Mamma says the
Negros will not work unless she is sight after them and so she has not been in here. I like this
room right well _ it has a carpet and is much more nicely furnished than the room up stairs, and
then we are down even with the rest of the world and can see all that is going on. No one here today
_ it is so wet that I would be surprised to see any-one and yet not so very much surprised either. I
have</p>
            <pb n="58" facs="0012_001496_000200_0058.jpg" xml:id="d3e1309"/>
            <p>been half way looking for some one even against reason. It is not more than three o&apos;clock and
some one may come yet. Robert Stone came home late last evening from Louisa. all well house full of
company, pressing invitations for me to come down to spend Christmas, and they will return with me
and spend New Year&apos;s. Mamma does not want me to go. She thinks people should not dance, and be gay,
at such a time as this. I almost feel with her yet it is hard for a young light-hearted girl not to
enjoy fun and frolic when she has no immediate and pressing sorrow upon her. Besides Mamma has no
sugar and getting such things is impossible now.</p>
            <p>Do not know if I shall go or not. I do wish I had some nice book to read. I read a good deal but
very unprofitably for the want of good books. I should like some large History of Rome. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">Niebuhr&apos;s</unclear> or some, perhaps, more interesting anthem. What a
dismal day. It reminds</p>
            <pb n="59" facs="0012_001496_000200_0059.jpg" xml:id="d3e1321"/>
            <p>(This was a most un kind and unfounded speech</p>
            <p>me of a couplet I heard applied to my &quot;cousin&quot; the other day on some one saying that he
had boasted of how much liquor he could drink without feeling the effects. I can scarce believe it
though it is well authenticated. The couplet</p>
            <p>&quot;Many a bright and blooming morning &quot;Has been but a dark and dismal day&quot; was
repeated by Mamma at the time; all who know him entertain such high hopes for his future. I never
did (<unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">Sonie</unclear> you did) so confidently believe as did
others that he will become a great man, but I hope, pray, and believe that he will ever be good,
pure, true, noble ! his family almost idolize him;&quot; It would be a sad blow to them, were he to
fall. It is too late for him to come now.</p>
            <p>1863</p>
            <p>Jan. 1, ( Thursday.</p>
            <p>It has been so long since I wrote in you my journal and to me it seems as though it were longer
than it in reality has been. I have been down to Tennessee and staid out all night before Christmas
staying</p>
            <pb n="60" facs="0012_001496_000200_0060.jpg" xml:id="d3e1342"/>
            <p>one night at Louisa and returning home. Beckie &amp; Dora returning with me, also. Sam Mc Call
and Lieut Bill Baxter, only remained a few hours I had a very agreable time. The night I came home
Capt. Billingsly Maj Caldwell, Lt. Shepherd, or as we now call him &quot; Lt. Tugg &quot;, Lt
Blaakemore and several others were here. Had a very agreable evening. Next day Mr Barnes one of Capt
B&apos;s company netted 9 partridges for me. Lt Rogers came next day going south, stopped, escorted me
down to Louisa next day. Met there Capt B. or rather as I called him when he left today brother
Charlie, &quot; Lt Tugg &quot;, others and the family Danced. That night ( Christmas Eve ) caught
each others Christmas gift before retiring. Sam Mc Call and Captain Billingsly gave me a five cent
piece apiece Christmas night went to Mrs. Batson&apos;s &quot; Kickup &quot; that we had all talked
about so much Enjoyed the dance exceedingly Fannie Plummer there. She and Roger seem quite smitten,
rode home that night the way we came in a &quot; waggon &quot; went next day to such a nice dinner
at Mrs Jackson&apos;s, danced that night</p>
            <pb n="61" facs="0012_001496_000200_0061.jpg" xml:id="d3e1349"/>
            <p>Went back next day to Louisa in waggon Beckie on horseback with Captain Billingsly, each smitten
with the other. Lt. Rogers attentive to E. W. grows sentimental</p>
            <p>Sunday, Mr &amp; Mrs Mc Kiernan start to Ala. Bill Mc Call, Tom Baxter go with them. Many of the
&quot; beans &quot; leave. Sam Mc Call, Waltar Wilcox, Peaches, Mr. Baxter and Rogers remaining till
evening _ Wilcox Sam Mc Call and Peaches go off _ will not tell where they are gone. Come up to
Cumberland Monday Morning with Beckie, Dora, Lt. Rogers. Find Captain Billingsly Lt Shepherd here _
, that night several others. Capt. Moore, Sergeant Calardy &amp; others_ dance _ grand time.
Wednesday go down to Mrs Cunninghams <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">rool</unclear>a &amp;
home. Fannie comes also Mr Bill, Rode down to Mrs C&apos;s with Blakemore. Beckie, Billingsly, Dora
Shepherd Clardy and Baxter _ round generally. Danced that night as <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">sathos</unclear> last night, for so it was. Col Trantt Mc Sairy here Tuesday night also
Lonnie Kirkman.</p>
            <p>Thursday Morning, New Years day all leave_ so lonely, report last night, Yankees came from
Clarksville to Charlotte. Took 13 Captain Billings</p>
            <pb n="62" facs="0012_001496_000200_0062.jpg" xml:id="d3e1366"/>
            <p>lys Company prisoners; Now I have written a list of the time I can speak of the pleasure. Like
Sam Mc Call so much, also Captain Billingsly also Lt. Shepherd, Henry Clardy _ The dearest, funniest
little fellow, also every body. Lt. Rogers left this morning _ more sentimental than ever joined
&quot; Captain&apos;s &quot; Company. Gave me a book &quot; The last of the Fairies &quot; a Christmas
tale by James &quot; not good _ read it today.</p>
            <p>Another Year has begun. How many many weeks have transpired to engrave &quot; 62 &quot;
indellibly on the minds of men and on the annals of time. And Oh how thank-ful I should be that this
past year so filled with woe and hatred and despair has passed so pleasantly for me particularly
when it was growing old. Oh, God My Father Shield and guide me in every thought word and deed_ even
the most trivial during this New Year. Oh, Father make me better, purer holier and more beloved and
respected,</p>
            <pb n="63" facs="0012_001496_000200_0063.jpg" xml:id="d3e1375"/>
            <p>Saturday. Jan 3, 1863.</p>
            <p>Col. Brewer here last night, afraid of a surprise, left suddenly this morning on hearing that
Yankees were in Charlotte. We are expecting them here. They were in Charlotte last Wednesday only
staid a few hours, took several prisoners. it is reported that they took Captain Billingslys&apos;
father. I hope it is not so.</p>
            <p>We were all dancing here that night, Captain, and all the men acted so coolly and bravely. I do
most sincerely hope that they will none of them be harmed. Captain Billingsly is too noble and brave
to be immured within prison walls. Lt. Wright here last Thursday staid all night. Does not know
anything of Captain Charlie Tyler, is rather afraid that he is taken prisoner. I do most fervently
hope that it is not so. I should be so so sorry if it were really so. Perhaps if he is free he will
be here e&apos;er many days Lt. Wright says he has a letter for me from Florence. I would give so much to
see it. <gap reason="indecipherable" resp="NH"/> will perhaps be back e&apos;er long, and he will bring me the
news. I erase the name on reflection as its presence might do some harm.</p>
            <pb n="64" facs="0012_001496_000200_0064.jpg" xml:id="d3e1389"/>
            <p>It seems as though a just and pure heaven were frowning on the evil deeds of men. The Sun has
hidden his face from the sons of men so that they may know he loves not their deeds of evil How I
should love to have a landscape _ in the style of Claud Lorainne to gaze upon, on such a day as
this__ to turn from the somber, cold, and grey _ to do its beautiful, glowing, golden. I do so love
paintings. I would love to be surrounded by them. I could pass many a weary hour pleasantly away
gazing or gloating o&apos;er their beauties.</p>
            <p>What exquisite delight it would be to own a face beautiful, beyond all description &amp; awe that
most powerful language of the brush_ beautiful as that of Beatrice Cener&apos;_ for I can conceive of no
more beautiful face than that of some copies I have seen of the loveliness of this sad fated
daughter of Venus. This thought of a painting has brought back memories of my school days so
forcibly, of the days or rather hours spent so pleasantly in the dear old painting gallery Memories
of <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">Lexcie</unclear> and Sue and Lucie, Hennie and Annie and
Julia,</p>
            <pb n="65" facs="0012_001496_000200_0065.jpg" xml:id="d3e1401"/>
            <p>and of darling Irene, and Hannah.</p>
            <p>How strange it seems that we who were such intimate and devoted friends for years should now be
so widely severed, scarcely knowing if the others are living or dead. And my darling sister Hettie !
Cousin Christi says she is not a unionist as the rest of the family are, I am so glad. Oh I fogot to
state that Mr. Elliot had been released and is at Murfreesboro acting as Chaplain. I feel so
rejoiced that he is once more free__ he is looking very well too they say.</p>
            <p>It is quite late and the Yankees, reported to have been coming here, have not yet made their
appearance_ perhaps they will come in the morning. I do not feel any fear of them except that they
may make or endeavor to make Wayne take the oath, and will most likely take all our fire arms. They
are Kentucky troops from <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">Bince&apos;s</unclear> command I
think, and women have no cause to fear them as they had the Ft Donelson Yanks. The Ft. Donelson
troops do not forage in this direction now. I am so glad</p>
            <pb n="66" facs="0012_001496_000200_0066.jpg" xml:id="d3e1415"/>
            <p>We are expecting stirring news from before Nashville daily god grant that our great army there
may be victorious Oh, how I do wish that this war would cease ! God grant that 1863 may close on a
peaceful and happy South May the garments of this fair young year never wear the war stains of the
garments of 62</p>
            <p>Poor old &quot;62&quot; his locks were indeed blood stained and Oh what precious blood had caused
those stains __ the life side of so many warm, noble, patriotic hearts _ beating high with hope and
bravery, _ and yet this year of strife passed so gently away, a soft warm moon-lit night was the 31,
of Dec 1862</p>
            <p>Sunday 4.</p>
            <p>Mr. Leonard here from Clarksville last night. New Fighting before Murfreesboro. South Victorious
thus far. A terrible battle most likely going on there now. God grant that the Southerners may
conquer. The Yanks did not come. They returned to Clarksville with several prisoners</p>
            <pb n="67" facs="0012_001496_000200_0067.jpg" xml:id="d3e1430"/>
            <p>last evening. I can not hear certainly who they have taken I would like so much to know. Mr. L.
came to say that three of the negroes who ran away were in the jail at Clarksville.</p>
            <p>After a very hard rain last night it is as bright and clear as possible this morning. I always
feel so happy light and gay on such a day as this. I am to commence house keeping for Mamma
tomorrow. I scarce know how I shall succeed. I do not know any thing whatever about it.</p>
            <p>Wayne goes down to Mt. Vernon tomorrow on business if nothing prevents and perhaps Beckie will
return with him I hope she will. At night. I have been over the creek walking stopped in at Hughes
&amp; heard the sad-est, oh so sad ! news, that it is reported that my dear dear friend Captain, or
rather Col. T. W. Beaumont is killed. nothing can cause so much regret as to hear of the death of a
dear, dear, friend, and Col. Beaumont I always held one of my best and warmest. God grant that it be
written but if is so and it be not sacralige I pray _ Lord have mercy on his soul</p>
            <pb n="68" facs="0012_001496_000200_0068.jpg" xml:id="d3e1441"/>
            <p>Cheatham is not dead, later</p>
            <p>Our General Cheatham is reported killed also Rains. Oh how Tennessee should deplore the loss of
these two of her bravest and noblest Sons, yet she should not alone weep for these, the humbler sons
of Liberty should be mourned, for their lives were dearer than all to many hearts. I mourn the
Generals&apos; deaths as that of my country _ but I mourn Col. Beaumonts as my own loss. I do not believe
he is dead I can not, I do not feel as if it were so. I am not superstitious but I somhow, always
feel it when any thing evil has happened to my friends.</p>
            <p>Monday, Jan. 5, 1863.</p>
            <p>Commenced house keeping for Mamma today _ tis not much trouble__ Made some collars__ curled my
hair. I received a letter or rather note from Capt. Tyler, in the care of Katie Mc Cauley, dated
yesterday _ suppose he must have been there. Mc Cauley; he wrote to apologize for having forgotten
to bring from home a letter Florence wrote to me and sent by him. He left it in Vans&apos; possession. It
is reported that Alonzo Napier is killed _ I am so</p>
            <pb n="69" facs="0012_001496_000200_0069.jpg" xml:id="d3e1455"/>
            <p>sorry to hear it. The Yanks are reported whipped with several generals killed,__among whom is
Mitchell, and four taken Prisoners, two of these are Mc Cook &amp; Negley. They have renewed the
attack and are so far as we can hear still fighting before Murfreesboro. I have commenced the life
of Walter Scot_ have only the first vol. but trust I can gain some useful knowledge from even that.
Mr. Leonard advises me to read &quot;Wilson&apos;s Tales of The Border&quot; _ if I even should be so
fortunate as to come across them.</p>
            <p>The Yanks have been after Mr. Baxter, Walter Wilcox and several others, and they have, I believe
they have all started South. The Yanks will drive all the soldiers out of the country. Beckie and I
will be minus beaus now. Mr Hughes has gone to Clarksville has not yet returned. hope he will be
back soon and bring the news. It is reported that the Southern forces have gained another great
victory at Fredericksburg Va.</p>
            <p>Jan 7, 1863.</p>
            <p>Wednesday. The Yankees have been here ! Yesterday about 2 o&apos;clock</p>
            <pb n="70" facs="0012_001496_000200_0070.jpg" xml:id="d3e1469"/>
            <p>I was standing in the kitchen I saw 14 of them come riding by, they rode up to the cribs, and
there met Mr. Hicks and arrested him and have taken him off.</p>
            <p>But I cannot write of even a thing like the first visit of the Yankees now for I have just heard
again that Col. Thomas W. Beaumont is dead. It is said, that there existed such a bitter rivalry
between this Reg. 50 Tenn and a Miss. Reg. that they were anxious to fight each other; their
general, it being the eve of a battle placed them in front and told them to fight Yankees and they
did fight reppelling Thousands of the foe but alas ! They were nearly all left on the field. And
those glorious blue eyes have closed forever on the light of day, and there were no tears shed over
you, my friend, save those tears which the stars weep, drops of dew, but he is not dead I know it is
not true, but if he had so died, it would have been a glorious death, not only fighting for the
South, driving back the invaders, but, fighting for the honor of</p>
            <pb n="71" facs="0012_001496_000200_0071.jpg" xml:id="d3e1478"/>
            <p>his native Tennessee, such a death was worthy of him. Those two regiments of men stood up against
thirty-thousand for two hours. It seems too much for even Southern Valor, too much even for
Tennesseeans. The men the Yanks arrested have just returned, beside Hicks. There are two of the
neighbors Mr. Bowen and Mr. Jackson at tho <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">office</unclear>
just back from Clarksville, to which place the Yanks took them. The Yanks did not search the house,
did not even come in to it, they behaved very well.</p>
            <p>We are all somewhat astonished that they arrested Hicks and did not say anything to Wayne.
Something has happened today which I can not put down here, it does not however concern me. It has
been a very cold, clear day, beautiful to see but so unpleasant in temperature. Forrest is reported
wounded and the brave, dashing <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">Napiers</unclear> is certainly
dead he was killed when charging a battery at the head of his men. He was pierced by three balls.
Well may my native state lament the loss of a brave son in this, <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">Napier</unclear>! I had no idea when I saw him so short a while ago, that he would so soon
crown the name with honor</p>
            <pb n="72" facs="0012_001496_000200_0072.jpg" xml:id="d3e1496"/>
            <p>and glory and even <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">laster</unclear> life to sustain the
reputation he had won with so fearless a hand, from the foe, God pity his family, as well all those
who see thus bereft of dear ones by the ruthless hand of War.</p>
            <p>Jan. 8, 1863. Night</p>
            <p>Lt. Mc Guire has been here ! I heard some one knock at the door and went out and met him. He is
with Woodward who is on his way to Clarksville with a flag of truce to exchange prisoners. He came
just at our old dinner hour and I know expected something to eat, but we had four o&apos;clock dinner and
In consequence, had nothing to offer but two cold biscuits. I did feel ashamed to come in with the
two poor lonesome looking biscuits. Van is with Woodward, he captured a Yank and his horse, and is
now riding the charger which is a beautiful black one. Lt. Mc Guire captured five. The Lieut. is a
dear little fellow and so brave, yet so modest and unassuming. I like him exceedingly. He met
Captain Tyler at Willauerport and Captain Billingsly at Columbia. Capt Campbell has also</p>
            <pb n="73" facs="0012_001496_000200_0073.jpg" xml:id="d3e1511"/>
            <p>gotten safely through. I do wish Woodward would drive them out of this country. (The Yank). My
thoughts run so much faster than my pen, that I make sad mistakes sometimes.</p>
            <p>Woodward sent a waggon up here to be mended, a very peremptory Military order accompanied it. It
is reported that for some cause the Southerners have fallen back to a stronger position from
Murfreesboro. Our Cavalry however stil hold the town. It is also reported, though somewhat vaguely,
that the fighting has been renewed. We have heard that the Surgeons state that the Yankee loss was
three to one in the late battle. Woodward has been in ten fights. The weather has been cold and
cloudy all day, rained nearly all the evening, very slowly. Read nearly all day, Made a pair of
cuffs tonight</p>
            <p>Saturday Jan. 10. Night</p>
            <p>Col. Woodward has been here with the portion of his command who went with him under the flag of
truce to Clarksville, they took dinner here. Mr. Alexander and Dr. Holmes of the party, also Lt. Mc
Guire about 25 in all, only staid for dinner</p>
            <pb n="74" facs="0012_001496_000200_0074.jpg" xml:id="d3e1525"/>
            <p>Have gone on, perhaps as far as Charlotte. Col. Woodward says the War will be over in three
months. Lt. Mc Guire is afraid of being killed. I should not say afraid, for I do not think he fears
anything, but he seems to think that he will be. Captain Billingsly has joined Col. Woodward.</p>
            <p>Mr. Leonard is here from Clarksville brings Yankee papers which state that Capt. Snowden, my dear
old friend is wounded, it does not say seriously, so I hope it is only slight. I do pray it may not
prove fatal. I know of no young man, who would be a greater loss to his family, and friends. And
Orvell Ewing is reported killed, poor Orvell ! I am so so sorry. How many sad sad hearts runninig
over with woe there are in Nashville tonight. God pity them all ! Mothers, fathers, sisters,
brothers, wives, loves and friends</p>
            <p>Oh how I wish I could be at Murfreesboro, to sooth those poor wounded and dying soldiers. May
they all find womans sympathy and be nursed by womans care. The rough soldier is but a poor
comforter in ones hours of pain and anguish.</p>
            <pb n="75" facs="0012_001496_000200_0075.jpg" xml:id="d3e1536"/>
            <p>What suffering and misery God cast near me, that alone can I alleviate, I am too poor to bear
expense of going to a place like Murfreesboro to take care of the sick and wounded. I fear my wish
to do good in this way is not prompted purely by Love of God, and perhaps this is why He does not
gratify my wish, patriotism and a longing to make some one grateful is a great incentive to me, but
pity for their suffering would be one main spring of exertion.</p>
            <p>Poor, dear, Mr. Snowden, I do most fervently hope that his wound is not serious. The Southerners
have not fallen back from Murfreesboro. It was a most Glorious Victory for us.</p>
            <p>We have in these Yankee papers long and very wordy excuses for our having whipped them so badly
at Fredericksburg. They, as usual, now claim a victory at Nashville, but we all know otherwise.</p>
            <p>Sunday Jan 11, 1863.</p>
            <p>It is a beautiful day the air is so soft and warm and the sky is a pale silvery blue, save around
the sun, where it is ringed with a soft, golden luster.</p>
            <pb n="76" facs="0012_001496_000200_0076.jpg" xml:id="d3e1552"/>
            <p>It is about 3 O&apos;clock, Mamma is sleeping, and I am sitting all in <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">quietude</unclear>, with the yellow, lonesome sunshine streaming in across the floor,
through the western window. The fire is as it were dying away in the fireplace, and I am half
writing, half dreaming, dreaming of, I scarce know what, looking away over the hill tops at the sky
with half pleasant &quot;faraway feelings&quot;, if I may so express it. But in the midst of any
lazy, happy dreaming comes a vision of how woeful ! _ a vision of our poor boys suffering, dying, at
Murfreesboro. Oh God that I could be there to soothe away their pain ! to give them words of comfort
and of hope, but other hands are there I trust softer and more skillful perhaps. I hope Mr. Snowden
is not badly wounded. Mamma and I took a short walk this morning, though it seems to have tired her
exceedingly. She seems at times quite feeble.</p>
            <p>Wayne has gone down to Mt. Vernon Mr. Leonard left this morning.</p>
            <p>Cumberland Furnace</p>
            <p>Eleanora Willauer</p>
            <pb n="77" facs="0012_001496_000200_0077.jpg" xml:id="d3e1568"/>
            <p>January 12, 1863.</p>
            <p>Monday night.</p>
            <p>The wind whistles mournfully without shrieking out a dismal &quot;<unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">music</unclear>&quot; over the dead hopes which cling round the forms of so many brave and
gallant sons of Tennessee who are, perhaps even now, lying stiff and stark with the pale moon light
illuminating those features, never again so to be made brilliant by the light of life and hope and
joy.</p>
            <p>Many, indeed nearly all the young men from this neighborhood who were engaged in the fight at
Murfreesboro have been either wounded or killed. I knew none of them, but I deeply sympathize with
their mourning friends. A squad of blue coats passed here today under a flag of truce the negroes
say, they were going towards Clarksville. Said to negro that they had been to look for W. Bell, some
Morgan men, who are reported to have been in &quot;Cake&quot; and &quot;Captain Tyler, found
neither. Have been reading Scott by Lockhart also wrote a note to Mr Cunningham relative to having
my piano tuned as there is a man at her house who tuned hers. Have been sewing all day altering a
calico dress.</p>
            <pb n="78" facs="0012_001496_000200_0078.jpg" xml:id="d3e1586"/>
            <p>Wednesday. Jan 14, 1863.</p>
            <p>A man here, from Hillmans _ Musgrove, brings news _ Yanks, are whipped at Vicksburg ! He saw the
death of Col. Beaumont in the papers, it happened as I have before stated, and now, I suppose I must
believe that my dear friend is killed. It was at Ft. Hudson, on the coast of Lou. I think it is;
they conquered, but he was killed. I feel that in him I have lost a sincere friend, and who can
estimate the value of such, in such times as these?</p>
            <p>I have learned Hoods &quot;Bridge of Sighs&quot; today by heart. I have long known most of the
verses, but did not know their order, this is much the hardest part to remember. I think it one of
the tenderest, sadest, most touchingly beautiful pieces of poetry, that I ever read. Musgrove says
the Yanks lost seventy-thousand at Vicksburg._ The Southern loss was almost nothing. The Yankees
acknowledge that they are badly whipped.</p>
            <p>Mamma told me of such a thrillingly dreadful thing, that happened at Reading, Pa. long ago, when
she was young. Rained all day</p>
            <pb n="79" facs="0012_001496_000200_0079.jpg" xml:id="d3e1600"/>
            <p>Thursday. Jan. 15, 1863. Night</p>
            <p>Has been snowing all day and part of last night, about four inches of snow on the ground. It has
almost ceased to fall now. Wayne came back this evening, from Mt. Vernon, looked like &quot;Cris
Cringle&quot; when he came in, all covered over with snow. I was very glad he came, for Mamma was
very uneasy. All well below. Beckie and Dora sent me a little snow bird apiece, drawn and picked !
Sam Mc Call went south with Will Baxter. Prince, almost frozen to death, last night, so the blacks
say__ went for liquor, got drunk and lay out all night in the snow. I am so sorry I always rather
liked him; he is a smart, active, willing servant. It is reported that all or nearly all of
Robertsons negroes have gone off. Rumor states that Forrest and Morgan have captured five transports
and a gunboat on the River about twelve miles from here and have advanced on Clarksville. Not very
authentic.</p>
            <p>It is very dark out. Exceedingly cold, How I should like to go sleigh riding ! I never have been
in my life.</p>
            <pb n="80" facs="0012_001496_000200_0080.jpg" xml:id="d3e1612"/>
            <p>16. General Forrest here <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">3</unclear> thousand men!</p>
            <p>Tuesday,. Jan. 20Early Friday morning I went down to the office and begged the boys Wayne and
Bob. To have a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">&quot;jumper&quot;</unclear> made and take me
out sleighing.They very good naturedly agreed to do it and we had a grand time fixed up. Were going
down to Louisa<unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">Va.</unclear> I was highly elated at the idea
and was jumping round at a great rate, when some one came rushing along the porch and fell down just
at our window. I ran to see who it was and on opening the shutters who should step in but Van! I
never was more astonished in my life. He and Dr. Wood had come on in advance of Forest and
Wheeler&apos;s whole command. Dr. Wood I became acquainted with in Woodward&apos;s regiment. He is
now Forrest&apos;s Brigade surgeon</p>
            <p>They had been here about an hour when General Forrest and command came. I had just entered the
parlor after dinner when a man arose from the rock-</p>
            <pb n="81" facs="0012_001496_000200_0081.jpg" xml:id="d3e1634"/>
            <p>ing chair and Dr. introduced him as General Forrest. He is tall and Large (not very) and I think
very fine-looking. He is rather pale, has large blue eyes an almost strait nose, a little inclined
to retrouss, wears a black moustach, gotee, and imperial, his hair, which he does not wear shingled
in military fashion, &amp; is iron grey a large head mouth rather good. black arched eyebrows. very
pleasant in manner and conversation a little inclined to be egotistical his men say he is very
cruel, when excited. Captain Elliot was here in command of Woodward&apos;s - the Col not having
reached Columbia when they started. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">Lt Barkemore here also
Henry Claidy</unclear> got acquianted with Hieronymus, sings very well.</p>
            <p>The General told me I should not get married until I was twenty or twenty one! He guessed that I
was 17. I told him that I was nearer nineteen 19, Capt C. and Dr Wood thought that was very candid.
It was right funny the gen. giving me such sage advice</p>
            <pb n="82" facs="0012_001496_000200_0082.jpg" xml:id="d3e1646"/>
            <p>He told me I must marry for love he said he married a lady who was not worth a dollar. Dr Wood
complimented me very highly on my vioce particularly in <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">Lorenar</unclear> also Captain Elliot, John, General Forrest&apos;s chief <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">officer</unclear> says I have a &quot;voice like Jinnie Lind&quot;!!!
He played &quot;revelle&quot; at my door next morning. it was so pretty and so martial. Dr Wood says
I have a beautiful name! he wrote it on the window pane with his diamond ring. Also his own.</p>
            <p>Dr. has beautiful blue eyes. he knows Florence Antoinette and Cousin Rebecca The General&apos;s
headquarters have been at Ashwood .for some time. Mrs. Forrest is staying with Cousin Rebecca I made
the acquaintance of numbers of the officers one Capt Anderson. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">Hot. High. Gun.</unclear> sang a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">toast</unclear> to me, so
such a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">liquid aria</unclear>. there are other verses. </p>
            <p>Here&apos;s a health to Forrest&apos;s band Drink it down Here&apos;s a health to Forrests band
Drink it down</p>
            <pb n="83" facs="0012_001496_000200_0083.jpg" xml:id="d3e1672"/>
            <p>Here&apos;s a health Forrest&apos;s band &apos;tis the bravest in the land Drink it down drink it
down <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">down</unclear> drink the verse to me was.. &quot;To Miss
Willauer for the pleasures of the hour,&quot; There was one , &quot;To Tennessee For her son will
e&apos;er be free&quot; Andeson knows pa,. I think from the generals lecture he must have told him
that I was poor. I like him right well. . We played &quot;<unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">Imut</unclear>&quot; and they gave me a moustache and imperial and someone placing a hat on my
head, <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">Saint</unclear> Douglas remarked that I looked very
like, Captain Elliot The Captain said he thought so too. he is very handsome!! I like him so much Dr
Wood says he knows that I am high tempered from my face he does not like Florence much because he
thinks her high tempered. Gen Forrest left for Columbia Saturday. left a detachment behind Napiers
Command under De Moss, and Capt Elliott. staid here that night also. Blakemore, Hieronymus, Clardy
and a Mr. Bruckner, De Moss went down nearer the river All staid at Cumber</p>
            <pb n="84" facs="0012_001496_000200_0084.jpg" xml:id="d3e1688"/>
            <p>land next night Capt&apos;s Elliot and De, Moss alone, staying in the house Hieronymus and the
rest staid at Hughes. Last night Maj Holman stayed here about three hundred Cavalry. Maj Holman Lt.
(Somebody?) and Dr. Swanson stayed in the house. I do not like the Maj - why? I do not know. like
the Dr. Tolerably. They have all gone now. They took a transport and burnt it down at our landing
The Yankee gunboats shelled the place no harm done. I gave Henry Clardy my riding gloves, am
Knitting another pair. Wayne has traded off his horse for a pretty little mare he says, I can ride
it. Old <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">Gyp</unclear> was killed in battle poor old fellow! I
have had many a pleasant ride on your back! Hieronymus wrote off &quot;Tennessee my Tennessee&quot;
for me. Mamma was suffering nearlly all the time from sickhead.ache</p>
            <pb n="85" facs="0012_001496_000200_0085.jpg" xml:id="d3e1698"/>
            <p>Tuesday. Feb. 3. 1863. Have not written for so long. have so much to write Col. Woodward was hurt
down at River came up here staid several days to get well. Doctor Holmes the dear old man staid here
for some time Lt Mc Guire here ever since I last wrote left yesterday Col W. left day before sent
for by Gen. Wheeller who has come down with two or three brigade Dr H. left with Lt McG. I was so
sorry to see them go. Charlie Medly Col W&apos;s pet. was here was wounded some time ago almost well
Eddie Gray boy who &quot;ducked&quot; Gen. Forrest, here. I went riding on Charlie Medley&apos;s
horse with himself and Lt. Mc Guire one day such a pleasant ride. Have heard cannon in the direction
of Donelson this evening some of them intimated to me that Wheller was going down to take Donelson
God grant it may be a bloodless victory Oh how fervently I pray that none of my friends at least may
be hurt I like some of them so much Dr. Holmes and Lt. McGuine have both proven themselves to be
sincere friends</p>
            <pb n="86" facs="0012_001496_000200_0086.jpg" xml:id="d3e1706"/>
            <p>Col. Woodward brought me a letter from Florence a nice long letter. I was so glad to hear from
her I recieved a letter from her the other night, since, Though written long before, brought by the
famous &quot;Cousin John Handy&quot; he is good looking but not very polished. Cousin F. and Cousin
Rebecca have gone to Nashville. I wrote to F. by Mr Hughes who went out with some wagons to haul
grain to Columbia for Government. Mr. H. has just returned but I have not seen him. Wills Gould was
here, also Lt Dougless One Major Hodgson was here for several days from Montgomery. Ala so smart
well-informed and agreeable. Capt Harris here on Wheeler&apos;s staff knows <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">Jull</unclear> Watson. Lt Sheapherd here with a friend of his a bogus
&quot;Captain&quot; Nichols dis like, the latter and do not like the former <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">Imet</unclear> I find him in such company. Cousin F. is a great Belle
&quot; they say, she speaks very com placently of her number of beaus.</p>
            <pb n="87" facs="0012_001496_000200_0087.jpg" xml:id="d3e1719"/>
            <p>Col Demoss left here this morning. It is a bitter cold night a light fall of snow a day old on
the ground I do feel so deeply for the suffering I know our soldiers must be enduring down at
Donelson. How dreadful it must be if any of them are wounded. God pity them all! and may none that I
know be among the sufferers. Lt. McGuire staid here long enough for me to know him well. and I am
happy to call one whom I consider so good and sincere a friend. and to be myself considered a friend
by him. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">more of him anon</unclear>
            </p>
            <p>Feb. 4. 1863 Wednesday No news yet from Donelson I would give so much to know how the fight
turned out. It is a very cold day and is cloudy. I am afraid it is going to snow again. This is leap
year I did not know it until Today how well I remember the summer of last leap year. Poor &quot;Pat
Hooks&quot; Florence discarded him the other day. Mr Browder the gentleman to whose little son I
gave my pet squirrel last summer, was here the other night.</p>
            <pb n="88" facs="0012_001496_000200_0088.jpg" xml:id="d3e1731"/>
            <p>The pet is still living and in fine order. his family are in Montgomery Ala. It is snowing what a
dreary dreary, view I have from my window so cold and gray and desolate. Will my future life be
typefied by this evening? How darkly veiled the future is from mortal <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">Ken!</unclear> I have not the faintest idea of where or what I will be a year hence. Go
grant this cruel war may soon cease last February we lost Donelson it is February now perhaps we
retook it yesterday. It has been a long dreadful dreary year so fraught with sorrow pain, anguish,
despair, so many noble, brave, fine true hearts have poured out the last treasured drop of their
life tides, have sacrificed themselves on the altar of thier native land their sunny southern homes.
How good and pure our women should be when our men are so brave and patriotic and then. The
toughening influence of camp life should be counteracted by increased gentleness and refinement on
our part</p>
            <pb n="89" facs="0012_001496_000200_0089.jpg" xml:id="d3e1742"/>
            <p>Oh my Father make me better, purer, more gentle. holier more Thy child Thy servant! How I pray to
be guided in thought, mood, and deed and yet at times my prayers seem almost ineffectual I am so
selfish,vainfickle God teach me to know my faults and to correct them. It is night and still
snowing, how I do hope that my soldiers friends and acquaintances are none of them suffering in, and
from This bitter cold. Perhaps we shall hear from below <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">me</unclear> the morning I hope we may.</p>
            <p>Thursday. Feb. 5. 1863. Lt. Hieronymus and Baker <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">Jonson</unclear> have first left We were repulsed no we did not lake Donelson on account of our
amunition giving out. Col. McNairy is reported killed he was here the other day. I am so sorry
Jonnie Kirkman was slightly wounded. Col Woodward slightly wounded Dupoyster wounded in the finger,
slightly no one else that I knew, so far is heard from, hurt I am so thankful to our Father that he
has thus seemingly heard my</p>
            <pb n="90" facs="0012_001496_000200_0090.jpg" xml:id="d3e1758"/>
            <p>poor prayer. The forces have all gone on to Charlotte The Confederate loss was about a hundred
killed wounded and missing Col Woodward lost fifteen he only menton with 60. poor Col he will feel
their loss so deeply. Hieronymus did not seem to care <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">nureh</unclear> he would have me sing. To think of a hundred of our brave Southerners being
sacraficed for nothing sacraficed to the carelessness of some Commander, where the blame rests I
know not but blame there is. Is Bragg a Traitor?</p>
            <p>Night</p>
            <p>I was called away from my journal by Wayne in my sleigh, it is just finished I went out to ride
had such a nice time it has been snowing all day and last night snowing still The pleasure of my
ride was marred by the ever recurring rememberence of our disaster. Lt McGuire saw his brother. Gen
Forrest had two horses shot under him. William Forrest the Gen Son was wounded. Longstreet has not
superseeded Bragg.</p>
            <pb n="91" facs="0012_001496_000200_0091.jpg" xml:id="d3e1772"/>
            <p>Feds. reported to be in Franklin going to Columbia. Capt Tyler with the command. Hieronymus sings
so well. Major Holman, rumor states to be wounded in the thigh. I hope it is not true that Col.
Frank McNairy was killed. I am so thoughtless I did not ask after dear old Dr Holmes but H. said
none of those I knew were wounded, or killed. A man named Pierce was killed, shot through the heart,
while Hieronymus was leaning, up against him. I, so unchristian am I, I did not even remind That
Thoughtless young soldier, that he should have been thankful to his maker for having spared him. God
make me better. I did not pray this morning. It seems as if I grow worse, instead of better. I am so
vain and selfish. not stingy I mean my motive is self even my most generous acts, are in part, that
I did them. I am too fond of the applause of those by whom I am surrounded.</p>
            <p/>
            <pb n="92" facs="0012_001496_000200_0092.jpg" xml:id="d3e1780"/>
            <p>Sunday. Feb 8. 1863. Good news. The &quot;yanks&quot; have evacuated Ft. Donelson. They are badly
whipped at Ft Hudson, where my friends most likely are and Charleston harbor is open hurrah for
Beaure gard! he always was my particular admiration. </p>
            <p>There has been snow on the ground for several daysand it was very cold has moderated and is
cloudy The snow is melting slowly. Put up ice yesterday. Ice will not be of much use to no out here
in the country where we can get cool spring water when we have no sugar or anything else to make
good things of. but perhaps this horrid war will be over by summer time and we can have a few of the
now considered &quot;luxurys&quot; which we used to think so nessary to our existance There is not a
teacup full of sugar in this house</p>
            <p>Wayne has first come in with a basket full of robins <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">32</unclear> they caught 700 one night and 500 the next in</p>
            <pb n="93" facs="0012_001496_000200_0093.jpg" xml:id="d3e1795"/>
            <p>the cedar trees down at Dr Cunninghams I can scarcely believe that there are, or rather were so
many here, poor little robin red breasts!! Mrs. Hughes from the farm sent these to mamma &quot;Who
killed cock robin.&quot; how I used to admire that doleful but highly interesting and illustrated
&quot;poem&quot;! What a triumph it was when I could repeat it! had it all so myself in my own head.
I love the robins alive; poor little robbie with your plumes all ruffled and your neck broken!
however I expect I shall like you quite as well for dinner today. you see I do not forsake you
&quot;Rob&quot; as Lieut. McGuire calls you, even in death.</p>
            <p>Dear little Lt. I like you, better than your proud, much admired, handsome friend, the Captain I
like the Capt very much and should like him better if he were not, even though it be in a small
degree a flirt I blush to write such an epithet applying it to one I like, but its true I wish it
were not.</p>
            <p>I like you better though. I should like to have a gentleman. as sincere as you appear ro be for a
friend, all through</p>
            <pb n="94" facs="0012_001496_000200_0094.jpg" xml:id="d3e1806"/>
            <p>my young ladyhood like to have him near to advise and enlighten me.</p>
            <p>Wednesday Feb 11. 63.</p>
            <p>The sun shines once again. a few clouds go <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">sendding</unclear> over the sky and the wind is as high as March. The <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">crocus</unclear> and snow drops buttercups are all up and I think I see some traces of the
violets. I have been trying to sketchtook a sketch of Aunt Cilla&apos;s house from our window, also,
one, small, on letter paper, of the stable and barn, The negroes and others are still killing the
poor little robins I am affraid they will kill them all I hope the foolish little things will change
their roosting place after the 14. At this time last year the Yanks were making their grand move on
the Forts below. I wonder when this war will cease. I feel so strangely apathetical today tis not
the lazy, happy feeling which spring brings but a sort of unpleasant, half painful feeling pervades
my head and limbs and nothing moves me which is strange <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">in our
or keen by</unclear> alive to every emotion at least of pleasure.</p>
            <pb n="95" facs="0012_001496_000200_0095.jpg" xml:id="d3e1827"/>
            <p>
               <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">W.B.</unclear>
            </p>
            <p>A drunken soldier shot a man living near here, a short time ago. The man Harrison Nicols lives on
Bear Creek eight or ten miles from here. He shot him several times even after life was extinct he
then tried to shoot a wounded soldier, missed must have been made a maniac by the liquor. I never
will I register it here and sincerely hope I may never break the vow I never will wed a man who is,
to my knowledge, in the slightest degree intemperate. It is in itself bad, and leads to everything
evil. Wednesday after supper It has been such a delightful day as bright and soft and warm as early
June. Went out riding on my horse &quot;Mary Nichol&quot; for the first time this evening, such a
pleasant ride like her very much. Have felt so happy ever since morning, in the hope of Spring I
suppose I am a strange child I am nearly always so gay, and light-hearted and I dont know why</p>
            <p>The negroes meet me and say &quot;good evening Miss Ellen seems like you is always glad
&apos;bout somthing.&quot; Aunt</p>
            <pb n="96" facs="0012_001496_000200_0096.jpg" xml:id="d3e1839"/>
            <p>Cilla says, when I am alone &quot;De child have all de fun to herself.&quot; I am a perfect
little egotist, am. I not my journal? you must excuse it though it is so plasant to be made of some
importance, even though it be by one&apos;s self, and then too you know, I am nearly always alone so
what or who can I write about? I sit alone, in the parlor, and mamma sits in her room. Mamma is not
a talker and so we never have much to say. Been reading life of Scott today.</p>
            <p>E.W. 1863.</p>
            <p>Thursday Morning 12./63.</p>
            <p>Raining! &quot;Tho bright day is dead&quot; it lies cold, in the arms of Winter. I see the
bluebirds this morning hopping about in the rain. They were catching the robins again last night
Buck Harris took a wagon! I declare. I think it is shameful. There are numbers of them flying over
the house every morning going up the creek they return the cedars at Cunninghams in the evening.</p>
            <pb n="97" facs="0012_001496_000200_0097.jpg" xml:id="d3e1852"/>
            <p>Friday. Feb 13. 1863.</p>
            <p>Went out walking this evening. it was so pleasant The atmosphere as balmy as spring I went down
to cross the little poor plank to go up to the Mill found the creek so much swolen by last nights
rain that it was running over the plank quite deep so me, that is several of the little darkies and
all the dogs and myself had to go down to the - &quot;log&quot; in reality a bridge. we went across
the hill and went down near by up to the milldam - over which the water is pouring in fine style
quite &quot;a la cascade&quot; it looked very pretty and makes quite a repectable roar!!! <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">still &quot;I one living the joiner am,</unclear>and no lion&quot; what
a pity it is that I never saw or heard a real bona fide cataract. but then I should not appreciate.
my milldam.</p>
            <p>The water seems to shiver all along the top before taking such a leap. It comes down perfectly
transparent in a broad sheet except on the left bank where it stikes the shelving rocks and makes
some what I consider very pretty foam and spray rising up in quite a cloud.</p>
            <pb n="98" facs="0012_001496_000200_0098.jpg" xml:id="d3e1867"/>
            <p>as it foams down over the bank of rock into the stream. Bob shot an owl, a great big fellow, out
in the yard, to-night, he shot him in the eye, a right good shot for out in the dark. Mr. Hatcher
here of Woodwards used to belong to Captain Billingsly&apos;s company been sick. Yanks reported at
&quot;Harpeth Hall&quot; I hope they will not injure Mr. Robertson. Am almost through my first vol.
of Scott, like it so much.</p>
            <p>St. Valentines</p>
            <p>Such a dreary, dreary, day not a ray of sunshine and now (after supper) I hear the rain pattering
up on the window near which I am sitting I have been reading all day. read of the battle of
Waterloo. alas! how nearly many of its dreadful details resemble those pertaining to our own times
and country. Wayne went to Charlotte today a letter from Mr. Daniel Hellenam to mamma also one to
Wayne also a Southern Newspaper the first one I have seen I believe since this time last year. an
Atalanta, Ga Intelligence. I have not read it yet as</p>
            <pb n="99" facs="0012_001496_000200_0099.jpg" xml:id="d3e1879"/>
            <p>mamma has not finished it yet. I do not know how either it or the letters came. The rain is
coming down in torrents There is I believe some good news. tis only ten days old. Seeing a daily
paper makes me think of town and town life Oh! how I do wish the Confederates would take Nashville
The idea of a people like Tennesseeans being bound down under tyrants! we never get any but the
gloomiest side of our cause because what little news we do get, is always Yank, by the way the
Yankees are out at our landing <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">Soo</unclear> reported that
they are coming in tonight the weather, I hope they will think too inclement I do, if they
don&apos;t, would I am afraid sadly injure their health. How angry one feels to see them so
splendidly protected against the weather while they justly call our brave boys
&quot;ragamuffins&quot; How I do wish I was in Nashville with Florence and the yanks were out of
it.</p>
            <pb n="100" facs="0012_001496_000200_0100.jpg" xml:id="d3e1890"/>
            <p>I&apos;ve a sort of despondent fit this evening it seems as though our cause is advancing but slowly.
God grant the war may soon be over. I am but a small consideration but being so much alone is making
me <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">crabbed</unclear> and selfish in a high degree I wish I
could either look into the future or be perfectly contented with the present I am a sinful, selfish
creature. Bon soir. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">bonlor n ne!</unclear>
            </p>
            <p>Monday Feb. 16, 1863.</p>
            <p>A cloudy rainy day. rather warm. I have been reading &quot;Lockharts life of Scott.&quot; all day
long - I like it very much it is an old work of Cousin Chambers, by the name, but I got it from one
of the negroes, who though she does not know a letter, still keeps her house decorated with a few
worn and much inked vols. Scott I think must have been a truly good man a thing so rare connected
with great <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">Germins</unclear> sad though it be that I should
have to state it I could scribble for an hour or two but my</p>
            <pb n="101" facs="0012_001496_000200_0101.jpg" xml:id="d3e1910"/>
            <p>ink is at the lowest ebb and it being late at night I cannot now replenish my stand. I always
feel so many higher and holier impulses when in engaged in reading something improving than when
left for a long time to the bent of my own inclination.</p>
            <p>It seem doubly strange to me that men engaged in high pure literature should have in many cases
been even profligate.</p>
            <p>God look down with mercy on the perversity of human-nature that those who are gifted with the
greatest power of discernment of the pure am impure, and being gifted with an ideality, which one
would suppose would lead them on to a different path, should so often choose the baser! Reading
books of &quot;life and times&quot; always makes me so long for that to me unknown world society not
the mere acquantanceship of gentlemen I know that style, in many of my soldier friends but
intelligent society were man and women</p>
            <pb n="102" facs="0012_001496_000200_0102.jpg" xml:id="d3e1921"/>
            <p>of intellect give the tone to the social meetings of our day. I know exactly how people talked,
wrote, and acted a hundred years or so ago but have not the faintest idea of my own day. Almost
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">ageeing</unclear>with some of those sages of old who only
believed what they say, I have almost concluded that there is no &quot;society&quot; now better than
the parlors full of young men, which one, or at most two, girls are in the habit of entertaining
with a little frippery nonsense, and some bad music, in the evenings in town. Prince who I
registered as badly frostbitten some time ago is now nearly well he has a little son first child.
Peyton Au revoir, journal</p>
            <p>Tuesday Feb. 17. 1863.</p>
            <p>ReBS <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">I am</unclear> a gentleman? directly from the south
today Says he saw and talked with <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">T.W.B.</unclear> while
south, and That he is now Col. of the 50. Tenn The report of his being killed was totally unfounded
it has been very cloudy raining nearly all day - was the same yesterday</p>
            <pb n="103" facs="0012_001496_000200_0103.jpg" xml:id="d3e1942"/>
            <p>and though beautiful and clear Sunday Saturday was but a dark and dismal day. Saturday night a
little bird kept fluttering up against the window pane in vain efforts to enter (I suppose the
peculiarity of the ink is the cause of these blots) I was <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">anxious</unclear> to let the the poor frightened thing in. but mamma objected because it is
considered bad luck for a little bird to enter a room. I think superstition very absurd yet dear
mamma is quite so. She is at present very much on the &quot;qui vive&quot; on account of a very
unaccountable rattling of the windows in this house. The windows in this room are rattling at
intervals while I write, it is peculiar - for there is no apparent cause. and they rattle with a
regular beat. and that too at a time when there is no one stirring about the house. One of our
theories is, that, as it frequently occurs at rainy seasons, that it must be the jar of the ground
caused by falling water. It is inherently conjectural as to whether this can possibly be caused the
small quantity of water which falls over the mill dam. Mamma has an idea that it is streams in caves
- which run near the house. Cousin Chris asked me to write to him when he was here - he was not very
pressing but</p>
            <pb n="104" facs="0012_001496_000200_0104.jpg" xml:id="d3e1952"/>
            <p>as there is a possibility of sending a letter south in a day or two I believe I shall write There
can be no harm in doing so. Still at Scott and like Sir Walter quite as well as if not better (were
that possible) than Walter Scott minus Sir. I like Biographies, they introduce you not only their
subject but all the contemporasus, of note, and then you feel when you read of so much of their
private, and as it were mine life. That you really know something of the persons. I like biographies
better than autobiographies because in the former, one has all the effects of the autobiog. in the
correspondence <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">etc.</unclear>, and has some one else to give
the detail.</p>
            <p>Thursday, Feb 19. 1863.</p>
            <p>Those subjects of the Storm Ring The spirits of the winds, and the spirits of the clouds, have
been waging incessant war today. At one moment all was dark, at the next we had brightest golden
sunshine, and then almost <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">exr</unclear> the eye took in the
beauty of the brillant landscape a shower would come, sometimes</p>
            <pb n="105" facs="0012_001496_000200_0105.jpg" xml:id="d3e1970"/>
            <p>very bleak, and dreary and at other times most most raidient. Every raindrop looking a diamond in
consequence we had this evening the most beautiful rainbow that I ever saw it was exceedingly
brilliant in color and almost <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">triple.</unclear> It is night
and the winds whistle wildly round the house corners and through the cedar tops; and I sincerely
hope this is a last &quot;fau de joi&quot; on their part as I am heartily tired of rain, today being
the first time we have seen old Sol since Sunday</p>
            <p>The battle may still continue however, as I saw dark masses of Clouds moored round the sunset
though mid heaven was perfectly clear. Amid all this brilliant display of nature I have to write a
sad, sad tale or tale. of<unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">darne</unclear>rumor&apos;s only
thank god, but perhaps soon to be made a certainty It is report confidently that poor little Johnine
Kirkman was left mortally wounded on the field of Donelson And we have heard that it is rumored
vaguely That our poor old Uncle</p>
            <pb n="106" facs="0012_001496_000200_0106.jpg" xml:id="d3e1985"/>
            <p>Anthony Vanleer is no more God grant that this be not true for although very old, and feeble yet
being a very rich man (this place belongs to him) there are many dependent upon him. and then he is
too almost the last link which draws my mother back to her early recollections. Her father was his
brother, and for years he has been very kind to her almost a father Then too it is a sad thing for
an old man, whose life has been spent in peace to go out in such a scene as this, in The midst of so
terrible a tragedy, as this to leave all those he loves in such a dreadful war. I hope it is not
true.</p>
            <p>Van Dorn is at Columbia with 17 thousand additional troops and it&apos;s reported that he has
superseded Wheeler. Good night.</p>
            <p>Monday Feb. 23. 1863</p>
            <p>Mr. Hughes has returned from below. He went down to see if he could hear anything of Johnnie
Kirkman He was killed at Donelson Frank Mc Nairy was killed also.</p>
            <pb n="107" facs="0012_001496_000200_0107.jpg" xml:id="d3e1999"/>
            <p>Col. McNairy was shot through the head the ball passing in just above one ear, and coming out on
the opposite side Johnnie was shot in the hip. It is said that he was very much intoxicated as they
passed the Mill and his Uncle, the Col tried very hard to make him stay there but in vain. Poor,
poor boy! Their bodies had been sent for and taken to Nashville the day before Mr. H. got to the
Mill. How sad They all must feel in Nashville. The report concerning Uncle is not now considered
true, as we can hear no confirmation of it whatever. Benny Robertson was here came just before
dinner Saturday and remained until Sunday morning</p>
            <p>Ben is a nice boy he seems to be a very good true hearted kind, considerate boy. he will make a
noble man I think as well in looks as in every thing else He will be much taller but looks a little
like Chris by the way I wrote a long letter to him the other day but did not nor do I intend to
finish it. so of course I will not sent it</p>
            <pb n="108" facs="0012_001496_000200_0108.jpg" xml:id="d3e2008"/>
            <p>It is very cold today quite clear. night</p>
            <p>Night</p>
            <p>Wayne has just bought for me 31/2 lbs of Maple Sugar. very good. I have been trying it. I have
been twisting thread and knitting all day. Benny says C.W.K. is still Major<unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">Hugg</unclear>Col. J.W.B. Lt Col. Have not been allowed to read any
today. Read a very foolish novel the other day &quot;Grey Rivers&quot; just glanced through an
exceeding silly book, Books should to one of these four ends <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">conduce</unclear> Wisdom, piety, delight. or use, and this book contained as little as possible of
either As I grow older I am becoming much more reflective I am often almost startled by the strange,
grave thoughts that come thronging unbidden to my brain Things appear to me now in a very different
light to what they did two years ago. Even the style of my brightest daydreams is altared now very
much and I think and hope they all is altared for the better. I know I take a much truer view of
life and things yet how blind I still am. Sometimes a thoughta conviction of some</p>
            <pb n="109" facs="0012_001496_000200_0109.jpg" xml:id="d3e2025"/>
            <p>thing will come to my brain and heart and it will be so true. yet so different from what I
thought true before if I thought at all.</p>
            <p>How they come I know Tis by no train of reasoning I reason after to ascertain its truth. Perhaps
My Heavenly Father sends me these for my protection and guidance.</p>
            <p>I expect all this would seem strange unmeaning language to others yet I understand so who cares?
Human nature is strangely selfish deepest, most intense selfishness allways lurks in one, and when
the poor mortal has triumphantly scourged this fiend from his heart in some form, he is not a little
astonished to find that Selfishness itself had prompted the scourging.</p>
            <p>To purify our motives is one of the hardest of our duties we are truthful it is that others may
not doubt us we are kind to gain the love of others we are good in every way that those we love may
smile upon us and love us in return</p>
            <pb n="110" facs="0012_001496_000200_0110.jpg" xml:id="d3e2038"/>
            <p>And yet there is very little love for us to gain I some times doubt if there be any perfectly
pure unselfish love. There is one great drawback to <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">wamans</unclear> happiness in the fact that she never can or rather does have any setteled plan of
life marked out in early youth, men learn professions and always at least look forward to the
practice of them. A woman is as it were adrift rudderless and floats about on the Ocean of
circumstances to be lodged by the current where ever it lists. God guide my poor frail bark, keep it
from the whirlpool and the rock of destruction let it rest in some haven of safety or keep it free
and glad on The calm high seas May its sails be ever spotless I wish I were with cousin Florence
tonight Poor Johnnie!</p>
            <p>Wednesday, I believe</p>
            <p>Feb 25</p>
            <p>Mr. Hughes has gone or rather Started to Nashville this morning wretched weather raining
incessantly since about ten o&apos; clock 10</p>
            <pb n="111" facs="0012_001496_000200_0111.jpg" xml:id="d3e2056"/>
            <p>this morning. Wrote a long letter to Florence Kirkman, also a short one to Pa enclosed in one
Mamma wrote to him. Have been reading Lockhart&apos;s Scott nearly all day finished a crochet
tidy<unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">d&apos;oiley</unclear>for the rocking chair in the parlor blue
and white, I am afraid it will fade quite pretty. I hope the Yanks will let Mr. H. out of town and
in I am so axnious to hear from there. What a very egotistical thing a journal is My illustrous
predecessor! Sir Walter Scott. thought as I do on this subject!!! as on many others</p>
            <p>Thursday. 26, 1863.</p>
            <p>Raining all day and scarce stopped all night last night It has ceased now but the creek is
booming high I do hope it will be bright again tomorrow. Picked up near dark a book of sentiment in
other words a novel glanced into it set me to thinking strange thoughts I intended that they should
be good thought but I fear they were strangely selfish in the end.</p>
            <pb n="112" facs="0012_001496_000200_0112.jpg" xml:id="d3e2070"/>
            <p>We are selfish creatures any way, but perhaps I am misjudging others by myself I hope I am but
selfishness says no you don&apos;t hope so you would much rather that you were at least equal to other
people in generosity. I am selfish not stingy not hoarding but selfish perhaps it is because I am so
much alone</p>
            <p>&quot;It is not good for man to be alone&quot; so says the Bible So many of my thoughts hopes,
wishes dreams center in Eleanora<unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">Wellaner</unclear>. God
chastin me gently! I do not know why but is writing &amp; in talking to others of myself I represent
myself as very lonely and as being made unhappy by that lonliness now when I come to analyze this I
find though I would be happier in congenial society yet where can one find congenial society? I am
not unhappy here and in some of my dreams scenes like these give me much happiness but a truce to
such sage, unintelligable nonsense no contradiction in those very happy descriptives</p>
            <p>
               <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">PSHAW</unclear>
            </p>
            <p>I&apos;m sleepy</p>
            <pb n="113" facs="0012_001496_000200_0113.jpg" xml:id="d3e2087"/>
            <p>Wednesday. March 11./63 Went down Sunday the first with Beckie who came for me to Louisa and
spent a week. Mrs. Finley, being here, went also. On getting there found the Watkins family and W.
Baxter also Miss Bettie Garland from Clarksville and her Uncle Hick Johnson who was staying there
being a captain in the 14 Tenn. Regiment wounded in the foot seven months ago and not yet
sufficiently recovered for infantry. While there Mr Hughes returned from Nashville bringing a letter
from cousin Florence. All well in town. He has gone to Ashwood for Cousin Rebecca&apos;s children perhaps
they will come by here. We returned from Lousia after he had left. Capt Johnson came with us We
implored him to stay all night as it was late but he would not as he had promised Mrs Watkins to
come back. He was taken prisoner that night. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">9</unclear> by
the Yankees. If he had staid here he would not have been taken. Mr Baxter and Mr Alex. Jackson were
also both</p>
            <pb n="114" facs="0012_001496_000200_0114.jpg" xml:id="d3e2098"/>
            <p>taken at Louisa. There were nine in all that we know of Mrs Finley&apos;s brother, Mr. Thom. Dixon was
taken. She has gone down to Louisa and Antonia and perhaps to Clarksville to see what can be done. I
am so so sorry. that the Yanks have taken them all.</p>
            <p>Capt Johnson is a handsome agreeable young man. reported to be engaged to Nannie Tyler. Young 23,
8 of next Nov. He was taken prisoner just exactly seven months from the day he was wounded he was
wounded on the 9 day of Aug 62. The ninth of Aug how many many changes have taken place since then
And I am changed so changed at not for the better. God guard me!</p>
            <p>Saturday March 28. 63</p>
            <p>Cousin Ellen went to Clarksville. with Mrs. Watkins Mr Dixon was let off. Capt J. and Mr Baxter
were sent to Nashville, also Headly and Mockaby. Headly made his escape. also the next night Mr
B.</p>
            <pb n="115" facs="0012_001496_000200_0115.jpg" xml:id="d3e2112"/>
            <p>and Mockaby Capt. Johnson made the attempt in female attire and was detected they say through
some &quot;silly contrivance of the girls. It is reported his sister Mrs. Hickman, and several young
ladies who were implicated were taken up by the Yankees and are now in confinement. Cousin Florence
visited them while in prison so I hear. We heard at one time that they had all escaped I was so
rejoiced but it made me very sad when I heard that poor Hick was caught how mortifying it must have
been to him! Last week cousin Ellen who is still with me composed two more verses for
&quot;Juanita&quot; at Mrs Watkins request I assisted her very slightly and when writing them off to
send to Mrs. Watkins composed a burlesque on the the last just for fun. I wonder of Aunt Madone does
not think it shows a lack of refinement. I will find out when I go to Louisa next.</p>
            <pb n="116" facs="0012_001496_000200_0116.jpg" xml:id="d3e2119"/>
            <p>I knit for Dora what I consider for the Material a very pretty pair of gloves. She wrote to thank
me thinks them very nice and says the are just the thing I was or rather Mamma and cousin Ellen were
afraid they were too small.</p>
            <p>I am now nineteen the day before yesterday was my birthday 25. Mamma made a cake for me we had
cake and wine There were several gentlemen here Mamma does not like for me to tell my age but I do
not think it makes any difference Time flies faster every year to my <unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">unnamill</unclear> memory it seems but the other day that I was just seven teen and yet it
is two long years. years of sin, sorrow carnage. May the end of my twentieth year, which I am just
now beginning, be amid a brighter prospect for the future of my country than that which closes
darkly o&apos;er my nineteenth. how darkly! Almost endless war carnage and suffering hangs like a dark
cloud over</p>
            <pb n="117" facs="0012_001496_000200_0117.jpg" xml:id="d3e2131"/>
            <p>the fair prospect which we fain would see and shuts out all the sunlight of peace and joy which
would so beautifully light up the landscap which hope paints for us all It is the bright soft spring
time, flowers are up and blooming - and a small boquet of violets daisy&apos;s and other little wild
flowrets decks my window sill young hearts bound up in hope fulnessat this bright season yet how
many are cut low oh so so low! by the fatal, whizzing, whirring, hateful bullet.</p>
            <p>We heard yesterday that the Feds. had left or been driven from Franklin towards Nashville Forrest
captured 800 of them. Heard from Van, well Woodward is under Cosby now. </p>
            <p>Mr H. returned from Columbia without the children on account of the bad weather. He went back for
them about a week ago has not yet returned. Yesterday was a fast day appointed by Jeff Davis. Cousin
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">F</unclear>and I kept it Wayne says &quot;Sis eat your dinner
I wont tell Jeff Davis on you! It is scarcely pleasant to keep a journal of events there is so
much</p>
            <pb n="118" facs="0012_001496_000200_0118.jpg" xml:id="d3e2145"/>
            <p>that I dare not put down. Went down to Antonia with cousin E. last Sunday came back same day 16
or 17 miles. Peach trees are in bloom hard rain last night. Have read this week a book which I like
exceedingly particularly the first part borrowed it from Mrs Finley &quot;Dream Life by FR.
MCarvel&quot;. (Mitchell). Am now reading what I have read before &quot;Fire worshipers&quot; in
Lalla<unclear reason="illegible" resp="IH">Book</unclear>
            </p>
            <p>March 29/ 1863</p>
            <p>It is Sunday calm still lonely Sunday Cousin Ellen is sick and Mamma is asleep The fire has a
lonely crackling sound as of someone walking slowly and alone over a fall of snow. The sunshine
falls on the world with a faint watery beam and makes every thing look so lonely the wind sobs and
sighs for very solitude now and then raising its low plaintive moaning cry to one of shrill agony
and then almost dying away. It is Palm Sunday how I wish I was in town so that I could go to church.
Mamma says she believes Florence will be a Roman Catholic! before she dies</p>
            <pb n="119" facs="0012_001496_000200_0119.jpg" xml:id="d3e2159"/>
            <p>I trust her surmised be not true I think Florence has too much sense and sincere unbigoted
piety.</p>
            <p>I have on a new calico today that I made myself. I have nothing that suits my fancy to read but
Byron and can scarce think it the proper book for the Sabath.</p>
            <p>It is quite cold and I am afraid my little friends those pure first loves of the early sunbeams
the dainty little wild flowers, that come forth all too trustingly in to the arms of rude March,
will have but chilling time of it.</p>
            <p>April Thursday 16. 63.</p>
            <p>How many events have transpired since last I wrote herein! Col Woodward has been all through this
country camped here two or three days captured two transports had beside his own command Whites
Battallion of Texan Rangers, and a section of Ring&apos;s Battery under first Capt King, but after
under Lt. Johnston a handsome young man very agreeable seems charmed with cousin Ellen.</p>
            <pb n="120" facs="0012_001496_000200_0120.jpg" xml:id="d3e2175"/>
            <p>Col. Woodward was here often - he and I are great friends - I gave him an Easter egg I also gave
one to Charlie Medley and one to Capt. Elliott. - Speaking of Capt E - I can <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SC">scarcely</unclear> think it possible that one who is an apparent gentle
man in the truest sense of the word- could have <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SC">acted</unclear> he is represented to have done with regard to the Garlands. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SC">Lieut McGuins</unclear> and he were here frequently - I like the Lt. so
much. he is such a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SC">sincere</unclear> friend. (They have all
gone now. (They left a member of <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SC">Co H</unclear>. sick with
Typhoid fever - Mr. James Peacher with whom I was slightly acquainted. He was very ill and we sent
for his <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SC">sister</unclear> Ms <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SC">Risgee</unclear> She came last Monday. Beckie, Dora, Mrs. McRiernan were here Mrs. Jackson
came but returned home Monday night we were playing cards and we heard Cavelry - we were expecting
Yanks The boys left out the back door when I heard a sabre clanking on the steps and who should</p>
            <pb n="121" facs="0012_001496_000200_0121.jpg" xml:id="d3e2204"/>
            <p>slip in but Col Woodward also Lt. Buckner. Henry Clardy was here that evening. They only had
about 20 men with them. They think I am exceedingly <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SJ">sorry</unclear> to write, that <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SJ">TGW</unclear> was slightly
intoxicated. I sang a toast to the commander the Col and many members which had been composed in
part by cousin Ellen and the rest by myself.</p>
            <p>The next morning Jim <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SJ">Mil</unclear> Peacher was taken much
worse poor boy and although he had received the strictest attention he died at about <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SJ">O</unclear> three o&apos;clock in the afternoon.</p>
            <p>I felt so very sorry for poor Mrs. Kagee alone among strangers with a dead brother but we did the
best we could.</p>
            <p> We burried this poor young soldier he was younger than I <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">am</unclear> only 18 eighteen in our quiet little grave yard which has been opened before perhaps
but once in my lifetime</p>
            <p> How heavily hollow do the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">clods</unclear> the cruel first
clods fall into a grave their dull sound going deep deep down into the poor torn bleeding heart
crushing and</p>
            <pb n="122" facs="0012_001496_000200_0122.jpg" xml:id="d3e2238"/>
            <p>so relentlessly the faint uncertain hope that still remains. Then there seems to be something
almost soothing in the gentle fall of the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC"> soft</unclear>
after <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">next while</unclear> the grave as filling- filling- Is
is even-the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">worked</unclear> are piling up the earth, one
smoothes over the little mound with an cruel spade. Poor Jimme, poor boy, poor young soldiers - gone
forever. We dressed him in his soldier clothes cap and all. He never spoke a word. Poor dear
Mrs.<unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">buried</unclear> left this morning with Beckie, Dora, and
Mrs. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC"> McRorerman</unclear> and Mrs. Finley. He was injured
late yesterday evening. Wayne and I rode part of the way with them this morning . God support me if
ever death should <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">bereve</unclear>me of any one near and
dear-I think I should die. Several of the cabins burned down last week!</p>
            <p>Mr. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">Broirdu</unclear> was here bring southern news. Fight
at Franklin-Freeman&apos;s Battering Cape <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">captured</unclear>
and recaptured. Poor Cap. Freeman killed. </p>
            <pb n="123" facs="0012_001496_000200_0123.jpg" xml:id="d3e2272"/>
            <p>The dastard foe are reported to have killed this -true gentleman and brave, and gallant, and <gap reason="indecipherable" resp="NH"/> - soldier after he was captured</p>
            <p> Ther are many things that I can not write.</p>
            <p> Dora? I do not like Mrs. Finley she is deceitful and if there is any one mean quality that I
detest more than another it is deceit.</p>
            <p> Food sent me Berry Blue Hog this evening.</p>
            <p> Tuesday 21 April 1863. Oh I feel as unhappy-Last night about 10 O&apos;clock Van, Col James
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">Brener</unclear> and Wallace Dixon, and I were playing cards
in the parlor when I heard some one in the hall and supposing it to be Bob or Wayne stumbling around
in the dark. I got up and opened the door- there stood two Federals. They said &quot;We want to see
if there are any gentlemen in here&quot;- I said &quot;Oh you must not come in&quot;- but of course
I could not prevent them- They then asked if Mr. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">Van
Rick</unclear> was there. I knew who they meant but as they did not </p>
            <pb n="124" facs="0012_001496_000200_0124.jpg" xml:id="d3e2296"/>
            <p>have his name I said there are no such gentleman here then they asked Col. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">Brerrer</unclear> his name and place of residence he sais his name was
Thomson and that he lived here. Then as a number of them had gotten in and Kagel was among the
members-<unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">Van</unclear> knowing that they would hear him- I said
I am Van Kirkman if he be the one you want, here are my arms and gave up his pistol</p>
            <p>Poor little boy he was as white as a sheet but was very cool.</p>
            <p>They then went to playing cards with the second in command all <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">nirler</unclear>. They had taken, Bob and Wayne down at the office. I sat on <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">Brerrer&apos;s</unclear> pistol, an excellent <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">gravy</unclear>. But the prisoners not being allowed to leave the room.
I had to go out to get them several things and the yankies saw it. They knew Brerrer the Ltint in
Command - Liut <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">Renn</unclear> knew him. They stayed all night
carrying them off - this morning - Col <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">Brewer</unclear>-Wallace <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">Dixon</unclear>
            </p>
            <pb n="125" facs="0012_001496_000200_0125.jpg" xml:id="d3e2331"/>
            <p> Van and Bob Stone- Mr. Hughes went with them to see if anything could be done. After they got up
on the hill Brewer jumped from his horse, and ran about 50 yards when- when the guard shot
him-though the man who came back for his clothes said it was a very slight wound. I hope it is.
Brerrer then confessed that he was a Colonel. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">McNister</unclear>said he was heartily tired of the army that all his relations except his
grandfather were Southern in sentiment and that his time was out in a short space-he was going
home.</p>
            <p> Every one insisted and I at last yielded to play for them-I am so sorry-but I thought perhaps I
could do some good.. I only played one or two southern songs, but I am exceedingly sorry that I
played at all- but I was excited and had no one to advise other wise I will with God&apos;s help
behave in future more as becomes a high bred Southern lady.</p>
            <p> God only knows the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">isenc</unclear> of events that are now
transpiring.</p>
            <pb n="126" facs="0012_001496_000200_0126.jpg" xml:id="d3e2348"/>
            <p>The day is gently dying in the glorious golden west</p>
            <p>The <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">winds</unclear> have ceased their sighing And the birds
have gone to rest. </p>
            <p> The gentle little <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">snow</unclear> drops Have closed their
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">narry</unclear> eyes</p>
            <p> The sun has huged the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">drak</unclear> clouds With his
yellow crimson dyes</p>
            <p>And there is a specimen of my <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">impromptu</unclear> poetry
this 22 day of April Ad. 1863. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">I am</unclear> exceedingly heartless to be writing in this way
when me have heard me yet morning of the fate of out poor prisoners. Nothing to write except that
Mrs. Hughes the elder and Mattie came over and spent the day. I planted some flower seed late this
evening. The <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">twilight</unclear> is dying now so fast that I am
not out there pale lines so Adieu</p>
            <p>25 of April Saturday night R.B.<unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">Land or Sand</unclear> and
J.K. returned from Clarksville -took the Oath_Oh I am so sorry! Brerrer? not seriously woounded- he
begged Bruce to let him take the Oath!-false <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">N.
Dixon</unclear>took the oath also he and the Old Col. left this morning for</p>
            <pb n="127" facs="0012_001496_000200_0127.jpg" xml:id="d3e2395"/>
            <p>West Tennessee I expect Beckie and Mrs. Finley up tomorrow. Van and Bob say my lady friends in
Clarksville are down mean two for forgiving the Yankies.</p>
            <p>Lt <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">Penn</unclear> the Yank bred Col. B- or Van says that
there was a very strong &quot;crush&quot; <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">lady out</unclear> him and Col
B asked why he did not bring her in-one asked &quot;is she good looking&quot; -only tolerable&quot;</p>
            <p>-Oh- I feel so bad!!!! -ha! ha I wonder what my soldier friends will think of the way in which I
asked- I think I acted badly enough-May I use my person to more advantage in future. The boys have
come up to play<unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">enchie</unclear>.</p>
            <pb n="128" facs="0012_001496_000200_0128.jpg" xml:id="d3e2415"/>
            <p>Cumberland Furnace</p>
            <p>Friday Nov. 20. 1863</p>
            <p> Has a long long time since I have written in my journal. 7 Seven months! and an oh <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">anthings</unclear> of the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">sythes</unclear> of time since then!-And yet this cruel war is raging still- <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">Urcably</unclear> too with no prospects of abatement And the Reaper
Death has gathered many in to his <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">gamer</unclear> Arnold
Anthony Vanlees is dead and Florence and I are doubly orphaned now. Van is in England in London at
school. Florence is in New York. I have been to New York since last I wrote</p>
            <p>Florence and I went on in August with Ms. Dam Hallman- Mr. George Hallman <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">Humie</unclear> and Mattie-were found at Louisville by Selina McAarry
and Nannie The princaple <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">object</unclear> of the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">liyo</unclear> being accompany Grandpa ships far on their way to
Europe. He spent some time in New York</p>
            <pb n="129" facs="0012_001496_000200_0129.jpg" xml:id="d3e2450"/>
            <p> and went down to the seashore Long Branch F.L. I bathed in the surf of old ocean. Oh the Majesty
of the Sea-I have seen of all glourious on the suns first beams and I have seen the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">invisible</unclear> wind ring lash the billows high and white. And
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">thin</unclear> it has been all dark with but one single star
to light its blackness. I made some very pleasant acquantances in New York-Among them a gentleman
who may prove a life long friend- he has written to me - Mr. Moore. Pa went with Van to <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">Europe</unclear> but has now returned and is here.</p>
            <p> I see that I have <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">commuened</unclear>it an Friday which is
Mamma&apos;s unlucky day- I hope it may not be an. Florence took me north. She and Salene are still
in N.Y. at Mrs. Cargills and they are having a splendid time</p>
            <p> Salene&apos;s health is very poor. Two of my best and dearest friends fell at the great and
terrible battle of Checkawanga. -Col. T.W. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">Beaumont</unclear>
and Major Chris Robertson. It is getting so dark now that I can not tell how these two brave and
noble hearts beat their last in Our Cause.</p>
            <pb n="130" facs="0012_001496_000200_0130.jpg" xml:id="d3e2476"/>
            <p>Cumberland Furnace Dec 27. 1863. Christmas week and dark and lonely. It is <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">druggling</unclear> and dark today. The federals from Charlotte were
here yesterday in force it as reported that they are gone to reinforce ft. Donelson as they fear an
attack there. Major Crumrin the commandant in Charlotte says the Clarksville Yankees had not any
right to come out here and carry off our negroes. Whether they had the power or not the deed is done
it was a very mortifying thing to us to have a regiment of blacks here on the place and have them
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">parent torally</unclear> order white people about. Poor old
Robbie Steel was shot by the feds the other day-shot coming down his own stair -way. They shot Sam
Roberts a week or two ago for no offense. They were drunk- a better man then Sam Roberts has but
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">nalely livese</unclear>. He leaves a wife and two little
children.</p>
            <p>Some Yankees went to Bells the other night and forced them to give up all their turkeys calling
the ladies all kinds of bad names- <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">such as dammed Seesh
bitches </unclear> There have five cases of rape been committed up on the sall.</p>
            <pb n="131" facs="0012_001496_000200_0131.jpg" xml:id="d3e2498"/>
            <p>road the other side of Charlotte- by negro soldiers and they were all young and respectable
women. It is Sunday and dark and dreary-it rains every day since the twenty fifth hers seemed like
Sunday to me . I have a very bad cold. Mrs. Cook is quite sick. I have not recieved one Christmas
present. Florence has returned from New York as not most likely and of course Rebecca&apos;s has
promised to be here by the middle of January. I is so hoped that time will cause this ink to become
more visible than at present -for if it does not <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">positively</unclear> will be deprived the use of these most valuable chronicles <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">dimed</unclear> it is so very pale that I can not see what I write.
Billy Moore was in Louisville with Florence and Lena has not yet I suppose so has not recieved my
letter-grant came- am rather glad-like him very much but then is so much trouble to write and then
he is an Union man</p>
            <pb n="132" facs="0012_001496_000200_0132.jpg" xml:id="d3e2511"/>
            <p>Expect Beckie and Mrs. Brown who was Mary Vanoy-in Nashville some years ago. The Yankees robbed
her of every thing even her under clothes.</p>
            <p>They mit not be apt to come today as it rains</p>
            <p>Cumberland Tenn. Jan 8. 1864</p>
            <p> 1864 -A regiment of Federal Cavelry here ever since Sunday- 3rd Kentucky. the offices of some of
them occupy The parlor and eat at the table with us. THe Col. and LT. Col seem very gentlemanly- Col
Manny is very young indeed they say he is not Twenty one- he is tall and good looking. Lt. Col King
is one of the handsomest men I have ever seen, seems about thirty. Both Kentuckians- It makes me sad
to see such gallant young Kentuckians fighting in the Federal army some of them <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">cause</unclear> Mrs. Willauer is an arrogant <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">and arrant</unclear>
            </p>
            <pb n="133" facs="0012_001496_000200_0133.jpg" xml:id="d3e2531"/>
            <p>rebel, so Wayne says They are burning up all the rails in reach and eating up all the corn and
hay. It is bitter bitter cold and until today has snowed almost every day for a week. The sun shines
bright by today but it is not thawing mud. It is too cold to write.</p>
            <p> Sunday, May 1. 1864.</p>
            <p>
               <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">Howe</unclear> just returned from Harpeth Hall late
yesterday evening. Florence, Mary Nichole and I spent a very pleasant week there. Poor Mrs.
Robertson seem crushed by the loss of her husband and best beloved child Dear old lady-poor dear
Chris-they have a picture of him -rather good, hanging in the parlor just over the piano-it almost
broke my heart at first when I would chance to glance at it- the thought, - what a dreary thought,
would come that this was all all that was left on earth of him- so fitted to make this world
brighter and better - and how much need it has of such- alas that goodness and genius should have
been linked so tightly in the chain of life!</p>
            <pb n="134" facs="0012_001496_000200_0134.jpg" xml:id="d3e2545"/>
            <p>Furnace Aug 18.</p>
            <p>Have been to St. Louis since last I wrote went shortly after my return from Harpeth Hall.
Florence received a letter from Darrel Hillman asking us all to make a party and go. She and Marry
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">hiecho</unclear> were nearly wild to go- I did not want to go
and only went because the girls vowed they would not go without me So I was loath to go because I
knew I should be thrown with Federal&apos;s -I was astonished that <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">Fl.</unclear> was so anxcious- for at Harpeth she seemed perfectly crushed by the death of
- -she and they thinking heard she were mutually attached I thought so too until after we went to
St. Louis- though I, who am perhaps from long association most in her <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">character</unclear> and confidance knew- I say it gently honestly-kindly-and after
thinking-knew she did not love him as he was worthy of being loved. </p>
            <p> She met in St. Louis a young man she had met before, a Federal officer-He addressed her- was a
capt. came disguised as a citizen to see her here, after we returned stayed over a week- is very
intelligent, handsome, and </p>
            <pb n="135" facs="0012_001496_000200_0135.jpg" xml:id="d3e2566"/>
            <p>so far as any woman of my capacity can judge good and <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">true</unclear> - a gentleman in every sense of the word- the only objection- being a Federal
Officer- I read many of their letters - he writes beautifully and seems to love with fevor -tenderly
instingly- I think she loves him with her whole power of loving- I think he perhaps loves most. All
of her family are so much opposed. He met several gentlemen we knew- and many men acquantancees male
and female were added to our lists- Met a Mr. Pettrman- who gave us flowers and books-mine
&quot;Raphael&quot;- has written to me since to know where he could find me that he could come to see me-wrote
I could not tell where I would be placed in so charming a situation sent me a magazine -Eclectic -
last week. Copy from my note book my trip-</p>
            <p>May 14- Steamer Imperial-</p>
            <p> Left home for St. Louis just after early dinner Saturday- my horse was stiff from a fall in
stable- fell down with me and I tumbled over his head, was hurt a little and consederably jarred-
jumped on again and arrived at Hands at Lancing- expecting find the boat there had to wait several
hours Mary N. F. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">Jo lanleer</unclear> and self.</p>
            <pb n="136" facs="0012_001496_000200_0136.jpg" xml:id="d3e2584"/>
            <p>Arrived at Clarksville about 10 O&apos;clock Jo got off and Wayne got on. Saw Mr. George H. for a
moment, went to sleep and woke very early at Empire <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">Iron</unclear> works in Kentucky- Mr. D. Hellrman. Mr. H came on and took us up to Empire to
breakfast. Saw Mrs. Barlow sick her mother in law, and sister in law Mrs. Baker-pretty. Stopped at
the Rolling Mill. </p>
            <p> Last night was intorduced to C. Helie from Clarksville got off at 6 -Mr. H son Timmy, daughter
Grace, and Servant also old Mrs. Baily got on. Dr. Newman along sorry <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">out</unclear>
            </p>
            <p> 15- Wrote to mamma this morning also Beckie Husbands- sleep in evening- <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">Paducah</unclear>- later went on deck- saw <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">Cairo</unclear> from Mound City- right down the river- <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">six</unclear> miles river scenery so beautiful Florence&apos;s iron on the bank at Mound
City As I sat there in deck after were just pass Mound C. the sun went down - the sky all glorious
and the water wide and bright with the lingering rays. As we came into the Mississippi at <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">Cairo</unclear>- the river looked like beautifully linked mother of
pearl-then great bars of darkness came and grew and crowded out the light. Sad, </p>
            <pb n="137" facs="0012_001496_000200_0137.jpg" xml:id="d3e2612"/>
            <p>sweet thoughts. </p>
            <p>Monday morning 16.</p>
            <p> Have just passed the &quot;grand tower&quot; a very high rock entirely surrounded by
waterperfectly bare sides but having trees on the top, known to have once been the residence of a
recluse. Opposite and making the river not more than half a mile more is another high rock or rather
two - not surrounded by water but with the grand old Mississippi washing the base of our. This
supposed that these rocks were once the summation of a great lake- the water having burst through
the mighty rocks and formed the Misssissippi. The country above is suddenly flat. It is wonderfully
picturesque. The river is so muddy -Evening -Went to sleep read some in my prayer book-some in
Harper- got up, dressed, and went into cabin about 4- four O&apos; clock Arrived in St. Louis next
morning - at ? arose about 7 got off as soon after as possible. Remained in St. L. one week. Have
been to Nashville with Florence to get her wedding things, stayed a week. Mrs. Cook, Mrs. Hughes,
and Fannie and self went up on North Western road. A yankee Liut. up at the station was quite
charmed with</p>
            <pb n="138" facs="0012_001496_000200_0138.jpg" xml:id="d3e2624"/>
            <p>the appearance of your humble servant Cousin Rebecca came while we were in town, guessed that F.
was engaged to a Yankee. Met two Yankee Captains while there one fell <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">much</unclear> in love with F. came near fainting when he heard she was engaged!-! Yanks
don&apos;t like me I treat them too coldly. Cousin invited us out to see her- we will go on a day or
two <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">I</unclear> expect. Will not return until after
Florence&apos;s wedding in September.</p>
            <p> We had two weeks of gaiety after we came from town. Madison Stewart - Emma Robb and Juliette
McDaaniel coming up for a week with Beckie</p>
            <p> We then spent several days with the party at Old Tennessee and Lansin. Beckie and Dora were in
N. just the week before we went up- went with Mary N. when she returned home. </p>
            <p> I am very sorry to write that I think Mary has proven herself to be weak in the extreme if not
wicked.</p>
            <p> Eddie Jems Jo. V. and George Conrad were of the Clarksville party George Conrad honored me with
a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">&quot;declaration&quot;</unclear> much to the surprise of everyone as
he said something to Florence</p>
            <pb n="139" facs="0012_001496_000200_0139.jpg" xml:id="d3e2648"/>
            <p>the very same evening which led her to think that he wanted an opportunity to address her. I
discarded him.</p>
            <p>Of course he is heartbroken <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">learn</unclear> never love
again and will still hope to sustain life. Sent me some pieces of music - very pretty - A fig for
any man who would address a woman that he had met but twice before and for one evening each time .
Tis always a high compliment though especially to a poor girl like myself . He has the reputation of
being a fortune hunter!!! I love like to write about him.</p>
            <p>Dora and Fannie Watkins are going to a Roman Catholic school in a few days. St. Catherines of
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">sienna</unclear> -Kentucky-. They have been having a sad time
at Harpeth Hall- Mr. Ward came home. The Federals heard of it went there and found him <unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">seculed</unclear> in the chimney. They took him and Benny then
afterwards took Gerty and Miss Margaret- taking them off<unclear reason="illegible" resp="KC">up</unclear> to the rail road- at night leaving poor Mrs. Robertson alone. Cousin Emmie was with
her husband. Mr Ward is I believe sick in Louisville the family are now at home. </p>
            <pb n="140" facs="0012_001496_000200_0140.jpg" xml:id="d3e2671"/>
            <p>It is reported that Johnnie is dead. God help his mother. Oh Christi cousin if you could know of
this I would break your heart were you alive. God grant the invader may not take <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Atalanta</unclear> to desecrate the graves of our dead. Oh! Florence
Florence! how can you marry a Yankee! Poor child. I fear such a match can not be happy- even though
he be good and true.</p>
            <p>D.H. and F have had a falling out - he wrote in consequence having resigned the trustee ship for
Van to come home- he (Van) arrived about a week since from England- brought us all presents- a
beautiful dressing case fitted up with silver to T.- a very nice convenient <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Fran welling</unclear> bag to myself- dressing cases to Wayne and Bob-
he has grown taller and broader- he is a tremendous boy for 15. fifteen.</p>
            <p>Aug 24, 1864. Not yet started for Maury. T. has been sick- will go tomorrow. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Thom Dirson</unclear> is burnt out. Yankees wife saved some few of her
things. All of Mrs. Tinley&apos;s things burned up- I feel sorry for her.</p>
            <p>Col. Woodward is dead! He was over in Ky raising a new regiment</p>
            <pb n="141" facs="0012_001496_000200_0141.jpg" xml:id="d3e2694"/>
            <p>or acting Brigadier in command of all southern books in there. They had a fight at Garrettsburg
and whipped the Yanks. The Col then took his men and encamped them just out of Hopkinsville- his old
home and then he and ten or twelve men started to visit their old home. The rest stopping to have
their horses <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">shod</unclear> the Col rode on into town with
only his &quot;pets&quot;- two boys- one a young <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">More</unclear>- they rode in little dreaming that there could be any but friends in Hopkinsville.
They were shot down like dogs, the Col was shot first in the back breaking his back bones in the
face, lungs, and arm- he fell from his horse- the horse was shot and fell upon the Col breaking his
leg in several places- he was left to lie there with the struggling horse upon him for half an
hour.</p>
            <p>Some of his old friends among them Jimmie Wheeler- then arrived and relocated him- he lived two
hours in agony.</p>
            <p>How such dastardly cruelty makes my blood boil. This I know to be the true account- the Yankee
papers do not state it so.</p>
            <pb n="142" facs="0012_001496_000200_0142.jpg" xml:id="d3e2711"/>
            <p>Van goes with us up to Maury- I do not see any improvement in him. Charles The Bold and <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Atilla</unclear> must have been boys like him. Good bye journal-
I&apos;ll have a heap to tell you when I see you again.</p>
            <p>Nov. 21. 1864, Sunday. How much more swiftly the time flies as the years come upon us. I can
remember when the weeks seemed as long as months are now. And it seems as if at each quick stride he
snatched a little of the beauty from life. I fear old age will be &quot;dark and unlovely&quot;
indeed. The path of happiness we cannot tread for there is none- the path of duty is so hard to
find- so hard to keep- so rugged and so dreary. If the angels could only talk to us and tell us what
God would have us do! The problem of life is so hard to solve- it is a nut I cannot crack- my brain
is all handle and no hammer. We went up to Nashville as we expected- but did not go out to Maury. I
do not think F wanted to go though she found a good reason for not going she thought. We spent the
time in Nashville previous to the wedding.</p>
            <pb n="143" facs="0012_001496_000200_0143.jpg" xml:id="d3e2724"/>
            <p>Cousin Rebecca and Antoinette came down previous to the wedding. Cousin was almost heart-broken
at the thought of Florence marrying a Yankee and too there were so many evil reports afloat in
Nashville about him which cousin believed. We could trace them to no reliable source and so
discredited them. She, cousin, was very kind to one as she always has been. I sympathize so deeply
with her- not exactly sympathize- either for I have no idea of the sorrow that she has known- but I
would so gladly lighten her burden if I could. And yet- there are burdens nearer home that I could
help to bear- and do not perhaps often make all the heavier. Florence was married on the (21) Twenty
first day of September- just two months ago today- The house was lit up for the first time since it
was built- 15 years ago. It looked like a pallace in the Arabian nights. Florence was dressed like a
princesss in a fairy tale. White silk and <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">costliest</unclear>-lace, and pearls and orange blossoms. They were married at eight in the evening
in a crowded church</p>
            <pb n="144" facs="0012_001496_000200_0144.jpg" xml:id="d3e2735"/>
            <p>at Christ&apos;s Church by Mr. Harlowe. The gas went out three times before we got to the church.
It all seems like a dream- coming back we found the great hall doors spread wide- and oh the
brilliant drawing rooms and parlors, the soft wonderful light of the gaily painted lamps!</p>
            <p>I wore a pretty white <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">drusse</unclear> and rolls and curls
with one scarlet geranium in my hair. I never looked so well- if it had only been for Confederates!
They left next morning at seven on the Louisville cars. How I hated to see her go. They went to New
York and to see his relations in Ohio. She was much pleased with them. They are now in St Louis,
having reached there just six weeks after their marriage. They are living in the house with Mrs.
Col. Haines. She sent me her picture the other day in all her bridal array.</p>
            <p>As I came home I spent a very pleasant week in Clarksville staying most of the time with Bettie
Garland.</p>
            <pb n="145" facs="0012_001496_000200_0145.jpg" xml:id="d3e2749"/>
            <p>I do love Mrs. Forbes and Bettie so much. Quite a large party came over with me spending several
weeks. During their stay there were two Guerillas shot here. One was shot from his horse near the
front gate. The other ran in to the cellar- remaining there from four in the evening until one at
night. When the Federal troops having come. They were attacked by the &quot;home guard&quot;- an
organization of Union men) he surrendered. He was the bravest man I have ever heard of. They shot
him about fifty paces from the house, near the stables. He faced death as I would a Summer breeze.
His name was Pallock- the other who died from his wound at about the same hour was a Smith. Both
were burried here and in the same grave. Col <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Brerrei</unclear>
was shot in Kentucky in retalliation for a man who someone else had wounded and is now well- Col
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Brerrei&apos;s</unclear> mother has gone crazy and spends her
time lying across his grave.</p>
            <pb n="146" facs="0012_001496_000200_0146.jpg" xml:id="d3e2762"/>
            <p>Charlie <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Larton</unclear> who is a Confederate soldier and
son of Dr. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Larton</unclear> of Clarksville was murdered by a
Union man near there not more than a month since. When his parents went to get his body, it was
stripped of its clothes- Federal having done it. Mr. James Kirkman was killed, little more than a
month since, in a skirmish near Athens Ala. He was a soldier in our cavalry- Confederate. Is it a
wonder that women and men are alike fierce and fearless, when the news current of the day is never
aught but a catalogue of blood.</p>
            <p>&quot;God pity us all&quot;</p>
            <p>I saw Mr P whom I met in St Louis- &quot;<unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">axed</unclear> one
for my heart and hand&quot; as the song saith- am heartless so could- or did not satisfy his
demands- he is rich. I wish sometimes that I could love someone. I sometimes wonder if there is such
a thing. I can not find it in the Bible. There are several persons that I would die for- and none
&quot;hath goodlier</p>
            <pb n="147" facs="0012_001496_000200_0147.jpg" xml:id="d3e2782"/>
            <p>love than this.&quot; This clinging to one must be a fond dream of mortals.</p>
            <p>Friday Dec. 2</p>
            <p>December! 1864- how little a while ago it seems since 1864 was a glad young year and now it is
December. Are gems the only things in the world that have not dark hearts and secret ugliness- the
purest brook has but earth for a bottom. The bluest sky is but thin cloud- the brightest stars are
perhaps wicked blind worlds like our own or they may be heaven- I think sometimes that the evening
star must be Heaven and that at the most hallowed season of the day the pure spirits of the blest
smile down upon the good whom they loved on earth. Last week- Thursday Van started for St Louis- Jo
went to town with him- I went as far a Louisa. We all went in one of the cinder <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">earls</unclear> with two mules hitched tandum! Mr Baxter went with them
from Louisa. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Staid</unclear> several days with Beckie and we
had a nice quiet time together. I miss Dora and <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Tan</unclear>.
Wrote to Dora Monday while at Louisa.</p>
            <p>Mr Charles Barker came out with Jo and</p>
            <pb n="148" facs="0012_001496_000200_0148.jpg" xml:id="d3e2805"/>
            <p>Bill. We all spent a day and night with Miss <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Dardie</unclear>. While we were at Louisa <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">50 or 70</unclear>
Confederates passed- one, so handsome, was at Lebanon with Cousin Chris. I do not know his name-
they were under Col Turner of <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">she SO.</unclear> Tenn. There
was a party of Confederate Cavelry under Col <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Rarba</unclear>
Ross passed here yesterday. Some of them escaped prisoners. Col Ross himself was one. I have heard
that The Robertsons are going to move away from Harpeth Hall- how dreary the Yankees have made that
once pleasant home! Mr. Ward came home some time ago. I have written three letters to Dora and have
as yet received no answers. Beckie got such a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">purty</unclear>
prison pin from &quot;Franklin&quot;</p>
            <p>December 5- Monday</p>
            <p>Yesterday and the day before two Brigades of Yankees passed on the retreat - The first negro and
white troops mixed under Thompson the Col. of a negro regiment who was on <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Rosecrans</unclear> staff. They were from Johnsonville- were cut off
from Nashville by the</p>
            <pb n="149" facs="0012_001496_000200_0149.jpg" xml:id="d3e2835"/>
            <p>Confederate forces that have invested that place!!! hurrah!!! The other was Coopers Brigade from
Duck River. They were also cut off from Nashville. They were all trying to get to Clarksville. How
fine it is to see the Yankees running- it is Ft. Donelson reversed.</p>
            <p>There were two Confederate Soldiers here to dinner today. Bill McCall and a Mr <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">S Border</unclear> both from Woodwards. Major Lewis has been killed. I
am so sorry. I was so glad to see Bill McCall, he looks well, speaks so hopefully, was so grieved
that Florence had married a Yankee- says he thinks they will confiscate her property- poor child-
how I wish you were Florence Kirkman still! They are <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">consampting</unclear> every one. I expect there is fighting going on now near/in Nashville- May
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">long</unclear> bless and prosper the Confederates and spare
them- have many on the wounded and grant us the victory. Mr McCall says our brave, brave boys have
suffered so, gone through so many hardships.</p>
            <pb n="150" facs="0012_001496_000200_0150.jpg" xml:id="d3e2853"/>
            <p>How can a Southern girl marry a Yankee! God bless the south and keep me always a pure, true,
steadfast Southerner at heart and in action.</p>
            <p>Wednesday Dec 7. 64</p>
            <p>So far as we can learn, still fighting at Nashville. There is a rumor that Hood has been
captured- it is however totally unfounded and untrue I believe. Wayne Jo and Davidson are away,
having gone after mules and cattle that the Yankees took. I am anxious that they should come back as
I know Mamma will soon be uneasy it being a few days since they started. Perhaps they will have some
news that will be reliable. Bill McCall says the war will be over in a year. I am reading
Macanlay&apos;s essays- I fear I will not remember much of them though for the events of the times
press so much more heavily on the memory than aught else that they almost efface the recollection of
things about which we have only heard. How natural egotism is and tis better than speaking ill of
others.</p>
            <pb n="151" facs="0012_001496_000200_0151.jpg" xml:id="d3e2865"/>
            <p>If you have nothing good to say, keep silent. There is no danger of this making you prosy my
dear. Miss <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Nonie</unclear>- you are too after-brained for that
depend upon it. Beckie went home Sunday before the last Brigade of Yanks came and I am so lonely
ever since. I wonder what fine small talkers- good conversationalists and entertaining people do
find to talk about. I should like so much to be one- the only subjects my brain furnishes me with
are first nonsense- which is bad- myself- worse- and other folks which in most instances is worstest
as the children lay. How I wish I could render some aid to those who are suffering near Nashville
and perhaps in it! Our brave Confederate soldiers. It is very warm and windy and raining in showers-
heavy black broken clouds scudding before the wind. The warm atmosphere will keep the wounded from
suffering so intensely while lying <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">imaaeed</unclear> for. If
there could only be women there to lighten their suffering! Will our revolution make us better or
debase us as a people?</p>
            <pb n="152" facs="0012_001496_000200_0152.jpg" xml:id="d3e2878"/>
            <p>Monday night- Dec. 12.</p>
            <p>Mamma met with a serious accident Saturday morning- she was in the smokehouse giving out some
meat, when a whole quarter of beef broke the hook on which it hung and fell upon her crushing her to
the ground.</p>
            <p>Everyone was so excited. I shall not soon forget how I felt when we were called hastily to find
her lying bleeding on the bed- her forehead much bruised, the back of her head bleeding, and her
poor left hand smashed, cut, bloody, useless, We were all frightened, but did what we could to
relieve her pain- she was afraid that she was more seriously hurt than could be seen and was
exceedingly nervous. I laid down on the bed by her and cried hard, after it was all quiet and she
was resting peacefully with her hand and head bound up. Mamma- how I love you, better than anything
else in all this world. &quot;No love like mother love ever has shone&quot; It is so cold- such
bitter cold- snow on the ground for the last three days. The cold is awful when one thinks of the
suffering it may cause to our</p>
            <pb n="153" facs="0012_001496_000200_0153.jpg" xml:id="d3e2890"/>
            <p>brave dear boys around Nashville. There were six Confederates here last night and to breakfast
this morning. I was so glad for them to be in out of the cold. They were Lieut. Pincard, John Barker
a cousin to Charlie, Allingsworth, <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Catlett</unclear>, Willis
Border. Pinkard was in the Manny Greys in the First- he is fine looking and seems intelligent- he is
blind in one eye Jo says- though it does not look so and is a little bald- but he looks young. I
expressed my good opinions of him- and they all tease me about falling in love with one blind and
bald!- as for that- it would only make me like him the more did I like him at all, but this is
insufferable nonsense. I love every good Confederate soldier- I sang for them. Pincard says he is
coming back. I am quite busy now having to keep house, wait on Mamma, and combat my natural and
habitual laziness. I write this egotistical affairs to know myself- it is best to ignore self, and
live nobly for those you love. But I am too selfish. I can not forget self- so my next best plan is
to study self and try when I know self</p>
            <pb n="154" facs="0012_001496_000200_0154.jpg" xml:id="d3e2900"/>
            <p>to govern self. It is a task. I am cold. Good night.</p>
            <p>Tuesday night. I am sitting here, with most of the household gone to bed, waiting in my room
alone. I wonder if in after years <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">monght</unclear> will wander
back in memory&apos;s path to this quiet bedroom- to the pleasant hours spent in it alone writing
reading dreaming- growing older. How sad it is that we must so many of us grow old- age seems so
dreary. What a word dreary is- it almost makes the tears start to <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">waits</unclear> it. But my blue curtained, brown carpeted, white <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">cowelied</unclear> room was not the starting point to bring one to
sorrow and old-age- my pretty plaid shawl is enough to make one feel happy it is so bright. I love
bright colors. I am going to have &quot;my house&quot; all just as glowing as good taste will allow-
Ah! What a fairy palace I sometimes make this famous &quot;my house&quot; of the future! Will it be
a little log cabin or will it be O Florence and I had our fortunes told once. To has come true! so
far- I was to be married either this month or next! I have</p>
            <pb n="155" facs="0012_001496_000200_0155.jpg" xml:id="d3e2919"/>
            <p>forgotten which- no prospect- my fate is hard to read? I think it is wrong to try even foolishly,
and carelessly as girls do to open the sealed book of futurity. God himself has closed it and we
should not even toy with the clasp. Mamma is better- her hand is badly cut and her face, forehead
around the eyes, and nose are much bruised and discolored- she does not now however suffer much
pain. It has moderated very much and though it has been very cloudy, not a ray of sunshine today it
has thawed very much and the water now dripping from the eaves sounds like the plashing of rain. I
am so glad it is warmer- it is so much better for our soldiers. Lyon is reported to have captured
four boats and gone to the other side of the Cumberland. Hood is fortifying in front of Nashville-
he will take if it will not be too great a sacrafice of life. The army lay they <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">in lind wirgtering</unclear> in <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Penhecky</unclear>. God bless the soldiers and the South- how I wish I had never seen- never heard
of a Yankee</p>
            <pb n="156" facs="0012_001496_000200_0156.jpg" xml:id="d3e2932"/>
            <p>I wonder where all my soldier friends are tonight scattered over the Confederacy. I wonder if
they ever remember the little school girl or young lady that they knew who remembers them so kindly
and so often. I am keeping house. I wish &quot;Pickie&quot; was here with me. I want to see my
Pickie now. I so lonesome, Journal. Pickie is a bad girls, who will read you sometimes, though I
tell her not, but Pickie wont tell, Journal and I lock you up from other inquisitive folks.
Pickie&apos;s name is Rebecca Abernathy- she&apos;s a bad girl- she&apos;s done something that made
Miss Nonie cry- oh! but you needn&apos;t to prick up your ears journal- I can&apos;t tell you that
it&apos; Pickies you know- but she&apos;s done it and may be it will make her do something else when
Miss Nonie will laugh- won&apos;t she! and eat cake- won&apos;t she? &amp;candy <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">cuph</unclear>! <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">smack</unclear>!</p>
            <p>Dec 23. Friday night.</p>
            <p>It has been very very cold again with a fall of sleet and snow. But today the sun shone out for
the first time for days- and the snow thawed some. Though it is so cold that my ink is frozen</p>
            <pb n="157" facs="0012_001496_000200_0157.jpg" xml:id="d3e2950"/>
            <p>which they will so soon look longingly back. How far off death and eternity seem in childhood-
and yet how much nearer Heaven, and heavenly things. The Furnace blew out today- things seem so
quiet without the puff and noise of the machinery. Jo came back from Clarksville late last night.
Wayne went on to Nashville on some business I presume for Florence. I received letters from Dora and
Bettie. I was glad to hear from both- such sweet affectionate letters. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">R.M.C.</unclear> was here for dinner today. Florence forbids my receiving Confederates
when they come- if she means what she writes, I see no alternative but to leave the place. I have no
other place to go, what I shall do God alone knows. I wish I could be a nurse in a Confederate
hospital. How I love the South. My love strengthens every day, grows with my maturing mind.</p>
            <p>How quickly I seem to have grown from a light gay girl to a sad and earnest woman. It seems as if
I am making life so useless a thing and we each and all should strive to make it so &quot;real&quot;
and &quot;earnest.&quot; What a pity it seems that one life past our early youth- how happy it would
be did we but slip from childhood</p>
            <pb n="158" facs="0012_001496_000200_0158.jpg" xml:id="d3e2962"/>
            <p>into Heaven- but God knows best. The cocks are crowing out of their usual hours tonight. I am
very sleepy.</p>
            <p>Christmas night, 1864</p>
            <p>A damp dull day, not cold- the negroes seemed however to enjoy themselves- they were racing over
the house catching the &quot;white folks&apos; Christmas gift&quot; from a little after day- I found
it almost impossible to dress myself and finally locked the door in dispair, after having been
rather too affectionately hugged by Aunt <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Chaney</unclear> with
her <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">heart</unclear> opened I expect by a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">dram</unclear> or two.</p>
            <p>Some of the negroes came round singing in the small hours of the morning- it sounded romantic,
reminded me of the little minisingers(?) of Germany and a story I read in my childhood of a little
girl who had a red hot copper thrown into her hand, while singing Xmas carol under some wicked ones
window. Marys and Marthas Hughes and Nicks came over just as we got up from the table (breakfast)
and <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">houd</unclear> sometime. Miss Sallie Bell is going to be
married- so states Madame <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Rumm</unclear>.</p>
            <pb n="159" facs="0012_001496_000200_0159.jpg" xml:id="d3e2991"/>
            <p>Mr. B. is with Beckie and I hope she is happy in his company. Beckie is a noble girl. I wish
Wayne would come home. I am uneasy about Florence&apos;s letter. It is so unkind. In looking back
over my journal, by the impress of character left there. I feel sad to find that there is fear that
I am not improving, I am afraid I lack energy- which is the good genius of this world in most
cases</p>
            <p>How little like Christmas it has seemed to me. &quot;Im alone all alone&quot; I find it so hard
to do right in little things. I will try a clean white page, with higher help to keep it pure and
spotless- New Years It is Sunday and Christmas and I have not opened the bible today or the prayer
book</p>
            <p>Friday 28, Dec. 1864</p>
            <p>The hard and dreary year is growing old _ only one day more of life _ and the young new year that
is coming brings little hope of anything _ save pain and sorrow, hard or drearier. Are we to
languish through four more dreadful years of War? God and the angels pity us all.</p>
            <p>Wayne came home this morning</p>
            <pb n="160" facs="0012_001496_000200_0160.jpg" xml:id="d3e3007"/>
            <p>before day. Van came several days ago, brought George McDaniel out with him- <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Jorhette&apos;s&apos;s</unclear> brother _ a boy about 17. Left Florence in
Cincinnatti- says her husband has sent in his resignation. He saw Antoinette in Louisville. Cousin
has not come yet from Memphis. Wayne had some splendid photographs taken in Nashville. The first
good pictures he ever had. I read the letter to him- he is wounded and angry- I will have to answer
it, and I do not know what to say. How I wish I had some way in which to prove my love for Wayne.
Wayne and Mamma, before all the world! I am afraid I do not love Pa enough. Cookey is a little sick.
The boys had <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">eq away</unclear> tonight. Wayne is sick, has
just been taken with a spill of asthma, which he is subject. My dear, dear brother- I would
willingly bear half your sickness could I by that means rid you of it.</p>
            <pb n="161" facs="0012_001496_000200_0161.jpg" xml:id="d3e3020"/>
            <p>1865. January 4th</p>
            <p>The old year is dead- dead in misery and hopelessness. The young year has slipped in with sadder
prospects than any other that I have yet seen. War to which we can see no end. We have heard some
good news tonight. Hood or rather the Southern army is reported again at Columbia- how true this may
be we can not tell. How such news would have thrilled me a while ago- but we are deceived so often,
and our last advance was attended with such disasterous results that an sensibly one gets apathetic-
not feeling deep interest even in their own fate even! Mrs Finley is here- came the last day of the
year- she sleeps in here with me. I can not tell why but she seems to draw out all the worse points
in my character, and by antipathy too- she is gentle- and calls out all the rough and unkind in my
nature. I feel all the time that she is too gentle- and yet I do not see how a woman can be too much
so- but I have no faith in <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">hast</unclear>. She is a poor
widow. I will try to conquer</p>
            <pb n="162" facs="0012_001496_000200_0162.jpg" xml:id="d3e3033"/>
            <p>this ill nature. We spent today at the Bell&apos;s- quite a pleasant day. I met Miss Parish and
Miss Larkins. They hear from the Captain quite frequently. Mrs B. is quite anxious to go to Camp
Morton to see him.</p>
            <p>We rode mules today. Van brought me a dancing negro from St. Louis- left his trunk in KY and
brought the small dancer all the way in his hand- this was kind <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">son</unclear> Van exceedingly. He is going back to England to school soon. I am so glad, I
hope he will improve. I have not heard from Beckie for some time.</p>
            <p>Wednesday Jan 11 &apos;65</p>
            <p>With the spell of the enchanter hanging round me, thought and feeling wrapped alike in a most
blissful dream _ I lay down <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Idyls</unclear> of the King with
&quot;Enid&quot; only read- blessing the gifts God gave to man in the power to be catch the beauty
of life and bind it in an everlasting chain of words- to lighten heavy hearts and brighten weary
eyes all over the world. Wayne Van and Jo- also</p>
            <pb n="163" facs="0012_001496_000200_0163.jpg" xml:id="d3e3053"/>
            <p>George McDaniel and the Hughes have gone to Clarksville this morning. Wayne and Van to go on to
Cincinnatti and Van of the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">carries</unclear> and his expressed
intention on to England again. It has been a bright and beautiful day though cold- the first
sunshine we have had for so long. I got two nice notes from Beckie several days ago- dear Pickie she
seems very happy- may her dreams of bliss ne&apos;er know awaking.</p>
            <p>Mamma is quite sick one of her billions attacks. I have been with her sitting quiet nearly all
day - fancy seems to have had the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">ascendancy</unclear>. I have
been wearing gorgeous <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">sixpences</unclear> and building
wonderful pallaces in mystic dreamland</p>
            <p>I wrote the letter - also one to George- one to Cousin Annie and one to cousin Rebecca. I wrote
notes to Beckie and Bettie. Beckie says Bill heard that Bett was to start north very soon. I hope I
shall see her before she goes. Mrs Forbes will be so lonely. I am going in to meet Wayne when he
comes back. Mrs Finley is sitting near me reading. Some cowardly home guards fell upon Mr Davidson
and beat him the other day.</p>
            <pb n="164" facs="0012_001496_000200_0164.jpg" xml:id="d3e3073"/>
            <p>Thursday, Feb 2, 65</p>
            <p>I have been in Clarksville two weeks. Mrs. Cook went up to Nashville. Florence and the Captain
are keeping house there- have bought a new house on Spruce <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Street</unclear>, the old one to be rented out. Beckie and I went in with <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Cookey</unclear>- had a delightful time- learned to skate a little.
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Staid</unclear> most of the time with Bethe. Nannie was in
town. Stayed all ngiht with <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Emma</unclear> Robb- also with
Mollie Boyd- at Mrs CH Smiths and at Florence Johnson&apos;s. dined out several times- was invited
out to Dr <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Drane&apos;s</unclear> but could not go. Mrs B is
afraid, I have heard, that Charlie is in love with my own sweet self- she need not worry.</p>
            <p>Wayne was sick in Cin. He and Bob have gone up to Nashville. F wrote me a long kind letter with
almost blots out the harshness of that other. Cousin Rebecca and family have gone on North- speak of
going to Europe. Van has gone or rather started back to school- we heard from him in</p>
            <pb n="165" facs="0012_001496_000200_0165.jpg" xml:id="d3e3100"/>
            <p>New York. Mamma is sick or rather not well- her health has never been at all good since she was
hurt by the beef. I trust she may be better soon. I do love Mrs Forbes- she is so sincere and
lovable in every particular. Pickie and I came out together and I stayed all night at Louisa. Aunt
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Doin</unclear> was well and as dear as she always is, which is
no small praise. Florence asked me most kindly to come up and christen the new home. God grant it
may be a happy one to her. I do not much think I shall go.</p>
            <p>Mamma looks so badly that I shall not leave her for any time until she is better. Mrs Finley is
still here - she is using my desk tonight- this is one reason why I have written so miserably
tonight. Mamma heard from Willie the other day he was well... There has been a fortune-teller here
today at <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Hughes</unclear> she created quite an excitement. Had
my pictures taken in C. Ambrotype in Mamma&apos;s <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">pin</unclear> considered good have not yet seen the photographs- rats and mice. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">full face.</unclear>
            </p>
            <pb n="166" facs="0012_001496_000200_0166.jpg" xml:id="d3e3121"/>
            <p>Cumberland Furnace. Sunday</p>
            <p>March 12, 1865</p>
            <p>I have been reading all day: Macanlay&apos;s Essays last; the prayer-book first. There is yet
quite a space of the evening left. I finished &quot;Lord Clive&quot; and could not at first decide
between Tennyson and my journal. Tennyson is certainly the more important, but the present I will
not have hereafter and Tennyson I will most probably have always. I am very dubious about continuing
my journal. It seems almost time thrown away. Although it seems that it would be pleasant in after
years to bring back my youth by looking over it, yet write often as I may <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">and/or</unclear> however great a length I can not put down half my
thoughts and feelings and those that do get in are oftenest <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">leaw</unclear> worthy of preservation. A mere chronicle of events will not have much interest. Yet
I think I&apos;ll stick to events thereafter.</p>
            <p>Life is a mystery that I can not</p>
            <pb n="167" facs="0012_001496_000200_0167.jpg" xml:id="d3e3141"/>
            <p>solve or strictly speaking fathom</p>
            <p>Mamma has been quite sick almost ever since I returned from Clarksville- she is getting well now
however and is able to do some of the house keeping.</p>
            <p>There was a Concert and Tableaux given in Clarksville for the benefit of the Church. I was sent
for to act and sing but of course could not leave Mamma sick. Bettie was a good deal worried that I
could not come. Beckie seems to have deserted me she has scarcely been to see me this whole winter.
Cousin Rebecca has gone to Europe. Antoinette&apos;s health is very bad. I am so sorry to hear this.
Van is back in England some time ago if he made the voyage easily. Oh how I long to travel. Europe
has been my dream since I knew of its existence. The country around here is in a terrible condition.
The Home Guards, a band of lawless men most of them of the lowest <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">east</unclear> under Federal</p>
            <pb n="168" facs="0012_001496_000200_0168.jpg" xml:id="d3e3155"/>
            <p>protection commit many lawless deed and make this place their <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">chief rendevous</unclear>. They rarely do any thing very wrong when not drunk- but they
are almost always drunk. They twice <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">maltreated</unclear>
seriously a worthy and respectable old man who came here on business last week. They knocked a
gentleman on the head with a pistol today until he bled profusely- for no offense- except that he
stayed at home when the Southerners were in here. They wounded <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Brince</unclear> and took a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">mant</unclear> and broke a bureau
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">cookey</unclear> had given him all to <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">pieces</unclear>- and just because they were drunk and wanted to. They
also <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">today</unclear> took the stirrups off of Van&apos;s new
saddle. And these are the men against whom we have no power to protect ourselves.
&quot;Levelers&quot;-</p>
            <pb n="169" facs="0012_001496_000200_0169.jpg" xml:id="d3e3184"/>
            <p>&quot;<unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Perllers doron</unclear> of the Aristocracy&quot;
they style themselves. I sometimes think women should not have any sense. Which is a very foolish
thought. Charleston has fallen into the hands of the enemy since I wrote and many other conquests
they have made of <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">fairlitus</unclear> and broad plantations. I
wish we were all in Heaven or the South was sunk under the sea and we were all turned to mermaids
and mermen and the dead soldiers were alive again. I think of Captain Beaumont and cousin Chris so
often.</p>
            <p>Sunday, March 19 1865. We have been cut off from Clarksville for several weeks by the high water
but I went into town with Mary Hughes Friday and came out last night and we have letters and papers
innumerable. This morning I received a nice long letter from Florence, one from George and one from
Bettie, also a note from Bettie. Wayne had several communications from Mr Martin, Van&apos;s tutor
in England.</p>
            <pb n="170" facs="0012_001496_000200_0170.jpg" xml:id="d3e3200"/>
            <p>Van is there and seems safe and happy. Mr. Martin from his letters seems so polished. I would
like so much to go to England to mingle with refined and truly elegant people. War has battered out
the polish of our people and much too of the pure and true that underlay mere smooth exterior. The
world- society- seems so wide and bright from our war-clouded standpoint. Youth seems so fleeting:
sorrow so loathsome and dark. And yet who would wish to be gay in <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">forughaties</unclear> when dismantled battered bleading desolation is all that is left of
so much of our fair South</p>
            <p>So fair a land and so brave a people is a fearful sacrafice to Negro Liberty. There is a picture
of a negro regiment marching into Charleston in the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Haysen</unclear>.</p>
            <p>They are singing &quot;John Brown&quot; and look like _____________ (dont pollute your paper
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Monie</unclear>). It is certainly a strange philanthropy in
the white race to sacrafice so proudly and so gladly its own kind to the inferior race- black- and
by the curse of God.</p>
            <pb n="171" facs="0012_001496_000200_0171.jpg" xml:id="d3e3220"/>
            <p>And the negro after all is no better off than he was before, and in a short time will be much
worse off than now. The Abolition of Slavery was and is but the pretext of an illfounded hate. They
have issued a new order for ladies to take the oath tomorrow is the last day of grace. I believe
they intend sending us South if we do not comply. Bettie and Emma have determined not to take it. I
shall do nothing- we go to Nashville Tuesday to see Florence - I expect they will make one take it
there. I hope not it will be purest purgery- but I can not leave Mamma and to go South any way would
be but starvation to me.</p>
            <p>June 9. 1865</p>
            <p>Hope is dead and Liberty is on her grave! Oh God that such an hour should have ever come! It is a
sin to wish that oneself were dead and half</p>
            <pb n="172" facs="0012_001496_000200_0172.jpg" xml:id="d3e3232"/>
            <p>forgotten. All the brightness and glory seems gone from my life. God only knows how I have loved
my native land- the South. I am tossed on every wave and have no purpose of my own. A brother in the
Federal army and perhaps dead in a southern prison. The South overpowered, conquored, subjugated! I
seem to have little to make life desirable since the South is dead. Oh the tears that have bathed
the dead body of Southern Liberty! I was in Nashville. Florence seems so happy. I was further</p>
            <pb n="173" facs="0012_001496_000200_0173.jpg" xml:id="d3e3239"/>
            <p>polluted by Yankee association while there. Went to a party at Heklens just after Lee&apos;s
surrender and danced with my country&apos;s murderers over my country&apos;s grave. I am so easily
persuaded. Florence was so kind to me while I was in town. Mamma came up while I was there, only
stayed a week, when we both came home, I was away over a month. Mamma and I intend going North for
Ma&apos;s health in about a week. I do not want to go but it is duty- Wayne received a letter from
cousin Rebecca from Paris tonight. She wants me to come to her. I wish I could go. I can not leave
Ma so it is useless for me to dream of it even. Van came home from London a day or two ago.</p>
            <pb n="174" facs="0012_001496_000200_0174.jpg" xml:id="d3e3246"/>
            <p>December 1865 Sunday 3rd</p>
            <p>I have been away all summer- only returned about a week ago.</p>
            <p>We left here about the middle of June. Mamma fell in the river as we went over to Clarksville-
did not get hurt. Wayne Pa and Mr. Baxter pulled her out. I was quite sick after from fright. She
had to ride to Clarksville- 8 miles in her wet clothes. I went up town in the evening- took supper
with Bettie and Mrs Forbes. Was introduced to Polk Johnson <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Betsnnele</unclear> also to Capt. Clark. Went next morning in cars- several young men down to see
one off- although I was very early. Polk gave me a beautiful magnolia bud. Found Mr. and Mrs. Kisee
going to Cincinnati. Were detained by broken locomotive and missed connection at Boling green- went
on night train- car crowded- sat in seat with two <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">kute</unclear> brush children. Pleasant trip to Cincinnati- parted there with Mr and Mrs <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Kisee</unclear>- also Pa went on under care of a Mr. Tevis from
Kentucky- another also in party was Mrs. Jones. T.H. Cross&apos; teacher</p>
            <pb n="175" facs="0012_001496_000200_0175.jpg" xml:id="d3e3267"/>
            <p>Several ladies in party. Went first to Pottstown to Aunt Beckie <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Minzers</unclear>. Mamma was quite sick for some time after she reached there- spent three
delightful weeks after she got better- spent several weeks then at Uncle Allans in Downingtown- then
went to Uncle Isaac&apos;s spent some time there. We heard during the Summer of the death of my poor
brother Willie- he died last January in Salisbury prison- it was a hard stroke to Mamma. God help me
to devote myself to her- to make her life as bright as I can- it has been but dreary hitherto. We
spent a very pleasant summer. I made many new friends and acquaintances. And I know what dear, sweet
people my northern relations are. Our old Aunt my grand mothers sister- Ann Hunter died this Summer.
She left Mamma a little prosperity. We spent some time with cousin <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Tammie</unclear> while in Philadelphia. Wayne came on for us- was sick poor dear boy
almost all the time he was in Pa</p>
            <p>We spent a week with Florence</p>
            <pb n="176" facs="0012_001496_000200_0176.jpg" xml:id="d3e3282"/>
            <p>in Nashville- she is now a mother- her baby was born here this Summer- it is a little boy called
Hugh Kirkman- a pretty, sweet, little blue eyed fellow- like his mother. Florence and the Captain
wanted me to stay in Nashville as it will be very pleasant there, being opera and party season- but
Ma wanted me to come with her. Florence has written thrice for me to come up since we left but Mamma
did not wish me to go, besides, gay society is too expensive a thing for penniless girls like
myself. The negroes have most of them been sent away from here and the few that remain are going
soon. The Captain believes in white labor. We are going also.</p>
            <p>Cumberland Furnace.</p>
            <p>April 1866.</p>
            <p>They have negroes at the Furnace now and are going into operation as soon as possible.</p>
            <p>Wayne is there</p>
            <pb n="177" facs="0012_001496_000200_0177.jpg" xml:id="d3e3299"/>
            <p>Sunday Baxter and Robert came up to see me and tell me that the rest had come to the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Niennan</unclear> place- Ma and I had intended going down in the
carriage- Ma would not go after the boys came, so I took them home and spent the evening. Met Aunt
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Dorn&apos;s</unclear> sister Mrs. Vaughn also Mr. Vaughn and
their little boy- so pretty received invitations to Gen Cheathams Wedding today- next Thursday</p>
            <p>&quot;Gen. B. T. Cheatham&quot; &quot;Miss Anna B. Robertson&quot; &quot;Miss Florence Clark at
home&quot; It is reported that Gen Lee is to be there! Gen. Hood is certainly to wait on them- Oh
how I wish I could go! I have no dress and no money to fix one with- so expect to stay away. I shall
go to the Church- perhaps I shall see there the idol of the South- the soldier &quot;without fear,
and without reproach&quot; Robert E. Lee! How he has stamped himself upon our hearts. Note from
Florence with cards- she was not invited. I think they might have asked her. An invitation for a
sociable at Mrs. Gen. Donelsons- Federal- will <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">meet fourth
time</unclear> at Florence&apos;s.</p>
            <pb n="178" facs="0012_001496_000200_0178.jpg" xml:id="d3e3317"/>
            <p>Baby has a tooth! I am his Godmother- dear little Hugh. Cousin Annie kindly wrote out for me to
come in and stay with her- but I did not go. Ma rather wished me not. I expect I missed a pleasant
week and I am afraid she will be hurt but I could not go.</p>
            <p>Cousin Rebecca came home with <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Wee</unclear> from Europe in
January- is or was down on her plantation- she expected Wayne to take charge of her business- was
rather vexed I think that he did not, and will be more so than ever now that he has returned to the
Furnace. She came to see Florence and Florence would not see her. I do not know if it was right or
wrong. I should have gone down and kissed her had I been F- but she is best judge of her own
affairs.</p>
            <p>Antoinette is at school in <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Saretjer Land</unclear> Van also
Cousin Andrew did not come with her. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Wee</unclear>- or
&quot;Miss Rebecca&quot; is so pretty. I am catching cold. 11. P.M. fire out</p>
            <p>April 4. I have been in town for over two weeks during Captains <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">alscance</unclear> at the Furnace. Saw Gen C&apos;s wedding at the church- was very pretty
crowded.</p>
            <pb n="179" facs="0012_001496_000200_0179.jpg" xml:id="d3e3343"/>
            <p>Gen. Cheatham says &quot;Miss Eleanora Willauer is the finest looking girl&quot; he has seen in
Nashville! Things pleasant, and otherwise while I was in town feeling clashes sometimes when in
F&apos;s household. Think would be best, perhaps for all, not to stay there so much in future. Hugh
is such a sweet little fellow. My twenty-second birthday came and went while I was in town. There
are to be grand tableaux and concert given by the ladies in town to buy cork legs for disabled
Confederate soldiers- I was requested both to act and sing. I was forced to refuse both as I can not
be in town and it would be expensive. I know of no worthier cause and would do all possible gladly.
I love the poor fellows so dearly.</p>
            <p>Van came out with one of the cars- got left in the evening and had to stay all night- he went
down the Watkins- girls away- climed into the graveyard where his great grandfather is buried. He
lifted me in and out. He is seventeen</p>
            <pb n="180" facs="0012_001496_000200_0180.jpg" xml:id="d3e3352"/>
            <p>He was to have started for England this evening. I pray God to shield him, he is a kind hearted
boy. I sat the lamps lit on the parlor windows that he might see the light as he passed on the
train. Jane Nichol stayed with me twice while I was in town -- all night.</p>
            <p>We went to the theatre with two of the &quot;beaux&quot; Monday night.</p>
            <p>Met a Col. Nesbitt  Confederate from Georgia. Mr. Johnson came over to see me in his old red
coat this evening  think he likes me  hope he may continue to do so. Aunt Doris says Miss <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">Nieuman</unclear> likes me. Mamma is busy with her garden -- We have
three dogs and four puppies  two cows, two calves, five pigs and some chickens.</p>
            <p>Mrs. Robertson  cousin Chris&apos; mother is in Heaven with her loved ones  and cousin Eunice
is lying ill at Vicks-burg</p>
            <p>April. 5. Friday</p>
            <p>It has been very bright and warm until yesterday evening for several days  but tis quite
cold</p>
            <pb n="181" facs="0012_001496_000200_0181.jpg" xml:id="d3e3373"/>
            <p>now and is raining tonight. Cousin Morgia came over and spent the day  she is so pleas-ant and
pretty. She told us of a Confederate soldier who has lost a leg that is getting sub-scribers for The
Southern History of the War <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG"> &amp; c.</unclear> He came when
she had been here a little more than a hour. His name is Stewart and he is nice looking  lost his
limb at Shiloh. It was near dinnertime and I let him go away without asking him to dinner  I was so
provoked at myself for being so unkind and stupid. I subscribed for The &quot;Women of the
South.&quot; I read while staying with Florence I read Mrs. Kitty Trevilyan&apos; Diary also by same
author as a part of The Shnberg-Cotta Family  I like these so very very much. Cousin Rebecca was
in town when I came out  she says she has a present for me which Antoinette sent me. I am trying to
teach Bett and Cinth to spell</p>
            <p>Saturday 7. Rained</p>
            <p>all day today. I have been sewing.</p>
            <p>There are to be grand tableaux and concerts in town  by the ladies</p>
            <pb n="182" facs="0012_001496_000200_0182.jpg" xml:id="d3e3390"/>
            <p>for buying artificial limbs for disabled confederate soldiers.  I was asked to act  but
reluctently declined  because Ma wished me to  she needs me here  and it would have involved some
expenditure, and we are forced to be very economical now to get along.</p>
            <p>I have thought of getting a situation as teacher somewhere  but then I think it is better for me
to stay at home.</p>
            <p>I have no piano here  we all miss the music very much.</p>
            <p>April 15, 1866.</p>
            <p>It is Sunday and 15 minutes to one by my little watch which Wayne gave me almost three years ago.
Three years!  how swiftly they have sped. There is one thing which I can not settle in my mind  it
is  does the Bible warrant us in believing that God rules our lives in little things? We know that
the great end of our lives, the life hereafter is in <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">His
hand</unclear>  but the little things that are so much in this life but have no effect on our
future life  They fret and</p>
            <pb n="183" facs="0012_001496_000200_0183.jpg" xml:id="d3e3409"/>
            <p>worry us so  if we only knew that they were from God we could bear them so much better There are
so many sins that we can not help committing  we know that they are washed away for eternity in the
blood of our blessed Lord  but they bring thus consequences I fear on earth. Sometimes I feel that
&quot;He giveth his angels charge over thee, to keep thee in all thy ways&quot; meant me, that He
does always  but sometimes I doubt and it is so dreary thinking that all this little tossing about
on the wave of circumstance is to no end and for no good. I believe that over all the greater events
in the lives of Christians our Father watches and rules. God has given me a very bright and pretty
home here for which I trust I am sufficiently thankful </p>
            <p>I received a letter the other day, while Dora Robert and cousin Morgia were spending the day with
us. The letter was from my old friend <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">Hettie</unclear> Stokes
of Lebanon  asking me to be brides-maid at her wedding on the 16th of May  she is to marry a
brother of an old school-mate and friend  of both of us -</p>
            <pb n="184" facs="0012_001496_000200_0184.jpg" xml:id="d3e3421"/>
            <p>His name is Harry Sheets, from Indianapolis  he was in the Northern Army  on Gen Van Cleve
staff  I am to be thrown still more if I go into Yankee association  and my Southern <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">acquantanship seems warping</unclear> away from me  yet my heart is as
true as ever to my native land  to her dead sons, and poor defeated soldiers. I do not hate the
North  God keep me from hate of any-thing  but ones native land is like a mother. I fear for
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">Hettie&apos;s</unclear> future  I have seen Harry Sheets
drunk and she is such a lovely girl. She has been engaged to him for a long time. It is raining
today, a gentle warm rain that is bringing out the leaves and flowers wonderfully  how beautiful
the spring time is! Dora and Fan walked up to our gate yesterday even-ing and I ran down to meet
them  and walk with them part way home  they are such sweet girls! I was to have gone there today
 I wrote to Beck-ie yesterday I hope she will come up soon I want to see her so much  She is
staying with her sister now.</p>
            <pb n="185" facs="0012_001496_000200_0185.jpg" xml:id="d3e3434"/>
            <p>I dreamed of Chris Robertson last night - &apos;twas the winter of &apos;62 that I saw him last.
He is burried in Atlanta Georgia. His family have many of them fallen into the grave since then 
father, mother, brother  and perhaps a sister  she was not expected to live when last I heard from
her. Have I told you journal that I am twenty two  I did not get a birthday present  I was in
town.</p>
            <p>April 19. 1866</p>
            <p>I am sitting in the parlor in front of the open window which opens to the floor  it has been
raining gently all the morning but now at five o&apos;clock it is sunshine made brilliant by the
rain diamonds on every thing on which his rays fall  every blade of grass is a jewelled spear, and
the leaves flash out  fit for crown jewels. How beautiful every thing is  the tender green
foliage, the little frail flowers, and the beautiful sky. The little birds which always seem so
happy. I received a large and beautiful bouquet from Col Plosser and Dr. Jamison</p>
            <pb n="186" facs="0012_001496_000200_0186.jpg" xml:id="d3e3446"/>
            <p>Col Plosser was in the Federal Army and has bought the Anderson Place near here.</p>
            <p>Mr Johnson brought quite a pleas-ant gentleman to see me the other night  Mr Corley, he was in
our army. I should have to decline waiting on Hettie I expect, because it will be too expensive.</p>
            <p>I am afraid I am growing mer-cenary  money seems such a good thing to have in this world</p>
            <p>I should like to be up in Heaven where there will be no money.</p>
            <p>I think it is a bad thing for a poor girl to be reared among rich relations. There is a grand
picnic near here May day. I am invited but do not know that I shall go.</p>
            <p>Monday June 3 /4, 1866.</p>
            <p>I did go to Lebanon, had some trouble arranging to get there, finally went up in the carriage
with the Groom and waiters. Major Wells regretted that he was not expected so that he could drive me
up in his buggy  Had a most delightful time. Both his and her family are such lovely people</p>
            <pb n="187" facs="0012_001496_000200_0187.jpg" xml:id="d3e3466"/>
            <p>They insisted on my going with them to Indianapolis. I would have gone but for the old <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">bar</unclear> - expense. I am confidant I should have had a charming
time  There was to be several large parties given Hettie.</p>
            <p>There were several parties in Lebanon. I spent some time in Nashville after coming home  with
Wayne  who came up with Major Wills and the Captain  spent two days at home. Then returned to town
and met the bridal party on their way north.</p>
            <p>Who should arrive in Nashville but Mr Pittman, came to see me frequently and went with me to
church did not <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">renew</unclear> the old subject  but if I can
judge looks as if he would like to  I was as chilling as the Artic Sea. He is rich and makes money
constantly  they all who take an interest in me would like that I should fancy him  he is good, a
member of the church  is sensible and quite well read  is of good family  and suitable age  is
not ugly, Florence says  I never thought wheather he was or not  but he is not as large as I am,
and looks so little and weak that I could never love him, or lean on him, or <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">trust</unclear> him. It was foolish and wrong perhaps, I can not though
care for a little man  however great his soul may be.  I am very sorry. </p>
            <pb n="188" facs="0012_001496_000200_0188.jpg" xml:id="d3e3487"/>
            <p>I fear it is a sin to marry without love.</p>
            <p>There has been a grand Tournament in Clarksville to which every one went, for raising funds to
build a southern orpans home. Capt Elliott won the wreath and gave it to Molly Boyd. Lieuts Buckner
and McGuire rode and did excellantly. I should have liked to have been there. There was a ball in
the evening. Mollie was there with her wealth on  was very becoming I hear. Mary Nichol is to be
married the twenty seventh of this month  I am to be bridesmaid  She is to marry Major <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">Hunt</unclear> from Mississippi.</p>
            <p>Wednesday  5 or 6  June</p>
            <p>Who should come to see me yesterday but Mr Walter Drane- stayed until this morning He is such a
nice man  What a pity he is so deaf. Dora stayed all night last night</p>
            <p>There is some hope of my going to the cave this summer  I should so much like to go. Van is safe
in Europe</p>
            <p>June 9, 1866</p>
            <p>I am fast learning I fear that money is about the greatest earthly blessing</p>
            <pb n="189" facs="0012_001496_000200_0189.jpg" xml:id="d3e3512"/>
            <p>That sounds like a terrible thing to say  but so much sin and misery arise from the want of it
Love is beautiful still without it  but how much more beautiful with it. Poor cousin Archer has a
great loving heart I think, and Auntie says is devoted to, and so proud of his wife and little boy
but he has to work so hard and makes nothing. Capt <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">Droullard</unclear> can be proud of his wife and little boy and feel no fear of any want for them.
Their home is so beautiful  and they have every thing they wish.</p>
            <p>God pity us all and lead us out of this labarynth of sin. I have a pleas-ant house to live in 
pretty scenery to look at and the dearest, most devoted of mothers  and many kind dear friends 
have all the necessaries of life Yet I am often very unhappy  ingrate  I have no piano, and have
not time to read, can not for want of money gratify many little tastes and fancies that I have I
know it is sinful  selfish ungrateful  I battle against but can not conquer it  When thought</p>
            <pb n="190" facs="0012_001496_000200_0190.jpg" xml:id="d3e3524"/>
            <p>becomes intolerable  I just go to sleep and forget it  I can always go to sleep. But then I
wake up at the same old place in the battle. I sometimes think perhaps my mind is not so well
ballanced as other people&apos;s. I do not think every one is so troubled by such things I am afraid
my Heavenly Father will teach me to prize the blessings I have by taking them from me. &quot;He that
hath no rule over his own spirit is like a city that is broken down and without walls&quot;I am so
fond of society and am too poor to enjoy it.</p>
            <p>Father what e&apos;er of earthly bliss,</p>
            <p>Thy sovereign will denies,</p>
            <p>Accepted at thy throne of Grace,</p>
            <p>Let this petition rise, - </p>
            <p>- Give me a calm, a thankful heart,</p>
            <p>From every murmer free;</p>
            <p>The blessings of thy grace in part,</p>
            <p>And make me live to thee,</p>
            <p>Beckie has come up to Aunt <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">Doris&apos;</unclear> - I am so
glad  Dear dear Beckie</p>
            <pb n="191" facs="0012_001496_000200_0191.jpg" xml:id="d3e3553"/>
            <p>I believe laziness  absolute hate of work  drudgery  is my besetting sin  I work from a sense
of duty but &apos;tis non con amour (<unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">?/</unclear> certainly I
wish I was not so lazy. I believe all my trouble comes from that. </p>
            <p>Sunday</p>
            <p>I do not know what to write I am sure but I have a sort of lazy inclination that way  so open
journal and take pen It is raining a thunder shower sunlight shining through very beautiful after
six, sun low, beams, slant and golden. Going to look for rainbow. Saw it bright and double. Ah
beautiful ever young earth! It is very warm and the rain does not cool it a bit. Wanted to go to see
Beckie this evening  she is sick. I can see myself in the glass as I sit - look right pretty this
evening  always look best when there is no one to look at me. Wish some one I <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">wot</unclear> of was here to see me - always have looked my worst for
that person - would like as a mere matter of curiosity to be seen at my best  A golden sunset
darkening down and the little birds singing their last notes for the day  clouds in mid heaven
amber and crimson make a rosy twilight</p>
            <pb n="192" facs="0012_001496_000200_0192.jpg" xml:id="d3e3571"/>
            <p>Breaks of sky bright blue  dim clouds mingle with the fire and flames now  and make the heavens
more lovely.</p>
            <p>Mr Walter sent me a box of candy - <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">bet</unclear> with a
note which I must answer I think today that Christian contentment is the greatest earthly blessing 
God give it me  and keep me thinking so.</p>
            <p>Sunday June, 24, 1866</p>
            <p>I am sure I do not know why I continue to write here I am fully persuaded that it is all nonsense
except as a mere chronicle of events  and I never put most impor-tant ones down. Have been in town
for a week Emma Robb is visiting Florence  We were at several large parties. I am to be
bride&apos;s maid to Mary Nichol next Thurs-day night. I am not well today  was quite sick
yesterday. Cholera Morbus. feel weak and badly He that hath no rule over his own spirit is like a
city that is broken down and without wall  does spirit and heart mean the same? I am in a miserably
defenseless condition if it does. The breakers of the sea of life are dashing my bank rudely against
reefs of</p>
            <pb n="193" facs="0012_001496_000200_0193.jpg" xml:id="d3e3588"/>
            <p>doubt and unrest and although I know the safe course will be reached at last I can not help
shrinking from the apparent danger  I long so for the quiet haven  and perhaps when it is reached
will look wistfully back to the excitement of the storm Real storms are beautiful  I enjoy them so
much  how I wish I could live near the Sea. My head aches. I am very im-patient- &apos;tis a noble
thing to learn to wait  to endure Gods will  I had beautiful fan given me the other day. How very
bitter the Southern people are still  I wish they were not  I think it is a sin.</p>
            <p>How we <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">fret</unclear>against the gyves of mortality 
wishing for the happiness of heaven - of sinlessness here on earth.</p>
            <p> &quot;Break, break, break,</p>
            <p>On thy cold grey stones O sea,</p>
            <p>The tender grace of a day that is dead</p>
            <p>Will never come back to me. &quot;</p>
            <p>Dash! dash! dash!</p>
            <p>&apos;Gainst the shoal of nonsense O heart!</p>
            <p>and never be done with silly strife</p>
            <p>Till soul and body part.</p>
            <pb n="194" facs="0012_001496_000200_0194.jpg" xml:id="d3e3617"/>
            <p>We women think I believe that our hearts are footballs to be kicked at by every passing player
who chooses. And if one comes who would raise the quivering heart from the dust  we snatch it from
him saying he would not know to use it well. </p>
            <p>O wronged and tender heart!  alas that you are part of witless woman!</p>
            <p>Cumberland Furnace</p>
            <p>Sunday  Sept 23. 1866.</p>
            <p>My old trick of writing on Sunday yet it is a nice day to write  and this  tis a match-less day
 such a peerless day as those first few sinless days of Eden must have been. Sin herself must be
happy in such an air  such sunshine. I have been here at the Furnace since the first of August. Rob
brought me down by the N.W. RR  there were beautiful moon light nights and we came out home in the
carriage  reached here about 2 o&apos;clock. Have spent a pleasant quiet uneventful Summer here
with Florence  I  we all expected to have been home long before now but the cholera is in
Nash-</p>
            <pb n="195" facs="0012_001496_000200_0195.jpg" xml:id="d3e3633"/>
            <p>ville and we can not go up.</p>
            <p>The only visitors we have had this Summer except the Bells  were Major Wills and Captain
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">Coward</unclear> who came last Sunday in the Major&apos;s
buggy</p>
            <p>They started on Saturday but broke down. They remained until Wednesday and left in the rain  and
it rained all day long. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">In a </unclear>short note which the
Major wrote to Florence to tell her of the cholera being no better  he said reach <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">N.</unclear> is safely though very wet and muddy He rode with me every
evening. I had heard some very bad reports of him  and I told him of them  it was so hard to do 
but I prayed to do right. I sometimes think it has made him dislike me. I hope not  his friendship
is very precious to me. I trust the tales were false  I referred him to the Captain and I do not
know what the Captain told him  there are some things which the Capt does not know  which I can
not tell any one  even Mamma. He seemed so wounded  and I told him I had never believed them 
before he denied that any that were bad were true  I am afraid </p>
            <pb n="196" facs="0012_001496_000200_0196.jpg" xml:id="d3e3653"/>
            <p>I did not tell the truth for though I have not believed  it was not entire disbelief and if it
is true any of it  my saying this will I am afraid make it harder for him to tell me of it  should
he wish to do so.</p>
            <p>The Captain went last Thursday on a grand deer hunt to be gone a week or ten days  Major Wills
and Capt Coward thought of joining the hunt  I hope they did and are out of Nashville It is
horrible to think of the cholera being so bad in town I wish Mamma was here with me  she is so
lonely without me  I write to her twice a week whenever I can send the letter</p>
            <p>What a charming day this is for the hunters. F. and I are going walking.</p>
            <p>Saturday  Sept 29.</p>
            <p>Captain D. has come home came about an hour ago  Major W. and Capt. H. did not join the hunt. I
think I shall go home at last  I begged Wayne to take me to Clarksville early next week  Mamma
writes she is so lonely without me.</p>
            <pb n="197" facs="0012_001496_000200_0197.jpg" xml:id="d3e3669"/>
            <p>The cholera is raging in Nashville. The sky is clouded and my life seems dark  Fin went to town
from the Camp  dead being carried out in <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">drays</unclear> If
God should take my mother from me I do not know what I should do  when I was little I used to pray
to die when she did  but I know that it would be a sinful prayer now.  Yet I should be very
miserable without her</p>
            <p>Wayne and Mamma are the only persons in the world who really love me.</p>
            <p>There has been cholera within a mile of our home. I must go home.</p>
            <p>Jim Waller is dead  Mick <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">Camey</unclear> shot him. I heard
that Becky was at Church with him  Camey  the Sunday before and these stupid country people have
reported that she is engaged to him!  it is shameful. </p>
            <pb n="198" facs="0012_001496_000200_0198.jpg" xml:id="d3e3688"/>
            <p>Woodland Heights -</p>
            <p>Nov 5  1866 -</p>
            <p>Journal  I am at home  came from the Furnace a month ago. Wayne came up with me only remained
one day and returned  we came by way of Clarksville - <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">Ian</unclear> Emma and Mrs. Forbes  Bettie was out at Nannie <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">Tiglees</unclear>
            </p>
            <p>Florence and Captain and the rest came just a week after I did  remained over a week in town  I
went in  made a little cap for Hugh  they have gone to Ohio to visit Capt D&apos;s relations  to
be away for a month  have been gone over a week. Our neighborhood is quite gay and pleasant  a
number of young per-sons  some very pretty, refined girls  I was at a nice little party of about
thirty at Mr Paynes down the pike last Tuesday night Wednesday evening Major Wills came out to tell
us good bye  he is going away to County Memphis  he is sta-tioned there this Winter The Major came
alone  the first time he ever came alone  wished me to go into town with him and stay at cousin
Annie&apos;s  Mr. Over-ton  a nice handsome young gentleman here the same evening  both remained
to</p>
            <pb n="199" facs="0012_001496_000200_0199.jpg" xml:id="d3e3708"/>
            <p>Supper  Major left first as he had an en-gagement to a Supper in town. I promised to make the
Major a smoking cap  have no material now but will make one for him as soon as I can get something
to make it of.  It is a philapina. I went to the the-atre  the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">Miltoncan</unclear> Tableaux and to church sunday night with him while we were in
town.</p>
            <p>Now journal do not stretch your stupid old eyes and say &quot;Why  Miss <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">Nona</unclear> you must be engaged&quot; - Oh you horrid old thing! to
confuse one so!  I am not  he has never even told me that he cared for me  but he has acted it 
he has acted too much and I could not help it  those young men who saw him there in town think as
you did just now  dont you think it was unkind in him? Mr. Pittman was in town and as attentive as
ever  he happened to come the night that the Major was not there. He is pleasant and well read and
devoted and so hopelessly and submissively so, that one can not help feeling sorry for him  he is
to be in Nashville this Winter He sent me &quot;Lucile&quot; and I am so charmed with the poem. He
is I find quite a favorite in society  considered a &quot;catch&quot;</p>
            <pb n="200" facs="0012_001496_000200_0200.jpg" xml:id="d3e3723"/>
            <p> Last Thursday morning I was sitting here and Col. Prosser came;- he has sent me flowers and
visited me a few times when I have been at home but I never dreamed that he was a suitor</p>
            <p>Pa was away and Mamma was busy in the kitchen so I entertained him  he got up and I thought he
was going  he wan-dered nervously around the room and came back to me and made a
&quot;declaration&quot;</p>
            <p>I was so astonished that I really did not know what to say  Pa came home just then so I have not
fully answered him yet  he was here last night but I was away. I feel so sorry for him  he is not
young  35 or more I should think  seems good  is much respected here and had much to battle
against when he came  has made his own way in life and has been but little in society  yet is
educated and refined. He says he never cared for any lady before  and I think this is true as I am
probably the first cultivated woman he has met possibly since he was a man. He is ter-ribly bashful.
I thank God for what truth and beauty there may be in me but I am sorry if my good prove evil</p>
            <pb n="201" facs="0012_001496_000200_0201.jpg" xml:id="d3e3734"/>
            <p>and that it was not right for me. To go so much with him  and then I was embarrassed and hardly
knew what I was saying  and he asked to come home from church with me  I told him I did not know
to which church I would go; - and I think he is angry for he was not there to come with me though I
did go to the church he ask-ed me to go to. I have not seen him since  perhaps he will come
tomorrow he used always to come on Sunday</p>
            <p>Perhaps he will never come again. I have been unkind to him and untrue</p>
            <p>Yet I have prayed always to My Father to guide me and I have tried to do right.</p>
            <p>Perhaps it is Gods will that the waves of life should rock us apart  Yet it has seemed a safe
and pleasant place for my little <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">barke</unclear> to anchor
near this great ship but the ship might have crushed the little <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">larke</unclear> and received no good from her. God knows best. </p>
            <p>I pray for him always. He thinks I will marry Mr. P.- he might have trusted me more  and less 
than he has. I have not seen the Col. since  he was here while I was away.</p>
            <pb n="202" facs="0012_001496_000200_0202.jpg" xml:id="d3e3755"/>
            <p>Cousin Annie&apos;s little Aimee came out and is staying with me.</p>
            <p>I wish I was a clairvoyant just for a little.</p>
            <p>Monday night </p>
            <p>Dora came up yesterday spent the day and remained all night - had cousin Morgia and Mr. Shute in
the evening  Mr Corley  Granville and the Col. after supper  I fear I was too kind to the Col. it
is so hard to act just right  he has asked pa&apos;s permission to visit me. Poor fellow! he looks
so bright and hopeful. I looked a little for a knock that did not come.</p>
            <p>I am very sinful  I fret so against what it is Gods will that I shall bear The cry of my heart
is always that of the horrible horseleech&apos;s daughter. I can not see the good that God has given
me. I dreamed one night not long ago that a snake had crawled into my heart. God pity me  but I
believe the snake is there A snake that writhes and tosses and sometimes threatens almost to cast
out Faith and Trust who have sat there enthrone in calmness for so long.</p>
            <pb n="203" facs="0012_001496_000200_0203.jpg" xml:id="d3e3771"/>
            <p>And I had thought that this wicked thing if it ever came would be an angel of light Christians
should not have passions - they should be so controled and subdued as to be only emotions. But there
is a passion within me that is a whirlwind. I pray but not as I should  not weekly</p>
            <p>Tuesday night</p>
            <p>&quot;Why <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">really</unclear>&quot;! you will say journal -
&quot;she is getting to have quite regular habits&gt;&quot; - &quot;when did I ever know such a thing
before writing every night?&quot; The truth of it is I have to come up to put Aimee to bed and it is
too early for bleep to visit and so as I have nothing else to do I write  Mamma went to town today
in the carriage  Aimee was out playing and father was out on the farm  I spent the day alone
except at dinner  I wrote a long letter to Emma Robb  Em is going to Florida this Winter for her
health  I do trust it may restore her she is such a sweet, pretty, smart girl </p>
            <p>Wrote a short letter to Beckie also  she is in Giles County visiting her relations</p>
            <p>I have felt as happy and contented as a bird all day. Father is cross to me which makes me
unhappy when I am with him</p>
            <p>It is trouble has made him so.</p>
            <pb n="204" facs="0012_001496_000200_0204.jpg" xml:id="d3e3792"/>
            <p>Men can not bear such things as women can  that is the only thing that troubles me about Andie 
If he cares for me and is vexed with me he may go and do wrong and I fear he is bad enough already
They do say such cruel things of him  and he looks and seems so good. Our influence is a terrible
responsibility  if I had used it right I might have had much over him I think  but I may be
mistaken  he may not care for me except as a friend. I have a peculiar affection for him  born I
think of his kindness to me and a sort of championship which these cruel reports raised within me 
I could not believe him base with such a good innocent face. I believe it is the feeling which his
guardian angel  if there be such must have for him </p>
            <p>It is a deep feeling of friendship which nothing can change</p>
            <p>Florence is expected home from Ohio tomorrow  Marie Drouillard is coming with them.</p>
            <pb n="205" facs="0012_001496_000200_0205.jpg" xml:id="d3e3803"/>
            <p>December <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">6</unclear> / 66</p>
            <p>This is Jimmie Arkmans wedding night  it is to be quite a grand affair and I am invited  wish I
could go  Florence and Marie are going  Marie is the Captains sister. There was a little storm
party here at our house two weeks ago tomorrow Florence had just gotten home and she cousin Annie
and Marie came out  I went into town afterwards and remained a week or more  I like Marie.</p>
            <p>There is to be a little party  at Dora&apos;s tomorrow night</p>
            <p>I made a smoking cap yesterday which I promised to the Major  I have not seen or heard any thing
of him for nearly a month  perhaps he will never come for his cap  I would send it to him if I
knew where he was but I do not</p>
            <p>I wish he would come  Tenysons Palace of Art has been running in <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">my head</unclear> all day long  I built my soul a lordly pleasure house wherein for aye
for dwell&quot; </p>
            <p>Our idols are <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">margy</unclear> - and hard to break up and
throw down.</p>
            <pb n="206" facs="0012_001496_000200_0206.jpg" xml:id="d3e3829"/>
            <p>December 30, 1866.</p>
            <p>The old year is on its couch of Death and nature hangs grey days of cloud around it - &quot;It
gave me a friend and a true, true love And the New Year shall take them away. &quot; </p>
            <p>Florence and I &quot;received&quot; last New Years but will not this year.</p>
            <p>There is to be a masquerade at <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">V.&apos;s</unclear> New
Years night to which I promised to come. I have only been out of town for a few days after a visit
of a week or more. <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">T</unclear> gave me a set of furs for a
Christmas gift. </p>
            <p> Gen T. and staff were in town about two weeks ago. I was not in town  but expected daily  The
Major  Col he is <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">cross</unclear> was there and did not come
out to see me  the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">reporsts</unclear> he acknowledges to be
true I fear by this  or else he does not care for me and I know that if he is unchanged this is not
so. I came into town just after he had left and he said he remained a day over to meet me there  he
could have come out if he had been so anxious  though it was horrible weather.</p>
            <p>He desired though that I should send his smoking cap which I did express the evening before
Xmas</p>
            <pb n="207" facs="0012_001496_000200_0207.jpg" xml:id="d3e3859"/>
            <p>I had promised my picture in return for one he gave me of himself so I put one in the cap and a
little note  depricating it&apos;s the cap simplicity  but hoping that so slight a token of
friendship might not be valueless&quot;  &quot;a merry Christmas&quot; - and nothing more  I have
as yet received no answer. Marie says - &quot;he speaks so openly of you and seems to care so much
for you&quot; - or something like that  I sometimes fear that I am acting all wrong for him and for
myself  but then the fear that it is is Sin to doubt of the way things are or may be  for the
Bible says &quot;command thy ways unto the Lord and he shall direct thy paths&quot; - &quot;In all
thy ways acknowledge Him and lean not unto thine own understanding&quot; - I asked my Father to
guide me  and how can I doubt  I am as blind as Bartemus here surely - and the Father will give me
sight. Surely such things in a Christian womans life are not too little for the Lord  if they are
then she must be also for they are so much to her  nay they are all of this life  and of the other
much <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">smee</unclear> the life here bears so much upon the life
beyond </p>
            <p>I can not reason on such things clearly I fear  for my heart is stronger than my brain  It
seems sometimes  and it is a terrible thing to think that I am almost challenging my Maker by
putting thing so  but I can not see any other way. I only can pray for guidance</p>
            <pb n="208" facs="0012_001496_000200_0208.jpg" xml:id="d3e3871"/>
            <p>Sometimes I think I am a little brain struck fool who took a summer&apos;s flirtation for love 
a grand passion  then Miss <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">Nona</unclear> all you can do is
to &quot;whistle it down the wind&quot; - and &quot;let it go&quot; &quot;it is not worth the
keeping.&quot; - but the winds I could whistle it down&quot; - would I fear be the &quot;Wind
Euroclydon.&quot;</p>
            <p>I have been reading all day - De Quincey&apos;s Literary Reminiscences  a pleasant colloquial
book which I like.</p>
            <p>There is one thing which troubles me much of late  it is some how thus  the crops were bad this
year and with all economy on their part  Pa and Ma come out in debt  now I think that my
expenditure for the year would have made them about even  indeed I am sure it would  I did not
spend so much  only as Ma authorized me did I spend that  and I felt it to be little enough at the
time.</p>
            <p>I know they <unclear reason="illegible" resp="SS">none</unclear> of them grudge it to me  but I
am the youngest and strongest of the whole family it is not right that I should be a burthen to them
But I do not know what on Earth to do  to get money!  the very sound of it is ridiculous in
connection with myself. But if they will only let me I am willing to do any thing that I can do.</p>
            <pb n="209" facs="0012_001496_000200_0209.jpg" xml:id="d3e3890"/>
            <p>I am no use or comfort to any one in the whole world except Mamma a little  and a vast deal more
of trouble to her than comfort  I wonder if it is very wrong to wish that God would take me up to
Heaven  where I could not be a burthen to anyone</p>
            <p>I am so light hearted amid all this trouble that I think it almost a sin  but I do feel it
deeply  deeply  I will try for some kind of work-</p>
            <p>1867.</p>
            <p>Jan. 6, - New Years Gift my journal!  I spent the &quot;first&quot; in town went in on the cars
after spending the last night of the old year over at cousin Morgia&apos;s with the Minnies 
Granville went in with me and who should I meet in the car but first Mr Ringold from Clarksvill and
 Mr. Hewett  I was so glad and surprised to see him  he has I expect returned to Arkansas before
this as he only was to be away a few days.</p>
            <p>I came out of town the 2nd in Capt Bain&apos;s carryall  We <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">ucrebed</unclear> New Years  In my old brown poplin that I bought in New York 3 yrs</p>
            <pb n="210" facs="0012_001496_000200_0210.jpg" xml:id="d3e3910"/>
            <p>ago  Marie in the blue moire antique and point lace  Florence in silk <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">with</unclear> pearls, about 35 <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">oallers.</unclear>
            </p>
            <p>Mr. Andrews and Mr Calhoun drove out to see me this evening  pleasant gentlemen  both.</p>
            <p> The masque did not come off. </p>
            <p>I recieved a letter acknowledging and thanking me for  the smoking cap and picture and asking me
to write to him  deploring that I did not come in to town in time to be seen of him. I hardly think
I shall write to him.</p>
            <p>A strange thing has befallen me which I can in no wise explain  I trust I am not fickle  I
always thought before that I was too sincere  no that is almost impossible  but more earnest than
was good for me in this world I thought I cared for   but almost all feeling of interest even has
left me suddenly  I <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">bauled</unclear> against my inconstancy
at first but &apos;twas useless - I can not care for him now  nor do I care for any one  I do not
understand myself  and I deplore it  I thought I was better. </p>
            <pb n="211" facs="0012_001496_000200_0211.jpg" xml:id="d3e3933"/>
            <p>So a splendid bubble that has amused me for year has burst and I find its beauty and glory are 
naught  are but a drop of soap suds  tough!</p>
            <p>It has been a beautiful day  clear and not very cold.</p>
            <p>Home  Friday night</p>
            <p>Jan, 25 - 1867</p>
            <p>I have been looking back over my journal tonight  I was eighteen when I commenced it and next
March I will be twenty three  five years of life!  how swiftly they have sped  these years and
the two which came before will hereafter be most probably those to which my heart will ever turn
back in its journey down the Valley of Life  so sunlit then but growing darker every year  yet as
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">lk</unclear> Marvel says  Fancy ever loves to cheat the heart
and hang gorgeous tissue along the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">horizon</unclear> of the
years that are to come  But the lives of others teach us that youth is life&apos;s season of joy 
and somehow my youth seems to have been fleeter than some other women I have known</p>
            <p>Many women still seem girls at  even twenty five  but I feel as if my youth was past  utterly
gone forever</p>
            <pb n="212" facs="0012_001496_000200_0212.jpg" xml:id="d3e3957"/>
            <p>Wayne  who is home now  having left the Furnace and not being very well  has not as yet gone
into any other business  Wayne and I went into town yesterday and remained all night  came out
this evening.</p>
            <p>Marie is getting homesick  she does not recieve any attention in Nashville at all  so it is no
wonder. </p>
            <p>Florence too is dissatisfied and talks of selling the house and going to the Furnace for six
months  and then to New York  which is to her <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">fancy</unclear> a haven of happiness. I shall miss her when she is gone  but I think she will be
happier so I am glad</p>
            <p>I was invited to Mrs. M. Crea&apos;s party  Wednesday night but did not recieve my invitation
till the party was over as I was sent to F&apos;s</p>
            <p>Beckie has come home from Giles Co  where she has been for several months  they think she looks
sad and pale  she begins to look a little faded  she is twenty five I think.</p>
            <pb n="213" facs="0012_001496_000200_0213.jpg" xml:id="d3e3975"/>
            <p>It is just a week today since cousin Sam Varileer died  he leaves a young wife and three little
sons  Life seems so sad of late  no one I know is happy  The young girls do not seem gay now. 
no I made a mistake  Twas Wednesday a week that poor cousin Sam died</p>
            <p>&quot;-My heart was hot and restless</p>
            <p>My life was full of care</p>
            <p>And the burden laid upon me</p>
            <p>Seemed greater than I could bear&quot;</p>
            <p>- I wonder when if ever I shall so conquor this high sinful heart as to finish the verse  I wish
I had a piano.</p>
            <p>Home. Feb. 11 1867.</p>
            <p>Monday night -</p>
            <p>Dora and Beckie came up and stayed all night with me last night  went home early this morning.
Ah journal I have sad news for you  my dear dear Uncle William Mintzer is dead  he died on the 26
of Jan. He was such a good noble man  everything to his family  poor Aunt Beckie  I know it
almost kills her  and George was devoted to his father.</p>
            <pb n="214" facs="0012_001496_000200_0214.jpg" xml:id="d3e4000"/>
            <p>He left them wealthy so that other suffering is spared them. I have lost a good friend in him.
Wayne is not well and is low spirited  poor fellow out of employment and in bad health with us all
dependent on him  it does seem hard. They wanted to reduce his salary at the Furnace was the reason
why he left. I hope our Heavenly Father will make it all for the best. All trouble seems hard for
the present. I have a bad cough which frightens Ma  it is only a cold I am sure. If I only could
work some way to help them all  I think sometimes Wayne regrets that I am not married  Perhaps I
have done very wrong I might have married some one of them and helped all of us along so  but it
seemed then so wrong  so sinful to  sell oneself  for that it would have been that  there was no
love  and there was love I fear for some one else. I have prayed God always to guide me in such
things and now I seem to have gone so wrong  and worse than anything it sometimes shakes my trust
in Gods immediate providence</p>
            <p>The thought comes sometimes that if I had trusted less and followed the dictates of my head and
not my heart I could have made them all so much happier. But I love the Lord my God and this
rashional</p>
            <pb n="215" facs="0012_001496_000200_0215.jpg" xml:id="d3e4009"/>
            <p>ism takes me so far from him  He seems then only the Creator  far away in the center of all
things  not our Heavenly Father who loves us all as his children. &quot;Whom the Lord loveth He
chasteneth.&quot; Some persons say &quot;help yourself and the Lord will help you.&quot; I can not
see through that  how can we help ourselves when we are groping so in the dark.</p>
            <p>I think I shall pray God to send me some work so that I can help them all  or at least help
myself so that I will not be a tax on them. There seems nothing that I can do to make any money  no
women even the most competent now are able to make much and I  why I know nothing.</p>
            <p>&quot;Ye can not serve God and Mamma&quot; Yet money seems so necessary  my teeth need plugging
 and they are such pretty little teeth  if I thought it right to spend so much I would have them
done  but &apos;twould cost so much and would be so selfish in me to spend so much on myself  so I
must let them go I fear. Mamma has spent so much on them already.</p>
            <p>Marie has gone home left unexpectedly  was homesick  I was in town last week with F. during the
Capt&apos;s absence at the furnace - </p>
            <pb n="216" facs="0012_001496_000200_0216.jpg" xml:id="d3e4022"/>
            <p>They were I think a little unfair to Wayne  they did not tell him about reducing his salary till
after Xmas - when all the other places were full. They profess so much love and friendship for us
and they are so rich and Wayne&apos;s salary was every thing to us. These are complaining pages
unworthy of a Christian  all these things I try to subdue and by Gods help I will be content I
trust someday  But &quot;my heart is hot and restless&quot; and I may as well write it out. I am
not so always  sometimes I am willing  and I think if twas only for myself I could be willing
always.</p>
            <p>I think the matter of the teeth comes from vanity  men and women flatter me and vanity perhaps
is at the bottom of much of my trouble. I have tried to be so kind and true to Florence and some how
it comes back to me in gall and wormwood. It my be that I have envied her.</p>
            <p>We are expecting our cousin Annie <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG"> Baugh </unclear> - and
her husband to visit us soon they are on a southern tour. Capt Howard was in town  came to see us
while I was there. The Major  no Col was in Washington he said.</p>
            <p>Bed time <unclear reason="illegible" resp="RG">12 or</unclear>
            </p>
            <p>11 oclock</p>
            <pb n="217" facs="0012_001496_000200_0217.jpg" xml:id="d3e4042"/>
            <p>Corinth. Miss. Nov 9 -</p>
            <p>1869.</p>
            <p>After many days I sit today in a home made for me by my darling and I am his happy happy wife 
we were married at Woodland Heights Sep 15. 1869  not yet two months ago. He is so good to me and I
can not thank my Father in Heaven enough for His goodness in giving us to each other</p>
            <p>Business troubles of magnitude have lately come upon him - but I try with Gods help to lighten
the load. &quot;Trust in the Lord with all thine heart and lean not unto thine own
understanding&quot; - Wait on the Lord and he shall give thee the desire of thine heart.</p>
            <p>I loved him so long but when he came and took me I was almost on the brink of a sadder destiny
than any other that may befall a woman who tries to be good  a loveless marriage. But I am saved to
happiness in my husband&apos;s love and can bear bravely whatever may befall while God leaves me
this.</p>
            <pb/>
            <p/>
            <pb n="219" facs="0012_001496_000200_0219.jpg" xml:id="d3e4064"/>
            <p>Sketches.</p>
            <pb n="220" facs="0012_001496_000200_0220.jpg" xml:id="d3e4071"/>
            <p>Elleanora</p>
            <p>Willaner</p>
            <p>Ellanora</p>
            <p>Eleanora</p>
            <p>Willanor</p>
            <p>Sketch with label: Stables and Barn</p>
            <p>C.E.</p>
            <pb n="221" facs="0012_001496_000200_0221.jpg" xml:id="d3e4091"/>
            <p>[Inside Back Cover.]</p>
            <pb n="222" facs="0012_001496_000200_0222.jpg" xml:id="d3e4098"/>
            <p>[Back Cover.]</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
