<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000091_000201_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter, 
<name>David L. Jones</name>
 in Nashville, Tenn. to Anna Jones in Alleghany City, Pa. <date when="1865-03-18">1865 March 18
 </date>
            </title>
            <author>
               <name type="person">Jones, David L..</name>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>Williams, Nancy</name>
               <name>Williams, Sherry L.</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_000091_000201_0000</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more information,
            contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special Collections
                Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Letter, David L. Jones in Nashville, Tenn. to Anna Jones in Allegheny City, Pa., 1865 March 18</title>
               <date>1865-03-18</date>
               <author>
                  <name>Jones, David L..</name>
               </author>
               <extent>4  digital images;  4 pages</extent>
               <note type="abstract">Letter dated March 18 1865 David L. Jones in Nashville, Tenn. to Anna Jones in Alleghany City, Pa. Describes inflated prices in Nashville, visit to Fort Negley, thievery in the barracks and life at camp.
</note>
               <note type="collection">David L. Jones Letters, 1865</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS.2685</note>
               <note type="item">5</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee Libraries
                Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
                omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Soldier -- Pennsylvania -- Correspondence.</term>
               <term>Curfews -- Tennessee -- Nashville -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Offenses against property -- Tennessee -- Nashville -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Nashville (Tenn.) -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865. </term>
               <term>Jones, David L., Union soldier -- Correspondence. </term>
               <term>United States. Army. Pennsylvania Cavalry Regiment, 19th (1863-1866). </term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-10-02" who="bds">Migrating from
                XML to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter" xml:id="d3e156">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_000091_000201_0001.jpg" xml:id="d3e157"/>
            <p>Nashville Tenn March 18th </p>
            <p>My Dear Wife I take my pen in hand to write you a few lines in hope that they may find you and the children also enjoying your usual health as I do Thank the Lord for it I cant write a very long letter now we have not much time to ourselves Just now it takes all of our time in Sleeping Eating and Drilling We have been on two days Parade since we have been here it is a pretty thing to see the Capn of each company and other officers Superior to them saluting each other and holding conversation at a distance from the <gap resp="Williams"/> I went and visited two forts since the one is not much of a Fort i went all through it the other one is called Fort Negley which is a very strong Fort the out side is built of stone wall I went all around the out side of it I had no time then to go inside for it was too late in the day if i am spared I shall</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_000091_000201_0002.jpg" xml:id="d3e169"/>
            <p>Take a good look at it there is a good view from off these forts we can see Several Battle fields where <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NW"> Thos </unclear> fought Rebel <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NW"> Flood </unclear> there is not a<unclear reason="illegible" resp="NW"> fewer</unclear> to be Seen about the whole place i have not been out any distance yet but everything looks desolate if you see a horse it is that poor and hardly able to walk alone We are here right among the Niggers of the Blakest kind the is under Martial Law no one is allowed to be out after 9.o clock except soldier&apos;s and they must keep sober the tavern keepers durst not give them any liquour soldiers durst not smoke on the streets either those fellows that we left behind on the road came on yesterday the 17th those that we left behind at Alleghany is not here yet I guess the Provost-guard has them if i had been 1/2 hour later i would have been left behind too There is some regular thieves in this bo one of our fellows hung his Pants up one </p>
            <pb n="3" facs="0012_000091_000201_0003.jpg" xml:id="d3e186"/>
            <p>night he had 6 Dol in his watch Pocket which some fellow took the Cap offered a Reward of 25$ for any information he allowed that he would put him where he would not steal for a while so the next day they took my canvass tent but my Partner went around the next day and found it I ate 2 of them apples the other day I have not touched the Beef yet I have ate some of the crackers I have some of the Beloney which i shall eat tomorrow if i live tomorrow is the Sabbath I dont know whether we can hear a sermon or not it is not likely though they tell me that the govt has most of the churches turned into hospitals and different things it is very hard to write here sitting in <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NW"> your Derth</unclear> where there is a lot below playing cards <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NW"> shakeing </unclear> so Sabbath morning 6 o clock I was up at it is a nice morning i went down to the spring and washed myself The Robin was up ahead of me for she was </p>
            <pb n="4" facs="0012_000091_000201_0004.jpg" xml:id="d3e200"/>
            <p>singing beautiful when <gap resp="Williams"/> out. I should like you would let me know when you get the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NW"> Jax </unclear> receipt from the West I should like you would send me a little supper in the next letter dont put too much so as to make the letter too heavy Every thing is awful dear here a Bottle of peppermint what we pay 5 cents for there 25 here shoes 10$ a pair Boots 20 to 25$ Newspapers 15 I wrote to Robert, Wills &amp; Dunham this week. I dont think i shall write to any one else for they did not ask me to do it. I hope that the children behaves themselves Tell James that I shall write him a Letter next week if i live And one for andrew inside of it I mentioned in my last 2 letters for you to buy Tom Sharon and the Babe a ginger horse but i always forgot to put the money in Please send a word up to <unclear reason="illegible" resp="NW"> carnel s </unclear> mother that he is well Kiss all the children for me So I must draw to a close Your Husband </p>
            <p>David</p>
            <p>bo i 78 P Vol</p>
            <p>Nash Tenn</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
