<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000060_000340_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter, <name>J.G.M. Ramsey</name> in Mecklenburg, Tenn., to Andrew
Jackson, at the Hermitage, near Nashville, Tenn. <date when="1823-05-28">1823 May 28</date>
            </title>
            <author>
               <name type="person">Ramsey, J. G. M. (James Gettys McGready), 1797-1884</name>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>Dyson-Smith, Bridger</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_000060_000340_0000</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more information,
            contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special Collections
                Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>1823 May 28, Letter (copy), J.G.M. Ramsey in Mecklenburg, Tenn., to Andrew Jackson at the Hermitage, near Nashville, Tenn.  Draft letter, May 30, 1823, to Judge Haywood.</title>
               <date>1823-05-28</date>
               <author>
                  <name>Ramsey, J. G. M. (James Gettys McGready), 1797-1884</name>
               </author>
               <extent>1 digital image; 1 page</extent>
               <note type="abstract">1823 May 28, letter (copy), J.G.M. Ramsey, Mecklenburg, Tenn., to Gen. Andrew Jackson, the Hermitage, near Nashville, Tenn. Explains his interest in publishing a pamphlet on the Mecklenburg Convention and Declaration of 1775. Reports that while visiting relatives in North Carolina, he learned of Gen. Jackson&apos;s participation in the Convention. Requests information concerning the officers of the Convention. Includes draft letter, May 30, 1823, to Judge Haywood, (North Carolina?). </note>
               <note type="collection">J.G.M. Ramsey Papers 1790-1869</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS.253</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee Libraries
                Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
                omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Pamphlets -- North Carolina -- Charlotte -- History -- 18th century.</term>
               <term>Political conventions -- North Carolina -- History -- 18th century.</term>
               <term>Declaration of intention -- North Carolina -- History -- 18th century.</term>
               <term>Tennessee, East -- History -- 19th century -- Pamphlets.</term>
               <term>Mecklenburg County (N.C.) -- History -- 18th century.</term>
               <term>Ramsey, J. G. M. (James Gettys McGready), 1797-1884 -- Correspondence.</term>
               <term>Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845 -- Correspondence.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-10-02" who="bds">Migrating from
                XML to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter" xml:id="d3e155">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_000060_000340_0001.jpg" xml:id="d3e156"/>
            <p>Mecklenburg near Knoxville</p>
            <p>Dear General</p>
            <p>A pamphlet has recently published wich you have probably seen containing - documents of an interesting
nature. From it the fact is established beyond controversy that a convention composed of &amp;c &amp;c vested
with unlimited powers met at Charlotte in Mecklenburg <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">county</unclear>
N.C. to deliberate on the existing state of things - From <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">these</unclear> 
deliberations <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">resulted</unclear> + the convention made a declared - Which
declared themselves &amp; represented a free &amp; independent of the government + a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">transaction</unclear> as glorious &amp; eventful as it is honorable to the virtuous firmness
patriotic <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">dream</unclear> &amp; the intelligence of the Convention
They met on the 19th May 1775 &amp; on unhappily been suffered to remain the united in declaring themselves 
a free &amp; independent people &amp; <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">however absolved</unclear> themselves
from all allegiance in a great measure unknown &amp; forgotten &amp; has to the British Crown. This Declaration
of Independence is in its <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">letters</unclear> &amp; never been inserted in
the historical records of our Country. The memory of such an event ought to be perpetuated &amp; cherished in the
bosom <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">onwards</unclear> 1st. of the American people. On a late visit
to my relations in Mecklenburg I was informed 2nd that the 2nd Hero of New Orleans + the distinguished Citizen
of my native State was the Deliverer of his <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">country</unclear> present
at Charlotte on that memorable occasion - you when other &amp; Wishing to obtain all more important the
information that can at this late period be collected relative to this <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">avocation</unclear> will permit to inform me who were members I have taken the liberty
to request your leaders in that transaction of the Convention - especially who were the President &amp; Secretary
or the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">primary</unclear> members of the Convention - and any thing else
on <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">these</unclear> such part character in forming the declaration yet
you may think proper to communicate will be received most gratefully may <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">allow</unclear>
to wrest from oblivion one of the most briliant transactions of in the early history of this Country. I have the
honor to be with much respect yours &amp;c</p>
            <p>May 30, 1823</p>
            <note type="transcription">The following text is a second rough draft, upside down, at the bottom
of the first page.</note>
            <p>Judge Haywood</p>
            <p>I have in my possession a pamphlet which you have no doubt seen establishing the fact that Convention met on the
19 May 1775 at Charlotte &amp; declared themselves a free &amp; independent people. I have thought that perhaps
in your historical researches you have received some information on the subject or that you have some
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">
                  <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">recollection of that</unclear>Mill place</unclear>
important fact in the early history of <gap resp="Dyson-Smith"/> Country. I should be happy to hear from you on this subject as soon
as your other valuable engagements will permit</p>
            <p>yours</p>
            <p>May 30, 1823</p>
            <note type="transcription">The preceding text is a second rough draft, upside down, at the bottom
of the first page.</note>
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_000060_000340_0002.jpg" xml:id="d3e231"/>
            <p>Mecklenburg near Knoxville</p>
            <p>May 29, 1823</p>
            <p>My dear Sir</p>
            <p>I have in my possession a pamphlet that contains <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">certificates</unclear>
and attestations from many persons of respectability &amp; standing in North Carolina that a convention
vested with unlimited powers met at Charlotte <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Meck</unclear> County N.C.
and on the 19 May 1775 declared themselves a free &amp; independent people This declaration as it is
more than thirteen months sooner than the national one of July 4, 1776 and as it is not only similar in its
spirit &amp; letter to it but also in some parts identically the same is considered a momentous transaction
&amp; one altogether honorable to the virtue intelligence &amp; independence of that section of the
country when it took place. The members of that immortal Convention have with the exception of two or three
left this for the world of spirits. One of the survivors <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Zacheras</unclear>
Willson resides near Gallatin and my object in writing to you at this time is to procure from him through you
any information he can at this late period of his life give of that eventful transaction. Particularly the
first moves of the business - the members names - pursuits in life &amp;c. the name of the President &amp;
Secretary &amp; the feelings of the mass of the people on the subject, &amp; any thing else he may think
proper to communicate. A certificate from him will bear with it a kind of official authority as he was a
member of the Con &amp; must have understood all the first steps of the that glorious event &amp;c</p>
            <p>Rev. J.R. Bain</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
