<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000060_000339_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter, <name>Rev. J.R. Bain</name> in Gallatin, Tenn., to J.G.M.
Ramsey, in Knoxville, Tenn. <date when="1823-06-20">1823 June 20</date>
            </title>
            <author>
               <name type="person">Bain, J. R., Rev.</name>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>Dyson-Smith, Bridger</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_000060_000339_0000</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more information,
            contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special Collections
                Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Letter, Rev. J.R. Bain in Gallatin, Tenn., to J.G.M. Ramsey in Knoxville, Tenn. 1823 June 20</title>
               <date>1823-06-20</date>
               <author>
                  <name>Bain, J. R., Rev.</name>
               </author>
               <extent>4 digital images; 4 pages</extent>
               <note type="abstract">1823 June 20 Rev. J.R. Bain, Gallatin, Tenn., to Dr. J.G.M. Ramsey, Knoxville, Tenn. In reply to Dr. Ramsey&apos;s letter of May 29, 1823, relays information concerning Mecklenburg Convention gathered from Zacheras Wilson. Urges Dr. Ramsey not to be discouraged by unchristian behavior in others but to set a Christian example himself. Refers to the 1824 presidential election.</note>
               <note type="collection">J.G.M. Ramsey Papers 1790-1869</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS.253</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee Libraries
                Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
                omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Christian ethics -- Tennessee -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Christians -- Conduct of life -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Conduct of life -- Religious aspects -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Tennessee -- Politics and government -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Bain, J. R., Rev. -- Correspondence.</term>
               <term>Wilson, Zaccheus -- Political activity.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-10-02" who="bds">Migrating from
                XML to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter" xml:id="d3e154">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_000060_000339_0001.jpg" xml:id="d3e155"/>
            <p><note type="transcription">The following text is a continuation of the fourth page of the letter.</note></p>
            <p>absence, that I intend to drop my correspondence with you. I have indeed neglected almost all my old
correspondents; but I hope I shall never neglect you. My friendship for you is intwined with my very heart;
and I know I shall never forget you, or cease to love you.</p>
            <p>Write to me soon, &amp; remember me to Mrs. Ramsey, your brothers &amp; sister &amp;c.</p>
            <p>I am, dear Sir, with</p>
            <p>much esteem yours &amp;c.</p>
            <p>J.R. Bain</p>
            <p><note type="transcription">The preceding text is a continuation of the fourth page of the letter.</note></p>
            <p>Gallatin T</p>
            <p>June 23</p>
            <p>Dr. James M&apos;G. Ramsey</p>
            <p>Received June 29, 1823.</p>
            <p><note type="transcription">The following text is a continuation of the fourth page of the letter.</note></p>
            <p>P.S. I continue to preach, but with little apparent success. I frequently feel discouraged. My School
is tolerably good. Our <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">impending</unclear> Presidential election
has also given a new start to Politics in this county. I hope Adams will be elected. This must be your
desire of course. J.R.B. No Jackson is forever J.G.M. Ramsey</p>
            <p><note type="transcription">The preceding text is a continuation of the fourth page of the letter.</note></p>
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_000060_000339_0002.jpg" xml:id="d3e193"/>
            <p>Gallatin June 20th 1823</p>
            <p>Dear Sir,</p>
            <p>Just as I received your letter of 29th May, I was about to answer your former letter; but I have waited
two weeks longer and shall reply to both at the same time. At your request I went directly to see
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Zacheras</unclear> Wilson. He is very old and infirm, and although
he has a faint recollection of the transaction you mentioned, yet he has forgotten all the particulars. I
mentioned the particular things on which you wanted information, and he said he would think about it, and
endeavor to recollect all he could against another time. I accordingly left him, and in a week returned again
to see him; but he could not recollect any thing particular about it. He says he recollects that there was such
a convention, that he was a member, that there were several others, perhaps to the number of 20 or 30, that as
far as he recollects they were all farmers, and true Republicans, that there motive was to write together
in proving faithful in the defence of their country against the British and Tories; that some thought
they were rather premature; he thinks perhaps Col. George Alexander (if I mistake not) was Clerk, but he cannot
re-</p>
            <pb n="3" facs="0012_000060_000339_0003.jpg" xml:id="d3e208"/>
            <p>collect the name of the President. This, Sir, is all the information that I could get. Perhaps he has not
thought of it for 40 years before, and he is now just tottering over the grave, and I suppose will never recollect
any thing more. - Although I, with great pleasure, endeavoured to collect all the information I could for
you on that subject, yet I should be glad to know what interest you can have in it at this late period. But
this is only curiosity in me.</p>
            <p>In my last, I requested you to authorize the Editor of the Knoxville paper to put my name down as a subscriber, if
you considered it worth taking. I know not whether you forgot it, or misunderstood it, I have never received
the paper; nor did you in your last mention whether you had attended to it or not. However I am now well
enough satisfied it never came on; for I am taking, perhaps, too many papers already.</p>
            <p>In your former letter, you seem to complain of the unchristian manner in which you see many <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">professors</unclear> of religion conduct themselves. Dear Sir, this is
to be lamented in every part of Christendom; but this is no argument against the reality of religion.
Christians, no doubt, by their disorderly conduct,</p>
            <pb n="4" facs="0012_000060_000339_0004.jpg" xml:id="d3e223"/>
            <p>do more harm to the cause of Christ, than all the infidels in the world. But when we meet with a counterfeit
note, (and indeed there are several in circulation) we never look upon it as an evidence that there is
no genuine money. Indeed the very term counterfeit, implies that there is something genuine which
has been counterfeited. Let us then deal as candidly with respect to Christians as money, and believe that
there are some worthy of the title, though they may have their imperfections. Let us not reject
the good with the bad. But you say, you do not do this. I do not accuse you of it. I know you have too much
good sense. But let me as a friend tell you that the misconduct of Christians, &amp; particularly of 
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">parents</unclear> with respect to their children, should not
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">rebar</unclear> you from the church, or hinder you from offering your
children to God in baptism. Do you do your duty, and let others be accountable to God for their own
conduct. Resolve that, let others do as they may, you &amp; your house will serve the Lord. Attach yourself,
(if you have not already done it) to the Church of Christ, and set others an example. Let your light so
shine around you that others beholding your good works, may also be constained to glorify your heavenly Father.
You have now got a family, and have become a father; remember the duties of a father <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">desolve</unclear> upon you. I hope my dear Sir, that you will remember the ways of your
pious father, and walk in his footsteps. Try to fill his place, &amp; be a father to your younger brothers &amp;
sister, a blessing to your wife &amp; children, and an example of piety &amp; virtue to all around you.</p>
            <p>My dear Friend, do not suppose, from my long</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>