<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_001564_000204_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter, 
               <name type="author">Robert A. Ragan</name> near <name type="place">Jonesborough, Tennessee</name>, to Emeline Ragan, 
               <date when="1863-10-20">1863 October 20</date>
            </title>
            <author>
               <name>Ragan, Robert A.</name>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>White, Park</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <availability status="restricted">
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
                  information, contact the Special Collections Library.</p>
            </availability>
            <idno>0012_001564_000204_0000</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Letter, 
                  <name type="author">Robert A. Ragan</name> near <name type="place">Jonesborough, Tennessee</name>, to Emeline Ragan, 
                  <date when="1863-10-20">1863 October 20</date>
               </title>
               <author>
                  <name>Ragan, Robert A.</name>
               </author>
               <extent>4 digital images</extent>
               <note type="collection">Robert A. Ragan Letters</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS.0743</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for The University of Tennessee Libraries
               Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Corrections have been applied to the text only where there is a high degree of
               certainty of an error and if the correct spelling is known.</p>
            <p>Corrections are represented by editorial tags.</p>
            <p>Quotation marks and apostrophes have been replaced by entity references.</p>
            <p>All unambiguous end-of-line hyphens have been removed.</p>
            <p>Names of persons, places, and organizations are indicated in the transcription when
               identifiable with a high degree of certainty.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Knoxville (Tenn.) -- History -- Siege, 1863.</term>
               <term>Soldiers -- Tennessee -- Correspondence.</term>
               <term>Tennessee -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.</term>
               <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Religious aspects.</term>
               <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-06-17" who="nl">Updated earlier transcription from the old TEI.2 system to anticipate and resolve difficulties and issues with re-formatting letters from this collection into TEI-P5 lite.</change>
         <change when="2013-07-15" who="nl">Added "idno" element, 
            editorial declaration statement, subjects/keywords and abstracts 
            from EAD finding aid. Removed box and folder notes, reference 
            declaration element. Changed the formatting for blank pages. 
            Added resp attributes to editorial changes, and added name 
            tags.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter" xml:id="d2e171">
            <pb facs="0012_001564_000204_0001.jpg" n="1" xml:id="d2e173"/>
            <opener>
               <dateline>Near 
                  <name type="place">Jonesberough</name> 
                  <date when="1863-10-20">Oct. 20th 1863</date>
               </dateline>
            </opener>
            <salute>Dear Wife</salute>
            
            <p>I have again Seated My Self to Write You a few Lins It is all the Sadisfaction I See. is When I am tring to write you a histry of my tryals.  I rote you a Letter Last Sondy.  I Studyed all Sonday about home.  If I New You all was Safe but You live where You will be In danger all the time.</p>
            <p>We had orders to be ready this morning to move at five O clock we had ever thing packed up ready to Start and the order was Countermanded.  And now I dont Know When we will move.  we may move in the morning but I cant tell the dispach came in this morning that the Rebels had captured 2 Companies of the Second Ten Regment &amp; I expect It Is Sow.  I think we will be ordered down to <choice><orig><name type="place">Greenville</name></orig><corr resp="pw"><name type="place">Greeneville</name></corr></choice> in a few days  I dont want to go below</p>
            
            <pb facs="0012_001564_000204_0002.jpg" n="2" xml:id="d2e205"/>
            <p><choice><orig><name type="place">Greenville</name></orig><corr resp="pw"><name type="place">Greeneville</name></corr></choice> for I Seen more trouble when I was down at <name type="place">Lick Creek Bridge</name> than I have Saw in five Years to think I was So Close home and them Low down Infurnel black thieveish murel Clan was Stealing thru our country I recond Mis Mary Chapman was very well pleased when they come back  If I come back down there Soon again I will make that big Eye browed Bill Chapmond run faster than he did before, and then let Mary Say I will get My Self in a scrape after I went to Greenvill I was acting as provost  I had sent for some four or five in that country.  If pleas Williams had come up there I would mad him, walked a rale for something</p>
            <p>We taken that Thief of a Thomas Easterly down to <name type="place">Knoxville</name> &amp; we lost the papers that we had taken the Evedence down on and there was no profe aganst him and they releast him</p>
            
            <pb facs="0012_001564_000204_0003.jpg" n="3" xml:id="d2e226"/>
            <p>but we are not done with him yet.  There will be a Strating up of things Em I am a frade they have taken your Leather that I got If they have I will be down before Long and I will have as much more.</p>
            <p>We have bad Newes in our company we have Lost four out of our company I will give you there Names.  Thomas Easterly David Canon, Daniel Cntraell, Alexander Etherton. You dont no how It hearts me to heare of one of my boys dieing but we all have to die and It looks Like this ware is going to distroy all of us.  but I hope for the better, and trust in one hoo rules all.</p>
            <p>Oh that the time would come when we all could be together again in peace and harmny.  I cant Stand It of a Sondy I now how Lonsome You are If I could be at home and go to meeting and be with you I would give all the wourld</p>
            
            <pb facs="0012_001564_000204_0004.jpg" n="4" xml:id="d2e238"/>
            <p>but we will have to bare It  I will have to bring my few Lins to a close I told You I would write as often as I could and I am going to do It and I want you to do the same  write and send your letter to <choice><orig><name type="place">Greenville</name></orig><corr resp="pw"><name type="place">Greeneville</name></corr></choice> and It will come to the regment give my Respects to all of the family.</p>
            <p>good by<lb/>
               Your affectionate husband<lb/>
               R A Ragan</p>
            <p>Oh that this war would end And I could return to my home And the balance of my days I will spend Let them be Short or Long</p>
            <p>I want You to write me whether you got all of them things I sent you  I am going to send you 50 cts mone in silver.  I want you to take care of it I have not drawed any money yet but I will before Long.  I rote this letter a few days ago and Last night Robert Kelly &amp; Georg Fresh &amp; Peat Lovett came up But Debusk never came.  I thought you owt to Rote to me  tel Debusk to come</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
