<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000060_000355_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter, <name>V.B.M.</name> in Baltimore, Md., to J.G.M.
Ramsey, near Knoxville, Tenn. <date when="1824-07-20">1824 July 20</date>
            </title>
            <author>
               <name type="person">V. B. M.</name>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>Dyson-Smith, Bridger</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_000060_000355_0000</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more information,
            contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special Collections
                Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Letter, 1824, July 20, V.B.M. in Baltimore, Md., to J.G.M. Ramsey near Knoxville, Tenn. </title>
               <date>1824-07-20</date>
               <author>
                  <name>V. B. M.</name>
               </author>
               <extent>4 digital images; 4 pages.</extent>
               <note type="abstract">1824, July 20, V.B.M., Baltimore, Md., to J.G.M. Ramsey, near Knoxville, Tenn. Expresses the writer&apos;s interest in history of the Mecklenburg Convention and gives advice on how best to record history. Also features a discussion of books. Encloses a sermon by the Rev. Mr. Duncan (missing) and discusses Rev. Duncan&apos;s admirable but controversial methods.</note>
               <note type="collection">J.G.M. Ramsey Papers 1790-1869</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS.253</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee Libraries
                Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
                omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Historians -- Maryland -- Baltimore -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Authors, American -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Preaching -- Maryland -- Baltimore -- History -- 19th century. </term>
               <term>Mecklenburg County (N.C.) -- History -- 18th century.</term>
               <term>North Carolina -- History -- 18th century -- Biography -- Sources.</term>
               <term>Ramsey, J. G. M. (James Gettys McGready), 1797-1884 -- Correspondence.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-10-02" who="bds">Migrating from
                XML to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter" xml:id="d3e152">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_000060_000355_0001.jpg" xml:id="d3e153"/>
            <p>Baltimore July 20, 1824</p>
            <p>Dear Sir,</p>
            <p>In my last I dwelt pretty largely upon our old theme, &quot;the Presidential Election - And if you thought
too largely, attribute it to an anxiety that men generally, and you in particular, should have an accurate judgement
on a Subject of Such immence importance, to our country, to the world at large, to ourselves, and to posterity - That
my exertions are attended with <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">sucess</unclear>, however that may be ardently
wished, is to me, not the great matter, for the reward is, not as to the efforts, but &quot;according to the
labour&quot; - one may plant and another may water, but the glory of the increase belongs still to another - Thus
much for the present, on the old subject - </p>
            <p>I have not been inattentive to your request touching the Mecklinburg Declaration - but I regret having to inform
you, that my research, as yet, has been productive of nothing important - Niles&apos; Register from No. 1 to the
last published No. has been examined, and I am not able to find any thing relation to the Subject - I regret this, not
solely that it will be a disappointment to you, but also, that I am thusly deprived of the pleasure of contributing
somewhat, towards elucidating a matter, so interesting to the true patriot - I could wish to be intimately
conversant with the history of every individual man, concerned in the American Revolution - Not only acquainted
with their actions but the operation of their hearts during <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">those</unclear>
trying times - And by the way, <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">I would</unclear>
            </p>
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_000060_000355_0002.jpg" xml:id="d3e175"/>
            <p>remark that he comes far short of a true historian who, forgetting, or thinking it of little importance, to
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">record</unclear> the secret springs, and to trace out, with <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">discernment</unclear> of a philospher, and the accuracy of an adept, the
first conception, through the labyrinths and <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">anfractuosities</unclear> of
the human mind, until it becomes <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">embodied</unclear> in words, or is made
tangible by their doings; &amp; only aspires to be a chronicle of events as <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">presinted</unclear> to the eye - I know that you in your account of the Mecklinburg Declaration,
will penetrate deeper than the surface - and present to view as will the intellectual and moral process as the
event as left upon record - Thence my anxiety to see your production - There is encouragement for you to
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">proceed</unclear> in the work, in the consideration, that it will show
to the world, that the opposition to tyranny and oppression, then manifested, was not a spark lit up, entirely,
by the denunciations of the assembled wisdom &amp; patriotism of the &quot;Continental Congress&quot;, but that it
was a feeling, principle I would rather say, intuitive in the American bosom, and which shone forth with
exceeding splendour, at numerous places in the country, without the aid of a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">preconcent</unclear> - And our <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">enemies</unclear>, if any
we have, will learn therefrom, the fact, that if <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">it is necessary</unclear>
for the whole mass to be tainted, before the ship will be given up - That to be shorn of our locks, however much
they may add to our beauty, is not sufficient, for that our strength is dispersed throughout, and extended to
every member of the body politic - And that that strength is felt there - </p>
            <p>Augt 2d Scott&apos;s late novel &quot;Redgauntlett&quot; was published here on Saturday last, - I have not read
it - but if you can form an idea of the incidents of the work from the title, it is more than many others can - - I
have said Scotts novel</p>
            <pb n="3" facs="0012_000060_000355_0003.jpg" xml:id="d3e213"/>
            <p>for I do not know why we should have any doubt about that matter, when there appears to be no doubt (or
good information) among his immediate neighbours as to the circumstances - True Sir W. has survived some of the
Waverly family, but this no doubt was only <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">move effectivally</unclear> to
blind the puclick; besides, I am informed, however improper it may be, that this is not their first instance
of the kind, that has occured in Edinburg, of an author reviewing his own production - So that fact is no longer
of any value, as evidence of his not being the author - &quot;The actor of <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Bailie Jarvis</unclear>, one of the characters in Rob Roy, recd. a present of <gap resp="Dyson-Smith"/> guineas
in a note signed <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Jed. Cleishbottom</unclear>, as a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">mark</unclear>
               <gap resp="Dyson-Smith"/> his approbation, and it is pretty well known that
the note came from the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">desk</unclear> of the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">sipious</unclear>&quot;</p>
            <p>
               <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Grisom&apos;s Year in Europe</unclear>
            </p>
            <p>To the author, be him who he may, my individual thanks are due, not only for the source of amusement his
works have been to me, but they have had the effect of disgusting me with all other novel writers ancient or
modern, with a few exceptions - This I consider quite a happy circumstance - There may be some of the
&quot;blue stocking&quot; <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">familys</unclear> who would think me
more happy were they given up in toto - Inform them, if you know any people who come under that description,
that I would have no objection to try the experiment, provided they would, first, procure for me some other
employment, to fill up the time, now devoted to that <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">species</unclear>
of reading, that will be equally innocent and amusing - </p>
            <p>Griscom&apos;s Year in Europe&quot; - A journal of a tour in Europe occupying the space of a year, by Professor
Griscom, of New York, a member of the Society of Friends, published the latter part of last year, and which
I have just read, I found to please me very much - I send you herewith a Sermon by the Revd. Mr. Duncan of
this place - the title page will inform you on what occasion it was preached - I consider Mr. Duncan - the
most powerful preacher of the Gospel I ever heard - And my <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">over</unclear>
            </p>
            <pb n="4" facs="0012_000060_000355_0004.jpg" xml:id="d3e258"/>
            <p>opportunity of judging has not been very slight for I have been a pretty constant bearer of his, since
1814 abating the time I was in thhe <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">west</unclear> - There <gap resp="Dyson-Smith"/>
an unhappy controversy between Mr Duncan, and some of the members of his <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">sission</unclear> and congregation, going on for some time - It is thought that, Mr D. is
too liberal in his opposition of the Gospel, and not paying sufficient deference to the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">ascensions</unclear>, of some of the &quot;Fathers&quot; of the
Presbyterian Church Such as Calvin - and the ministers who composed the famed Westminster Assembly
&amp;c, Mr D&apos;s course differs somewhat from that of the generality of preaching <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">principally</unclear> in this subject - he takes any of the books
of the N. Testament, and from the beginning goes on with his exposition until the book is gone
through - <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">generall</unclear> establishing his view of the Subject
from other portions of the Scriptures - always referring to the Bible, as authority, paramount to that
of confissions or cruds, reason, experience, or the opinions of men, however profound they are, or may
have been; thinking himself, aided by the Spirit of his office, as capable of a fair and just exposition
as any of them - Is it not (do you judge), too commonly the case, that ministers of the Gospel, take up
some of the doctrines found in the system of theology taught them at the Schools, and searching out
passages of Scripture, through which a coincidence of doctrine is found to run, and taking up such
passages as their texts, deducing from the whole, the very doctrines, found at the commencement of
their course, and which is oftentimes the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">caption</unclear>
itsilf - you will be able to understand Mr Duncan much better from the perusel of his sermon, than
from any description of mine - You see my paper is full, and the post <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">horn&apos;s</unclear> blowing, altho I break off leaving half that I have to say
unsaid - </p>
            <p>V.B.M.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
