<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000074_000200_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter, <name>
John Watkins
</name>
in Knoxville, Tenn., to John Probert in Pittsfield, Ohio,
<date when="1863-09-25">
1863 September 25
</date>
            </title>
            <author>
               <name type="person">Watkins, John</name>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>Hogan, Josh</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_000074_000200_0000</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more information,
            contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special Collections
                Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Letter, John Watkins in Knoxville, Tenn. to John Probert in Pittsfield, Ohio, 1863 September 25</title>
               <date>1863-09-25</date>
               <author>
                  <name>Watkins, John</name>
               </author>
               <extent>5 digital images; 5 pages</extent>
               <note type="abstract">In this letter, dated September 25, 1863, from John Watkins in Knoxville, Tenn. to John Probert in Pittsfield, Ohio, Watkins describes in some detail his march with the 19th Ohio Battery from Crab Orchard, Kentucky to Knoxville. He also discusses a march against Confederate forces at Cumberland Gap and the subsequent return to Knoxville. </note>
               <note type="collection">The John Watkins Papers, 1863</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS.1161</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee Libraries
                Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
                omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Knoxville (Tenn.) -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-10-02" who="bds">Migrating from
                XML to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter" xml:id="d3e139">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_000074_000200_0001.jpg" xml:id="d3e140"/>
            <p>Mr. John Probert</p>
            <p>Pittsfield, Swain</p>
            <p>Co Ohio</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_000074_000200_0002.jpg" xml:id="d3e152"/>
            <p>Knoxville Tennessee Sept 25th 1863</p>
            <p>Friend John</p>
            <p>I have a little time this afternoon to write you a few lines, and I dont know as I can make any better use of my time than to write you a little of my experience as a soldier in a mountain country, which is I must say altogether different and harder both on men and horses than our Kentucky soldiering was. We never had so long a march as this one was and as for riding that was entirely out of the question for us, unless sick, and such a road as we came over I never heard of before nor never want to hear of again. I dont believe there is another such road in the Confederacy; if there is it ought to be blocked up forever. the last place that we stopped at in Kentucky was Crab Orchard. we left there the 21st day of August. there we commenced walking (the commoners I mean) and we have not got done yet. we marched towards Somerset and made 17 miles the 1st day. the next day the 22nd we marched through Somerset and on to the Cumberland river making 20 miles and over some awful rough and rocky road most all hills up &amp; down. Sunday August 23 we forded the river and of all the hillls I ever went anywheres here was a pair of them. one to get down to the river and the other to get up from it. the engineer corps were working</p>
            <pb n="3" facs="0012_000074_000200_0003.jpg" xml:id="d3e164"/>
            <p>on the both hills in the morning so we did not start out of camp till 8 oclock, and all we done was to cross the river and get up the hill that day. the hill to go up from the river the way were going was about 1 1/2 miles long, and there was two or three places in that it did not seem possible to get up, but by doubling up half of the Battery at a time we go along without any trouble. that is without breaking anything. but to avoid any trouble we got long poles and run them into the guns so as to keep them from sliding of the bank when going around very short turns. we stayed on the hill till about 1/2 past 11 oclock, Monday forenoon the 24th, then marched 6 miles that day and encamped for the night in a big orchard. on the 25th we marched 10 or 12 miles and on account of a little rain that we got in the morning it was quite comfortable traveling. on the 25th we marched till after sundown and crossed the line making 28 miles. here was a place called <unclear reason="Illegible word. Looks like Chesswood or something similar."
                        resp="Josh Hogan">Chesswood</unclear> some 4 or 5 houses around in the woods. stayed there the 27th and 8th, left camp about 6 oclock on the morning of the 29th and marched 28 miles, crossed a little stream called New river. on the morning of the 30th we started about 6 oclock and that day went 15 miles over awful roads, our horses giving out all along the road. Monday the 31st we started at 5 oclock in the morning, marched 15 miles, and went through two places called Montgomery and Wartsburg, the road was very dusty and the weather pretty hot. on the 1st of this</p>
            <pb n="4" facs="0012_000074_000200_0004.jpg" xml:id="d3e175"/>
            <p>we left camp with 8 days rations in our haversacks and knapsacks. we marched 14 miles and began to have better roads having got over the mountains. on the 2nd we stayed in camp till 2 oclock in the afternoon. then started on our direct-south to Knoxville about a 40 miles march for us. we marched till midnight and made 12 miles. on the 3d we left camp about 6 in the morning and marched till 1/2 past 3 in the afternoon. that day we crossed the Clinch river by fording. on the 4th day of Sept we left camp about 4 in the morning just 22 miles from Knoxville. marched till within 5 miles of the place and halted for a lunch. then we started again, got into camp just outside the town about 6 oclock. the Cavalry force marched into the town the day before but the gallant rebels was gone without firing a gun. on the 5th we left camp about noon and marched through town and went into camp on the west side of the town. Sunday the 6th we stayed in camp all day, and about all that I done was to sleep that day, and I guess it was pretty well put in, for on the morning of the 7th (Thursday) we were called up (our section) only about 2 oclock and at 4 we were marched out of camp. for where we did not know for a day or two after, there was only the 44th 104 regiments and Kunkles Battery of 4 guns and our two pieces. that day about noon Burnside and staff came up and I came to the conclusion that there was something in the wind of some importance. we marched 21 or 2 miles and did not get into camp till after dark</p>
            <pb n="5" facs="0012_000074_000200_0005.jpg" xml:id="d3e183"/>
            <p>on the morning of the 8th we got started at 5 oclock, marched till noon, rested an hour and then marched till 10 oclock that night - made 26 miles. on the 9th we left camp at 6 in the morning and marched to within 2 1/2 miles of Cumberland Gap. and there we went into park making about 10 miles. we got there about 11 oclock. Burnside had got there earlier in the morning and gave the rebels till 3 oclock that afternoon to surrender the place, and they done it. on the 10th stayed in camp. on the 11th we started about 6 in the morning on our return. there was not a gun fired at the rebels after we got there. we marched 13 miles the 1st day out. Saturday the 12th we made 19 miles, Sunday 13th 21 miles and Monday the 14th we marched into Knoxville again, making the 8th day out of camp and 120 miles travel, and what a looking set of horses we had. what few we had left were on there last pegs, and we had 8 mules hitched in the teams if it had not been for them I dont know when we should have got back from there, on the, from the 15th till the 19th we stayed in camp. on the 19th we moved over to the east side of town and have been here since. I tell you what we have had a pretty busy time and some of the time pretty rough and hard, but I have been well and hearty all the while. and I hope this will find you all the same, little one and all. give my respects to all the boys, and except the same for yourself. </p>
            <p>write soon, and direct to Knoxville</p>
            <p>Tennessee, care of Capt Jos. C. Shields 19th</p>
            <p>Ohio Battery, 1st Brigade 3d division 23d Army Corps</p>
            <p>Yours truly,</p>
            <p>John</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>