<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_002414_000305_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Report,
					<name>Jacob Shaltz, William Poyntell, John Large</name>
				                    in City, State., to Recipient in City, State., <date when="1807-11-17">1807 Nov. 17</date>
            </title>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>White, Park</name>
            </respStmt>
            <author>
               <name type="person">Jacob Shaltz, William Poyntell, John Large</name>
            </author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <availability status="restricted">
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_002414_000305_0000</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Report, Jacob Shaltz, William Poyntell, John Large in City, State., to Recipient in City, State., 1807 Nov. 17</title>
               <date when="1807-11-17">1807 Nov. 17</date>
               <author>
                  <name type="person">Jacob Shaltz, William Poyntell, John Large</name>
               </author>
               <extent>3 pages</extent>
               <note type="collection">Insurance Company of North America Records, 1792 December 1-1843 February 18</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS.1184</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
						omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Adams, John Quincy, 1767-1848</term>
               <term>Insurance Company of North America.</term>
               <term>Madison, James, 1751-1836</term>
               <term>Morris, Robert, 1734-1806</term>
               <term>Webster, Daniel, 1782-1852</term>
               <term>Insurance companies -- United States.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change who="White, Park">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
         <change when="2013-10-03" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_002414_000305_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e39"/>
            <p>Report</p>
            <p>Committee in Case</p>
            <p>of Woodrapp Sims</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_002414_000305_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e47"/>
            <p>The Committee appointed to enquire into the case of the Ship Woodrapp Sims, Heath Master</p>
            <p>Report</p>
            <p>After due enquiry, and consideration of all the facts that can be ascertained, they are of opinion, that the damage sustained in the
				       first instance, by cutting away a part of the Masts and rigging for the preservation of the People and Cargo after She took ground,
				       is the only proper charge to a general average   This opinion they conceive is supported by the following considerations.</p>
            <p>1st.   Because it appears in testimony that no human efforts could have prevented the ship from grounding somewhere at the time,
				       the direction therefore said to have been given to it, was only a choice of immenent dangers.</p>
            <p>2nd.  Because after She had taken the ground, a considerable intervening time elapsed when it remained doubtful whether She would
				       not be eventually and totally lost, no question therefore could have existed during that period as to the general average embracing
				       any subsequent charges ; such an Idea could only have occurred when the circumstance of her being got on floats was ascertained.</p>
            <p>3rd.   Because the doubtful state of her ultimate preservation existed so long as to occasion the entire breaking up of her intended
				       Voyage and was the cause of a considerable part of her funds being shipped on board other Vessels.  For</p>
            <pb n="3" facs="0012_002414_000305_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e61"/>
            <p>these reasons your Committee thinks that the subsequent expences incurred on the ship, are inadmissable under the claim of general
				       average.</p>
            <p>As regards a question of referrence, your Committee feel some doubts as to the propriety of acquiesence as it would involve a
				       concession of principle in a case that appears to them to be conclusively plain.   If however for the honor of the Office, and to evidence
				       a disposition to meet all questions of claims in a prompt and amicable spirit of accomodation the board should think it advisable to refer,
				       (in case a majority of the Offices concerned agree to the measure,) your Committee respectfully submits the decision to their better
				       Judgement.</p>
            <p>Will. Poyntell</p>
            <p>Jacob Shaltz              } Committee</p>
            <p>John Large</p>
            <p>Insurance Office of No. Ama.</p>
            <p>Nov. 17, 1807.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
