<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000060_000346_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter, <name>Francis A. Ramsey</name> in Swan-Pond, Tenn., to J.G.M. and William Baine Alexander
Ramsey, at Washington College, Tenn. <date when="1815-07-24">1815 July 24</date>
            </title>
            <author>
               <name type="person">Ramsey, Francis A. (Francis Alexander), 1764-1820</name>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>Dyson-Smith, Bridger</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_000060_000346_0000</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more information,
            contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special Collections
                Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Letter, Francis A. Ramsey in Swan-pond, Tenn., to J.G.M. and William Baine Alexander Ramsey at Washington College. 1815 July 24</title>
               <date>1815-07-24</date>
               <author>
                  <name>Ramsey, Francis A. (Francis Alexander), 1764-1820</name>
               </author>
               <extent>4 digital images; 4 pages</extent>
               <note type="abstract">1815 July 24 Francis A. Ramsey, Swan-Pond, Tenn., to his sons, J.G.M. and William Baine Alexander Ramsey, Washington College, Tenn. News of the family&apos;s health and of harvesting wheat. Instruction for the improvement of the boys&apos; handwriting and his expectations of their spiritual development.</note>
               <note type="collection">J.G.M. Ramsey Papers 1790-1869</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS.253</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee Libraries
                Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
                omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Christian ethics -- Tennessee -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Penmanship, American -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Moral exhortation -- History -- 19th century. </term>
               <term>Washington College (Tenn.) -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Ramsey, Francis A. (Francis Alexander), 1764-1820 -- Correspondence.</term>
               <term>Ramsey, J. G. M. (James Gettys McGready), 1797-1884 -- Correspondence.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-10-02" who="bds">Migrating from
                XML to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter" xml:id="d3e157">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_000060_000346_0001.jpg" xml:id="d3e158"/>
            <p>James G. My. Ramsey</p>
            <p>Student at Washington College Tennessee</p>
            <p>By the politeness of Squire Brown.</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_000060_000346_0002.jpg" xml:id="d3e170"/>
            <p>Swan-pond July 24th 1815</p>
            <p>My Dear Sons</p>
            <p>thro the kindness of indulgent Providence we are all yet alive, tho Ma &amp; Grand Pa - both complain
almost dayly - I believe your Ma and Uncle Samuel will go next week to the Yellow Spring at the head of Little
Pigeon - Your Uncle has had a very bad spell for two months past, is now something better and thinks he is
gathering strength, but is still very weak - we have succeeded (with difficulty) in getting in our 
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">gadin</unclear>, wheat began to grow in the shock before it was
got out of the field; I have this morning began to cut the meadow but I am still afraid we shall have wet
weather, upwards of four weeks we have had rain almost every day and the weather yet appears
unsettled - </p>
            <p>we have had one letter from your Uncle <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Caldwelle</unclear> dated
the 20th of June, all were then well, we have had no other word from Carolina Friends but the letter
from <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Winslow</unclear> that accompanies this - I have got Mr Brown
to engage to call upon you - he can give you neighborhood news - </p>
            <p>we were very much grateful in hearing from you by your first letter, as we had not heard the
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">least</unclear> account from you, since we parted with you, and
were <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">getting</unclear>
            </p>
            <pb n="3" facs="0012_000060_000346_0003.jpg" xml:id="d3e200"/>
            <p>
               <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">getterig</unclear> very uneasy to know your situation, I think
my son James you ought not to write so small and so cramp a hand as you do - If you were to accustom your self
to write a longer hand, your writing would appear better and more masculine than it does - Billy my son, you
ought to write to me or some of us, to keep you in practice, and to improve your diction and writing, make
your letter large and fair, and dont allow your self to fall in to a careless and indifferent habit,
but strive to improve by every epistle you write be particularly attentive to your spelling, to the
grammatical construction of your words and to the forming of your letters, these may be
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">denomise</unclear> both learned and elegant accomplishments, and
they will always be expected from both of you.</p>
            <p>your sister is now at school with Mr <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Nelson</unclear> your Cousin
Jane is in town, I believe she intends going to school to learn drawing, Jane is really a fine woman
posessing some of the greatest &amp; best accomplishments - </p>
            <p>My Dear Sons there is one thing needful, see that you be not negligent or baseless as to the
attainment <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">of it</unclear>
            </p>
            <pb n="4" facs="0012_000060_000346_0004.jpg" xml:id="d3e222"/>
            <p>For what is a man profited if he should gain the whole world, and lose his own soul, or what
will a man give in exchange for his Soul? my dear sons earnestly, constantly and fervantly strive
to possess that better part which cannot be take away</p>
            <p>give me joy and not grief concerning you - Tell young Mr. Doak that in consequence of a
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Sacrament</unclear> at Bakers Creek, one at Poplar Creek,
and one at Washington, Mr <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Nelson</unclear> could not make
an appointment to administer a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Sacrament</unclear> at the
Fork - But if Mr Doak would himself appoint <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">a time</unclear>
when he could attend, and give two or three weeks notice before hand Mr Nelson would certainly
attend here with him - </p>
            <p>My Sons I konw not of any thing else to write that you would have any curiosity to know, be
careful to miss no opportunity of writing to some of us, as it refreshes us greatly to hear from
you</p>
            <p>May that God who has hitherto preserved you, Still have you in his Holy keeping, and Preserve
you from every false, wicked, and deceitful way is the earnest Prayer of your affectionate
Father.</p>
            <p>F.A. Ramsey</p>
            <p>To J.G.My. &amp; <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">ppn</unclear> B.A. Ramsey</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>