<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_001560_000200_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>
               <name>Henry R. Pippitt</name> Diary, <date from="1862-09" to="1863-05-19">1862 September 18-1863 May 19</date>
            </title>
            <author>
               <name type="person">Pippitt, Henry R.</name>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>Deane, Christine H.</name>
               <name>Dyson-Smith, Bridger</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_001560_000200_0000</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more information,
            contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special Collections
                Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Henry R. Pippitt Diary, 1862 September 18-1863 May 19</title>
               <date>1862 September 18-1863 May 19</date>
               <author>
                  <name>Pippitt, Henry R.</name>
               </author>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee Libraries
                Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
                omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Civil War Diaries</term>
               <term>Pippitt, Henry, 1842-1927 -- Diaries</term>
               <term>United States. Army. Ohio Infantry Regiment, 104th (1862-1865)
              Company G.</term>
               <term>United States. Army. Ohio Infantry Regiment, 104th (1862-1865) --
              Personal narratives.</term>
               <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Regimental
              histories.</term>
               <term>Ohio -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Regimental
              histories.</term>
               <term>Fort Mitchell (Ky.)</term>
               <term>Frankfurt (Ky.)</term>
               <term>Danville (Ky.)</term>
               <term>Richmond (Ky.)</term>
               <term>Blue Ridge Mountains.</term>
               <term>Gilmore, Quincy Adams, 1825-1888.</term>
               <term>Reilly, James William, 1828-1905.</term>
               <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Hospitals.</term>
               <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Military
              life.</term>
               <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Campaigns &amp;
              battles.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-10-03" who="bds">Migrating from
                XML to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="diary" xml:id="d4e160">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_001560_000200_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e161"/>
            <p>H. R. Pippitt</p>
            <p>Salem, Ohio</p>
            <p>
               <gap  resp="Deane"/>
            </p>
            
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_001560_000200_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e176"/>
            <p>Th. Sep. 18th 1862. Left Fort Mitchel at<unclear reason="illegible" resp="R.M.">5:00</unclear>p.m. marched miles camped in the Florance fair ground</p>
            <p>Fr. Sep. 19th 1862. Marched with a force of 5000, did not overtake them but camped in
          their quarters</p>
            <p>S. Sep. 20th 1862. Pursued them<gap  resp="Deane"/>; still two hours in advance. Camped at
          Grittendon</p>
            <p>Sn. Sep. 21st 1862. Could not overtake them and retreated back 12 miles.<gap  resp="Deane"/>in for the
          night</p>
            
            <pb n="3" facs="0012_001560_000200_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e200"/>
            <p>M. Sep. 22nd 1862. Lay at camp near Walton nothing exciting</p>
            <p>T Sep 23rd 1862. Called up at two o&apos;clock in the morning to fire<gap  resp="Deane"/>for battle; but
          nothing took place</p>
            <p>Wedn. Sep 24th 1862. Nothing of interest</p>
            <p>Thurs Sep 25th 1862. Song roll beat at ten a.m. no fighting done. The<unclear reason="illegible" resp="R.M.">18</unclear>Michigan had fifty one men taken prisoner;
          give up without firing a gun</p>
            <p>Frid. Sep 26th 1862. Lay at camp near Walton nothing of interest</p>
            <p>Sat Sep 27th 1862. On picket-duty; but no firing on our lines</p>
            <p>Sun. Sep 28th 1862. No important movements</p>
            <p>Mon. Sep 29th 1862. Use water out of a<gap  resp="Deane"/>pond which has a grain service on it
          something<gap  resp="Deane"/>than an eigthth of an inch thick</p>
            
            <pb n="4" facs="0012_001560_000200_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e235"/>
            <p>Tues Sep 30th 1862.<gap  resp="Deane"/>an alarm was given<gap  resp="Deane"/>double quicked into camp &amp;<unclear reason="illegible" resp="R.M.">fanned</unclear> in line of battle; it was false
          alarm</p>
            <p>Wednesday Oct 1st 1862. Ordered out on picket some firing along the lines; one of our men
          wounded in the leg</p>
            <p>Thursday Oct 2nd 1862. Nothing of interest took place</p>
            <p>Friday Oct 3rd 1862. I was ellected as cook. it rained hard until noon. Had a miserable
          time getting dinner</p>
            <p>Saturday Oct 4th 1862. Moved the nine prisoners to<gap  resp="Deane"/>to have their trile</p>
            <p>Sunday Oct 5th 1862. Went on picket at one p.m. All went off right Were ordered to march
          at four oclock monday morning; left according to orders</p>
            
            <pb n="5" facs="0012_001560_000200_0005.jpg" xml:id="d4e266"/>
            <p>
               <unclear reason="water damage" resp="R.M.">Monday Oct 6th 1862</unclear>
               <gap  resp="Deane"/>
            </p>
            <p>[Unclear due to water damage.]</p>
            
            <pb n="6" facs="0012_001560_000200_0006.jpg" xml:id="d4e281"/>
            <p>went to bed (all but those who wer out after honey) We had rather a rough night</p>
            <p>Saturday Oct 11th 1862. Had plenty of honey and turkey for break fast. Four of the boys
          wer arrested by the general for stealing potatoes and marched before the Reg. The Band
          played the<gap  resp="Deane"/>for them. I pitied the boys for they did not deserve such treatment</p>
            <p>Sunday Oct 12th 1862. Had Company inspection at ten a.m. and Brigade inspection at half
          past one. no religious service</p>
            <p>Monday Oct 13th 1862. nothing of interest, only one<unclear reason="illegible" resp="R.M.">Butternut</unclear> was<gap  resp="Deane"/>in</p>
            <p>Tuesday Oct 14th 1862. I was guarding a<gap  resp="Deane"/>at Camp Wells. The Regiments wer out on
          Brigade drill</p>
            
            <pb n="7" facs="0012_001560_000200_0007.jpg" xml:id="d4e309"/>
            <p>Wednesday Oct 15th 1862. Ordered out on picket; posted on a hill; when laying down had to
          secure our boot-heels firmly in the ground in order to keep our position</p>
            <p>Thursday Oct 16th 1862. Marched sixteen miles south on the Sesington Pike and halted in a
          place where there was not room to turn a four hors team &amp; no water; had a trip of two
          &amp; a half to get water to make coffee</p>
            <p>Friday Oct 17th 1862. Saying still resting to be ready to march on the morrow</p>
            <p>Saturday Oct 18th 1862. Still laying at Camp Wilder<gap  resp="Deane"/>, waiting orders</p>
            <p>Sunday Oct 19th 1862. on a march as advance guards reached Big Eagle Creek at four
          Oclock, Say there untill twelve Oclock that night then left for Georgetown</p>
            <p>Monday oct 20th 1862. reached Georgetown a distance of 12 miles in</p>
            
            <pb n="8" facs="0012_001560_000200_0008.jpg" xml:id="d4e333"/>
            <p>four hours march, the citizens wer truly glad to see us; found plenty of water; lay
          untill twelve that night then started for Sesuington</p>
            <p>Tuesday Oct 21st 1862. reached Sesington at daylight recieved many news for the Union
          took up quarters in the farm ground. The General left us without a guard &amp; upon our
          honor not to leave all stayed but Capts Bainy Stevil, &amp; Sturgeon, a guard was then put
          in to catch them, &amp; we did</p>
            <p>Wednesday Oct 22nd 1862. Moved our Camp Riverside to the east pitched tents &amp; it
          seemed more like living</p>
            <p>Thursday Oct 23rd 1862. Regular drill. I was<gap  resp="Deane"/> to do my washing. Capt Bainy
          challeneged the Colonel to come out as a citizen &amp; fight him. He would not</p>
            <p>Friday Oct 24th 1862. All fixed up in our best &amp; marched round Sesington, there are
          some very fine buildings</p>
            
            <pb n="9" facs="0012_001560_000200_0009.jpg" xml:id="d4e354"/>
            <p>, but the inhabitants put me in mind of the devirion of land &amp; water on the globe;
          one fourth white and three fourths black; got back at noon, took dinner</p>
            <p>Saturday Oct 25th 1862. At Camp near Sesington it rained all day &amp; in the Eve- began
          to snow</p>
            <p>Sunday Oct 26th 1862. The morning came forth &amp; the ground was covered six inches deep
          with snow the like was never known before in<gap  resp="Deane"/>. At 8 Oclock we wer called out to go on
          picket.</p>
            <p>Monday Oct 27th 1862. It was very pleasant and the snow passed rapidly. Wer released at 8
          Oclock</p>
            <p>Tuesday Oct 28th 1862. The snow has disappeared and is quite plesant</p>
            <p>Wednesday Oct 29th 1862. Brigade Review by orders of General Gilmore</p>
            
            <pb n="10" facs="0012_001560_000200_0010.jpg" xml:id="d4e378"/>
            <p>Thursday Oct 30th 1862. Regular drill Two hours in the morning and Batallion drill at two
          p.m</p>
            <p>Friday Oct 31st 1862. Brigade Review by orders of General D.A. Gilmore</p>
            <p>Saturday Nov 1st 1862. Regimental inspection of all our equipage by order of Col. James
          Relly</p>
            <p>Sunday Nov 2nd 1862. Company inspection in the morning, and nothing of interest the rest
          of the day</p>
            <p>Monday Nov 3rd 1862. Moved our camp one quarter of a mile; aside of the fair ground</p>
            <p>Tuesday Nov 4th 1862. Regular drill. Nothing of interest</p>
            <p>Wednesday Nov 5th 1862. Regimental inspection General Judas Afternon<unclear reason="illegible" resp="R.M.">new cuts</unclear>for the tents. Eve got the bell<unclear reason="illegible" resp="R.M.">tins</unclear>
            </p>
            
            <pb n="11" facs="0012_001560_000200_0011.jpg" xml:id="d4e407"/>
            <p>Thursday Nov 6th 1862. Nothing of interest. Regular drill</p>
            <p>Friday Nov 7th 1862. Regular drill in forenoon and Batallion in the afternoon</p>
            <p>Saturday Nov 8th 1862. Nothing of interest</p>
            <p>Sunday Nov 9th 1862. Review in the morning and religious service at five Oclock</p>
            <p>Monday Nov 10th 1862. Regular drill in the forenoon and Batallion drill in the
          afternoon</p>
            <p>Tuesday Nov 11th 1862. Went on a reconnoisance tour and found a Cave twenty feet high,
          fourteen wide and fifty-feet back pathed with stone by nature</p>
            <p>Wednesday Nov 12th 1862. Squad drill, nothing of interest</p>
            
            <pb n="12" facs="0012_001560_000200_0012.jpg" xml:id="d4e432"/>
            <p>Thursday Nov 13 1862. Regimental inspection. Give us praise for our clenliness</p>
            <p>Friday Nov 14th 1862. Squad drill in the morning and Company drill in the afternoon</p>
            <p>Saturday Nov 15 1862. Regular drill</p>
            <p>Sunday Nov 16th 1862. Sunday inspection in the morning and religious service at two
          oclock</p>
            <p>Monday Nov 17th 1862. It drizzled rain all day. We received our new Endfield rifles which
          are good and reliable</p>
            <p>Tuesday Nov 18th 1862. It rained all day</p>
            <p>Wednesday Nov 19th 1862. Nothing of interest</p>
            <p>Thursday Nov 20th 1862. Regular drill, new order issued to call the roll seven times a
          day</p>
            
            <pb n="13" facs="0012_001560_000200_0013.jpg" xml:id="d4e458"/>
            <p>Friday Nov 21st 1862. Squad drill in the forenoon and Batalion drill in the afternoon</p>
            <p>Saturday Nov 22nd 1862. A very pleasant day; had a general cleaning up of cloths removed
          of tents etc.</p>
            <p>Sunday Nov 23rd 1862. Inspection at ten Oclock and church at two</p>
            <p>Monday Nov 24th 1862. A very pleasant day. Nothing but regular drill</p>
            <p>Tuesday Nov 25th 1862. Squad drill in the fornoon and officers drill in the afternoon</p>
            <p>Wednesday Nov 26th 1862. Skermish drill in the fornoon and batalion drill in the
          afternoon</p>
            <p>Thursday Nov 27th 1862. Regular drill, at eight Oclock at night we received orders to be
          ready for review at eight O. in the morning</p>
            
            <pb n="14" facs="0012_001560_000200_0014.jpg" xml:id="d4e482"/>
            <p>Friday Nov 28th 1862. Grand review at the appointed time and the 104th for the second
          time took the ribbons</p>
            <p>Saturday Nov 29th 1862. General cleaning up of tents, Camp<unclear reason="illegible" resp="R.M.">groung</unclear>etc</p>
            <p>Sunday Nov 30th 1862. Camping inspection in the morning. It rained the rest of the
          day</p>
            <p>Monday Dec 1st 1862. Regular drill. Nothing of interest</p>
            <p>Tuesday Dec 2nd 1862. Regular drill.</p>
            <p>Wednesday Dec 3rd 1862. Squad drill in the morning and Batallion drill in the
          afternoon</p>
            <p>Thursday Dec 4th 1862. Regular drill, nothing of importance</p>
            <p>Friday Dec 5th 1862. Slipped in with the city guards and went to visit the sentry</p>
            <p>Saturday Dec 6 1862. General Camp cleaning, a rather a blustery day</p>
            
            <pb n="15" facs="0012_001560_000200_0015.jpg" xml:id="d4e513"/>
            <p>Sunday Dec 7th 1862. Camp &amp; Company inspection, Very calm and cold day</p>
            <p>Monday Dec 8th 1862. Regular drill</p>
            <p>Tuesday Dec 9th 1862. A very pleasant day. Nothing transpired of interest</p>
            <p>Wednesday Dec 10th 1862. Aroused at two oclock in the morning to march. We are marching
          under cealed orders. Advanced nine mile where we could see the Blue Ridge Mountains which
          was a beautiful sight. Advanced forteen miles from Sesington and Camped on the banks of
          Kentucky River; which is a very rough and hilly part of the country</p>
            <p>Thursday Dec 11th 1862. Arose at two Oclock; Some of the Reg forded the river;<unclear reason="illegible" resp="R.M.">Onrs</unclear>crossed on the ferry Boats; marched twelve
          miles and camped at Richmond. We wer tired Boys</p>
            
            <pb n="16" facs="0012_001560_000200_0016.jpg" xml:id="d4e535"/>
            <p>Friday Dec 12th 1862. Lay in Camp at Richmond. No drill; we all rested</p>
            <p>Saturday Dec 13th 1862. Picked up traps and moved to the opposite side of town a distance
          of one mile.</p>
            <p>Sunday Dec 14th 1862. Policed the camp struck out the entrenchments. Religious service at
          two Oclock</p>
            <p>Monday Dec 15th 1862. Commenced the breast works at Richmond Kentucky</p>
            <p>Tuesday Dec 16th 1862. Working on the Breastworks. No drill at all.</p>
            <p>Wednesday Dec 17th 1862. A new order issued allowing all men on duty a gill of whiskey a
          day. Still on the Breastworks</p>
            <p>Thursday Dec 18th 1862. Still at work on the breast works</p>
            
            <pb n="17" facs="0012_001560_000200_0017.jpg" xml:id="d4e559"/>
            <p>Friday Dec 19th 1862. Continuation of the Breastworks</p>
            <p>Saturday Dec 20th 1862. Part of the breastworks are completed.</p>
            <p>Sunday Dec 21st 1862. No inspection<unclear reason="illegible" resp="R.M.">nos</unclear>
          duty of any<unclear reason="illegible" resp="R.M.">Kind</unclear> The first Sunday off of
          duty since enlistment.</p>
            <p>Monday Dec 22nd 1862. This Childs birthday. Very warm and pleasant day</p>
            <p>Tuesday Dec 23rd 1862. Still at work on the fortification</p>
            <p>Wednesday Dec 24th 1862. Continuation of the fortification</p>
            <p>Thursday Dec 25th 1862. Christmas at work in the Breastworks. I spent part of my time in
          Richmond. It was rather dry for me</p>
            <p>Friday Dec 26 1862. Rained most of the day and at night overflowed some of the tents</p>
            
            <pb n="18" facs="0012_001560_000200_0018.jpg" xml:id="d4e591"/>
            <p>Saturday Dec 27th 1862. Continuation of the Breast Works</p>
            <p>Sunday Dec 28th 1862. Sunday Inspection</p>
            <p>Monday Dec 29th 1862. Left Richmond for Danville; marched twenty miles<gap  resp="Deane"/>for the
          night<gap  resp="Deane"/>
            </p>
            <p>Tuesday Dec 30th 1862.<gap  resp="Deane"/>at five Oclock in the morning and ended the march (a distance
          of twenty two miles)<gap  resp="Deane"/>ten miles<gap  resp="Deane"/>
            </p>
            <p>Wednesday Dec 31st 1862. Lay in Camp at Danville for the afternoon. Wer mustered for
          pay.</p>
            <p>Thursday Jan 1st 1863. Lay at Camp near Danville. rather a dry New years</p>
            <p>Friday Jan 2nd 1863. Nothing of interest</p>
            <p>Saturday Jan 3rd 1863. drew rations in the morning &amp; Batallion drill in the
          afternoon</p>
            <p>Sunday Jan 4th 1863. Inspection at ten in the morning &amp; preparing for a<unclear reason="illegible" resp="R.M.">mus</unclear>
               <gap  resp="Deane"/>
            </p>
            
            <pb n="19" facs="0012_001560_000200_0019.jpg" xml:id="d4e630"/>
            <p>Monday Jan 5th 1863. Left Danville for Frankfort. The first day we marched 22 miles &amp;
          camped by the side of the road</p>
            <p>Tuesday Jan 6th 1863. Renewed the march before day; it rained &amp; I got a perfect
          soaking. Camped by the road side the second day</p>
            <p>Wednesday Jan 7th 1863. Left before day for Frankfort a distance of 5 miles &amp; camped
          two miles on the opposite side of town</p>
            <p>Thursday Jan 8th 1863. Got our tents pitched and felt ourselves at home once more</p>
            <p>Friday Jan 9th 1863. Policed the ground and then rested the remainder of the day</p>
            <p>Saturday Jan. 10 1863. Nothing of interest no duty whatever</p>
            <p>Sunday Jan 11 1863. Grand review by orders of General Gilmore</p>
            <p>Monday Jan 12th 1863. Commenced drilling for the first in this Camp</p>
            
            <pb n="20" facs="0012_001560_000200_0020.jpg" xml:id="d4e655"/>
            <p>Tuesday Jan 13th 1863. Company E &amp; J went on an escort to a funeral of Lieutenant
          Colonel belonging to the 12th Ky Calvary</p>
            <p>Wednesday 14th 1863. It rained all night and at five o’clock in the morning it drown us
          out</p>
            <p>Thursday Jan 15th 1863. Rained and snowed all day. The snow fell eighteen inches deep</p>
            <p>Friday Jan 16th 1863. Clean and cold. We policed the quarters</p>
            <p>Saturday Jan 17th 1863. Clean and cold. The snow to deep to be on duty</p>
            <p>Sunday Jan 18th 1863. Nothing but snow to be seen</p>
            <p>Monday Jan 19th 1863. It moderated</p>
            <p>Tuesday Jan 20th 1863. It began to rain</p>
            <p>Wednesday Jan 21st 1863. The snow is going fast</p>
            
            <pb n="21" facs="0012_001560_000200_0021.jpg" xml:id="d4e683"/>
            <p>Thursday Jan 22nd 1863. Snow still leaving</p>
            <p>Friday Jan 23rd 1863.<unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">Donate</unclear> pleasant
          and warm</p>
            <p>Saturday Jan 24th 1863. The mud is dride up and the weather very pleasant</p>
            <p>Sunday Jan 25th 1863. Company inspection nothing of interest. Mr. Turner called to see
          me</p>
            <p>Monday Jan 26th 1863. Very rainy and wet</p>
            <p>Tuesday Jan 27th 1863. It ceased raining and began to snow</p>
            <p>Wednesday Jan 28th 1863. The day was clear and cold</p>
            <p>Thursday Jan 29th 1863. Went to Frankfort Ky went through the<unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">penipoteniny</unclear>There are 260 convvets within</p>
            <p>Friday Jan 30th 1863. Nothing of interest</p>
            <p>Saturday Jan 31st. Shooting target</p>
            
            <pb n="22" facs="0012_001560_000200_0022.jpg" xml:id="d4e719"/>
            <p>Sunday Feb 1st 1863. Rained all day</p>
            <p>Monday Feb 2nd. Largest shooting</p>
            <p>Tuesday Feb 3rd 1863. Clear and very cold</p>
            <p>Wednesday Feb 4th 1863. Cold and clear</p>
            <p>Thursday Feb 5th 1863. Moderated</p>
            <p>Friday Feb 6th 1863. Thawed and gal quite sleeky</p>
            <p>Saturday Feb 7th 1863. Rained all day</p>
            <p>Sunday Feb 8th 1863. Cold and cloudy. Inspection as usual</p>
            <p>Tuesday Feb 10th 1863. Clear and pleasant</p>
            <p>Wednesday Feb 11th 1863. Moderated</p>
            <p>Thursday Feb 12th 1863. Damp and drisling</p>
            <p>Friday Feb 13th 1863. Rained irregular intervals</p>
            <p>Saturday Feb 14th 1863. Rained all day</p>
            
            <pb n="23" facs="0012_001560_000200_0023.jpg" xml:id="d4e756"/>
            <p>Sunday Feb 15th 1863. Sunday inspection. The weather quite favorable</p>
            <p>Monday Feb 16th 1863. The<gap  resp="Deane"/> pleasant</p>
            <p>Tuesday Feb 17th 1863. Wet and rainy</p>
            <p>Wednesday Feb 18th 1863. The weather pleasant</p>
            <p>Thursday Feb 19 1863. Wet and rainy and in the East rained and drowned us out</p>
            <p>Friday Feb 20th 1863. Wet and mud to all<unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">rivr</unclear>
            </p>
            <p>Saturday Feb 21st 1863. Struck tents and marched. It began to snow and sleet. We marched
          ten miles by that time we were completely sleeted with snow. We camped in the military
          academy situated on the road from Frankfort to Danville</p>
            <p>Sunday Feb 22nd 1863. Marched before day it still snowed. We marched five miles and then
          got breakfast at a little town by the name of rough and ready. We passed through farm
          towns before we reached our destination. The towns were Lawrenceburgh, Palvica and
          Paldanado. We then reached Harrodsburgh where we camped in the Old Soldiers home. We
          marched thirty miles that day. I shall ever remember Washingtons Birthday and that days
          marched</p>
            
            <pb n="24" facs="0012_001560_000200_0024.jpg" xml:id="d4e786"/>
            <p>Monday Feb 23rd 1863. Left Harrodsburgh for Danville a distance of ten miles reached
          Danville about noon. We were<unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">lind</unclear>
          Boys</p>
            <p>Tuesday Feb 24th 1863. In camp all in good spirits. Trusting we will get rested and then
          will be for any ease of emergency</p>
            <p>Wednesday Feb 25th. At Camp near Danville. The day is clear and pleasant</p>
            
            <pb n="25" facs="0012_001560_000200_0025.jpg" xml:id="d4e804"/>
            <p>Thursday Feb 26th 1863. It began to rain in the afternoon and at two o’clock we struck
          tents and moved in to Danville and put up in the Church</p>
            <p>Friday Feb 27th 1863. Still camped in the Presbyterian Church waiting orders</p>
            <p>Saturday Feb 28th 1863. Still in the church. The excitement has gone down. One of Co. A
          men died last night with the heart disease. Left for Lexington at five o’clock went as far
          as Camp Dick Robeson</p>
            <p>Sunday March 1st 1863. Started at four o’clock and reached Lexington at five in the eve a
          distance of 27 miles. Camped in the<unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">Cunn</unclear>
          house</p>
            <p>Monday March 2nd 1863. Moved to the edge of town and camped</p>
            <p>Tuesday March 3rd 1863. Regular drill. Policing and<gap  resp="Deane"/>
            </p>
            
            <pb n="26" facs="0012_001560_000200_0026.jpg" xml:id="d4e830"/>
            <p>Wednesday March 4th 1863. Clear and beautiful day. Regular drill</p>
            <p>Thursday March 5th 1863. Drew rations. It was cold and windy</p>
            <p>Friday March 6th 1863. Wet and rainy. Rained all day</p>
            <p>Saturday March 7th 1863. Rained most of the day one drill as other duty</p>
            <p>Sunday March 8th 1863. Rained all day set almost every thing afloat</p>
            <p>Monday March 9th 1863. Clear and the sun shone all day. Regular drill</p>
            <p>Tuesday March 10th 1863. The weather is clear and the sun shone bright</p>
            <p>Wednesday March 11th 1863. The day clear and a high gale of wind. Regular drill</p>
            <p>Thursday March 12th 1863. High gale of wind. Clear and cold. Regular drill</p>
            <p>Friday March 13th 1863. The day is clear and pleasant. Regular drill</p>
            
            <pb n="27" facs="0012_001560_000200_0027.jpg" xml:id="d4e860"/>
            <p>Saturday March 14th 1863. The sun shone all day. But all<unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">wu</unclear> drill in the afternoon</p>
            <p>Tuesday March 17th 1863. Ordered to march to the Ky river to guard the bridge and
          afterward was countermanded. Regular drill</p>
            <p>Wednesday March 18th 1863. No drill. Policed the camp and in the afternoon went
            and<unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">muoh</unclear> the artillery to see them
          practice shooting target</p>
            <p>Thursday March 19th 1863. The rain off and on all day. General inspection by General
          Easten</p>
            <p>Friday March 20th 1863. Wet and stormy. No drill</p>
            <p>Saturday March 21st 1863. The day is pleasant. Regular drill. Ordered to Danville</p>
            
            <pb n="28" facs="0012_001560_000200_0028.jpg" xml:id="d4e886"/>
            <p>Struck tents at dusk and lay downtown until four o’clock next morning waiting for the
          train. West to Nickolasville on the train a distance of twelve miles from there went to
          Danville on Sunday March 22nd</p>
            <p>Monday March 23 1863. Lay in a church at Danville untille eve then moved one half mile
          north of town and camped for the night</p>
            <p>Tuesday March 24th 1863. Lay until noon and then packed up and retreated. The Rebles in
          the rear skermishing tride to out flank us but we were rather to hot for them. Retreated
          to the Ky river bridge. Camped for the night; it rained all the way on the retreat</p>
            <p>Wednesday March 25th 1863. Lay on the bank by the road until ten o’clock then were
          deployed on the river bank a very romantic place. Lived on the best of ham fell back to
          the wagons in the eve</p>
            
            <pb n="29" facs="0012_001560_000200_0029.jpg" xml:id="d4e903"/>
            <p>Wednesday March 25th 1863. Pitched tents and signed the pay sells</p>
            <p>Thursday March 26th 1863. Marched for Nielolus at four o’clock; reached there in the
          afternoon and drew three days rations in the<unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">laves</unclear> sack</p>
            <p>Friday March 27th 1863. Called up at two o’clock to go back to the river and it was
          raining hard. Away we went reached the bridge where the bank sloped and troops went in to
          Camp Dick Robeson. We reached there a little after dark and pitched tents</p>
            <p>Sunday March 29th 1863. Left Camp Dick Robenson for Lancaster went in to camp</p>
            <p>Monday March 30th 1863. Lay in Camp ordered to pack and load then unload then pack again
          then unload</p>
            <p>Tuesday March 31st 1863. Went to Lancaster hospitle with the measles</p>
            <p>Wednesday April 1st 1863. At the hospitle just covered with<unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">slit</unclear> measles</p>
            
            <pb n="30" facs="0012_001560_000200_0030.jpg" xml:id="d4e933"/>
            <p>Thursday April 2nd 1863. At the hospital and the measles and thick</p>
            <p>Friday April 3rd 1863. At the hospital measles going in; the weather pleasant</p>
            <p>Saturday April 4th 1863. Able to go and find the room</p>
            <p>Sunday April 5th 1863. Still going about</p>
            <p>Monday April 6th 1863. The regiment moved ten mile south of Lancaster and camped in the
          Dick river</p>
            <p>Tuesday April 7th 1863. At the hospital able to run around town</p>
            <p>Wednesday April 8th 1863. Left the hospital and went to the regiment which was at Dick
          river</p>
            <p>Thursday April 9th 1863. Squad drill from 8 to 10 in the forenoon. Redd orders so pack
          and be ready to move. Started at 12 Oclock went two miles and camped adjoining Crab
          Oneland. The 100th and 4th Ohio Battery are encamped here</p>
            
            <pb n="31" facs="0012_001560_000200_0031.jpg" xml:id="d4e959"/>
            <p>Friday April 10th 1863. Company drill in the morning and Battallion in the afternoon. Cap
          Capped sent on his<unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">nesiy</unclear> ration</p>
            <p>Saturday April 11th 1863. No drill this forenoon. Battallion drill this afternoon dress
          parade</p>
            <p>Sunday April 12th 1863. Sunday inspection by Mag. Sterl</p>
            <p>Monday April 13th 1863. Company drill in the morning and Battallion in the afternoon</p>
            <p>Tuesday April 14th 1863. Regular drill</p>
            <p>Wednesday April 15th 1863. Raining this morning. Got orders to march at 6 oclock in the
          morning</p>
            <p>Thursday April 16th 1863. Roll call at 4 Oclock packed for a march. We gave our tents up
          to a Company. The order to move is countermanded. I went to no. 4s bunk</p>
            
            <pb n="32" facs="0012_001560_000200_0032.jpg" xml:id="d4e986"/>
            <p>Friday April 17th 1863. Regular drill</p>
            <p>Saturday April 18th 1863. Marched at 7 Oclock, marched forteen miles over a rough road
          and a miserable country. Camped at two Oclock near Mt. Vernon</p>
            <p>Sunday April 19th 1863. Review by order of Sam Gilbert. Major Sterls horses was stolen by
          some of the citizens. Wes payed for two months</p>
            <p>Monday April 20th 1863. The Majors horses was brought in and also some of the men engages
          in the theft</p>
            <p>Tuesday April 21st 1863. Company drill in the fornoon and Battallion in the afternoon</p>
            <p>Wednesday April 22nd 1863. Regular drill. Rained all night and toward morning drown us
          out</p>
            <p>Thursday April 23rd 1863. The left wing went on a scout down to wildcat B. G. &amp; K
          went</p>
            
            <pb n="33" facs="0012_001560_000200_0033.jpg" xml:id="d4e1010"/>
            <p>Friday April 24th 1863. It is warm and quite lonesome without the Co. I drew rations
          today</p>
            <p>Saturday April 25th 1863. No drill. Policing and cleaning up in general</p>
            <p>Sunday April 26th 1863. Sunday inspection. Preaching at three O by an old 1Ky rather old
          fashioned</p>
            <p>Monday April 27th 1863. Regular drill. I was to see the artillery drill. A prize offered
          for the fastes movements. One section dismounted peace and carriace in thirteen
          seconds</p>
            <p>Tuesday April 28th 1863. Battallion drill to day. It rained and drowned us out in our
          tent</p>
            <p>Wednesday April 29th 1863. Pleasant and warm. Regular drill</p>
            <p>Thursday April 30th 1863. Wer<unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">musterded</unclear>
          to day for two months pay</p>
            <p>Friday May 1st 1863. The sun shone bright all day</p>
            <p>Saturday May 2nd 1863. No drill. Policing cleaning up washing<gap  resp="Deane"/>
            </p>
            
            <pb n="34" facs="0012_001560_000200_0034.jpg" xml:id="d4e1043"/>
            <p>Sunday May 3rd 1863. No inspection rather wet and rainy all day</p>
            <p>Monday May 4th 1863. Raining most of the day</p>
            <p>Tuesday May 5th 1863. Raining by spells all day</p>
            <p>Wednesday May 6th 1863. Raining by showers all day. No duty</p>
            <p>Thursday May 7th 1863. Raining and drizzling all day</p>
            <p>Friday May 8th 1863. Still raining. Joseph Anglemise died at 1:20 at night</p>
            <p>Saturday May 9th 1863. Clear and pleasant. Washing day</p>
            <p>Sunday May 10th 1863. Sunday inspection in the morning and church at two Oclock</p>
            <p>Monday May 11th 1863. Regular drill</p>
            <p>Tuesday May 12th 1863. Drill in morning and battalion in the afternoon</p>
            <p>Wednesday May 13th 1863. Detailed men to clean up a camp close to town<unclear reason="illegible" resp="S.C.">W. tenner</unclear>
            </p>
            <p>Thurday May 14th 1863. More men detailed to clean up the camp</p>
            
            <pb n="35" facs="0012_001560_000200_0035.jpg" xml:id="d4e1079"/>
            <p>Image Not Available</p>
            
            <pb n="36" facs="0012_001560_000200_0036.jpg" xml:id="d4e1093"/>
            <pb n="37" facs="0012_001560_000200_0037.jpg" xml:id="d4e1097"/>
            <pb n="38" facs="0012_001560_000200_0038.jpg" xml:id="d4e1101"/>
            <pb n="39" facs="0012_001560_000200_0039.jpg" xml:id="d4e1107"/>
            <p>Wm E. Marshal. Franklin Square. Columbiana Co. Ohio</p>
            
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
