<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_003423_000207_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter, 
               <name type="author">Joseph Oliver Freeman</name> in <name type="place">Tipton County, Tennessee</name>, to his sister, 
               <date when="1863-09-16">1863 September 16</date>
            </title>
            <author>
               <name>Freeman, Joseph Oliver</name>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>White, Park</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <availability status="restricted">
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
                  information, contact the Special Collections Library.</p>
            </availability>
            <idno>0012_003423_000207_0000</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Letter, 
                  <name type="author">Joseph Oliver Freeman</name> in <name type="place">Tipton County, Tennessee</name>, to his sister, 
                  <date when="1863-09-16">1863 September 16</date>
               </title>
               <date when="1863-09-16">1863 September 16</date>
               <author>
                  <name>Freeman, Joseph Oliver</name>
               </author>
               <extent>2 digital images</extent>
               <note type="collection">Joseph Oliver Freeman Letters, 1861 December 22 - 1864 June 12, undated</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS.0806</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for The University of Tennessee Libraries
               Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Corrections have been applied to the text only where there is a high degree of
               certainty of an error and if the correct spelling is known.</p>
            <p>Corrections are represented by editorial tags.</p>
            <p>Quotation marks and apostrophes have been replaced by entity references.</p>
            <p>All unambiguous end-of-line hyphens have been removed.</p>
            <p>Names of persons, places, and organizations are indicated in the transcription when
               identifiable with a high degree of certainty.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Chickamauga, Battle of, Ga., 1863.</term>
               <term>United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Correspondence.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-06-17" who="nl">Updated earlier transcription from the old TEI.2 system to anticipate and resolve difficulties and issues with re-formatting letters from this collection into TEI-P5 lite.</change>
         <change when="2013-07-15" who="nl">Added "idno" element, 
            editorial declaration statement, subjects/keywords and abstracts 
            from EAD finding aid. Removed box and folder notes, reference 
            declaration element. Changed the formatting for blank pages. 
            Added resp attributes to editorial changes, and added name 
            tags.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter" xml:id="d2e166">    
            <pb facs="0012_003423_000207_0001.jpg" n="1" xml:id="d2e168"/>
            
            <opener>
               <dateline>State of 
                  <name type="place">tipton county</name> tenn
                  <date when="1863-09-16">Sept th 16th</date>
               </dateline>
               <salute>fare sister</salute>
            </opener>    
            <p>I resieve your kind letter this evening whitch I was very glad to see it found us all up but Mr Stokes  he has bin rite Sick every Since last Sunday he has had the doctor with him but he is better to nite  the fever is broke but he is not able to Set up yet but I hope he Will be in a day or So</p>
            <p>Inda you ought to ove bin her last wendesday and Saw Wat a time we had  there was to be a triel here between ed angers and kid well and thay got mad and kid well presented his gun to Shoot angers and Marion Chatnon tooke the gun from him and then angers took out his pistol and it fired ouf before he got redy and it went throu</p>
            
            <pb facs="0012_003423_000207_0002.jpg" n="2" xml:id="d2e191"/>
            <p>the tope of the house and then he Shot at kid well but mist him and the bali went in the wall rite by the water bucket  if ever you ever Saw a Scird Set it was her  Mrs burton was her as wel and She had not <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">ov</unclear>it when Started home at nite  henry wants to see Jose very bad last nite he waked up and called his par and Says poor J gone I cant See her no more  he Says Jo lives at Mr tabers  well I well have to close for the want of paper</p>
            <p>rite Soon looke over bad Spelling and riting  Termeliu Stokes to I freeman</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
