<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000060_000258_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter, <name> J. Crozier Ramsey </name> in Nashville, Tenn., to Mrs. E.A.R. Breck 
in Charlotte, N.C. <date when="1865-08-05"> 1865 August 4 </date>
            </title>
            <author>
               <name type="person">Ramsey, J. Crozier</name>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>Dyson-Smith, Bridger</name>
               <name>Galloway, Helen</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_000060_000258_0000</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more information,
            contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special Collections
                Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Letter, J. Crozier Ramsey in Nashville, Tenn., to Mrs. E.A.R. Breck in Charlotte, N.C. 1865 Aug. 4</title>
               <date>1865-08-04</date>
               <author>
                  <name>Ramsey, J. Crozier</name>
               </author>
               <extent>7 digital images; 6 pages, 1 envelope</extent>
               <note type="abstract">1865 Aug. 4 J. Crozier Ramsey, Nashville, Tenn., to his sister, Mrs. E.A.R.
Breck, Charlotte, N.C. Expresses happiness that his parents are taking
defeat and loss of property well. News that he has entered the practice of
law. Encloses his business card. Information for the members of his family
concerning the advisability of their returning to Knoxville. Reports that
sentiment against Confederate sympathizers is still strong in Knoxville.
Mentions their applications for pardons, his attempt to find a position for
McKnitt, and Margaret Jane&apos;s new husband. Finds equal treatment of both
Union and Confederate sympathizers in Nashville. </note>
               <note type="collection">J.G.M. Ramsey Papers 1790-1869</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS.253</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee Libraries
                Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
                omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Quality of life -- Tennessee -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Family -- Employment -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Peaceful coexistence -- Tennessee -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Tennessee -- Politics and government -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Knoxville -- Politics and government -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Ramsey, J. Crozier (John Crozier) d. 1868 -- Correspondence.</term>
               <term>Ramsey, J. Crozier (John Crozier) d. 1868 -- Health.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-10-02" who="bds">Migrating from
                XML to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter" xml:id="d3e158">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_000060_000258_0001.jpg" xml:id="d3e159"/>
            <p>Mrs. E.A. R. Breck</p>
            <p>Charlotte</p>
            <p>N.C.</p>
            <p>Via Richmond Va</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_000060_000258_0002.jpg" xml:id="d3e173"/>
            <p>Nashville Ten Auugust 4th</p>
            <p>My Dear Sister</p>
            <p>I was please to receive your very kind letter by to-days mail and was very glad to hear that Papa and Ma are
well and that they stand our defeat and their loss of property with Christian fortitude that is as it should be, but
few persons of their age could have stood the troubles and trials they have had with such fortitude. I have no
doubt but what we all by industry and energy will be enabled to get along comfortably and happy yet, and after things
get quiet may be able to recover their property, if not we can get along very well without it I was also pleased to learn
that <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Ehisk</unclear> Robert and Mark were well you did not say any thing about Susan,
but I <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">presume</unclear> she is well. I have commenced the practice</p>
            <pb n="3" facs="0012_000060_000258_0003.jpg" xml:id="d3e191"/>
            <p>of my profession and have had some business I am boarding with Uncle William, they are all very kind to me, my health
has improved though I am still weak, the walk however in the morning and evening I think will be of service to me
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">soon Tenes</unclear> I have no doubt will pay your coupons when presented, but I would
not have the money sent by mail, if the Express is running as far as Charlotte, have it sent that way. I am at a great
to know how to advise you all I am like you I have a great distaste for East Ten but I dont think that their would be
any impropriety in you and Mack returning to Knoxville on a visit and see if you cant get your property back and then
rent or sell it. I suppose you could get transportation. Mr Simmons and Dr Hall are both living here I spoke to Mr S if he
could not get Mack employment as a clerk here</p>
            <pb n="4" facs="0012_000060_000258_0004.jpg" xml:id="d3e202"/>
            <p>he said he thought he could. I told him that I did not know whether he had employment or <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">weather</unclear> he would like to come here he told me to write to him and if he wanted a situation he
would try and get him one see Mack about it It will not be safe for Robert to come to Tennessee at present. I will let
know when to come if he wants to return. Their are some cases pending in the State and Federal Courts at Knoxville against
me expect I will be compelled to be there in October or November to attend to them. I will however try to have them arranged
without having to go there. I have much appreciation for <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Pardon</unclear> and my
papers are in charge of Judge Patterson (the Presidents son in law and M.S. Senator from Ten) He is a particular
friend of mine and visited me while imprisoned at Knoxville I saw him a few days ago as he was going on to Washing</p>
            <pb n="5" facs="0012_000060_000258_0005.jpg" xml:id="d3e216"/>
            <p>ton and had a long conversation with him he also agreed to take charge of Papas case he seems to think that we will
have no dificulty in getting them through. I expect to hear from him in a week or two about our applications and will
let Papa know the result of his application. Uncle <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Carrick</unclear> and family
passed through here a few weeks ago on their way to Clarksville Ten they have settled there and I hear that he is getting
some practice. I frequently hear from Knoxville and see every day or two some one from the place the sentiment is still bad
and outrages are still committed upon Southern men No prominent Southern men have returned and what are there are making
arrangments to leave</p>
            <p>I get letters from M.J. (my Sister) most every week she is well as to her marrage I presume she is satisfied with it and of
course I am I hope she Mr McKnitt will make her a kind and an affect</p>
            <pb n="6" facs="0012_000060_000258_0006.jpg" xml:id="d3e229"/>
            <p>ionate husband She has had a hard time of it few women could have gone through what she has She was very devoted to me
while I was in prison there and was of great service to me</p>
            <p>She writes me some very good letters (one of the very best I ever received) I am saving it to show it to you all She is a
Christian and a noble woman What a great pleasure it would be to us all if we were all living near each other. I dont know
how Pap would like to live in East Ten again but I have no doubt but what he could live in comfort and with more
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">care</unclear> on Margaret Janes place than any other. I have not doubt but what
it would be perfectly safe for him there (after while) No one would do him any personal</p>
            <pb n="7" facs="0012_000060_000258_0007.jpg" xml:id="d3e242"/>
            <p>harm the class of man that are committing them these outrages are worthless and the moral men of the country are doing
all they can to put a stop to it public sentiment will soon correct the outlaws I doubt the propriety of a man of his age moving
to a new country among strangers unless he had means these are questions for future considerations you are all
<unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">quaintly situated</unclear> and it is best to <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">wait</unclear>
patiently until the country becomes settled and peace entirely <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">returned</unclear> and then
we can better judge as to what will be the best. What a great contrast between this peace place and East Ten here their is now now
distinction between Union and Southern men that is as it should be. I often think of you all with the kindest of feelings and would
be pleased to be with you all once more and I hope I may be able to do so some time. Remember me kindly and affectionately to all
Will be pleased to hear from you all often</p>
            <p>Yours truly</p>
            <p>J.C. Ramsey</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>