<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000060_000471_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter,
<name>Lyman C. Draper</name>
 in Madison, Wis., to J.G.M. Ramsey in Knoxville, Tenn.<date when="1880-08-02">1880 Aug. 2</date>
            </title>
            <author>
               <name type="person">Draper, Lyman Copeland, 1815-1891</name>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>Roberts, Jason</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_000060_000471_0000</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more information,
            contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special Collections
                Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Letter, Lyman C. Draper in Madison, Wis., to J.G.M. Ramsey in Knoxville, Tenn. 1880 Aug. 2</title>
               <date>1880-08-02</date>
               <author>
                  <name>Draper, Lyman Copeland, 1815-1891</name>
               </author>
               <extent>3 digital images; 1 envelope, 2 p.</extent>
               <note type="abstract">1880 Aug. 2 Lyman C. Draper, Madison, Wis., to J.G.M. Ramsey, Knoxville, Tenn. Informs J.G.M. of the writer&apos;s need for information concerning the Western part of the route of the King&apos;s Mountain men. Discussion of Tennesseans who could have been at the Cowpens. 

</note>
               <note type="collection">James Gettys McGready Ramsey Papers</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS.0253</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee Libraries
                Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
                omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>King&apos;s Mountain, Battle of, S.C., 1780.</term>
               <term>Cowpens, Battle of, Cowpens, S.C., 1781.</term>
               <term>Frontier and pioneer life -- Southern States.</term>
               <term>Tennessee -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783 -- Sources.</term>
               <term>United States -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783 -- Sources.</term>
               <term>Draper, Lyman Copeland, 1815-1891. King&apos;s mountain and its heroes.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-10-02" who="bds">Migrating from
                XML to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter" xml:id="d3e151">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_000060_000471_0001.jpg" xml:id="d3e152"/>
            <p>Dr. J.G.M. Ramsey,</p>
            <p>Knoxville --</p>
            <p>Tennessee.</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_000060_000471_0002.jpg" xml:id="d3e164"/>
            <p>Is there any Atlas of Tenn. by counties, or a large seale map?</p>
            <p>Conecting proof of my 4th Chapter.</p>
            <p>Madison, Aug. 2nd 1880.</p>
            <p>My Dear Dr. Ramsey --</p>
            <p>This morning I recd. yrs. of the 29th. I am making some progress in getting light on the route -- but still there some dark passages in those mountain recesses. I am having the most uncertainty on the western part of the route.</p>
            <p>The evidence is that the Mountaineers crossed Yellow Mountain; but I am not clear as to all its locality: The principal Yellow Mtn., on the maps I have, extends nearly East &amp; West -- and a little to its south in Bakersville; while on its north &amp; round its East <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JR">side</unclear> runs North Toe river: And yet one account -- perhaps</p>
            <pb n="3" facs="0012_000060_000471_0003.jpg" xml:id="d3e185"/>
            <p>more than one -- mentions the Crab Orchard -- &amp; Brights, as being on North Toe -- possibly at a point which they crossed North Toe before crossing over Yellow Mountain. I am a good deal puzzled, but hope light will yet dawn.</p>
            <p>About Tennesseeans at the Cowpens. There could have been embodied party -- it occurred at the wrong time in the year, I shd. think for the Wataugans to be so far away on the war path. Moses Shelby, (brother of Gc.) Jordan Roach &amp; Alexander Greer were at the Cowpens -- &amp; perhaps Evan Shelby Jr. -- I say perhaps, for I had it from Col. George Wilson, an old-time editor at Knoxville &amp; elsewhere in Tenn. whom I met in his old age in Nashville in 1844. He had the fact from his father-in-law, Alexr. Greer that Roach &amp; Evan Shelby were at the Cowpens -- no particulars; but as the obituary of Moses Shelby&apos;s death states that he was at the Cowpens, I thought perhaps Col. Wilson may have forgotten, &amp; that Greer said it was Moses -- &amp; Le Wilson, had forgotten. It is not impossible that both Evan &amp; Moses were there. These few Tennesseeans must have been adventurers, seeking to share stirring events. I have only this to add -- that</p>
            <p>when you want to know any thing abt. Cowpens, &amp; other Rev. events, in that quarter, you shd. turn your eyes Wisconsinward, not towards South Carolina. Ahem! -- Truly Yours, Lyman C. Draper</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>