<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_003423_000203_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter, 
               <name type="author">Joseph Oliver Freeman</name> in <name type="place">Corinth, Mississippi</name>, to Indiana Freeman, 
               <date when="1862-03-25">1862 March 25</date>
            </title>
            <author>
               <name>Freeman, Joseph Oliver</name>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>White, Park</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <availability status="restricted">
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
                  information, contact the Special Collections Library.</p>
            </availability>
            <idno>0012_003423_000203_0000</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Letter, 
                  <name type="author">Joseph Oliver Freeman</name> in <name type="place">Corinth, Mississippi</name>, to Indiana Freeman, 
                  <date when="1862-03-25">1862 March 25</date>
               </title>
               <date when="1862-03-25">1862 March 25</date>
               <author>
                  <name>Freeman, Joseph Oliver</name>
               </author>
               <extent>4 digital images</extent>
               <note type="collection">Joseph Oliver Freeman Letters, 1863 October 13, to 1864 April 11</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS.0806</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for The University of Tennessee Libraries
               Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Corrections have been applied to the text only where there is a high degree of
               certainty of an error and if the correct spelling is known.</p>
            <p>Corrections are represented by editorial tags.</p>
            <p>Quotation marks and apostrophes have been replaced by entity references.</p>
            <p>All unambiguous end-of-line hyphens have been removed.</p>
            <p>Names of persons, places, and organizations are indicated in the transcription when
               identifiable with a high degree of certainty.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Knoxville (Tenn.) -- History -- Siege, 1863.</term>
               <term>Soldiers -- Tennessee -- Correspondence.</term>
               <term>Tennessee -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.</term>
               <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Religious aspects.</term>
               <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-06-17" who="nl">Updated earlier transcription from the old TEI.2 system to anticipate and resolve difficulties and issues with re-formatting letters from this collection into TEI-P5 lite.</change>
         <change when="2013-07-15" who="nl">Added "idno" element, 
            editorial declaration statement, subjects/keywords and abstracts 
            from EAD finding aid. Removed box and folder notes, reference 
            declaration element. Changed the formatting for blank pages. 
            Added resp attributes to editorial changes, and added name 
            tags.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter" xml:id="d2e175">
            <pb facs="0012_003423_000203_0001.jpg" n="1" xml:id="d2e177"/>
            
            <opener>
               <dateline>    
                  <date when="1862-03-25">March 25 D 1862</date><lb/>
                  <name type="place">Corinth</name><name type="place">tishmingo CO</name><lb/>
                  State of <name type="place">mississippi</name>
               </dateline>
            </opener>
            
            <salute>my Dears wife</salute>
            
            <p>I take the opetuney of Riten you a few lines to lete you no that I am yeat a live hope when thes few lines comes to hands that thay may finds you in gud helth my Dear has noth new to Rite oly all is well  I has Rote and Rote and hav never hav receve no letter from you yeat  I hav lost all hopes of ever heren from you evr moer thay is A bote ninty thousent Chalgs her</p>
            <p>wee ar fixten to Draw our money and as son as i can Draw hit I will send hit home the ferst chanch I git</p>
            
            <pb facs="0012_003423_000203_0002.jpg" n="2" xml:id="d2e208"/>
            <p><unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">pucky A</unclear>member of hor Comney <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">Dibe</unclear>to day we ar
               in <name type="person"><choice><orig>genrel Chalmes</orig><corr resp="pw">General Chalmers</corr></choice></name> brigad  I noth no to rite Indy Rite to me as son as you git this let me no how you ar a to me as son as you git this  let me no how you ar a gitten along and how times is thar so noth mo at present</p>
            <p>giv my lov and repecekes to all my frends so no but remane your Dears Boy so far you well my Dear Inday</p>
            <p>Direck you letter to the <name type="org"><choice><orig>fiftey first Rigman tennssee</orig><corr resp="pw">51st Regiment, Tennessee</corr></choice></name> voltears Comney A</p>
            <p>Inday I am mity <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">ovessey</unclear>abote you my harte all most brak sumtimes when I thik abote us A ben paret bute we muste taket hit the best way we can we hafter weark evr Day Dige in the Diches</p>
            
            <pb facs="0012_003423_000203_0003.jpg" n="3" xml:id="d2e244"/>
            <p>and chofendon trese thay ar forfine this plase I sene luis Daves and gorge smith her noles Rigmon is her I excpek you Brother Frank is her but cant git a chance to look for him for I Cant git A Canch to goe ef From the Rigman  I did git A chanch to go and see luis the erthr Day</p>
            <p>tel Brother Charle that I receve his litter that he sent by fil boles and I was sarre to her that he was sick  tel Mrs Scales that ed is well all the rest is well  tel Chrle that we hav move abote A mile From whor we wer  tel all my Frends to Rit to me I wod like to git A leter ever Day so noth mo but remane you afection Husban so Far you well my Dears Inday  Direck you letters to the Fiftey First Rigman tennessee volters to - Compeney A  So Far you well my Dears</p>
            
            <pb facs="0012_003423_000203_0004.jpg" n="4" xml:id="d2e253"/>
            <p>Joseph. O. Freeman</p>
            <p>Inday I am A Com home as son as I can thay hav shot don on Furlow thay onl let no one leve no long then tow ower at time</p>
            <p>giv my Repeckes to Mrs Dennis and Famley and John Stokes and Famley and to all the conneck</p>
            <p>So Far you well my Dears and Fection <unclear reason="illegible" resp="PW">of</unclear>Wife</p>
            <p>I Joseph. O. Freeman</p>
            <p>So Far ye</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
