<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_001180_000201_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter,
<name>Henry B. Wetzell</name>
 in Easton Pa., to Aaron Wetzell in Slifer, Pa., <date when="1866-09-25">1866 Sept. 25</date>
            </title>
            <author>
               <name type="person">Wetzell, Henry B.</name>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>Mincey, Jennifer</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_001180_000201_0000</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more information,
            contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special Collections
                Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Letter, Henry B. Wetzell in Easton, Pa., to his father, 1866 Sept. 25</title>
               <date>1866-09-25</date>
               <author>
                  <name>Wetzell, Henry B.</name>
               </author>
               <extent>1 digital image; 1 page</extent>
               <note type="abstract">Henry B. Wetzell wrote to his father, Aaron Wetzell, on September 25, 1866. He mentioned two fairs. He mentioned how he was getting his &quot;specimens and circulars ready&quot;. He had some fine specimens and was going to distribute 10,000 circulars. He had asked for &quot;newboys&quot; and they had arrived. He was ready to commence the next day. He felt proud of what he had to present at the fair. He felt other people dropped out of competition due to him being there. He mentioned a Democratic meeting being held in Easton that night.</note>
               <note type="collection">Henry B. Wetzell Letter</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS.2782</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee Libraries
                Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
                omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Fairs -- Pennsylvania -- Easton.</term>
               <term>Fairs -- Pennsylvania -- Chester County.</term>
               <term>Specimens -- Competitions.</term>
               <term>Wetzell, Henry B. -- Correspondence.</term>
               <term>Wetzell, Aaron -- Correspondence.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-10-02" who="bds">Migrating from
                XML to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter" xml:id="d3e150">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_001180_000201_0001.jpg" xml:id="d3e151"/>
            <p>American Hotel</p>
            <p>Easton Pa Sep 25.66</p>
            <p>Dear Father</p>
            <p>Amid the noisey and Babel of confusion I will write brifly a few lines tonight not having the necessary advantages for writing a long one. Yesterday and today I have been busy getting my specimens and circulars ready. I am now ready to commence <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">tomorrow</unclear> morning and if I dont create a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">&quot;furow&quot;</unclear> among the Fair people it will not be my fault. We have some of the finest specimens I ever saw, sent on from NY this morn I wish you could see them. I will distribute 10,000 circulars by Friday I telegraphed to Kimberly at Phily this afternoon for newboys and they have just arrived. Tomorrow I begin <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">nisk</unclear> in earnest. I want to get through here that I can attend Chester Co Fair on Sat. This Fair is said to exced anything of the kind ever held in the State Everything is well represented. our Cell stands far ahead of all the rest in display of Penmanship. Several <unclear reason="illegible" resp="JCM">Cillegs</unclear> intended entering but when they found me there they kept back. There is a very large Democratic meeting here tonight only a few doors from the Hotel.</p>
            <p>Yours truly</p>
            <p>H.B. Wetzell</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>