<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000060_000264_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter, <name>J. Crozier Ramsey</name> in Nashville, Tenn., to J.G.M. Ramsey,
Charlotte, N.C. <date when="1865-10-08">1865 October 8</date>
            </title>
            <author>
               <name type="person">Ramsey, J. Crozier (John Crozier)</name>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>Dyson-Smith, Bridger</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_000060_000264_0000</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more information,
            contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special Collections
                Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Letter, J. Crozier Ramsey in Nashville, Tenn., to J.G.M. Ramsey in Charlotte, N.C. 1865 Oct. 8</title>
               <date>1865-10-08</date>
               <author>
                  <name>Ramsey, J. Crozier (John Crozier)</name>
               </author>
               <extent>4 digital images; 4 pages</extent>
               <note type="abstract">1865 Oct. 8 J.Crozier Ramsey, Nashville, Tenn., to his father, J.G.M. Ramsey, Charlotte, N.C. Relates his trip to Washington, D.C., at which he spoke with President Johnson about their pardons and the hope his case will be postponed until the next session of the court. Warns that Robert should not let his whereabouts be known as he is wanted for murder in Knoxville. Mentions current prices of bank notes, having his photograph made in Washington, and his Uncle William&apos;s daughter, Mamie.</note>
               <note type="collection">J.G.M. Ramsey Papers 1790-1869</note>
               <note type="manuscript">253</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee Libraries
                Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
                omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Pardon -- Tennessee, East -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Quality of life -- Tennessee -- History -- 19th century. </term>
               <term>Family life -- Southern States -- History -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Knoxville (Tenn.) -- Politics and government -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Washington (D.C.) -- Politics and government -- 19th century.</term>
               <term>Ramsey, J. Crozier (John Crozier) d. 1868 -- Correspondence.</term>
               <term>Johnson, Andrew, 1808-1875.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-10-02" who="bds">Migrating from
                XML to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter" xml:id="d3e155">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_000060_000264_0001.jpg" xml:id="d3e156"/>
            <p>Nashville Ten Oct. 9th</p>
            <p>Dear Sir</p>
            <p>I returned from Washington City a day or two ago and was pleased to get your letter on my return and was glad to hear that
you were all well and so comfortably situated. I think under the circumstances you all have done very well. I visited Washington
for the purpose of attending to some business for a friend - who paid me for my services - and if I should be finally successfull - I
will get a good fee - but that is &quot;inter <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">nos</unclear>&quot;. I had been very anxious
to visit Washington on my own account - but had not the money to spare - so you see it happened very well</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_000060_000264_0002.jpg" xml:id="d3e171"/>
            <p>as I got to see to my own case and yours without the expense of the trip. The President received me very cordially so did his son
Robert and my friend Judge Patterson - The Judge assured me that I would get my pardon next week or any how by the time the Federal
Court meets at Knoxville. I then went to the Attorney Generals office to examine your case. I found that your application had
passed through his office with his approval and was on the Presidents table for his signature and also our friend R.B. Reynolds
application was in the same situation. I then called the attention of the Judge to those two cases and he <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">assured</unclear> me that they would be approved of by the President</p>
            <pb n="3" facs="0012_000060_000264_0003.jpg" xml:id="d3e182"/>
            <p>I have no doubt but what you will get them soon - if not you need not give <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">yourself</unclear>
any uneasiness about them as I have not doubt they will be approved of when they are reached in their proper order I was always
satisfied that my application would be approved of but the great object I had was to see if I could so arrang it as to
prevent my going to Knoxville on the 3rd Monday in this month - the goverment can not directly interfere with the State Courts - but
Judge Patterson has advised the Attorney General at Knoxville to have my case continued until the next term of the Court - waiving my
appearance at the present Term - this I hope he will do - as I dislike to go there at this</p>
            <pb n="4" facs="0012_000060_000264_0004.jpg" xml:id="d3e193"/>
            <p>time very much I will however hear in a day or two whether I will have to go. Robert ought not to let any body in Tennessee know
where he is - he is indicted for the murder of <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Picane</unclear> - and if they knew where he
was he might be <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">demanded</unclear> - their is no <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">case</unclear>
of his being uneasy or leaving the country on account of it for their is no danger about the case - but it is best not to be arrested
at present - for things are compelled to improve in East Ten in a few months. I send you a circular of prices current of Bank Notes &amp;c.
While at Washington I had my Photograph taken and as Lizzie was anxious to have one I send it to here. Cousin <unclear reason="illegible" resp="bds">Maria</unclear> (Uncle Williams youngest daughter) says you all send your love to all but her - She told me to ask you
if you had forgot her - She is the best Southern young lady I have ever met - she is beautiful and a very good girl - Uncle William has
got well and the rest of our relations are well and always are anxious to hear from you all. Our friends and relatives are all well at
Knoxville. I will be pleased to hear from you all at any time. Your Middle Tennessee friends have all returned Love to all</p>
            <p>Yours truly</p>
            <p>J.C. Ramsey</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>