<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000060_000428_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter,
<name>Lyman C. Draper</name>
 in Madison, Wis., to J.G.M. Ramsey in Knoxville, Tenn.<date when="1875-08-03">1875 Aug. 3</date>
            </title>
            <author>
               <name type="person">Draper, Lyman Copeland, 1815-1891</name>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>McClain, Lindsay</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_000060_000428_0000</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more information,
            contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special Collections
                Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Letter, Lyman C. Draper in Madison, Wis., to J.G.M. Ramsey in Knoxville, Tenn. 1875 Aug. 3</title>
               <date>1875-08-03</date>
               <author>
                  <name>Draper, Lyman Copeland, 1815-1891</name>
               </author>
               <extent>3 digital images; 2 pages, 1 envelope</extent>
               <note type="abstract">Lyman C. Draper, Corresponding Secretary, State Historical Society of Wisconsin, Madison, Wis., wrote to J.G.M. Ramsey, Knoxville, Tenn on August 3, 1875. He requested that Dr. Ramsey find out and forward specific information to him on early Southern Presbyterians in regards to how they treated Saturdays. He referred to the book he is writing and to ex-President Johnson&apos;s death. He thought highly of Johnson. J.G.M. Ramsey attached a letter to the end of Draper&apos;s letter. He sent it to Rev. Dr. Park. Ramsey asked Park to help him answer Draper&apos;s letter. Ramsey was not aware of Presbyterians ever using Saturdays in preparation of the Sabbath. He mentioned he knew that four days were devoted to the communion service and Friday as a fast in olden times. He thought there was preparation for the communion service. He asked if this was a practice of the whole church or just in North Carolina and Tennessee.</note>
               <note type="collection">James Gettys McGready Ramsey Papers</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS.0253</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee Libraries
                Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
                omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH">
               <term>Historians -- Correspondence.</term>
               <term>Presbyterian Church -- Southern States -- History.</term>
               <term>Presbyterian Church -- Special days.</term>
               <term>Southern States -- Religious life and customs.</term>
               <term>Draper, Lyman Copeland, 1815-1891 -- Correspondence.</term>
               <term>Ramsey, J. G. M. (James Gettys McGready), 1797-1884 -- Correspondence.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-10-02" who="bds">Migrating from
                XML to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter" xml:id="d3e158">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_000060_000428_0001.jpg" xml:id="d3e159"/>
            <p>Dr. J. G. M. Ramsey,</p>
            <p>Knoxville --</p>
            <p>Tennessee.</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_000060_000428_0002.jpg" xml:id="d3e171"/>
            <p>Madison, Aug. 3d 1875.</p>
            <p>My Dear Dr. Ramsey--</p>
            <p>I have one point I wish to have your opinion on -- in common with others --- it is</p>
            <p>To what extent did the early Presbyterians of the South make use of Saturday as a preparation day for Sunday -- whether merely in temporal matters, or whether this day was in whole a part used as a religious preparation, by meeting with or without a pastor?</p>
            <p>I don&apos;t see anything in Foote &amp; other Presbyterian writers on this point.</p>
            <p>My associate, Mr. Butterfield, takes hold finely -- &amp; we are digging away on our first</p>
            <pb n="3" facs="0012_000060_000428_0003.jpg" xml:id="d3e189"/>
            <p>book -- on Border Forays &amp; Adventures, simply first, because the book we said it wd. pay best, &amp; we needed something for bread and butter.</p>
            <p>In haste-- Truly Yours,</p>
            <p>Lyman C. Draper</p>
            <p>I am sorry to hear of Ex-President Johnson&apos;s death. I once spent a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="LM">pleasant</unclear> hour with him. He was thoroughly honest --- that goes a great ways in these, or indeed any times.</p>
            <p>Rev. Dr. Park</p>
            <p>Help me to answer this letter of Hon. L. C. Draper. I did not know before that Presbyterians ever used Saturday as in preparation for the Sabbath -- on the other hand in the olden times when the communion was to be administered, four days were devoted to that service but Friday was then observed as a Fast days &amp; was oficially observed as preparatory to the sacredness of <unclear reason="illegible" resp="LM">a</unclear>communion occasion -- Am I correct in this? &amp; was this the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="LM"> unmonied</unclear> of <unclear reason="illegible" resp="LM"> bon</unclear> whole church or only of North Carolina &amp; Tennessee Presbyterians? Please return this letter &amp; your observations on the subject matter of it.</p>
            <p>J. G. M. Ramsey</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>