<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000435_000204_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter,
					<name>Andrew Jackson Donelson</name>
				                    in Washington, to his father <date when="1854-05-31">1854 May 31</date>
            </title>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>Elizabeth, Smither</name>
            </respStmt>
            <author>
               <name type="person">
                  <name type="person">Andrew Jackson Donelson</name>
               </name>
            </author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <availability status="restricted">
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_000435_000204_0000</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Letter, Andrew Jackson Donelson in Washington, to his father 1854 May 31</title>
               <date when="1854-05-31">1854 May 31</date>
               <author>
                  <name type="person">Andrew Jackson Donelson</name>
               </author>
               <extent>2 pages</extent>
               <note type="collection">Andrew Jackson Donelson Letter</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS.1158</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
						omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH"/>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013" who="Elizabeth, Smither">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
         <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e38">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_000435_000204_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e39"/>
            <p>Washington May 31st 1854</p>
            <p>Hon A J Donelson</p>
            <p>Nashville</p>
            <p>Tennessee</p>
            <p>My Dear Father</p>
            <p>I arrived here last Sunday morning, and at New York on Thursday. I wrote to you from Asheville on the Isthmus of Panama by the New Orleans Steamer, hoping that by those means you would get the letter much sooner than if I waited until arriving at New York.</p>
            <p>Brother John came down from New Haven to see me. He is in good health and much improved in appearance. His final examination commenced on Saturday. He will not wait for the commencement but expects to go to Tennessee in two or three weeks.</p>
            <p>I was at <unclear reason="illegible" resp="EMS">Mess Pouir</unclear> for a day, and though I did not see him I heard that Andrew Jackson was doing well. I did not hear that Sister Mary had gone to Texas until I arrived in New York.</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_000435_000204_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e60"/>
            <p>Although all I talked with on the subject speak in the highest terms of San Antonio, I do not much like the move, and fear Sister will not be content to live there. However she has a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="EMS">spirit</unclear> to make her home happy, wherever she goes.</p>
            <p>With the execption of a letter from Ma dated in August last and received on my arrival at Fort Vancouver in November, I have not had a letter from any member of the family since I left St. Louis, and while there I only had one from you. I really almost came to the conclusion that you had all <unclear reason="illegible" resp="EMS">cut</unclear> my acquaintance. There is no news of importance here; opinion is divided as to whether there will be war or not. I have heard some distinguished men say they thought there would be war. Give my best love to ma, sister Rachel and all the family. Tell them to write to me, I hope you will write me a long letter, and say how things are going in Tennessee. I hope to hear that you have gotten over all you difficulties and are now doing well.</p>
            <p>Your affectionate son</p>
            <p>AJ Donelson</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
