<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_002408_000201_0000">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Memoir,
					<name>Edwin Floyd Wiley</name>
               <date>undated</date>
            </title>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
          <name>Hutson, Aaron</name>
        </respStmt>
        <author>
          <name type="person">Edwin Floyd Wiley</name>
        </author>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
        <date>2013</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
        </availability>
        <idno type="SPC">0012_002408_000201_0000</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Memoir, Edwin Floyd Wiley</title>
          <date>undated</date>
          <author>
            <name type="person">Edwin Floyd Wiley</name>
          </author>
          <extent>134 pages</extent>
          <note type="collection">Edwin Floyd Wiley Memoir and Photograph, 1861-1865</note>
          <note type="manuscript">0433</note>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
        <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
        <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
        <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as "turn page over" have been
						omitted.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy>
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="LCSH">
          <term>Tennessee -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.</term>
          <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Prisoners and prisons.</term>
          <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change when="2013" who="Hutson, Aaron">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
      <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e35">
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_002408_000201_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e36"/>
        <p>I came of age on Jan 13th 1860 about the same time or in the same year Pres Lincoln was elected and the Civil War excitement was on. The Union people of the state of which at that time were largely in the majority, elected to have Union home guards in many places over the state particulary in the eastern portion of the state. This continued for some time while conventions were being helled the most noted one at Greenville Tenn &amp; at that time the majority was largely on the Union side and an election was held &amp; that resulted in a majority for the Union over the whole state after the firing on Fort Sumpter the Gov declared the state out of the Union and secesion a fact this part of the state was at once filled up with the Sou soldier &amp; Knoxville head qurts. This soon stoped the Union home guard &amp; the people (Union) began to be very uneasy</p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_002408_000201_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e40"/>
        <p>as the troops were sent out into the mountains to overaw the Union people &amp; to guard the Gaps &amp; passways through the mountains to Ky &amp; the Union Army. In Aug 61 the first larg detachment of Union people crossed the mountain. Some 3000 got through and byvoact at Camp Dick Robinson Ky. There after they were going at all times through the by ways and at night. The principal road &amp; Gaps in the mountains guarded by the C.S. Soldiers During that year 61 the opposite side organized home guards &amp; I being about the right age was many times solicited to joine &amp; by my near neighbors all of which I had to pretend to be in favor of &amp; to do <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">Kinkte Co</unclear> This kind of work did not suit &amp; so I was told if I did not join the jail in Knoxville would be the nexed move. After a time Cumberland Gap was occupied by the Sou troops &amp; detachments of troops all through the mountains. Some two hundred had camped within 1/2 mile of the house at Oliver Springs, my home, at one time and as we had some fine hogs</p>
        <pb n="3" facs="0012_002408_000201_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e47"/>
        <p>the soldiers soon dispatched a numb of them. so to get pay for the hogs I made it my business to go among them and get my pay if I could I soon found they were not in a paying mood &amp; kept me around from one man or soldier to another representing them as officers that would pay. This did not suit me. So as it happened the officer in command was then at the house for the night &amp; I approached him in regard to pay for the hogs which he agreed to do if I would prove the hogs this I could not do though knowing they were all dead but he paid me a small amt any way. Later on troops began to move from Cumberland Gap by the way of Oliver Springs Montgomery Jamestown into Ky Gen Zollicoffer in command. quite an army passed the house during a week or two that theywere on the move by this time about every thing we had had been killed and used up by the army except some two or three horses &amp; they were kept out of the way as much as possible as soon as this came to be known</p>
        <pb n="4" facs="0012_002408_000201_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e51"/>
        <p>During the time and befor the troops moved from C Gap I had to take care and not get into jail as threatened me The only chance for me was to move for Ky &amp; taking the by ways and the brush for it. I had heard of some of our friends who would start at a later date &amp; eventually got in with them &amp; we struck the mountains some 30 or more. After having gone a day or two the crowd became panic stricken &amp; dispersed leaving me in the mountains for the time. I could not remain there and as bad to go back as could not stop at as I thought after remaining a day or two with a mountain woman her husband hideing out I took the risk to go back home which I reached in the evening &amp; lay in the woods nearby until I could see someone to tell of the situations at the house It happened so that my nephew a little boy came in calling distance &amp; I hailed him &amp; from him learned that the house was about full of Confed Officers stoping for the night This was bad but I told him to tell his Grandma that I would come in after</p>
        <pb n="5" facs="0012_002408_000201_0005.jpg" xml:id="d4e55"/>
        <p>dark and see her. After dark I took my chance &amp; went into her room. She was certainly glad to see me but could not be easy while I was in the house as at any time some of those men in the other part of the house might come in I remained with her up to 11 oclock &amp; she passed me out at the back door. taking my coarse down the creek &amp; through the corn to an outhouse in which I remained until the next night after dark at which time I struck the road again walking 16 miles to a friends &amp; with the intention of getting a guide to pass out into Ky After a time found that the guide had gone and to stay So here I was away from my own neighborhood but not out of the country I work here for a month in Teanery up in the woods took my meals on main road which house was used very extensively by the soldiers. During this month it became more quiet &amp; the Union men were not hunted down as they had been &amp; owing to proclimation that they could remain at home if they would not leave or take part in trouble</p>
        <pb n="6" facs="0012_002408_000201_0006.jpg" xml:id="d4e59"/>
        <p>So one day after having been with them a month or so, it happened that a southerner from the army at Cumberland Gap a Maj Bridgeman took dinner at the house and had a lead horse while at dinner it was mentioned that if I wished that I could ride the extra horse &amp; go home times seemed to be quiet again I accept the offer &amp; with the officer road home 16 miles away. On the trip nothing was said as to when &amp; why I was away only that as a farm hand reaching home. Met my mother and she told me of a Batalion of Cavelry which was camped some two miles from the house &amp; that the Maj of the Regt &amp; a Mr Adams a friend of ours had taken dinner at the house that day. Two of my old comrades came along soon after to have me go with them to the camp After some hesitation I agreed to go as I could meet Mr Adams if I did. We walked out &amp; as it happened the guards would not pass us in so we retraced our steps and was way back &amp; about dark when we heard the rush of horses &amp; very soon were surrounded by the riders with the word to return to camp which we immediately don. I was you say</p>
        <pb n="7" facs="0012_002408_000201_0007.jpg" xml:id="d4e63"/>
        <p>sure frightened but was in for it now and could not help seeing the jail in my mind I was conducted into one of the tents and was anxious to see Mr Adams though had said nothing of knowing any one. I so happened that he was passing the tent &amp; saw me came in with a howdy do very friendly and wish to know how I came to them I told him had come out to see him &amp; was captured &amp; brt in said he had been at at noon &amp; took dinner with my mother but did not see me I told him I was not at the house while he called Well he said he could vouch for me to the commander &amp; brot the maj round to see me &amp; from him I learned it was in a great part the other two they wanted. We were put through a court martial that nigh &amp; I was the only witness to prove the darings of the other two my partners. So I had not seen them for a long while &amp; did not know any thing of there doings. &amp; they with myself wer let go the two men left the country and remained at home for a time under the rule that Union men would not be desturbed at their homes. Later on the army at Cumberland Gap broke up &amp; moved for Ky by the way of Oliver</p>
        <pb n="8" facs="0012_002408_000201_0008.jpg" xml:id="d4e67"/>
        <p>Springs &amp; then on to fishing Creek Ky. by this move of so many soldiers passing about all we had was scooped away even to the turnips in the ground in fact every thing from a horse to a chicken if found to be handy. The horses we had had been away &amp; the army people had found it out so early one morning they called to have them returned as they wished them with a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">disorte</unclear> help in the moving supplys over the mountain My mother frightend orderd me at once to walk off 18 miles &amp; get them. on the way I met two coming with the horses &amp; so reported the fact of the arrival to the proper offiers &amp; in time I was placed in line with the regular army train as a driver This was on the eve of the battle of Mill Springs &amp; where Gen Zollicoffe was killed &amp; a gen <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">rout</unclear> of the confed army My position was not very pleasent &amp; the weather very bad &amp; in time the battle had come off &amp; we met the retreating army strgglin all kinds of shapes some afoot some on <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">bare</unclear> back two or three on a horse with no bridle saddle or anything. At this junction I was ordered to turn my teme towards Knoxville or retrace my steps as therewere no more use from</p>
        <pb n="9" facs="0012_002408_000201_0009.jpg" xml:id="d4e80"/>
        <p>Bacon &amp; Hardtack &amp; that divertion. After driving for them at different jobs I was inclined to return home which I did with many thank. In March 62 another attempt to cross the mountains this leaving the home without a man person on the ground only my mother &amp; two sisters without protection of any kind in the hands of the enemy even the neighbors were of the opposite side &amp; there was no telling how soon all would go up in smoke. but go we had to or take a position on the opposite side The Sou soldier was then on the ground to tak father to Knoxville as charges had been made against him Starting in the evening and <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">taking</unclear> The woods at once &amp; thinking about all night falling many times over rocks and other things in the mountain passes After some four or five days reached the Barborsville Ky where the Team were collecting and forming Cos &amp; Regts The time was March and a very bad one at that The town was small and but one Hotel so the only chance was</p>
        <pb n="10" facs="0012_002408_000201_0010.jpg" xml:id="d4e87"/>
        <p>to find the dryest peace on the ground &amp; mak you bed they had been no arrangments for our reception &amp; thousands of others as no one knew of our coming Some 20 of us got into an old house near the town with no floor &amp; little roof but after filling in between the sleepers with straw got on moderately well for a time though many of the healthy strong boys were soon sick &amp; no provision for them to be taken care of During this month I was sick with the measles &amp; layed up for a time although had had the measles one year before Renegades were still coming in and the work of organization began Regt No 5 was begun &amp; I began to collect all my friends and others if I could enlist with me in a co which in time was mustered &amp; I was elected as 2d Leut in one of the Co Then came the drills &amp; prepration for war in fact I was green but I had the satisfaction that I was not alone</p>
        <pb n="11" facs="0012_002408_000201_0011.jpg" xml:id="d4e91"/>
        <p>This was kept up with a trip now and then towards Cumberland Gap and return to the same place but in June a move was mad in that direction with it seemed with more determination and with all the force Some 15000 men on different road but all heading in the same direction Cumberland Gap Some 40 miles away This looked like business &amp; all were in good spirits that we were on the road home. After the Second or third day could see the camps of the enemy on the mountain side of the Gap. The hills were white with their tents &amp; with a glass you could see the heavy guns on the points of the mountain. We were then deployed in fault line &amp; took the woods &amp; fields creeks and all as we came to them with a line of <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">seirmerokers</unclear> in front climbing the mountains all the time covering near to the tented ground. each one thinking</p>
        <pb n="12" facs="0012_002408_000201_0012.jpg" xml:id="d4e99"/>
        <p>and looking for something to happen from the other side of the question, but none came The Gap had been quietly evaacuated leaving their tents standing though split up with knives. The little army was not long in taking possession on the same ground that had just been occupied by the other Then came more work in little <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">grub</unclear> as was not long befor the small army was surrounded by the enemy &amp; all communication cut of from the outside world. This was kept up until it became necssary to dispatch a small force each day to forage and cut corn in the fields of the surrounding county &amp; in each cas had to bring on a small fight to draw the small force of the eney to one given point so that the other parts of the country could be foraged over The first man killed of my Regt was one one of these rades. After going out with the Regt a hault was made and the Regt</p>
        <pb n="13" facs="0012_002408_000201_0013.jpg" xml:id="d4e106"/>
        <p>The Regt having halted for a time a detail was asked for of twelve men &amp; Com officer I took charge of the men with orders from the Col to go on down the roadThis was all the ordr I recd &amp; well knew that I could go but a short distance before I would meet with the enemy or hear from them. We had gone not more than 1/4 mile untl we came to an opening on the right of the road 150 yards wide &amp; from the back side of which a volly of shots came into our ranks as soon as possible led my men to the fence and began fireing the balls came thick and fast &amp; with only the fence with some scattering trees to cover my men Many balls came into the fence within a foot of me infact striking all round me a branch came out of the field very near to wher we stood. Not long after the fireing began a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">bomb</unclear> whizzed into the branch some 6 feet from me &amp; threw the water onto me. This came from the top of the mountain 1 1/2 miles back of us and was a shot from our own guns from the Gap The next shot passed</p>
        <pb n="14" facs="0012_002408_000201_0014.jpg" xml:id="d4e113"/>
        <p>over us as that was the intention of the first &amp; droped too short of the intention In time an orderly arrived &amp; I was ordered to take my men out in an other moment After giving me the order he was shot &amp; wounded I then ordered my men to get back as best they could but the chancs were very slim it seemed reaching the Regt and taking count found had lost one man killed &amp; the orderly wounded. So that I say</p>
        <pb n="15" facs="0012_002408_000201_0015.jpg" xml:id="d4e117"/>
        <p>The next trip I had was detailed with others making about 1000 men under Col Cooper afterwards Gen Cooper This was an important trip some 18 milesaway &amp; to the big Creek rout to Ky as we then surrounded with the Souther army had go very quietly at night &amp; though the woods and byways to reach the point. The main Confd Army had passed through this gap into Ky but no of straggling commands was going through this rout every day after reaching this road of which time before the mountain side road had been blockaded by falling the large time across the road This had all been choped out leaving the ends of the timber sticking out on each side of themain road making it very dangerous for cavelry to pass through except in slow numbers good <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">shap</unclear> The command under Cooper were deployed in Companies to occupy about 3 miles of this road &amp; in the brush near to it It was not long after getting settled in this way that a small command passing through two or three hundred was let come into the trap fired on by the first Co on top mountain an this started them with a rain</p>
        <pb n="16" facs="0012_002408_000201_0016.jpg" xml:id="d4e124"/>
        <p>down the mountain with a rush between this timber what recently been cut away at each 60 they were fired upon at short range killing many &amp; wounding more. when my Co orthe detachment I was with was a sight I had never seen befor &amp; I thought a rather cowardly again though all is fair in war When the dust and smoke lifted so I coud see &amp; being hungry I slid down among thedead &amp; took of a haver sack pretty well filled with striped bacon &amp; brot back into line the man I got it from did not need it after that the remainder of the command surrendered to our men a while further onWe then had about 200 prisners &amp; quite a number of them wounded on our hands 18 miles in theenemys county after providing for the wounded the best we could and destroying all there armes we had to save ourselves through the mountains &amp; woods with all the horses prisoners <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">&amp; C</unclear> to the Gap again. We had been in such a strengh to live for two month that all was consumed &amp; on the 17th Sept at dark wasordered to file out of the strong hold to what point no on seemd to know the 5 Tenn my Regt was</p>
        <pb n="17" facs="0012_002408_000201_0017.jpg" xml:id="d4e131"/>
        <p>among the first that moved out &amp; was haled some mile or more beond the mountain I think about where Martellesboro is now. There we lay on the side of the road until all the army passed out evey thing which could burn in the way of corn building &amp; was let on fine during the night the roadbehind us was blown away &amp; there we lay until it looked like a small ridge of sand. The dust from the passing troops At the break of day the 18 we were on the march but where no one knew that was for thehigher offices to know. The night was memorable by the absence of many of the Tenn troops as they thought best to go home &amp; also memorable of a trip with no food. What was before us no one knew buta forced march seemed to be on hand</p>
        <pb n="18" facs="0012_002408_000201_0018.jpg" xml:id="d4e135"/>
        <p>The was called up about daylight and a dirtyer set of men I never saw as they all were after having laynin the heavy dust near the roadside all the night &amp; the whole army passing them when the sand was verydeep just before daylight we were treated with quite a novel sight to us at that time all the Govt Commbuilgs on to mountain were burned and quit a lot of heavy amunition with the explosions &amp; the burning of the buildings was a grand sight This forced march began on the morning of the 18th Sept 1862 &amp; continued for the next 17 day &amp; night without intermission except for a very short rest and sleep &amp; without any thing to eat except as it came in the way in the march &amp; from the small mountain farms</p>
        <pb n="19" facs="0012_002408_000201_0019.jpg" xml:id="d4e139"/>
        <p>It was not long before one could march on a year of corn though he may have never done so before water was very scarse and hard to find enough at the crossing of the mountain beds of the creeks The only place to get water was the holes which still contained some water I remembr to grave gone to one of these places for coffee water &amp; placed my cup on the fire with water as near like coffee as could be before the coffee was in it Coffee had to be made quick &amp; I got mine to boiling befor the call was made to move but I carried it as it was to cool but before drinking found I had a tadpole &amp; small fish swimming on to of the coffee This did not keep me from drinking the coffee. It was found that</p>
        <pb n="20" facs="0012_002408_000201_0020.jpg" xml:id="d4e143"/>
        <p>by soaking hard cane in water it would do to grit and as they were may tin plates among the soldiers it did not take long with a Bayo net to make gritters to grind the corn taken in the fields I have seen as many as one hundred men at one time sitting on the road gritting into a haversack ready for useif ever a stop was made long enough to cook it The Confed were before us and in rear cutting timber in the roade in front of catching &amp; shooting all strgglin If a wagon got out of fix it was at once set on fire with all it contained The line of march passed though Manchester Ky at this point I was detailed to be present with others to carry out a decision courtmartial a man</p>
        <pb n="21" facs="0012_002408_000201_0021.jpg" xml:id="d4e147"/>
        <p>to be shot for something done some time before &amp; the day of execution came on that day &amp; their It was a Ky man &amp; I learned in his own county when shot This wall was made to avoid a larger Confed army which had gone into Ky West &amp; the part opposing us was not enough toonly detain the movement of our forces until a larger force could be brot up &amp; fore we could reach the Ohio River I remember one moring I was very hungry and as the command had stoped for a few moments I steped into a small cabbin on the road near our Co. The first thing that took my eye was a hot hoecake on the table near the door just layed out &amp; the woman putting more doe in the bake &amp; while shedid that I took the cake from the table Hot as it was</p>
        <pb n="22" facs="0012_002408_000201_0022.jpg" xml:id="d4e151"/>
        <p>and put it under my coat It burnt me but that was not to be considered with a hungry man This Hoecake divided among four was not enough but helped out In a few day we reached the Ohio river and got a long breath agan We lost many men by smuggling &amp; capture There is one instance which I did not mention before The orders of march that weshould not break in to the fields &amp; gardens promicusly but many times it was alone &amp; a garden eat up &amp; passed over but at this speacal time early in the moring came to a cabbage patch or it had been &amp; thestalks were standing so the boys were in the patch getting all the stalks they could but were fearful of theguard and all at once the Gen rode up with his staff to the fence &amp; evy man droped the stalks &amp; began toedge away when the Gen called to them as if he was displeased and politely asked for a stalk it seemed each man wanted give him one although they all wanted one themselves So above we reach the Ohio &amp; <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">assed</unclear> into Ohio we came into the army in March &amp; now stil last of Oct&amp; had had no pay. being cut</p>
        <pb n="23" facs="0012_002408_000201_0023.jpg" xml:id="d4e159"/>
        <p>off from the outside &amp; the pay office. Here at Gallipoliswe were paid &amp; drew new cloths tints &amp; in fact nearly every thing new. at this place we had a rest ofabout a month when we shipped on steamboat for Cinn &amp; Louisville. My first &amp; about all my sick spellcame on while on the boat I was quite sick when we arrived at Louisville on our landing late in theevening I tryed to keep my place in ranks though the city but failed to keep up so stepd out of line to thesidewalk &amp; stat down How long I had been sitting on the kirb with my face in my hands &amp; my elbow onmy knees I could not tell but lookd up &amp; the city had been lit up &amp; there was not the sign of a soldier onthe street &amp; I was lost for the time but took the middle of the street where sign of the Regt remained Icould follow them to the camp It was late when I got in &amp; our possion in line of camp came to be in a sinkhole &amp; we were on the ground that night came a storm &amp; the water came from all directions &amp; before we could get out the water was half way up the tent side &amp; I was sick enough before this wetting</p>
        <pb n="24" facs="0012_002408_000201_0024.jpg" xml:id="d4e163"/>
        <p>The Regt remained at Louisville but a short time when they were ordered to Nashville&amp; to march not by train I had been out at boarding house during the short stop at Louisville Had not recovered from the jaundice I could have reported sick and gon on train to Nashville which would been much the best for me as a 300 mile walk was no small matter even in war times the days marches wereshort owing to the fact the days were short and that we were guarding a great <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">ivory</unclear> ambulance through toNashville. This was the latter part of Novr 62 and cold &amp; disagreeable reaching Bowlingreen and afterspending the night in the mud as it had rained very much the day befor. Were called up in quick orderabout daylight marched upon the hill above the town to some old breastworks &amp; told to get into the ditches which we did &amp; they were half filled with water. It was only for a short time when we were ordered out cooked breakfast &amp; passed on our march This was on the eve of the battle at Murfreesboro&amp; the ambulancs were for that <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">any</unclear>
            </p>
        <pb n="25" facs="0012_002408_000201_0025.jpg" xml:id="d4e172"/>
        <p>on marching Nashville I was still not well by anymeans. Camp was made west of the town and we had about gotten settled when my Co &amp; another Cowere ordered to go foraging A hik of this kind would take you some ten or fifteen miles away until the train sent with the escort was filled up with corn &amp; we had gone over one of the pikes westward about 10 miles where one of the picket came riding back with the word that we were meeting with a fuel brigade of cavelry &amp; artilery but that they seemed to be turning of to our right our two Cos with 40 wagons were then in a cave on the pike but get back we must the two Cos went to the end of the caveand in sight of the cavelry &amp; ordered the wagoners to come up and turn which a few of them did but when they began to thunder back passed the others they began to turn on the pike &amp; in the fields by anear accident the got heads the otherway &amp; raised a big dust In the mean time the two Cos were watching the other line comeing up and moving off our road there was not</p>
        <pb n="26" facs="0012_002408_000201_0026.jpg" xml:id="d4e176"/>
        <p>a gun fired from either side although we in plain sight while standing in I noticed considerable excitement among the men not fear but to hide something soon found they were loded down with fac simle Confed money and they were trying to hide it destroy it in any to not have it on their persons if captured. Base counterfit money bought Cinn &amp; Louisville 50 ¢ per 1000 They tore it up put it in the gunsand chewed it up as fast as possible It was said to be death to have it &amp; come from the Yankee army After getting the wagons all in line to return the two Cos fell in line &amp; marched back or in that direction The whole cause of robbing taken in was that the Confed forces wished to pass the neighborhood of Nashville very quietly so did us no harm The next day we the Regt was order out on that same pike to catch cavetry which had passed that point 4 hours before on coming to the crossroad We followd all day but no idea of catching up with them. Soon after leaving the city</p>
        <pb n="27" facs="0012_002408_000201_0027.jpg" xml:id="d4e180"/>
        <p>it began to rain &amp; on this crossroad a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">creek</unclear> rain down between the hills for miles it seemed with the rain and the waiding the creek almost continuously</p>
        <pb n="28" facs="0012_002408_000201_0028.jpg" xml:id="d4e187"/>
        <p>We marchd down that creek and in the rain for two hours or more until night came and the Regt was called a hault to prepair for the night marched up into a field tocamp The rain was still poring down It was so bad that the dry rails would not burn all that we could do to make them I should of said the creek spoke of is Dog Creek, the rain continued to pour don until about 12 at night then it began to snow as fast as it had rained before 12 the whole regt standing or passing around in the rain snow &amp; slush I notice a small cabbin not far away &amp; turned away to go to it &amp; if possible get a dry spot to rest in as I was <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">some</unclear> ill not having gotten over the jaundi Going down the first came on a soldier with his gun trying to take the bed of an old sow &amp; pigs He would drive them out from under the boards &amp; get in but the pigs would at once come in and over him The sow was</p>
        <pb n="29" facs="0012_002408_000201_0029.jpg" xml:id="d4e194"/>
        <p>was trying to come in also but the soldier was keeping her off with his gun &amp; it was a fight all the time I passed on no chance with him &amp; the other finally getting down to the cabbin it was filled tothe door and no chance ever to look in went back behind to the kitchen &amp; smokehouse no chance in either. In the dark I could see enough to see the end of a place <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">cake</unclear> a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">dairy</unclear> or potatoes I climed up to the square hole and put one foot in and some one swor at me to get off o him I fixed my feet so that I would not be on him &amp; let <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">allhats</unclear> go in tumbled Just so I was in all I cared to know &amp; remained in that position until daylight when I crawled out of a potatoe hole &amp; in to the snow about four inchs deep After a breakfast of Hard tack &amp; bacon. The day before march was to be made over with the exception of the rain but we had the snow and the creek to contend with. We made the trip to Nashville during the night with our cloths frozed stiff on us</p>
        <pb n="30" facs="0012_002408_000201_0030.jpg" xml:id="d4e207"/>
        <p>Dec 62. While making the foregoing trip the Murfreesboro battle was going on part of the time in leaving. The stop in Nasville was only to get ready to move on to the last of war then at Murfreesboro The weather was very cold and pikes frozen The 18 miles between N. &amp; M was a perfect waste country the pike passed a very fine farming country The pike was all that was left of it it seemed It was so that as far as you could see on each side was fealds &amp; had been fine farms but not a rail or a barn out house or any thing of the kind at times a fined welling stood on the pike alone and at one place a piano stood out against the house &amp; a soldier passing give it a thrump &amp; pass on This lookd like war and it was just ahead of us coming on the battle was over but fireing was going on some miles forwd in the direction of Hawkin Tn It came to us to bury the deadboth in our &amp; beast</p>
        <pb n="31" facs="0012_002408_000201_0031.jpg" xml:id="d4e211"/>
        <p>Which took a week or so I could not say how many dont know they were many ditches 1/2 mile long &amp; even in the road dint drawn from the side of the soldier as he lay in the road I noticed one in particular when the road crossed one of the ditches a mans foot &amp; leg stuck up above the ground and another his back all open as a wagon had passed very near him removing all the dirt from his back A small creek ran down through our camp &amp; that suppled us with water. It wash flush &amp; full but in time rundown into banks &amp; in that stream was many dead men as well as horses &amp; mules laying on the banks &amp; in the branch The Regt remained at this place until Apl 1863 wen we march northard to Carthge Tenn on the Cumberland river above Nashville This seemd to be a camp of rest as we remained here on small duty, for the soldier But while at this place my brother Andrew <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">C</unclear> was killed <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">Gattilen</unclear> was 22 miles away in</p>
        <pb n="32" facs="0012_002408_000201_0032.jpg" xml:id="d4e221"/>
        <p>the L &amp; N road was making way from Murfrsboro by the way of Nashville to our camps and was ambushed &amp; killed with others in the party. During the mo Sept the little army broke camp &amp; moved in the direction of Chattanoga were reports two armies were getting together The first place of any importance McMinnville here we stoped for a day &amp; in this town I had two young lady cousins &amp; they had a sister in Kingston my home so they took up the idea to come through with the little army &amp; get to friends On the army leaving Mc I was left making arrangment to take them Had to get conveyance at last got started with an old Ambulance &amp; by had doing caught therear of the army at foot of mountain about night Just on top some miles ahead was Busheba spings &amp; the army were going into camp at that place but we were behind a narrow road &amp; 100 wagons ahead of us.So it was very late in getting them to camp even let alone when I could put them in</p>
        <pb n="33" facs="0012_002408_000201_0033.jpg" xml:id="d4e225"/>
        <p>safety the only chance was to put them into a small camp house &amp; drive the ambulance to the door &amp; sleep in that the Girls in the camp house &amp; to sleep with out supper or any thing to sleep on The next night got them with the Col wife who was with the army The next day the Ambulance broke down &amp; beside that we were being pushed on with all haste as a battle was eminant near Chattanooga Coming to the Tenn River a pontoon was layed which took time but finished so the army could cross during the night but by this time I had to give up any attention to girls and left that to Lieut Bacon who was sick &amp; allowed to ride &amp; they got horses after the ambulance gave out crossing the river at night I lost sight of them until next morning at daylight they turned up again that day at noon wen in hearing of the battle &amp; every thing on the move</p>
        <pb n="34" facs="0012_002408_000201_0034.jpg" xml:id="d4e230"/>
        <p>At daylight &amp; after marching nearly on a run all nigh we were in hearing of the big guns at Chickmague though 12 or 15 miles away the two young ladies came up with the command during the morning having found a place to stop at a farm house Lieut Bacon taking care of them The season had been dry for quiet awhile and the army road was worne out dry as it was. The push was kept up &amp; late in the evening we arrived in the neighborhood of Chatta &amp; Shitehed Tn The night towards Raesville. This was on the eve of the retreat or falling back of Rosechans part of the army after marching in the direction of Rossville &amp; charge was made &amp; we were made to form in battleline across the vally night resting on Lookout Mountain. It was now dark &amp; we five miles from the battlefield no one knew why we were deployed in this way except the high offices but it was not long befor we could see that something was wrong &amp; by day light it seemed the whole of Rosenwans army was ontop of us &amp; we had order to stop them &amp; keep them back They were run like cattle &amp; would run over</p>
        <pb n="35" facs="0012_002408_000201_0035.jpg" xml:id="d4e234"/>
        <p>my small fence. After the Infantry came tho artilley taking possition at intervales &amp; wheeling round fireing &amp; then on again towards Chatta This was going on for the day Thousands passing going somewhere no one knew but supposed our army was whipped. At last the end came with arush of soldier artiley wagons rigers citzens and no one could tell what but the nois behind was enough satisfy any one. The fireing was heavy for a time &amp; we were thrown out of the valley on to the side of Lookout Mountain &amp; not long before the firing came hot and heay on our little bregade The enemy was too strong for us &amp; we were forsed slowly up the mountain Then came some not fighting for a time The next day the two armys were in sight below us. we could see both sides as they moved here &amp; there We were then cut off from any other command Rosecrans in Chatta &amp; a part of the army somewhere east ofus but we had enough to day to care for any one else. After two 3 days a plan was fallen on to befor daylight to pass down the bluff to the river brink within a few hundred yards of the enemy</p>
        <pb n="36" facs="0012_002408_000201_0036.jpg" xml:id="d4e238"/>
        <p>and under cover of the river bank got into Chatta join that part of the main army I had not seen the two girls now for four or five days Did not know what had become of them as the town was full of strgglers wounded men dead men and in fact every thing which could happen to a routed army. During the day Lt Bacon found us &amp; reported that he had put them back with them in it into the line of wagons ambulances artillery &amp; C going across the army bridge. They were then safe or as much so as could bein the circumstances The enemy closed in on Chatta very close so near that a band playing in one army would be taken at times for the other. During the month the 5th Infty ordered to guard the Tenn Riverabove Chatta &amp; were placed at different point up the River a Co at a place This was nice work only had to watch out for balls from the opposite side of the river &amp; make them feel the same way This continued only for a short time when we were ordered to</p>
        <pb n="37" facs="0012_002408_000201_0037.jpg" xml:id="d4e242"/>
        <p>Kingston where I was born and partly raised. The stop was for only one night as Knoxville was the point we seemed to be moving for. At the time that we were marching up the north side of the river a Southern force was marching up on the South side This force under Longstreet coming to Loudon the Regt was stoped to guard the bridge They had been some fighting at Lenons 18 miles from Knoxville While on the River guard below Kingston I met with the misfortune to be arrested and not allowed to take command of my Co or to <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">warn</unclear> my sword to keep in camp in my tent This was all owing to my <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">entrusting</unclear> a man into my Co that some other fellow <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">arrested</unclear> in his &amp; he had the son of the General &amp; I was not heard in the affair I was approached a time or two by the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">Ma</unclear> marshal to make statement to the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">goal</unclear> that I was wrong &amp; the charges would be released. This I would not do &amp; so when I came to my home town was <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">under a cloud</unclear> but soon after leaving Kingston the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">signs</unclear> was good for a fight at Loudon &amp; soon had my release</p>
        <pb n="38" facs="0012_002408_000201_0038.jpg" xml:id="d4e268"/>
        <p>The Regt was stoped at Loudon guarding bridge Just after the battle of Knoxville After a week we were ordered on towards Knoxville the siege having been raised and Longstreet was on his march to Va &amp; Burnside to the taking care of the wounded &amp; burying the dead which was almost entirely on the one side The Confed Soldier, we were no stop about Knoxville passing through and on up to Straw plains the first stop we made as Longstreet was much ahead &amp; no chance to catch up with him from Straw plains we moved on up North bank of the Hosteston to opposite New Market If I remember right first part of Dec 1863 One of the coldest nights I ever experienced was at this point near New Mar</p>
        <pb n="39" facs="0012_002408_000201_0039.jpg" xml:id="d4e272"/>
        <p>After being here some two months broke camp &amp; turned south over the same ground through Knoxville landing at ConCord some 18 miles below Knoxville. At this point it was found the Regt was afficted with small pox and were scattered one Co at a place until the desease would subside. My Co had some 14 cases of it Camp was boken about the 1st of May 64 and march was contined Southward &amp; in a few days reach Cleveland where we branched off towards Dalton &amp; was soon in a part hearing of Sherman army at Buggard Roots of Rocky fall ridge The soldiers under Johnston were soon diven back and we in the neighborhood of Dalton &amp; a part of Shearmans army of 60000 men with Joston in front of him with about</p>
        <pb n="40" facs="0012_002408_000201_0040.jpg" xml:id="d4e276"/>
        <p>the same number Johnston had made a stand and was behind breastwork at Snake Creek gap when some fighting came of betwen parts of the army Seemed only to be the outpost of the main position which Johnson had selected at Rassuca Ga &amp; by the 14th of May all prepration were made to alter his positionMy Regt was in battle line in sight of the works the night of the 13 and remained all night on there arms It was 9 oclock on 14th before any move was mad but the two picket lines between the two armies were fireing back In front of us an open field some 300 yds wide between the two lines with now and then a dead tree &amp; in the center of the field a long ridge which extended paralel with the line of battle at about9 oclk as we were in front the order was givn to forward &amp; on we went</p>
        <pb n="41" facs="0012_002408_000201_0041.jpg" xml:id="d4e280"/>
        <p>at a right shoulde shift until the crest of the hill spoken of was reached &amp; in plain view of the enemys was across a hollow &amp; small branch and up the hill when the line reached the top the fireing became terrific as the whole line was at the time in plain view for their works not more than 200 yards away we wer soon across the branch and climbing up the hill &amp; the works which driving the enemy out &amp; settling into the ditch the enemy had only moved out of one to take possesion of the next. Two or three of my men ranback down the hill and I to bring them back which I did &amp; mussed the line &amp; passed on betwen the two contending lines where I was wounded with a ball through my arm as well as all the men brot back in bringing the men back in line as I thought we had passed the enemys ditches which our <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">men</unclear> was</p>
        <pb n="42" facs="0012_002408_000201_0042.jpg" xml:id="d4e287"/>
        <p>and at the point where we would reach the ditch there was no ditch or work &amp; so passed the fireing line &amp; between the two contending armys just beond the first ditch &amp; works on anothe hill they had the 2nd works &amp; I was betwen two fires the Regt came to me at once and ordered me back to theline and at the same moment ask me what was the matter My answer was that I could not raise my hands &amp; he at once said was wounded &amp; of which I realized my left. One of the men had a shot through both thies &amp; died in a day or so after an operation The other two or three were wounded The Rgt had me to fall back to the line and still behind it under the brow of the hill &amp; <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">to</unclear> an old fallen tree which the roots had held &amp; made a safe place to be. By this time I had become sick &amp; feeling bad as the ball was about half way through my arm coming out near the wrist &amp; was very painful After crawling up under the old roots a driver boy came passed &amp; he tied up my arm as well</p>
        <pb n="43" facs="0012_002408_000201_0043.jpg" xml:id="d4e294"/>
        <p>and while he was doing this a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">burub</unclear> came down within about 8 feet of us and burried itself in the ground &amp; in a second burst &amp; nearby covered us up with rock &amp; dirt the Rgt sent me one of my own to go out with me one Bird Card &amp; as soon as I felt that I could go started by side of him with my well arm round his neck or shoulders but with much missgivings as we had to pass over a small ridge to get out which was being litterly torn all to pices with burub shell let alone the small arms fire. After going a few hundred feet we came in tothe midst of this and my man being too fast for me I droped loose and he made for a dead tree in thefield &amp; I to scramble the best I could for an other quite a large tree &amp; stood very high dead with bark &amp; limbs on it but not to be long as they were falling all round when I got to it &amp; got round so the bullets would hit the &amp; not me I got round &amp; with my back to it with the limbs and bark</p>
        <pb n="44" facs="0012_002408_000201_0044.jpg" xml:id="d4e301"/>
        <p>falling all round but I was safe if no sollid ball of large size did not hit the tree The bark &amp; limbs I could stand for a time The tree was being filled with lead but I was not hurt. After I had rested up a little for another move to the woods &amp; down hill made anothr move &amp; went to the woods &amp; down the hill where I found some surgeons and many wounded ansked to be attend to but they refused saying that I could walk and they had many to attend that could not walk I passed on with the ball beteen the bons of my arm giving me much pain at this point my man came to me again and helped me on for a time but getting sick againlay don to rest not thinking where I was but very soon a battery which had just stationed itself in the brush a short distace above us opened out with the full six guns just over my head &amp; not far away so this would not do &amp; I tryed to walk on as the main hospital was a mile</p>
        <pb n="45" facs="0012_002408_000201_0045.jpg" xml:id="d4e306"/>
        <p>or so further on. At this point my father met me on horse back &amp; said that he expected something of the kind Told me to rid his horse which I tryed to do but could not &amp; let him go on and I would do the same I followed the ambulances &amp; by this time they were many, to the gen Hospital &amp; soon had the ball out &amp; feeling well. This ground was a fearful sight The operating room of place for that purpose was an old shead used Isuppose to store cotton qute lenghty rails had been put up on forks making tables for operation puposes and the wounded put upon them The building &amp; tables were full when I arrived and many laying on the ground outside I asked why so many and some of my own Co and acquaintances were left out in that way &amp; the answer was they were hurt too bad to pay any attention to that is they would die anyway &amp; I saw them living that day &amp; the next &amp; so on dont begin to know how</p>
        <pb n="46" facs="0012_002408_000201_0046.jpg" xml:id="d4e310"/>
        <p>many I was issued a little tent called in the army a dog tent and put it up on some bushes so I could keep dry. Soon aft putting my tent another was put up beside of me I soon learned that he was a Ky Col and seriously wouned That night the Col made so much nois that I could not rest so I moved to anothr place this battle began on Saty morning and continued until Monday morning I had counted on going back but the regulations would not allow of it my right arm being uslesless. About for or five days afer the battle I had orders to board a stock car and report at Chattanooga when I landed at Chatta soon found no place for me but should report top Lookout Mountain Offies hospital. On arrival at the last naimed place was shown my quarters a small building had been used for parties visting the mountain before the unpleasentness begun</p>
        <pb n="47" facs="0012_002408_000201_0047.jpg" xml:id="d4e314"/>
        <p>There was a very large building on same ground had once been a hotel now used by the army as Hospital orating room I had fought over this ground more than a year befor this I knew something of it After bing cooped up for a time I becam anxious to go back but could not go until I was regularly dischged from the hospital They were so many offices who seemed to me were their having a regular picnic and keeping away from the fireing line So I began to think of someway to get away from the Hospital &amp; asked the Dr in charge Dr<unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">Kitchen</unclear> to tell me when he would give leave to go back to the army He promised to do so and in a few day made examination of my wound &amp; my gen health &amp; when he finished I asked him what about it and he answered that he could letme off inside of 90 days or 3 months I was surprised at this and told him so but he said I was not only wounded but sick other</p>
        <pb n="48" facs="0012_002408_000201_0048.jpg" xml:id="d4e321"/>
        <p>ways &amp; that the rules would not let him do so soone. but said he would give me a pass Chattaga This was about the 15th June 64 and in a few days gave me pass to visite Chatta for 3 days &amp; told me would then want to come back I got the pass and boarded the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">track</unclear> for Chatta was well fixd for money as I had drawn my pay at the Hospital &amp; had some $500 in large bills Arriving at Chatta a very hot day and the first thing got my pass counter signed by the provo officer for the 3 days that I had to spend Then I went to a small steamer which ran to Kingston &amp; up the River thinking to send a good portion of my money home in this I failed at I could find no one that I knew to whom I could turn over the money coming back into town my first ida was to find if I could board a train for the front Had no pass to go on passenger so looked up a freight and after questioning the engineer of a very long train he gave me to know he would move out 4 Oclock then</p>
        <pb n="49" facs="0012_002408_000201_0049.jpg" xml:id="d4e328"/>
        <p>went back into town and purchased about all that I thought would need on the way &amp; some clothing some cheese &amp; crackers &amp; I came back to the back end of his train which was a long one climed up with my purhases &amp; through a small window The doors being all locked up the car was loaded with cornsacks &amp; made a clean place to travel The sun was very hot for a while as in a close car with tin roof made it very uncomfortable until the train moved off I had no way of knowing we were going the right direction but cou not think that train could be going any where else than to the front the train moved off about 4 Oclock &amp; my situation became better as the heat was not so bad with train moving I had been in the car for some hours &amp; nearly dark when the train stoped &amp; the engine had water then they moved on until my car came to the tank &amp; the engine taking on wood so I climed out filled my canteen and back to have say <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">susapen</unclear> Done with that I made</p>
        <pb n="50" facs="0012_002408_000201_0050.jpg" xml:id="d4e335"/>
        <p>myself as commfortable as I could and went to sleep on the corn sks I knew nothing more as I sleped soundly until the ring of Musketry and the crash of the cars one climbing on top of the other in a cut of the RR I could feel that my car was standing at about 45 Dg but the balls coming through I took more notice of than how the wreck was going on My position was not good as the balls came through the tire both sides &amp; hit in the middle so as I could only use one hand I managed to set up a corn sack with my left hand and took my place where the sack had layn This proceeding kept on for some little time but long enough for me When the officer gave the command to cease fireing then they was quiet for a time until a scramble cound be heard of the whole business coming down on each side in to the cars which</p>
        <pb n="51" facs="0012_002408_000201_0051.jpg" xml:id="d4e339"/>
        <p>wer in a mess. Wile lying down in my bed betwen the sacks and the one sitting up by my head was a protection while the fireing was going on I thought of my money in my pocket in a bran new pocket book and about five hundred dollars Hadbeen paid five month salary at the hospital I managed to get my boot off with one hand and took the larger amt just as it happened and put into my boot putting it on again I hoped they would not enter thecar or open the side doors but that was not to be as in a few moments after they came down to the car they were hammering at the lock to break it which was soon done &amp; the sound of a hundred voices came in to me When the door was opened I could see out just enough to know when one was in the door and that was not long as the sound of a saber was rattling on the car irons &amp; it was not long before the person came in view with his saber in his hand He certanly looked big</p>
        <pb n="52" facs="0012_002408_000201_0052.jpg" xml:id="d4e343"/>
        <p>to me I felt smaller than ever I could only see him dimly The first thing he did was to see my traps near the big door when there was a kind of open among the corn sacks my traveling bag was a large haversack bought that day at Chatta for 500 <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">nunoer</unclear> and filled with good clothing. As soon as he saw it he reach out &amp; put in on himself asI would have done then saw my sword and belt all together he hung that on the hook of his own feet. by this time one or more had climed into the car In a few moments one of them moved out of my sight towards the other end of the car where I could not see him but could hear him all the time He would it seemed make a step and ram his saber as deep as he could down through the corn &amp; I could hear that &amp; knew it would be but a short time before he would be round near me if not just then</p>
        <pb n="53" facs="0012_002408_000201_0053.jpg" xml:id="d4e350"/>
        <p>I had heard the saber go down and thought it very close to me so raised up on my feet &amp; was just under him the next would have gon into me I gave up &amp; told him in the dark that I would &amp; he said certainly you will your <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">Dmd Seveokrsite</unclear> get out here &amp; took hold of my wounded arm which broke the would &amp; made it blead very much They pulled me around between them hunting valuables until I was pretty well cleaned up curseing me all the time I was then ordered out &amp; to get out was a hard matter for me as I only had one hand &amp; the car at about 45 dg I hit the ground in a bable of voices &amp; could hardly see any one. One man put his hand on my head &amp; swore I had a fine hat something I did not know myself as I had been lyingdown &amp; did not think but what had been relieved of all I had that was in any way loose So he took it off andput his old hat</p>
        <pb n="54" facs="0012_002408_000201_0054.jpg" xml:id="d4e357"/>
        <p>on my head but he had hardly passed on before another saw that I was aprisoner and he did the same thing I was swapping hats freely &amp; did not care after the first swap was made I had paid that day for my hat five dollars at Chatta When they had kept me standing at the car andrelieving me of any thing they could see ordered me to climb up the bank on RR Cut &amp; then into line bythis time they had a small fire giving some light I had stood in line a short time found that I had my papers from the Hospital still about me threw them back into the bushes An old fellow came along theline I suppos he needed a pr boots &amp; seemed to want mine I beged him off by running my boots down asworthless and standing pat on them He gave it up and went to annother prisoner for a pr I considered my boots to worth five hundred dollars or about that &amp; I would rather keep them They got all above that &amp; my new pocket book before I left the car I asked one of them while</p>
        <pb n="55" facs="0012_002408_000201_0055.jpg" xml:id="d4e361"/>
        <p>or rather told them Ihad in my haversack one thing which could do them no good if they would give that to me they might have the balance with pleasure &amp; that was my mothers photo. They answered me it would be fine to shoot at they told us some 40 who was not killed that when we came into the trap was about 2 Oclk inthe morning &amp; soon began to show signs of daylight &amp; I was feeling very bad indeed as my wound kept bleeding and I was sick besid sick for being a great fool to not stay where I could have been my own boss for 3 mos and lay in the shade &amp; now I was tied up for an unknown time possibly never see the old state again &amp; about this time coming daylight we were hussled off southward mostly thogh the woods seemed to be an old road I got sick &amp; as I was falling in the rear they told me to get hold of a horse tail so I could keep up I did not do that but the muzzle of a shotgun at the back of</p>
        <pb n="56" facs="0012_002408_000201_0056.jpg" xml:id="d4e366"/>
        <p>was a reminder that I should keep up After coming into a better road &amp; daylight our guards relaxed to some extent but kept us between two lines of horse The fact is when I came to see our crowd it made me smile if no more some had on tights Some half clothed some not at all you may say The man next to me had nothing on but socks drawes &amp; under shirt and this was only a sample of the 40 men in fact I had fared better than most of them My great uneasness was for my money which I was then tramping on and wearing out How long it would last I could not imagine &amp; then if they thought of it my boots might suit some soldier in the ranks of the other side. I was marching by the side of the man who was dressed so lightly and we becam friends for the time He said they had his boots but could not wear them as they hung on the saddle &amp; between us we got the officer to give them to him. It was not long before we came to a creek which was swollen</p>
        <pb n="57" facs="0012_002408_000201_0057.jpg" xml:id="d4e370"/>
        <p>from recent rains &amp; was waist deep or more and as I was anxious about my money and a good chance to clam sick ask my friend to carry me over or in other words ride on his back He was ready to assit me and I climed onto his back with my feet piching forward above the water This was done with many curs words from our guards as we were getting behind After waiding in he seemed to be very unsteady &amp; abut the middle of the stream he floundered somuch so that I went off over his head &amp; he was down &amp; I was under the water I came up &amp; at once wiped the water from my face &amp; told the guard had a gravel in my boot to please let me take it out. heswore at me and told me to take it out and if we go to behind he would loose us as Gen Forrest did and asked me if I knew how that was I told him I had heard how he did but I was going to keep up I pulled off the boot with the money in it and got the roll in</p>
        <pb n="58" facs="0012_002408_000201_0058.jpg" xml:id="d4e374"/>
        <p>my hand without his knowing it Then we ran to catch up with the other prisoners I was very uneasy with my money in that shape as they possibly &amp; did search for more booty which they had missed at the start The money was very wet and in bad shape but the longer I carried it in my hand the better During the day they fed the prisoners on cornbread &amp; raw bacon &amp; to eat the bacon had have a knife to cut it I asked for a knife &amp; one of the guards gave his &amp; as soon as I saw it knew the knife &amp; told him so He said the Yanks had it yesterday but wehave it today I would return it as soon as I finished my meal while I had the knife I cut a slit on the inside of my ristband and afterwards pressed the the money into it I shall here describe something of how the prisoners looked when it came daylight At the first sight I</p>
        <pb n="59" facs="0012_002408_000201_0059.jpg" xml:id="d4e378"/>
        <p>could not help but laugh alhough did not feel it the man walking by my side had nothing on at all but under shirt drawers &amp; socks The man walking before me was a tall westener and changed his good army blue for a very shortpr of pants &amp; it looked as if hey had been cut off at the bottom as well as the waist His drawers wer of his own &amp; hung don to the ground the pants only covered him in the middle &amp; so on The man I firstmention told me he was Adg_Gen on Gen Judahs staff I only had his word for it &amp; I think he was telling the truth but couldt prove it in any way neither could any one else but I knew that Gen Judah was in command in <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">How a</unclear> no army. He had taken the freight to be in time at the front &amp; got caught as I had &amp; his suit had been so fine that the Rebs had use for it all. and left him in a bad fix fight marching order</p>
        <pb n="60" facs="0012_002408_000201_0060.jpg" xml:id="d4e385"/>
        <p>After getting in line of march again I manged to stuff the money in my wastband not long afte one of the guard took out of his pocket a fine guantlet glove and said to the crowd that he had oneg love and would like to have the mate and if any one had the other he would be fare and pay for it I was walking near him and knew that I had the mate to the one he held up but was afraid to say so as then they would fall upon me &amp; take the other. After thinking over the matter I came to the conclusion that I would talk to him any way and if he ment wat he said I would sell him the mate I asked him if I could find it among the prisoners what would he give for it He at once said he would give $10 00 for the mate but I did not bite at once and as I kept my place near his horse and at last took out the whiteback &amp; held it to me I took it and turned over to him the glove</p>
        <pb n="61" facs="0012_002408_000201_0061.jpg" xml:id="d4e389"/>
        <p>This ment only about 1 50 in our mony as the Confed money was going 6 for 100 in greenback The next few days found us at a little place called cave Springs and a pretty place it was but we could not enjoy a stroll as others might at thispoint the Texas rangers who had taken us in returned and we about 40 men were left in charge of a homeguard Co and under them took the road again which was red clay &amp; very muddy I had known there was no use in trying to get out of the trouble with money with the first crowd but after traveling with the last batch began to think more about it so I began to complain of my wound also having been just out of the Hospital &amp; directing all my complaints to a certain old man who seemed to pay more attention to my situation than the others after a time I took hold of his stirup straps to keep up but all the time we werefalling to the rear It seemed to me the old man &amp; a young man roade together &amp; it was not long befor the</p>
        <pb n="62" facs="0012_002408_000201_0062.jpg" xml:id="d4e393"/>
        <p>the old man said to the young man that we were getting behind &amp; the prsoner would give out so they agreed that I could ride &amp; the young man walk beside me just what I wished as I could not talk to him from the ground without being heard by others I took the prefered seat in the saddle with pleasure as I was certainly tired but if could have had a chance then could have beaten a good horse for a short run After getting into the saddle I began to put the questions pretty fast and all the time feeling the old man as to the war <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">&amp;</unclear> he said as much as that he had been forced to come down and act in the capacity he was in and that he did not believe much in the war any way &amp; in his talk said he was a Tennsean from the neighborhood of Nashville &amp; that he would like to be at home I then told him that I was a Tenn &amp; if he liked we could go to gether that I would take</p>
        <pb n="63" facs="0012_002408_000201_0063.jpg" xml:id="d4e400"/>
        <p>if we could agree to make the attempt but he said no no they would catch him &amp; hang him up but I said they would have to catch him first It was growing late in the evening and I knew that we would all be put up soon in some safe place for the night and I possibly would have no other chance with him so I said now you do not wish to go with me will you let me go if I pay you He said no no but after a few moments said he would &amp; I proposed to give him $100 in Greenback to let me out as we said he &amp; the same guy ran by my side his nephew, would beon guard at 2 Oclock the next morning and that I could go for the money. It was not long before they called a halt &amp; marched the prisoners into one big log cabbin room about room for all to lay close together &amp; fill the room a porch ran beside &amp; the guards sat outside on the poarch one on each side with double</p>
        <pb n="64" facs="0012_002408_000201_0064.jpg" xml:id="d4e404"/>
        <p>barrelled shot guns crossed inside At 2 Oclock I was awake and having prepaired the money so as to hand it to the old man I could see enough to know the old man had told me the truth and was on guard I had taken out of my wristband two bills without seeing them knowing that I had now less than $50 each and my be $100 each that I did not care for if only I could get out I had whispered into the ear of my close neighbor on the floor &amp; told him what I was doing &amp; if he wished we would go together so when the time came I got up with my money in my hand steped over part of the crowd &amp; got near to the door &amp; the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">wring</unclear> end of the old mans gun I knew he saw me coming but did not seem that he changed the position of the gun I did not at once take that as bad &amp; steped over another man on the floor &amp; was near enough to take hold of the gun &amp; put it a little to one side when the other guard punched me under arm on the opposite side Then I came</p>
        <pb n="65" facs="0012_002408_000201_0065.jpg" xml:id="d4e411"/>
        <p>to understand they did not intend to let me pass and about the same time the old man spoke very loud &amp; told me to get back This I knew was to bring notice to the other soldiers that all was not right So I told the old man still holding his gun that I wanted a drink of water which was just over his head on a shelf After I got my water crawled back and replaced my money into my wristband with much fear in misgiving as I was ceartin they would take it the next morning but morning came and we were lined out in the road &amp; nothing done or said to me &amp; I could not see why but fell into line as near to the old man as I could but not convinced of his night, work It was not long before I got a chance at him &amp; here marked &amp; said my young man I saved your life for you as the officer had noticed the day before our talk and fixed himself to shoot me as</p>
        <pb n="66" facs="0012_002408_000201_0066.jpg" xml:id="d4e415"/>
        <p>I did not believe a word of it but it was all the same to me as it turned out We were then coming near to the junction on end of the Blue Mt &amp; SelmaRR which was built but so far in the direct of Dalton At this time the junction At this place I found where I could use some of my whiteback money and bought an old shirt though clean for three dollars It was not long before we were all on board the cars going further south not a word had been said as to our destination but I was guessing it to be Andersonville. After being on the tran a time I passed into the water closet and found that about half the slats in a narrow window was out and possibly I might get out through it I first put my head out but all I could do could not get my shoulders throug &amp; to put my feet out first would have to go out side wise</p>
        <pb n="67" facs="0012_002408_000201_0067.jpg" xml:id="d4e420"/>
        <p>which looked very dangerous as I had no way of throwing my self from the train just as I had got down the guard came hunting me. Arrived at Selmawere marched up in the middle of the main street ash hot as a June day could be We seemed to be on inspection by the citizens &amp; drunken folk generally. One in particular an Irishman for his <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">brague</unclear> After cussing each one as he came down the line came in front of me and stood looking at me very closely &amp; all at one he cam out with and where in the hll did you come from After a time I told him was from Indiana as I had a man standing with me from that state &amp; could prove it by him He said at once you are a liar you are a Kent or a Tenn and I was getting to be troublesome &amp; the guard took him in hand but I did not let him get away until I told him where</p>
        <pb n="68" facs="0012_002408_000201_0068.jpg" xml:id="d4e427"/>
        <p>I came from It seemed that we were to stop at Selma for the night and board boat next day We were given the upstairs of a high building if we would not attemt to get away we could remain during the night and they would not put us in stockade So we all gave our word to the post commander that we would not attempt to go Then we were offered tobe turned loose at will if we would take the oath of the Confed states but no one seemed desirous to swall it The next day put aboard the boat which was know as one of the best on the river &amp; a man which was familiar to all, Jeff Davis, We had not state room but the bear deck &amp; during the night all my little trinket in my pockets was cleaned out some litte thing they had missed over the bullet I had the wound from was taken but I had something to show for that</p>
        <pb n="69" facs="0012_002408_000201_0069.jpg" xml:id="d4e431"/>
        <p>the bullet hole it self and at the time giveing me trouble. The fact is I was pleased they did not fret about my shirt sleave as that was worth to me about $450 about daylight on a Sunday morning we found ourselves at a landing and was told it was Cahaba Ala and the end of the journey the prison, This Sunday moring we were all marched to the mining office in the little town &amp; passed through an examination as to what we had of value &amp; c &amp; if we had more watches or any thing of value The officer offered to give recipts &amp; after being in the prison the person was allowed to check on it for any thing he may wish to buy I did not indicate that I had t omuch money about me and was not sirched so very rigidly and was passed with the money in my sleeve After all being serched fell into line for the prison &amp; on the way through the litte town the church bells were ringing nearby somewhere </p>
        <pb n="70" facs="0012_002408_000201_0070.jpg" xml:id="d4e435"/>
        <p>and if I ever felt homesick that was the time as the bell sounded very much like the old bell at home in my boyhood coming to the prison A large buildg on the bank of the Alabama river had once been used for Cotton depot with large sliding doors and on our arrival the guard pused the doors apart and a sight was before us which I will never forget Looking in over the heads of three thousand ragged dirty men crowed up in a place which was not more I judge than 100 + 60 feet all to live eat and sleep as so many cattle &amp; the hum and noises would make you sick. Our crowd was marched or squeezed in among them to certain point &amp; there a place marked off with chal kor something to designate our home Some soldier on the ground and others stood up not a word was said not long after some the prison people brought</p>
        <pb/>
        <p>in about 1/2 gal corn meal &amp; sat the vessell down among us with a stick of wood about a foot long sawed off to suit Each one looked at the bill of fare or the fare it self for a time and the next thing was how could we work the two articles so that we could begin housekeeping I pushed my way a little off from the crowd and found a man sitting on what seemed to be a pile of old Blankets I asked him some question Dont know what but said at once Fresh fish I understood I said I guessed I was &amp; he asked me many questions as one would who had been in for a time &amp; knew nothing about what was going on outside I told him that we my comrids had so much meal &amp; chink of wood could he help us out in getting it into shape that we could have something to eat Eventually he began to move off off that pile and turn them over displayed a skillet &amp; said I dont know you &amp; if I did I would</p>
        <pb n="72" facs="0012_002408_000201_0072.jpg" xml:id="d4e443"/>
        <p>could not take the risk to let you take this &amp; held up the skillet but said he would take the article with him &amp; go to our ground so he did and among us found something to cut the wood managed to have a cake One would think how so many men could all have room when the time came for sleep This was made so that sheves or bunks built at one side up to near the top wide enough for the lengh of two men &amp; while asleep they were shoved with feet inward then a square in the center of the for others to stand or laydown next a 2 feet for those wished to stand then a foot from the wall called the dead line if on should step on that no word on order was given him but was shot on the instant At each end were two pieces of artilery looking through at you with full load of grap shot The guard walked above and in side on a platform which ran around the buildg This was about the situation &amp; bad enough when you take</p>
        <pb n="73" facs="0012_002408_000201_0073.jpg" xml:id="d4e447"/>
        <p>in the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">vermin</unclear> and fith of a prison I was sorry that I had not left my money with the officer out of the prison as if it had been found out that I had it my life would have been in great danger as was not uncomon for one prisoner to use coloroform &amp; steal <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">Clean</unclear> the cloths of another It was not long that I was in the main prison before orders came for all offices not commanding negro troops if they would sign parole they could have the privilege of better quarters and peace to exercise a little square of the town the prison so full that men could hardly live by this time 3500 men The parole was accepted and some 40 officers took advantage of it with my self no one only those who have gon through such a time can amagine how he would feel even to be liberated to that extent we could keep the place in a maner clean &amp; see the world outside These quarters we kept until about</p>
        <pb n="74" facs="0012_002408_000201_0074.jpg" xml:id="d4e457"/>
        <p>the 1st Sept 64 having been 3 mo since we first come in At this time great danger of the fedrals pouncing down and liberating the whole business <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">as</unclear> Stoneman was there in the south on a raid and it was found he would make this place a visite &amp; at this junction we were bundled off to Selma &amp; on the road to some point not known any one of us but we were going &amp; some thought were being exchanged &amp; some to Andersonville or worse. Getting to Selma I had wished to once more take a cup of coffee Lincoln coffee as called and asked the guard accomny me to a place where I could get the coffee We went to the market the cheapest place so he said I passed along down the market and at last found an old lady who said she had the real article I had thought to get a package &amp; take it back with me to the other part of the crowd but <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">as were ligating</unclear> the old lady she said here</p>
        <pb n="75" facs="0012_002408_000201_0075.jpg" xml:id="d4e467"/>
        <p>the coffee pot &amp; hers the cup I will let you have as much as you want I then asked her the price and she said $3.00 a cup and I then told her would take nine dollars worth Three cups as I had been used to at home soon after that I found that I could by 3/4 coffee but could not reach a trade owing to lack of funds but had the man to go back with me to the camp and among the crowd we manged to get the money in hand and made the purchase at $16.00 for for the whole lot We were on the train not long after and the greater part of the trip during the night with no head lights piloting along in the dark as we were in evry othr respect some thinking they were bound for liberty &amp; some for Libby quite a difference in the two places At some point we crossed the Oakloma river &amp; seemed to be going westward and in time </p>
        <pb n="76" facs="0012_002408_000201_0076.jpg" xml:id="d4e471"/>
        <p>landed at Maridean &amp; if I rember right at that point took the B &amp; O train twards Mobile and landed at Enterprise on the BO road. quarterswere made for us &amp; many liberties which we had not had before Had sweet potatoes &amp; straw to lay on which seemed one of the best feather beds I had ever slepet on Im speaking of the small number of us. It was selection of all the officrs at one time in the prison and kept to themselves &amp; given these privelages In numbers not more at any time than 100 men I dont remember how long we were at this point but later in the fall of 64 we took the same rout back to Selma Ala Enterprise being in Miss. On arival at Selma now the third time I had passed through the place During this trip we had for office of the guard we liked a drink &amp; also as much for us as he could under the rules &amp; mentioned that he had been a prisoner</p>
        <pb n="77" facs="0012_002408_000201_0077.jpg" xml:id="d4e475"/>
        <p>himself in our lines and had good treatment So when we were marchd from the train on one of the best streets in the city he led us opposite the best Hotel in the town The Gee house, &amp; lined us up gave us a talk &amp; said he was going to have us room in the Hotel instead of the barrock which all hands would prefered to being put in to this place &amp; take the insults of the patrons of the house but he would not hear to any thing but that &amp; came round for money to pay the bill which would amt to 40 00 the night After cleaning out every bit of furnture. we were <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">madld</unclear> into the room &amp; he at the door with a very big six shooter in his hand The next moring waiting for the boat to take us back to the pison the officer said that they were two or three ladies in the Hotel who desired to see us or some of us &amp; talk with us They wished to see a Yankee After looking round the crowd there was not one had blue coat except me &amp; that was a sight It was layed </p>
        <pb n="78" facs="0012_002408_000201_0078.jpg" xml:id="d4e483"/>
        <p>on myself and one other to see the ladies &amp; this brought on more trouble as our boats were worn and red with mudd Ordered to go and have a clean up &amp; to black our boots which cost us $3.00 a black &amp; we was well diked off for a call. This was all lost as for the reason as soon as we had settled into the Hotel parlor the boat whistle blew and we had to take to the river In another day we were in our old quarters in Cababa. Nothi of importance happened to excite the people except now and then a prisoner escaped or one shot by the guard on the dead line Dogs would soon bring in the escaped one and the other burried out of sight. Towards the last of Dec 64 we were again ordered to get ready for a move and as usual each one had his ideas as to the destination Selma was the first and on toward Jackson Miss which place we reachd in a short time</p>
        <pb n="79" facs="0012_002408_000201_0079.jpg" xml:id="d4e487"/>
        <p>remained one night and part of a day slept in the state capitol started on journey south and on the abandoned track of the Jackson road towards Buttenrough The whole line hadsome time before this I suppose during the Vicksbug seige been burned on at any rate all that would burn. The track had been repaired so that a hand car with six negro men for power was run over the line This kind of traviling was dificult &amp; dangerous as all bridges had been burned &amp; in the place of a bridge a post put up in mid stream &amp; the iron joints made on that. Very often coming to a train of cars or which had been a train of cars at our time but now nothing but 1/2 each place mile or so of wheels &amp; worked &amp; bent car irons &amp; just around the same place would be the Iron rails twisted while hot around the trees on the 4th Dec we halted at the little town and as the next day was <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">xmas</unclear>
            </p>
        <pb n="80" facs="0012_002408_000201_0080.jpg" xml:id="d4e493"/>
        <p>our exchange commissioner chose to stop &amp; take Christmas <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">living</unclear> with in an old house left for some peace in the neighborhood We fared at this place well for one reason that we were drawing near to the Fedrals lines and anothr that the officer in charge sent us a fine turkey or two for Chrstmas from here we left the RR line and marched through the swamps of Miss during the day we were a part of the time being watched &amp; followed by what the guard said was Jay hawkers Deserters from all the armies learned Gorilla and cut throats but wewere so pleased with the prospect of soon reaching our lines that nothing would affect us much The escort seemed to be uneasy during the whole day of the march &amp; in fact I was told</p>
        <pb n="81" facs="0012_002408_000201_0081.jpg" xml:id="d4e500"/>
        <p>they expresed the wish that we had arms and seemed to feel uneasy at the situation Some of our men becam bearfooted and need shoes So I had told one of them Capt Stacy that I had enough money to buy a pair of shoes &amp; would do so if I could find them &amp; had enough mony as at that time I cared little for money or its worth. Coming to a small shoe shop which seemed to be an abandoned lumber plant went in and asked the price of some old shoes thrown off possibly by some old negro as knew I would not have enough to pay for a good pair I asked the price with fear when the oldman answered they cold be had for $60 Thankt the half of that &amp; the whole crowd would</p>
        <pb n="82" facs="0012_002408_000201_0082.jpg" xml:id="d4e504"/>
        <p>not have the price in Confed Then I asked the price in silver &amp; he said $10 then in gold I had a $20.00 &amp; he said 4.50 &amp; I gave him my gold &amp; took the shoes to my friend. On a certain day about the last of 64 we got word that we were just 17 miles from Bottenrough and that the next day would bring us to the lines and the outposts of the fedral army. Arrangments to camp were made a hog killed and all lay down to rest Duing the night the better part of the crowd was with my self with the nois of a storm as we thought but that was soon vanished when the nois came near &amp; near &amp; finally a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">tirailade</unclear> of balls passed ovr our head &amp; some lodged in the camp</p>
        <pb n="83" facs="0012_002408_000201_0083.jpg" xml:id="d4e511"/>
        <p>fires &amp; in a twinkling were surrounded with bawling mob and being cursed &amp; shot at at evey turn or motion we could mak It was no use we thought the Jay hawkers had us in only a question of time befor we would look up a limb It was a perfect hubbub &amp; the sigh So many horsemen &amp; they shooting pistols at each man who showed his head above the ground. Eventually a boy in our ranks got to his feet without a shot &amp; called out that we were fedral prisoners on the way to the ferdal lines &amp; the office of the bitalion took notice and quieted his men so that explanations could be mad I was soon found out that thought the other the Jayhawker and a mistake had</p>
        <pb n="84" facs="0012_002408_000201_0084.jpg" xml:id="d4e515"/>
        <p>been made. It seems the officer of the Union troops had been sent out to catch a lot of these cut throats &amp; had been led to believe he had found a lot of them Hurry been attracted by our fires in the swamp One of our men was slighly wounded was about all we suffered aside from the scare we had all that saved us was being flat on the ground &amp; the others on horseback in a full view the officer made all appoligys after he knew how matter stood I did not sleep any more until the out lines of the fedral troops were reachd the next day No one but the one who has tryed it can tell the feeling he has to come through such <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">avet</unclear>
               <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">kercance</unclear>
            </p>
        <pb n="85" facs="0012_002408_000201_0085.jpg" xml:id="d4e523"/>
        <p>After stopping on the out post to rest a day or two were taken or went across the Missippi I was more than glad to get out particularly the long moss of the swamps It made me feel like every body had died long ago and the moss was a reminder of the fact To see the sun going down as if through this southern moss gave me a chill It did not take war to make it look like a graveyard to me It is said the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">moss</unclear> is beatiful and so it is growing on a green magnolia but to have it by the acre or by the mile is anothr thing We now stood on the rolls as paroled prisoners to await a regular transfer when that would no one could tell &amp; on to New Orleans was our next place before we could get money cloths on</p>
        <pb n="86" facs="0012_002408_000201_0086.jpg" xml:id="d4e530"/>
        <p>Arriving we at once found the soldiers home &amp; filled up with bread &amp; coffee &amp; then out to see the town and woeful sight we were in fact we had not realized how bad we appeared until we began to mix with decent people It was a month of this kind of waiting our papers had to go to washington and be inspected before a cent could be had for love or money if we had of had it. It seemed to strike the offices as very strange that some of Shermas army could be in that place &amp; at first we were not looked upon as all right &amp; that they were some trick in it all I could say nothing for any othr man as to his standing On the rolls but as to my own I could easly tell the whole story I knew</p>
        <pb n="87" facs="0012_002408_000201_0087.jpg" xml:id="d4e534"/>
        <p>that I was marked on the rolls as absent sick or wounded &amp; they at the Regt knew nothing as to how I happened to be in Ga on a freight train &amp; after in the hands of the enemy. The Dr at Lookout could only say that I left on a pass for Chatt &amp; had never heard from me I suppose Eventually my credential came and was all right &amp; I was allowed to draw money to purchase cloths food &amp; c The pay department showed which was the truth that I had not been paid in full for the last twelve months &amp; threfore I Icould have all the money I wished up to $1500. A moths or so at N O and was ordered to my department when I left it in the 23d army corps but when I would find it was the next moved &amp; I was given papes &amp;</p>
        <pb n="88" facs="0012_002408_000201_0088.jpg" xml:id="d4e538"/>
        <p>to Louisville Ky on arival at Louisville found that may changes had been made and that my Regt was not in the South in the direction I had left but was doing duty in NC Fort Fisher My destination was then changed to Annapolis Md parole camps I was anxious to learn of wat had become of my brother who had been by my side for over two years &amp; my father who was <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">GM</unclear> of one of the Tn Regts The 6th under Col Joe Cooper of Tn &amp; also of home &amp; friends The trip to Annapolis was a pleasant one but very cold beng in March and a very bad one at that I had not more than got settled at camps at the above place when I accertained the camps were being filled up with the fedral soldiers coming</p>
        <pb n="89" facs="0012_002408_000201_0089.jpg" xml:id="d4e546"/>
        <p>across from N &amp; S Carlina &amp; from the different prisons south many hundred of starved and ragged prisoners &amp; many who had been in prison for moths &amp; some for years Andrsonville the most noted as to <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">priation</unclear> and numbers being some 40,000 These men were being landed by the ship Road &amp; had to be moved further. So that more could take their places. So I with a Lieut who was like myself on parole waiting to be exchanged or for papers to again take our places inthe Regt was ordered to take charge of these people who were being moved to Camp Chase Ohio Columbus, This was a new experience taking charge of 200 starved &amp; weak men half of them would hardly make a shadow &amp; all the way we could keep them from eating them</p>
        <pb n="90" facs="0012_002408_000201_0090.jpg" xml:id="d4e553"/>
        <p>selves to death was to keep them up close in the cars &amp; feed them as you thought best not wat they wished This was all right while all was in the cars &amp; <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">viewing</unclear> The trouble came when near Weeling W Va had to move them out &amp; across the Ohio to anothr train and in doing so passed through a town which they about cleaned up every thing in sight which was to eat The train had to stop for a time and all the way we could get them out was to move the train a mile or so out of town that brot the most of them After reaching Camp Chase &amp; making report was short some 12 men Some may have ran away but the most sane ide was they eat them</p>
        <pb n="91" facs="0012_002408_000201_0091.jpg" xml:id="d4e560"/>
        <p>selves to death In fact I had two in the cars who gotten too much of boild eggs &amp; died from over eating I was glad to turn them ovr to the proper officer and be clean of such charge Camps were some 4 miles from the city and I thought I had seen enough of such and made arrangment to stop in the city &amp; report at camp at regular time. After being at this place about a month the war department sent me a furlough for 30 days giving me a chance to visite home if I desired</p>
        <pb n="92" facs="0012_002408_000201_0092.jpg" xml:id="d4e564"/>
        <p>take it all in a Tenn and soldier in Shermans Army And from Alastater from N O. That seemd to stump him a man in the crowd asked me if I was out of those Browlow Brigades. It seems they all knew Brownlow of <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">work</unclear> state of Tenn. Yes I said I was one among the 30000 from that state at this juncture I unbuttoned my overcoat and took it off caresley threw it down on the bench This made them all open their eyes as any cept <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">rerifore</unclear> was bright &amp; new. I then began to ask a few questions and to know if certain persons giving there name had moved from Tn within the last year. It seemed my friends if in the town were not well known at last one of them did remember of the men coming to the town After finding out the locality asked himif he would take a note for me to the people</p>
        <pb n="93" facs="0012_002408_000201_0093.jpg" xml:id="d4e574"/>
        <p>which he did &amp; soon he was off with the note to my sister Ms <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">Grees</unclear> when the note was read which was the right party she could not be brought to believe any thing of the kind as the last any one had known of me was a scrap of paper left on the railroad beond Dalton but the writing &amp; signature looked good &amp; then being as you many say in the city jail. It only took her breath a short time to verify the truth of the matter and she came with all hast. My fine &amp; cast had not been paid for the reason I had all my money in a belt next to my skin and to get at it thought to take a room at Hotel but none of this was now necssary as I was hauled away in quick ordr &amp; met my friends Two of them being the same that went to the battle Chickmagua a year before I remained with them <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">veatel</unclear> my brave was</p>
        <pb n="94" facs="0012_002408_000201_0094.jpg" xml:id="d4e584"/>
        <p>then back to Springfield and on to Indianappols Carthage was a noted place as it was where the moment started out and from these came the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">morman</unclear> church <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">crtaugh</unclear>
            </p>
        <pb n="95" facs="0012_002408_000201_0095.jpg" xml:id="d4e593"/>
        <p>and <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">Rasecrawe</unclear> was soon found back to Chattanooga with a pail of his <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">any</unclear> still Lookout Mountain.  My night with a this was left <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">schind</unclear> and after many fight back &amp; forth sliped off the mountain under cover of the fog from the river and came into chattanooga also.  After a short stay in Chatta was <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">stalsrod</unclear> guarding the river at Caltin Port and from <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">shot</unclear> port to Kingston passing <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">rife</unclear> the river <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">bu</unclear> both Sid and Longstreet on south side are making in the direction of Knoxville where <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">Burnside</unclear> was in command.  Only stoped at Kingston my birth place one night and on to Loudon where a stop was made of a day or two guarding bridge and sid the mean time Longswtreet had <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">woist</unclear> Knoxville and got badly whipped from Loudon to <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">sined</unclear>.  Just after the battle and on up to Newmarket Jefferson Co. where we wintered and a viry cold winter it was.  This the end of the Chatanooga Campaign.  Nothing of importance until next April 1864 Having been under <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">Goin</unclear> Sherman, army at Cleaveland <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">Lm</unclear> and very soon after leaving Cleaveland.  Met the enemy at Blue Spring and moving fight began which continued almost daily and in the begining of May 64 a junction of Sherman's army and <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">Schofield</unclear> was <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">uiad</unclear> near Dalton GA army and <gap reason="indecipherable" resp="Hutson"/>
            </p>
        <pb n="96" facs="0012_002408_000201_0096.jpg" xml:id="d4e642"/>
        <p>Creek Gap Sherman thorowing a large force through the Gap including Seofield Corps and met Johnsons army intrenched on the hills near the town this was on the 13th May May Right as well as the whole army lay in battle line the whol night with arms and accotements on at daylight not moving 14th found all ready &amp; the two Skimmish lines fireing away at each other and just beond the two lines in the woods could be seen the earth works of the enemy Confederate army and the 2d works just beond that and the contending lines of soldiers were not more than 1/2 mile about 9 oclock the order was to march on quick time towards the works which could be seen across the field marched at night sholder shift <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">awtils</unclear> the top a rige the field was gained at this point a perfect blaze of shot &amp; shell such that no one can describe then to charge down &amp; acros muddy branch and up to the works in the woods. Quiet reigned until the crest of the hill in the field was gained and a glance back just at that time was a beautiful sight line after line coming up in as regular order a terror to behold as in a second of time the smoke shot &amp; shell belched forth from those woods and the earth seemed to tremble but on we went and in less time than it takes to write it we were into the first works and a part passed over between the two and at this point the adjuntant ordered back into the works which had been taken but hard to hold</p>
        <pb n="97" facs="0012_002408_000201_0097.jpg" xml:id="d4e649"/>
        <p>and a cross fire was in this particular point. At this point and between the two Confed earth works is where I recd the wound through right arm It was a storm of lead &amp; Iron Fially back to the ditch as ordered I could begin to count the damage which I did not amounted to much but finding that I was growing sick one</p>
        <note type="transcription">The following text is written between the two lines and continues up the margin of the page.</note>
        <p> but while I was waiting a ball came into the ground nearby &amp; nearly coverd me <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">cedth</unclear></p>
        <note type="transcription">The preceding text was written between lines and along the margin of the page.</note>
        <p>of my men came to go out with me for attention To accomplish the trip out the same ground had to be goneovr that was passed in getting in but with the half of my man by name (Byrd Card) after getting into the little Vally Byrd could not stand to go slow &amp; I could not go fast so he left me &amp; went for the woods I stoped in the hale of shot &amp; shell behind a large tree but eventually got out safe and had the ball extracted &amp; was as I thought all right again and was for a couple of days when ordrs came for all noncombatants to report at train for Chattanooga. (The battle began Saturday 9 oclk ended Monday morng) Sherman had out generald Johnson &amp; the army going forward &amp; the cripples going back &amp; dead on field Arrved at Chattanoga and on to Lookout officer hospital remained about one month when permit was granted by request me &amp; one other visit to Chattanoga I had been paid my whole intention was to go front &amp; the Dr would not</p>
        <pb n="98" facs="0012_002408_000201_0098.jpg" xml:id="d4e662"/>
        <p>release me only to visit and return if I liked if not reaim in Chattanooga at the hospital &amp; needed may things as all my clothing except that I wore was in Ga with the wagon train After procuring these things thought to get train for the front although permission wasonly to Chattanooga buy successful a corn train would go out at 4 PM June 18th &amp; in that my partner and my self crawled through into the car Nothing to do but take it easy and that we did until about two oclock the next morning when we were awakened by the wreck of the train and the engine down in thewoods &amp; a hale of balls coming into the car which we were in and a very great crowd out side This was enough we were in the hands of the rebels and no chance of escape It was thought best while the fight was going on outside to get down in among the sacks of corn and await developments which was done &amp; money changed from the pocket to boots &amp; very soon the doors were thrown open &amp; in came our captors ordered us up &amp; out but not before the they had put us through and got all that was loose annd I lost all I had bought that day and some that which I had before my Hat remaind on until out of the car and swapping of Hats begun as the first man struck me got a good one as he said but anothr saw me &amp; dark a in was took it for granted I had a</p>
        <pb n="99" facs="0012_002408_000201_0099.jpg" xml:id="d4e666"/>
        <p>A Preminition. While in line &amp; just before the change one of my men came to the ordely &amp; said that he would go in but would not live on over the fight. the sargt prefered to detail him on other duty but here fused to take it &amp; got his death wound in 30 minutes afterB Daylight revealing a change of the crowd prisones that would have brought a howl of laghter in any other position Ludicous was no name for it 25 men some with suits hanging on some too short some with shoes &amp; others without &amp; some actually without anything but underware As it happened by one of this sort I was marching &amp; he complained that if he had his boots would be all right. The offier returned his boots as they were to small for the man who had them. From this we became acquanted &amp; he told me he was one of Gen Joudahs staff. Gen Judah being our bregade commander at Rassaca a month before He was in light marching order at this time &amp; no mistake We came to a creek soon after which was swollen &amp; deep &amp; asked him to ride on his back across the stream as I was just out of hospital &amp; then I had about $400 in my boot that I could not tell him of at the time With his consent I got onto his back with my feet out though it was waist deep but he had not gone far before he fell &amp; threw me off I got up and waided out. &amp; made complaint that I had a gravel in my boot that I stop to take it out pulled off &amp; found money &amp; all out but took it all up togethr again the bills were large amts &amp; did not make much show I</p>
        <pb n="100" facs="0012_002408_000201_0100.jpg" xml:id="d4e671"/>
        <p>Prison. The prison Castle Morgan situatd on the bank of the Ala River We were just taken to the office of the prison Registered and all valuables which you may have is left with the office and you are serched my money was still all safe &amp; I did not know what to do. To give it up would be a risk &amp; to keep it about as bad &amp; they did not find it in the search We were then taken to the prison where about 3000 were sweltering with the heat This was not for long as the officers were offered a parole of a part of the town which was thankfully recived Incident After having been at <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">Cahaboloe</unclear> were sent to Enterprise Miss and passing through Selma I asked to getsome Lincoln Coffee My guard told me that some could be had at the market and we went down made enquries and the lady said her coffee was $3.00 for Cup I told her would take $9.00 worth and drank 3 cup coffee The guard found 3/4 lb which I could not then buy as the lot would cost $16.00 we dubbed inand made the purchase</p>
        <pb n="101" facs="0012_002408_000201_0101.jpg" xml:id="d4e678"/>
        <p>At Louisville I had notice which canged all my formr anticipations and that was that my Regt instead of south of Svierville was then at Fort Fisher NC This changed any thought of going south &amp; an order was handed me to proceed to Annapolis Md In getting any transportation I ask that I may have a few days off the line of the order starting from Indianapplis Ind This was readly given me and when I reachd that place would branch off and look up some of my kins &amp; friends said to have vaguely to have gon west to Carthage Ill. Indianapplis at that time was considered a pretty hard place &amp; may soldier had beens and bagged &amp; robed. I got in about 4 in the eveng took a meal at the Hotel &amp; paid for it soon after as I would take a train for the west but did not know what train to take &amp; could not find my place on the map. All I did know was I had 6 days that I could use as</p>
        <pb n="102" facs="0012_002408_000201_0102.jpg" xml:id="d4e682"/>
        <p>I <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">beconed</unclear> while around the Hotel a common soldier becond me to step aside that he wishe to say something to me All of which I told him he could say on where he was. His story was that he knew of a party that was waiting for me &amp; would if they had the chance sandbag me He said he was then on duty with his Colonel who had him treated just that way a night or so before &amp; had caught what was said about me accidentally. I took care to not be sandbaggd &amp; left for the west not knowing where I was going but touse up 6 days allowed meAt midnight a Sleepr was the best &amp; by moing was fast on the way to Chicago cold then look up theplace I was giving. At 4 Oclock the next day I was at Chicago &amp; looking up where I was bound for &amp; very soon I found that I was very much out of line and had crossed the State without need of it. Carthagewas very much</p>
        <pb n="103" facs="0012_002408_000201_0103.jpg" xml:id="d4e689"/>
        <p>the other direction and I would have to about cross the state again to find it. This did not disturb me as I got to see Chicago and the trip to Carthage was a very uncertain quantity anway My train did not leave in my direction until 12 ocl at night &amp; I thought it best to see a play during the time was waitg but it was a question could I find a theater and find my way back as my knowlge of the city was a mith &amp; had nevr been deepr in the city than one square at the hotel. I took the risk and found the place. It seemed to me the play was being drawn out &amp; my time to be considered was getting short so before the end of the play I was out to hunt my train and for the life of me did not know which diretion to take to my train </p>
        <pb n="104" facs="0012_002408_000201_0104.jpg" xml:id="d4e693"/>
        <p>All aboard for Carthage and after traveling that night and 1/2 the next day Carthage was reached or at least the station to get off I looked around for a time viewed the muddy road and the town a mile away and about decided to take the next train towards Inda &amp; not go to the town but aftr considering made enquiries of the agt and learned they would not be a train before 9 oclock the next moring This settled it I had to tramp through the mudd to the town In fact my idea of my friends a brother n law &amp; some cousins being their was so uncertain that I was rathr ashamed of myself Coming into the little town my first idea was to get a hotel and make enquires for my people Met withan old man who told me no such men as I naimed him in the town I asked about a hotel &amp; he pointed out to where to go. Soon aftr in crossing the street a boy about 13 yrs old came behind me and in passing meused some language which I considerade an insult to me &amp; my calling I caught him by the should and gave him a shake</p>
        <pb n="105" facs="0012_002408_000201_0105.jpg" xml:id="d4e697"/>
        <p>he yelled like a mad man and the pliceman was on me at once I had on an overcoat which did not show that I had any rank in the army but they could see that I was a soldier &amp; made it worse for me I should have said in the first place this town as being one of the worst session towns in the west. afraid to take a hand where they belongd South, but lay back in the rear giveing the fedral soldies a stab in the back at every opperandy. The officer seemd to be rather dictatinal and let me away with the boy as company I was taken a part the way though town and led into building on the square &amp; before I suppose the reader may case was reported by the officer as an assault on a town citizen of Carthage The recorder asked me some questions as to where I came from I ansered from NO &amp; previous Alabam &amp; to that previous to that in Shermans army &amp; what state did come from. I answered Tenn. This was a little too much for him as he could not</p>
        <pb n="106" facs="0012_002408_000201_0106.jpg" xml:id="d4e701"/>
        <p>The day was a bright May moring and afte an hour of this kind of work the sun was obsured by the smoke and buring of the dry leavs but this did not detur him but on he went coming up back of the lineas now formed he road among the dead on the field &amp; in one case in particular saw a Confederate who seemed to resemble his son but from his horse he could not say what he thought might be the truth This did not satisfy him so he got off and examined the soldier carefully even going &amp; turning up his mustach. Henry by the way had a short uppr lip owing to some cut he had when small There was so much dirt and sand on the soldier that he could not satisfy his mind even aftr he had made the examination It was found aftr that Henry had nevr been in that army &amp; so his fears were groundless</p>
        <pb n="107" facs="0012_002408_000201_0107.jpg" xml:id="d4e705"/>
        <p>Speaking of my father. At the time he entered the army was 63 years old and had on appoinetment as Rgm in the 6th Tn bregaded with my own and beside this my brother WBS &amp; was orderley sargt of my Co and was in the fight This was why my fahter was so interested in the turn of affairs &amp; not only this but he had an other son Henry O who was known to be in the southe army. and possibly in front of us. After I had mounted my horse for a time found could not ride &amp; had him take his horse &amp; I would foot it back to the gen Hospital. now as I am speaking of my fathr. He was uneasy and had got to think it possible his other son Henry was then on the opposite side in this battle but to ride into that fight was something no one would do for a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">inpleasure</unclear> trip</p>
        <pb n="108" facs="0012_002408_000201_0108.jpg" xml:id="d4e712"/>
        <p>In 1860-61 we had an organzation of homegaurds in our town and when the southern troops came in that business had to stop and that at once during the time 61 a good number started for Ky and I was one of the number made a days march into the mountains and spent the night on top of what they call Mountain Nouse by the next day quite a number was over the war fievor &amp; in time abandoned the trip for the reason CS were between us and Ky. After disbanding I was left alone at a mountain cabbin where I remained for some days I could not return home without much danger and could not go forward for the same reason After a time I determined to go back and followed the woods for some six miles. On reaching home found that the house was filled with CS officers on the way to Ky but after dark I ran across the road into my mothers room where I remained up to 11 oclock &amp; she turned me out at the back door &amp; I passed into the corn field and to an old outhouse where I remained until the next night a very dark one for travil but I made 16 miles from home &amp; hired out as a tanner &amp; kept quit for time After being at that place about a month and finding that it was not possible to make my way on to the feral lines as the mountain passes were all week guarded with troops from Cumberland Gap &amp; Knoxville I openly returned home while the times seemed to be more quiet and an order had been issued that Union men should not be mounted if they would quietly return &amp; remain at there vocations. On my return home it so happened that ACS Batalion was camped near by and among the solders I had a friend who I wished to see &amp; made a visite to on man the camp at first and failed to get in through the picket line &amp; was returing home after night when a squad of horse men followed up and made me a prisoner with two others who were in company with me It was an easy matter to get in this time as well as to find my friend I was being guarded when my friend found me and certainly he was surprised to see me in that position and asked me how it happened as he remarked that he had been out the same day to see my mother but did not recollect seeing me I told</p>
        <pb n="109" facs="0012_002408_000201_0109.jpg" xml:id="d4e716"/>
        <p>him that I happened not to be in while he was to see her. In fact I had not arrived from my trip to the Tenn Mountains. Meeting of my friend was fortunate as he vouched for me at once but that did not satisfy the commander and we were all drawn up and courtmartialed &amp; but for the want of proof would have all gone to Knoxville jail together</p>
        <pb n="110" facs="0012_002408_000201_0110.jpg" xml:id="d4e720"/>
        <p>In the summer of 61 a small number of Union men who had befor this time been in an organzation known as home gaurds started for the Union army through the mountains of Ky I was one of the party and after a days march a hault was calld &amp; a caucus held and was decided that the company could not reach the Fedral army as the passes were too well guarded to make the attemt at that time This left me in a very bad fix as I could not return as the jail was awaiting me if I should go back and seemed could not go forwards The Co broke up and</p>
        <pb n="111" facs="0012_002408_000201_0111.jpg" xml:id="d4e725"/>
        <p>despersed some to their homes and others to hiding places in the mountains I found a small cabbin and remained at it for a day or two This was too slow so I determind to take the risk and go home even at the risk of being taken I bid the lady of the house good by late in the afternoon &amp; took the brush for hom &amp; to keep in the woods until I could communicate with friends or some of the family. This I did at a time our home was filled with Confed officers in the house and the soldiers camping round on their way to Ky I maged to meet my mother in room &amp; surprised her very much and made her very uneasy but I told her I would soon come again and after remaing with her until about 11 oclock at night she let me out and I went </p>
        <pb n="112" facs="0012_002408_000201_0112.jpg" xml:id="d4e729"/>
        <p>to an old house back on the farm &amp; remained in that until dak the next night when I walked out &amp; walked the road for 16 miles to a friend where I remained for a month or more I had thought from this point I could get through the mountains but found the chance for me had passed. &amp; if I got though would have to go back home &amp; start from that part of the country The day I determined to go home a major ofthe Confed army stoped for dinner at the place I was at on his way from Cumberland Gap to Miss. &amp; proposed for me &amp; as he would pass our place to ride a led horse he had with him I accepted the proposition and road with him the 16 miles home I was not at home but a few hours until one of my old friends came on and asked me to accompay he and another to the camps of a Battalion who cavelry camping some two miles</p>
        <pb n="113" facs="0012_002408_000201_0113.jpg" xml:id="d4e733"/>
        <p>It was about the 18th June 64 that I left the Hospital on Lookout Mountain with a pass for 3 days at Chatta as I had been examined as to condition to go front &amp; told that my stay at Hospital would be about 3 months &amp; this pass gave me an opportunity of making arrangments to go to the front &amp; befor night I was in day car at hind end of a long freight train going south as sick &amp; wounded as I was After I had been captured &amp; charged my blue for gray &amp; brown Started &amp; being sick I was allowed to hang to the tail of some of the guards horses when going up hill</p>
        <pb n="114" facs="0012_002408_000201_0114.jpg" xml:id="d4e737"/>
        <p>The first stop made was at Cane Springs Ga which seemed to be a very nice little place &amp; here our guards were sent back &amp; the prisonrs to continue the march south under home guards old men &amp; boys. I was hopeful that an opportunety through this change would give me a chanced to made my escape and as soon as on the road picked out my man to fill of him on the subject In the first place I told him my conditon a very sad one &amp; he agreed with I then asked him to let me hold to his stirrup strap &amp; then I could keep up This was all right with him. In this way I could talk to him &amp; soon found out he was a Tennan &amp; was not a very good sou soldier. After a time I seemed so bad to keep up that the guard next to him let me on his horse &amp; then I could talk with him &amp; before nighfall had made my arrangment toescape</p>
        <pb n="115" facs="0012_002408_000201_0115.jpg" xml:id="d4e741"/>
        <p>The young ladies caught up with the army the next moring Sept 18 I believe and on into the city and the army to the field as <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">RasiCause</unclear> was being pushed back with all his army into Chattanooga This was a fearful timeto be as they were in the midst of a retreating army It was in Apl 83 that the division which my Regt was attached we were orderderd from the battle field at Murfreesbroo to Carthage on the north side of the Cumberland river and some 75 miles above Nashville where we remained in camp until about the middle of Sept when we were ordered in the direction of Chattanooga. Called at McMinnville one day from McMinnville a forced march was ordered and beingon the eve of battle Chichmagua At McMinnville two young ladies Ellen &amp; Kate Hilks my cousins conceved the idea of crossing the mountain with me and to thire friends at Kingston and to get them in readiness and to start with the Brigade was not passible so I remained behind to procure ambulance or conveyance which I did and with them started on the run with a four horse ambulance caught up with the rear at the foot of the mountain below Beroheba springs at night and the road to the top filled with soldiers and trains making the assent slow We reach the top <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">regained</unclear> one 1/2 the night and when we reached the army incampment there</p>
        <pb n="116" facs="0012_002408_000201_0116.jpg" xml:id="d4e751"/>
        <p>was no betting where to go as the woods were full of soldirs camping every where&amp; no place in which I could get lodging for the two ladies in any case but as luck would have it a small cabbin was procured for them and I bedded in the wagon for the night. 5 Oclock found the divison up and beging to move out as dispatches had been relived to push on for Chattanooga This required all to bein place in line. and the two ladies were placed in the care of Lieut Bacon of my Co who was at that time on sick list and I retured to my duties in line of march The next night camped on the mountain the ladies going with the Col wife who was along with the army The next day ambulance broke down and abandoned side saddles were procured and they were put horse back and ambulance side tracked a halt was made at Tenn River in order to put in pontoon bridge. The ladies camping with us on the field. The army crossed about dark and they found place to stop wayside house but the army pushed on during the night to the battle of Chickamague</p>
        <pb n="117" facs="0012_002408_000201_0117.jpg" xml:id="d4e755"/>
        <p>During the occupation of Cumb<gap reason="indecipherable" resp="Hutson"/> in Aug 62 a raid was put into sent from the Gap <gap reason="indecipherable" resp="Hutson"/> was <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">sew</unclear> as vallies &amp; roads where a small confed force was camping Two Regts was sent out on this 5th &amp; 6 Tenn as it was tobe a secret move the great part of the march was made during the night but landing on the north bank of Clinch River about daylight the 6th Regt went up the river to a ford and 5th to swim at another point this order to swim a Regt was a hard one as many could not swim at all Gen Shears came up as our <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">Maj Rose</unclear> was having all to swim who could but did not force men in who could not. So this was disobedience of orders &amp; the Gen in fit of pasion drew his revolver and would have shot the major but for the timely soldirs guns which was leveled upon him and he reconized the situation and drew in could the men permitted to get on the best they could The crossing the river threw the Regt in bad shape and a junction was not made as desired and the Confeds got away through the Gap After taking the camp and eating their din<gap reason="indecipherable" resp="Hutson"/> they had cooked we turned to go back fording river up to your neck to get back on the n<gap reason="indecipherable" resp="Hutson"/> side again and then on back to the Gap</p>
        <pb n="118" facs="0012_002408_000201_0118.jpg" xml:id="d4e774"/>
        <p>It was on the retreat from the evacution Cumberland Gap Sept 1862 which embra<gap reason="indecipherable" resp="Hutson"/> 17 days &amp; nights almost a continuous move and to subsist on the country which ment corn &amp; poor beef one moring as I was very hungry went into small cabbin on the way and their on the table lay a corn cake and the woman at the stove putting in more doe. I sliped the cake under my coat and backed out and loved the bread</p>
        <pb n="119" facs="0012_002408_000201_0119.jpg" xml:id="d4e780"/>
        <p>Jany 1897 </p>
        <p>Born Kingston Tn Jany 13/39 His father Henry H Wiley who was away back in 1825 a merchant at Kingston and also held many responsible offices of the County Roane &amp; also could say that he had at one time for a boarder while at Kingston the noted Sam Houston of Texas <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">fame</unclear> In 1848 his father moved to Winter Gap New Oliver Spring Tn with his family East Tn the subject of this a boy of 10 years old for several years occupied his time betwen the saltworks of Estabrook and going to school At the begining of the war 1861 was 22 years old and at once took part in the Hand gaurds then organizing in this part of the state which was exciteing in the extream as both sides were making companies and drilling and they often came in contact with words if not to arms. This continued until the summer of 61 When Gen Leadbetter Zollicoffer made his head qr at Knoxville and detachments were sent out through the counties of E Ten to arrest Union men and to disarm the citizens of the country. A call was made at my father house and all the arms we had taken Two old shot Guns During the winter &amp; spring of 62 Zollicoffer moved his army from Knoxville &amp; Cumberland Gap to Mill Spring Ky which passed by home and made it very uncomfortable to Union peopl to <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">nwai</unclear>
               <gap reason="indecipherable" resp="Hutson"/>  home and take the insults of th <gap reason="indecipherable" resp="Hutson"/>
               <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">fed</unclear> soldiers <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">nd</unclear> he pressed into the <gap reason="indecipherable" resp="Hutson"/>
               <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">ice</unclear> by then</p>
        <pb n="120" facs="0012_002408_000201_0120.jpg" xml:id="d4e805"/>
        <p>The day after our capture on the train June 64 we were being driven along on foot and the guards on horseback with double barrel shot gun at our backs made it rather irritating at least It was a shabby crowed at best as at that time if we had any clothing at all it was of all colors &amp; shades I was marching by the side of a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">bro</unclear> prisoner who was in very light marching order as a soldier would say All the clothing he could claim at that time was socks drawers &amp; shirt and compared favorably with the other part of the prisoners It came soon so that I asked the favor of riding across the creek a large stream on his back He dident have much to pull off but went in as he was and made the attemt but fell and threw me in. After that he told me that he was Gen Judas Agt Gen Juda was in command of our Brigade at Rassaca I could only take him on his word as he had no insigna of rank and nothing to put them on if he had I felt that I had been much honored to have had the pleasure of riding on the Agt General &amp; thanked him although he gave me a good ducking in making crossing. I had been a little more fortunate in saving some clothing but they got the best part of all I had by some means they got one of my fine guantlet gloves &amp; I had the other the one glove was as good to me but I was afraid to say I had it as then it would be taken from me I bided my time and as we <gap reason="indecipherable" resp="Hutson"/>ched one of the guards said he had <gap reason="indecipherable" resp="Hutson"/>
               <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">ne</unclear> and he <gap reason="indecipherable" resp="Hutson"/>
               <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">wished</unclear> to find the man <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">te</unclear>
               <gap reason="indecipherable" resp="Hutson"/> mate I <gap reason="indecipherable" resp="Hutson"/>
               <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">d</unclear>
               <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">no</unclear> care to tell <gap reason="indecipherable" resp="Hutson"/>
               <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">er</unclear> of his <gap reason="indecipherable" resp="Hutson"/> at last I proposed to <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">much</unclear> he would place a price on it</p>
        <pb n="121" facs="0012_002408_000201_0121.jpg" xml:id="d4e843"/>
        <p>which he at once prposed to pay $10.00 in CS money &amp; the trade was made by him handing up the Ten before I gave him the glove The night or two after the transaction above I had made very quietly a trade with one of the guards to let me out that night &amp; to pay him $100,00 in greenback This money I had in my shirt ristband for safe keeping <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">Mr F E Jr. Wiley</unclear>
            </p>
        <pb n="122" facs="0012_002408_000201_0122.jpg" xml:id="d4e850"/>
        <p>During the summer of 61 the first Sou troops visited Oliver Springs befor that known as Winter gap &amp; this the first live soldier I ever met. The betalion made quite a display &amp; were a fine lot of men. They came for the purpos of taking possesion of the Gap as had been known before taking the name of Oliver Springs</p>
        <pb n="123" facs="0012_002408_000201_0123.jpg" xml:id="d4e854"/>
        <p>as <gap reason="indecipherable" resp="Hutson"/> &amp; 16 <gap reason="indecipherable" resp="Hutson"/> of life did not suit and a move was made to reach the Fedral lines in Ky &amp; with a portion of the home guard spoken of to the no of 30 or 40 men struck for the mountains between the souther soldiers and home guards bush whackers it was not a pleasant trip to make from the stat though with all the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">cicadey</unclear> possible the mountain top was made and a council of war was held to form plans to get through and safe. After two days of raugling the party broke &amp; scattered to the four winds of the earth and the subject of this was left about alone on the top of the mountain This could not last but what to do was the next move. Home was in the hands of the confed soldiers &amp; the house used as a stopping place at all times night &amp; day a place was at length found in the cove of the mountain where a sheltr could be had for awhile. At least a few days of this was enough &amp; to go on acrop the mountain was too hazzardous atthe time &amp; go home was nearly as bad but this was decided upon in the end The trip was made thrgh the woods within the neighborhood &amp; a message to the house but the soldirs were too thick at the time house to venture in but later at night was selected which was accomplished between the the trops this could be for a few moments only as a union man could not remain at home let alone</p>
        <pb n="124" facs="0012_002408_000201_0124.jpg" xml:id="d4e865"/>
        <p>one who had been a renegade for a time After an hour or two started out again.  This time with the confed in the front yard and I going out at the back throgh the corn to an old house in the field. This I occupied that night and the next day while the troop were passing in sight. The next night aftr it got dark started out alone on 16 mil trip to where it was thought a party would pass over the mountan Arrived at sun rise next moring only to find no one going soon &amp; those who had gone was to far away to over take in the mountains This was discouraging but was away family own neighborhood and out of sight of those who knew me remained at this place a month making head qr at Langard in the ridges but this did not suit so at the end of amonth times had quited down so that I might risk going back home and get with a party from that place again As it happened a maj of the confed army took dinner where I was one the day would go home &amp; he profered me a horse which he was bading &amp; a ride home This was good of him but he did not know who I was. Arrived at home &amp; soon aftr the same day two of my friends asked me to take a walk ovr to thecamps a Tenn Batalion which had come in during the day</p>
        <pb n="125" facs="0012_002408_000201_0125.jpg" xml:id="d4e869"/>
        <p>The camps was visited as intended and the picket line &amp; no admittance granted us my two comerads turned and rtraced our steps but had gone but about 1/2 the way when a detachment of soldiers came yelling after us to halt or they would fire on us It had become dark or near so at this time and at the command we all stood still beside the road &amp; the first horseman came up with such a rush that his horse fell and he was picked at my feet or near by in the road we were escorted back to camps and this time got in without trouble. I was very messy as matter stood I could not accunt for my self satisfactorly the last two or three minutes so kept quiet until somthing would turn up I knew I had a friend in the camp if he would come to see me &amp; possibly through him I could get out but the Knoxville Jail looked rather too close to be pleasant, It so happened that my friend Mr Adams had been to dine at my faths the same day &amp; he was in a mood to see that I was all right and as soon as I was brght up he very kindly vouched for me being all right but the othr two men were kept as charges against them were more cerious as complaints against them was that they had been frome home &amp; possiby to Ky soon all three were ordred up to the Col &amp; as no proofcould be made we were all turned loose near midnight. During the winter a month or so times seemed tobe a little more quit but the Confed army</p>
        <pb n="126" facs="0012_002408_000201_0126.jpg" xml:id="d4e873"/>
        <p>was in Ky and had to be fed and that great portion hauld from Knoxville across the mountans to Jamestown and on to fishing creek It so happened that we had a team and that team as I knew would not work the best together but this did not mattr the army had to be fed and it came very <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">convinted</unclear> to order me to take my team divide some of their army wagons loads into mine and start without delay to fishing creek Zollicoffes army twas not long before I was on the road drving team for the Confed army on my way to the battle if not then fought would soonbe so I was told. and anothr fear I had was the bushwhackrs would as soon shoot a union man as any other if he was drving the wagons in that cause. My bad teams came in very well at this time and I wasproud of them to get them up the mountan would take 6 soldies &amp; a corporal to get along this kind ofwork did not suit the office in command &amp; to make matter worse it was snowing and the ground very soft &amp; muddy. So with a great deal of work lots of mud &amp; more <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">swearing</unclear> we had made about four miles of the distance to Ky and at the same time began to meet soldiers from the other direction &amp; thefarthr we went the more we met until the road was full of soldies some on horse back some walking some with heads tied up &amp; in fact the road was full of a retreating army I did not know what it all ment</p>
        <pb n="127" facs="0012_002408_000201_0127.jpg" xml:id="d4e883"/>
        <p>and I was not the kind who they would like to tell of a defeat which in fact it was a retreating army somthing very new to me I could only guess. The officr in charge came up to my wagon among the stragglers and told me my train did seem to work well and he would order me to turn back which was good news for me as I had had about as much of it as I wanted My team on the rturn trip was better and after keeping me for a few days turned me loose and I retuned home but not to remain as was the excitment of the defeat of Zollicoffer and his death made it worse for the union men and they had to take side one way or the other</p>
        <p>Soon after this in March 1862 a party consisting only of our immediate family my fath H.H. A.C. WPH.HH &amp; myself five in all started for the mountains of Ky taking with us two horses and what provisin would last for a few days Nothing of importance happened during that march thrgh the wood only the meeting up with numbrs in all sorts of places in the mountains and augmenting our band to the number of two hundred before we reached Barbersville Ky here we were you might say tured loose in an openfield without any thing to protect us from from the cold march winds. Thousands were coming in anyday and no provision for them but this did not last long as soon organization of Cos &amp; Regmts began and was the 28th of March/62 My Regiment 5th Tn. Infntry</p>
        <pb n="128" facs="0012_002408_000201_0128.jpg" xml:id="d4e889"/>
        <p>was organzed with JasP Shelly Col who was a citzen of Roane Co and an old mexican soldier as well as maj of the 1st Tenn Regt having been a member of that Regt since its organization. My officered as follows Capt J S Hagle 1st Lieut John N Haggard 2d Lieut E F Wiley This was the begning of hard work and kept up for two months Drilling day after day and no rest. In came orders to march and each man thought he was going direct home &amp; no doubt They had come over after the guns and now had them and would go into Tenn &amp; dive the enemy out at once. As it tured out this was delayed for 3 years. and as no one knew the objective point no one cared so it was toward Tnn &amp; the direction was all right stoping one night at Wiliamsbug and then on towards Cumberland Gap and back to old Camp at Burbousville where we drilled as before and very little sign of going to Ten Duing the sumr anothr <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">point</unclear> on the Gap was made and return Tn June Gen Morgans whole force made a move for the Gap some throgh Big Creek &amp; some over the diffent low gaps of the mountan until his whole army of 20000 men were in the neighborhood of the Gap on the 19th June Many could be seen the tents of the Confederate army all ovr the mountains and to look at it was not a pleasant sight to consider among our troops</p>
        <pb n="129" facs="0012_002408_000201_0129.jpg" xml:id="d4e896"/>
        <p>A March long to be remembered 17 days &amp; nights all almost continuous move &amp; through a very wildmont part of Ky over 300 miles with nothing to eat ecept corn either <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">Gritted</unclear> or on the ear as you pleased The sadest part of a soldies duty is to carry out the decisions of court martial and deprive a bro soldier oflife by shooting This occured on March <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">7</unclear> and near the soldirs home as it happened be he being a Ky a</p>
        <p>Before the evacuation the road on the Ky side had been mined in order to blast it off after the army passed out and about the same time the large commissay on top mountan was to be fired the light which could be seen for may miles by the marching army The well spoken of us found a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">few</unclear> years ago was dugsome 40 feet deep by the confed and when they left the gape had filled it up with commisay store mostly Flour but it was soon found very useful to our soldirs The well was mined deep down and when Morgans army left it was filled with arms &amp; al. near the two commands burned The eveing before the evacuation I helped to haul a very large cannon up the mountain with 10 horses only to throw it off the same night into the valley below</p>
        <pb n="130" facs="0012_002408_000201_0130.jpg" xml:id="d4e911"/>
        <p>to Gallipolis Ohio This campaign had been so far made and not a dollar paid to the soldies as Cumberland Gap was <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">inaccesble</unclear> by the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">pay</unclear> master, here the solders got their pay and felt better. After resting up for a time order came to board steam for down the Ohio and in short time landed at Louisville and went into camp the weath was <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">noon</unclear> cold bitter and I was not well having at the time a spell of jaundice by accident my tent was placed in a sink after leaving the boat and that night was a hard storm &amp; rain and in the moring the tent was half way up in water &amp; all hands had to waid out From Louisville the march was to Nasville with horses &amp; ambulances on the way to the front and a few days before the battle at Murfreesboro on reaching Nashville change was made and instead of marching to Murfreesboro was sent down the Cumberland river to catch Forrest This was not easy done with <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">Fifty</unclear> This was in the latter part of Nov 64 and a very cold time Forrest was successful in his raid to burn the steam boats on the shores of the Cumberland &amp; numbers of them wentup in smoke our next point was Murfressbro but the battle was one having been fought while ourcommand was after Forrest</p>
        <pb n="131" facs="0012_002408_000201_0131.jpg" xml:id="d4e927"/>
        <p>The only work of importance left us to do was to bury the dead both of men and anamals which took quite a deal of time as the battle had been fought over three miles of cotton fields &amp; cedar brush. At this place I read my commisson as Capt of Co Having been promoted to 1st Lieut the passed Aug at Cumberland Gap Remained at Murfresbro until Apl 63/ and then to Carthage on the Cumberland where we remaned in camp the whole summ while at this place and in the month of April my brother Al was killed by ambuscade near Hartsville Ten with others who were connected with him in the Sutter busness trading with the army. They were all burned together by the citizens of the country and afterward a stone was placed at the grave by my bro WBH and a part of my Co who visited the place Sept 63/ orders to cross the mountan in the direction of Chattanooga Tn or the battle ground of Chickmague. Stoping a time at McMinnville Tn Here I met with two of my cousins young ladies and and as they had friends in E Ten took the risk to cross the mountan with me &amp; the army something they would not do again as later on would showThe first night at Bersheba had to camp out and in fact a very rough trip as it turned out to be for them.Order on the march came for forced march as a battle was on at Chickmague &amp; it was march night &amp; day until we were on the ground and defeat and rout of the Fedral troops on hand it seemed our arrival could only cheek the rest of the soldirs and the regiment placed in position to do this and do some fighting beside which came on later as they were too may for us to stop</p>
        <pb n="132" facs="0012_002408_000201_0132.jpg" xml:id="d4e931"/>
        <p>At Cane Springs our escort was changed from the Harvey Texas Scouts to another command old men &amp; boys I was soon informed by one of them guarg me that he was a Tenn &amp; was tired of the war I wished to talk to him but this could only be done very ` and not be heard or noticed by the officer but managed to walk beside his horse and have a word now &amp; then After some complants of mine he told his nephew to let me ride I then could talk to him &amp; tried to have him go to Tenn with me but that he was afraid to do and as it was getting late and we would soon be put up for the night I made him an offer 100$ in Greenback to let me out and he proposed to do it &amp; told me he &amp; his nephew would be on guardat 2 oclk that night at that time I was up and stiped to the door with money in my hand and the two leveled their gun on me I took hold of the old mans gun and the other held his shot gun on me I saw the game was up &amp; told him to let me have a drink of water &amp; he said well why did you not say so I dident feel like saying any thing much at that time The next morning I fell in near him again and as soon a I got the chance got his statement of the case &amp; that was the officrs were on the watch for me as they had suspicioned somthing wrong</p>
        <pb n="133" facs="0012_002408_000201_0133.jpg" xml:id="d4e936"/>
        <p>(Top half of page faded) they knew it did not mean towards Tenn but back and when that would be noone could tell The soldies were not in a good humor &amp; so when the ordr came to evacuate being at night numbrs of them deserted and moved for home with their guns. After the army had passed ovr on the Kyside the road was blown up the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">Country</unclear> burnd and the march to Ohio begun without as much as a days rations <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">in hands</unclear> with the Confeds behind and before no chance to forage and but little to forage for It was a ear of corn if you could find it and nothing if you could not. This march continued for Seventeen days and nights pretty near without stopping and after may small <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">mishaps slasses</unclear> of wagons trains &amp; men captured wereachd the Ohio at Greensburgh crossed the river on</p>
        <pb n="134" facs="0012_002408_000201_0134.jpg" xml:id="d4e949"/>
        <p>After <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">arolaade mday.  They day Cusrs were shrmne one on</unclear> either side <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">striaihing</unclear> from the tops of the mountans to away into the valley and on this way The march was kept up and each moment thrughts hear the roar of the Guns on the Gap but that was not to be as the enemy had quietly left the night before and left the tents all standing as they had used them <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">striped</unclear> up with the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">stuck</unclear> The Gap was in our hands without fireing a gun The Gap was in the possessin of the fedral troops until Sept 17th with little to do but go out now and then aftr provison got scarse and fight for a field of corn. The first experience I had was below the Gap &amp; was order by the Col to take a detail of 12men &amp; go down the road for what at that time I did not know but I soon found out as a hundred balls came spatting down around my 12 men and one being killed instantly and anothr shot throgh the arm acannon shot from top mountan our own men The fight was on so the othr 11 men done all they could buthad a small show with 200 on the back of the field and a <unclear reason="illegible" resp="AH">morman</unclear> field at that I was told afterwards I was sent down to draw the fire and I thought I had done it successfully but it took about 1000 men to get it stoped The plan was also to try some new gunnes off the top of the mountain and the first shell they fired a mile away came into the branch not more than ten feet from me &amp; throwing the water on me</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
