<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di_v2.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000599_000236_0000">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Letter,
					<name>Henry Brown</name>
				                    in camp near Spring Hill, to Caroline M. Brown,<date when="1862-03-28">1862 Mar. 28</date>
            </title>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
          <name>Wibking, Lyndy</name>
        </respStmt>
        <author>
          <name type="person">Henry Brown</name>
        </author>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
        <date>2013</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
        </availability>
        <idno type="SPC">0012_000599_000236_0000</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Letter, Henry Brown in camp near Spring Hill, to Caroline M. Brown,1862 Mar. 28</title>
          <date when="1862-03-28">1862 Mar. 28</date>
          <author>
            <name type="person">Henry Brown</name>
          </author>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <note type="collection">Henry Brown Collection</note>
          <note type="manuscript">MS.2117</note>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
        <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
        <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
        <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as "turn page over" have been
						omitted.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy>
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="LCSH">
          <term>Ohio -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives.</term>
          <term>Ohio -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.</term>
          <term>Soldiers -- Ohio -- Correspondence.</term>
          <term>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives.</term>
          <term>United States. Army. Ohio Infantry Regiment, 31st (1861-1865)</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change when="2013" who="Wibking, Lyndy">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
      <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e38">
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_000599_000236_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e39"/>
        <p>One Flag, One Country</p>
        <p>Camp Near Spring Hill</p>
        <p>31th Reg. Ohio Volunteers</p>
        <p>Company A</p>
        <p>March 28th 1862</p>
        <p>Dear wife I seat my self to respond to yours of the 21th It found me injoying good health you said that you ware in trouble the sene you beheld was anough to trouble any body it maid me feel verry bad when i heard that Sarah was dead i had heard it before i got that from you by one of the <unclear reason="illegible" resp="LW">tuax</unclear> i feel verry sorry for thomas in his situation i should feel so if it was my lot as it is his I would like to have the hole of the particulars in your next</p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_000599_000236_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e56"/>
        <p>Now i will say i received your third that Isaiah spoke of in his last it had bin mislaid he also spoke of geting the pictures i sent to you and all so the $5.00 whitch i sent in the letter i hope you will get the ten dollars that i sent by Exspress with Mr Lumm soon and then you must do the best you can with it pay them that neds it the most and them that use you the best now i have wrote so many letters to you that I have nothing new to tell you at present only that we are still at the same place and the talk is that we will stay for some time yet it is hard to tell what we will do</p>
        <pb n="3" facs="0012_000599_000236_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e60"/>
        <p>Now i will just state to you that Thomas said <unclear reason="illegible" resp="LW">Barbery</unclear> wanted her money soon i cant do any thing for it in my fix at present you may tell him that if he can get the money for her that i will make it rite with him tell him that he knows my situation is so that i can not Atend to it at present if I was thare i would attend to it myself i would like for you to see him as soon as you can after this comes to hand let him what i say about it i will stand responsible for what he does Now i shall close my scribling for this time to you still remain your <unclear reason="illegible" resp="LW">thee</unclear> husband</p>
        <p>To C. M. Brown by Henry Brown</p>
        <pb n="4" facs="0012_000599_000236_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e72"/>
        <p>My dear boys A few lines to you now i do sincerly with that you was here About 2 hours to day to see the troops in drill in the field that we are campt you would never forget it as long as you live the men and cannon anuff of that Now george Isaiah said that you and hugh casper marshall was trying to Ketch the old roosters to tye their tails together to see them pull each other About now boys i will have to clse my letter and say good by to you for this time i still reamin Dear Father write soon</p>
        <p>Henry Brown</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
