<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:id="ms0012_001303_000230_0000">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Letter,
					<name>James L. Dodds</name>
				                   in France to Ellen Smith in Jackson, Tenn.,<date when="1918-11-23">1918 Nov. 23</date>
            </title>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
          <name>White, Park</name>
        </respStmt>
        <author>
          <name type="person">James L. Dodds</name>
        </author>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
        <date>2013</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
        </availability>
        <idno type="SPC">0012_001303_000230_0000</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Letter, James L. Dodds in France to Ellen Smith in Jackson, Tenn.,1918 Nov. 23</title>
          <date when="1918-11-23">1918 Nov. 23</date>
          <author>
            <name type="person">James L. Dodds</name>
          </author>
          <extent>7 pages</extent>
          <note type="collection">Smith Family Papers</note>
          <note type="manuscript">1303</note>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
        <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
        <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
        <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as "turn page over" have been
						omitted.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy>
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="LCSH">
          <term>Jackson (Tenn.) -- History.</term>
          <term>Jackson (Tenn.) -- Social life and customs.</term>
          <term>Knoxville (Tenn.) -- History.</term>
          <term>Newton County (Ind.) -- Genealogy.</term>
          <term>Tennessee Volunteers (Football team).</term>
          <term>University of Tennessee, Knoxville.</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change when="2013" who="White, Park">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
      <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e38">
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_001303_000230_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e39"/>
        <p>J.L. Dodds</p>
        <p>Truck Co # 8 = 23 Engrs</p>
        <p>A.E.F.</p>
        <p>Miss Ellen Smith</p>
        <p>111 Hatton Street</p>
        <p>Jackson</p>
        <p>Tennessee</p>
        <p>U.S.A.</p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_001303_000230_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e57"/>
        <p>Vraincourt France</p>
        <p>Nov 23 1918</p>
        <p>Dear Ellen:</p>
        <p>Just received a letter from you. And was real good to here from you. This is some beautiful day just a little cold I can stand the cold if it wont rain.</p>
        <p>You said you would give any thing to know where I am  Well I am going to tell you  I am about fifteen Miles northwest of Verdun in a little town by the name Vraincourt which is in the Argonne Forest</p>
        <p>I know you have read of what the Yanks have done in Argonne  I have been here for the last two months.</p>
        <p>The drive started on sept 25, at 11p.m. I was out in My truck at the time and</p>
        <pb n="1" facs="0012_001303_000230_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e73"/>
        <p>I never will forget that day or that night rathes.</p>
        <p>I had been hauling lumber out near the front lines and the Germans sure were shelling the road where I had to go. </p>
        <p>I had almost gotten back to my Camp when the Americans started there drive  This sure was some fight the Germans had held this forest for almost four years and they were ready for the fight</p>
        <p>However the Americans were to strong for them and they soon began to retreat which they continued until the end of the war  The engineers following the inf real close to repair the road so the art. could be brought up.</p>
        <p>We worked Night and day for some time. I worked for 18 and 20 hours</p>
        <pb n="2" facs="0012_001303_000230_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e85"/>
        <p>and would go in and sleep while some one else would run the truck  I was in L. Co=23= at that time but was soon transfered to Truck Co # 8=23.</p>
        <p>It seems a little funny not to here the Art. firing away Now. But I am glad this thing is over for I am getting real home sick. </p>
        <p>I have been on the front since the 11 of May. We were on the Lorraine front the Luneuelle sect. all the summer. You remember of me telling you about going to a town on sundays that was Baccarat it is in southern France</p>
        <p>We all sure did hate to leave down there was quiet most of the time there. They would get in a little fight ever once in a while  But nothing like they did around here.</p>
        <pb n="3" facs="0012_001303_000230_0005.jpg" xml:id="d4e95"/>
        <p>I thank we will soon leave here  I havent any idea where we will go. But do hope it to some sea port to start home. I am in the first American Army I believe they will be the first to go home.</p>
        <p>I will try to tell you some thing about the country I have seen. We left the U.S. on saturday Night before easter sunday  Landed in Brest France on 13 of april. Were in Brest three days and then left for Bordeaux France</p>
        <p>I mean that is some city I would have liked to spent all My time there but only stayed there about two weeks then moved to Baccarat where I have told you about </p>
        <p>I havent had a chance to see</p>
        <pb n="4" facs="0012_001303_000230_0006.jpg" xml:id="d4e106"/>
        <p>murch of this country only in moving from place to place. There are lots of pretty places to see. I have seen some very pretty places in my moving  I will have lots to talk about when I get home.</p>
        <p>Guess Linn and Harold will write you where they are as the sencor will let us tell most ever thing Now. I know you was glad to see the shows open again. I would like to see any thing they call a show.</p>
        <p>Orr is some poplar man over here. He get letters from Unknown girl from the states most ever day. He has been answering a letter from Bardwell Ky</p>
        <pb n="5" facs="0012_001303_000230_0007.jpg" xml:id="d4e114"/>
        <p>to night. Said he never would get around to see them all</p>
        <p>Guess when you get this will be Christmas  Well just have a good time for me and I will do with out. </p>
        <p>It is most bed time and I have to get up early. So will quit for this time. Write me real often</p>
        <p>With lots of love</p>
        <p>James L. Dodds</p>
        <p>Truck Co#8= 23 Engrs</p>
        <p>American Exp Forces</p>
        <p>Via N Y.   France</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
