<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://diglib.lib.utk.edu/dlc/standards/tei/tei_lite_di.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ms0012_000204_000200_0000">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter, <name>Captain Cornelius Longfellow</name> at Camp Perry, Tenn., to Mrs.
                Lydia Longfellow <date when="1862-12-02">1862 December 2</date>
            </title>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Responsible for machine-readable version</resp>
               <name>Rozema, Laurel</name>
               <name>Dyson-Smith, Bridger</name>
            </respStmt>
            <author>
               <name type="person">
                  <name type="person">Captain Cornelius Longfellow</name>
               </name>
            </author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The University of Tennessee Libraries Digital Initiatives</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Knoxville, TN</pubPlace>
            <date>2013</date>
            <availability status="restricted">
               <p>The copyright interests in this collection remain with the creator. For more
					information, contact the <ref target="http://www.lib.utk.edu/special">Special
						Collections Library</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
            <idno type="SPC">0012_000204_000200_0000</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Letter, Captain Cornelius Longfellow at Camp Perry, Tenn., to Mrs. Lydia Longfellow 1862 December 2</title>
               <date when="1862-12-02">1862 December 2</date>
               <author>
                  <name type="person">Captain Cornelius Longfellow</name>
               </author>
               <title>Letter <date when="1862-12-02">Dec 2, 1862</date> Camp Perry Tennessee
                        to Mrs. Lydia Longfellow</title>
               <date>2006-05-17</date>
               <author>
                  <name/>
               </author>
               <author>
                  <name type="person">Longfellow, Captain Cornelius</name>
               </author>
               <date when="1862-12-02">Dec 2, 1862</date>
               <extent>4p</extent>
               <note type="abstract">In a December 2, 1862 letter, Capt. Cornelius Longfellow of
                        the Company E of the 69th Indiana Volunteer Infantry writes from Camp Perry
                        near Memphis, Tennessee, to his wife Lydia. It discusses buying a Soldiers
                        Memorial, his trip to Memphis from Indianapolis, the possibilities of
                        traveling after the war, the actions of the freed blacks, and his own men.</note>
               <note type="collection">Capt. Cornelius Longfellow Letter, 1862</note>
               <note type="manuscript">MS-2728</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Machine-readable transcription created for the University of Tennessee
						Libraries Special Collections.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Errors in transcription of the printed text not controlled.</p>
            <p>Editorial tags limited to gap and unclear.</p>
            <p>All unambigous end-of-line hyphens removed.</p>
            <p>Catchwords and directional notes such as &quot;turn page over&quot; have been
						omitted.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <bibl>
                  <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
               </bibl>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="LCSH"/>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013" who="Rozema, Laurel">Approximate date of original transcription and transcriber.</change>
         <change when="2013-10-08" who="bds">Migrating
					from P4 to validated TEI P5.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="letter" xml:id="d4e99">
            <pb n="1" facs="0012_000204_000200_0001.jpg" xml:id="d4e100"/>
            <p>Camp Perry Tennessee Dec 2&quot; 1862</p>
            <p>Mrs Lydia Longfellow</p>
            <p>Der wife,</p>
            <p>We are now in Camp Near Memphis Tennessee about 640 miles from home. we had a
                    very Pleasant trip down the Mississippi River. the weather was cold when we left
                    Indianapolis But it is Quite Pleasant here. the air is cool and raw but not what
                    we call cold in the norther. water does not freeze here and the inhabitants say
                    that it never gets much colder here</p>
            <p>I wrote you while I was at Indianapolis and I wrote you on Board the steamer
                    Chancellor forty miles above here on last sunday and I thought I would write now
                    and tell you where we are. I will still write when ever I can it will make no
                    difference to you so I pay the postage.</p>
            <p>When I wrote you last I said I had the headache and I took a chill just after I
                    got done writing and was quite sick that night. But I feel quite well to day I
                    think it was a deep cold I had takin. I forgot to tell you in either of my other
                    letters about Buying what they call a Soldiers Memorial. While at Indianapolis I
                    had them shipped to Richmond in care of William Campbell our old cook. I suppose
                    you have got yours before now</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="0012_000204_000200_0002.jpg" xml:id="d4e114"/>
            <p>I want you to write often as you can and also the Children. send them thick
                    &amp; fast and maybe I will get some of them.</p>
            <p>if ever this war comes to an honourable close I intend to spend one Fall
                    &amp; Winter in Arkansas hunting. I saw as we came down the River hundreds
                    of wild geese and other fowls. and on the Arkansas side there is thousands of
                    acres unsettled where there is plenty of game altogether 
                its a beautiful country I hope now to live to come here on a
                    pleasure trip with you and I intend to do it if we both live (and live
                    together). it is cheap travelling on the Boats and very Pleasant</p>
            <p>The Darkies are playing thunder generally here they have an encampment just above
                    here there is reported to be about three thousand of them and they dont work
                    only when they are paid for it They have some guns &amp; when any of their
                    Rebel Masters come after them they give them their walking papers double quick.
                    they cut wood for the union army. and Uncle Sam pays them for it. and they are
                    just as free as any boddy.</p>
            <p>Our Boys are all in good spirits and mainly well. Henry Reynolds has the Measles.
                    Thomas Cox has sore throat Two noble fellows. they are not dangerous</p>
            <pb n="3" facs="0012_000204_000200_0003.jpg" xml:id="d4e124"/>
            <p>I think I have the best set of Boys in the World. they all treat me kindly. and I
                    try to treat them the same way: it is generally thought here that there will not
                    be much more fighting. the Residents here think that the Rebels will Cave under
                    before long.</p>
            <p>I must stop writing. I have wrote more now than you can read. I expect I forgot
                    and thought I was just talking to you. {Hollingsworth is looking for his wife to
                    come down here to see him. She comes every week you know}</p>
            <p>Give my respects to all. Henry Nickols and Alf Price in particular</p>
            <p>Write often direct to</p>
            <p>Capt Longfellow Co. E</p>
            <p>69th Ind. Vols. Memphis Tenn</p>
            <p>let all read this that wishes to read it and tell them all to write to me</p>
            <p>Yours forever</p>
            <p>C Longfellow</p>
            <pb n="4" facs="0012_000204_000200_0004.jpg" xml:id="d4e144"/>
            <p>inclosed I send you my Kirby Smith Parole I want you to take care of it I dont
                    think I want it any longer</p>
            <p>also Georg Freemans hand his to his wife</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
